<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Barrow players catch lift with fans from Dover after bus breaks down - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Barrow</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/7B28/production/_110782513_mediaitem110782512.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>&quot;You never know what you're going to get on Barrow away days because things never seem to go to plan.&quot;

Barrow's recent history has been eventful to say the least as the Cumbrian club has bounced around the higher echelons of non-league football since last appearing in the Football League nearly 50 years ago.

With the side seven points clear at the top of the National League and seemingly closing in on promotion, surely nothing could go wrong now?

But Tuesday's 740-mile round-trip to Dover Athletic proved to be anything but plain sailing and became an away day that will live long in the memory for the 23 fans that made their way from Holker Street to The Crabble.

It started off well - Barrow manager Ian Evatt bought the 23 sausage and bacon rolls for the team's journey, which began at 10:00 GMT for a 19:45 GMT kick-off in Kent, and the fans got to the ground an hour before the game began.

But then things went wrong...

Having gone behind to Will De Havilland's early strike, Barrow searched for an equaliser and found it when John Rooney - former England striker Wayne's younger brother - slotted home an 81st-minute penalty.

But Michael Woods got Dover's winner with two minutes to go to break the travelling fans' hearts.

&quot;We threw everything at it,&quot; Barrow fan Taylor Nelson told BBC Sport. &quot;We made all three changes and ended up with five strikers up front to try and get something out of the game - and that worked.

&quot;But from that point Dover realised they were able to be less conservative and attack us as we lacked numbers at the back. They exploited it perfectly.&quot;

After getting on board the bus home, the 23 fans had expected to make a quick getaway in the hope they might be back in Barrow by around 0500 GMT and grab an hour or two's sleep.

It was not to be.

&quot;There was a lot of confusion,&quot; Taylor said. &quot;Eventually the message was conveyed that we were having to wait for the team because their coach had broken down.

&quot;We offered them the space on our bus so we had to wait for them to get showered and changed.

&quot;Before they came on we had a brief discussion and said to try to avoid football talk,&quot; added Taylor, who had goalscorer Rooney and team-mate Scott Quigley sitting behind him.

&quot;It was a bit awkward, but we avoided football talk where possible and kept discussions outside football to save any embarrassment.&quot;

With the confusion surrounding how the team would get home there was no post-match food for the players to eat.

That meant a stop at the motorway services as the players bought what any finely-honed athlete would eat after a game - fried chicken.

&quot;We didn't realise they were going to take so long,&quot; joked Taylor.

&quot;We just thought they were going to nip to the shop and get something quick, so we all sat and waited on the coach expecting them to come back rather quickly. But instead we were all waiting for about half an hour as they were queuing up for KFC orders.

&quot;Then there were lots of diversions and that held us up even more - the journey took an hour-and-a-half more than it needed to.&quot;

Eighteen-year-old student Taylor finally got home at 0700 GMT on Wednesday after the bus containing fans and players arrived back at Holker Street 15 minutes earlier.

But there was no time for him to catch any shut-eye.

&quot;I've had no sleep,&quot; he added. &quot;I was straight to college for a politics lesson at 1000.&quot;

Barrow's next game is a comparatively short 550-mile round-trip to Barnet on Saturday in the FA Trophy.

Let's hope the wheels don't come off - either figuratively or metaphorically.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51385914</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Lionel Messi criticises Barcelona sporting director Eric Abidal over interview - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>European Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/C771/production/_110775015_gettyimages-1203989171.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lionel Messi has criticised Barcelona sporting director Eric Abidal for saying players were not working hard under former coach Ernesto Valverde.

Valverde was sacked in January and replaced by Quique Setien.

Abidal, a former team-mate of Messi, made the comments in an interview with Spanish newspaper Diario Sport.

But on Tuesday Messi, 32, responded: &quot;When you talk about players, you have to give names because if not, it gives air to things which are not true.&quot;

Valverde was sacked when Barcelona were top of La Liga.

In the newspaper interview Abidal said: &quot;Many players weren't satisfied or working hard and there was also an internal communication problem.

&quot;The relationship between the coach and the dressing room has always been good but there are things as an ex-player that I could smell. I told the club what I thought and we reached a decision [on Valverde].&quot;

Six-time Ballon d'Or winner Messi responded on Instagram, writing: &quot;Sincerely, I don't like to do these things but I think that people have to be responsible for their jobs and own their decisions.

&quot;The players [are responsible] for what happens on the pitch and we are the first to admit when we haven't been good. The heads of the sports department have to take their responsibilities too and above all own the decisions they make.&quot;

In his interview with Diario Sport, Abidal also said he thought Messi was happy at the club and a new contract for the Argentine talisman was currently being negotiated.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51380481</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Mbwana Samatta: Name the other international Premier League goalscorers - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/13DE7/production/_110738318_samatta_index.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Aston Villa may have lost at Bournemouth, but their new signing scored on his Premier League debut - and created a little bit of history too.

Mbwana Samatta's 70th-minute header made him the first player from Tanzania to score a goal in the Premier League.

Who knows when someone else will join him? For now, he stands alongside 17 others as the only players from their respective nations to have found the net in the Premier League.

How many can you name? We've given you some clues to help.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51344390</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Christian Eriksen: I was the black sheep at Spurs - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>European Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/72AD/production/_110775392_christian_eriksen_epa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Christian Eriksen says he was &quot;the black sheep&quot; at Tottenham for being &quot;very honest&quot; over running his contract down at the club.

Denmark midfielder Eriksen joined Inter Milan for £16.9m last month, ending six and a half years with Spurs.

The 27-year-old's admission he wanted to leave in the aftermath of the Champions League final defeat by Liverpool led some fans to turn on him.

&quot;I did get the blame for a lot of stuff, for being the bad guy,&quot; he said.

His contract at Spurs had been set to expire this summer.

By the time Inter boss Antonio Conte offered an exit route, Eriksen says he had grown tired of the speculation about his future and weary of the finger-pointing from the stands.

In an exclusive interview with BBC Sport, Eriksen outlined his frustrations. In addition, he explained why he feels the treatment he received came because he wanted to be honest, the excitement he feels at joining Inter and Sunday's derby with AC Milan at the San Siro.

Is there a sense of relief to get all the talk of your future over and get playing at a club without all the background noise?

Eriksen: &quot;Yes. England, for the last few years, was very hectic. After what I said in the summer, it was just about 'when is he going to leave?' Every game it was 'Is he leaving? Is he not leaving?' Of course, a lot of people were speaking about it.

&quot;Even the fans you see on the street were like 'Thank you, goodbye and good luck'. But I was still there. It was a bit weird. In my head and for my body, it is good that I am in a new place and I can start again.&quot;

Can you wind back to the Champions League final? That was obviously a disappointing night. (Mauricio) Pochettino raised doubts about your future. You gave the interview when you said you were thinking about a fresh challenge. The conjecture went on for weeks. Did it play on your mind? Did that bother or affect you?

&quot;I wouldn't say it affected me. In England, when your contract is shorter, it is like you have to leave now. You are gone. In the end I played about 30 games that were like goodbye games. It was like 'this might be his last game', 'this might be his last game'. It kept rolling.

&quot;In my head I was ready to try something new but felt if nothing came, I was still ready to play for my place. I was not a different player in that sense. But I was in and out of the team. However, even if I had a four-year contract, this season would have been difficult after the Champions League final.&quot;

It seemed the problems Tottenham had were pushed back to you and your form...

&quot;But that is the thing. If you have a short contract, you will be the black sheep. Of course, I did the interview. I was very honest. I felt I had to be honest. I didn't want to hide like a lot of players do. Everyone is different. I was honest. I wanted to say it out loud.

&quot;I did get the blame for a lot of stuff, for being the bad guy. I read I was the bad person in the changing room, that ever since I said I wanted to leave, it was no good me being there. To be honest, over the last few years, if anything came up, any player would think about leaving but I was the guy who said it publicly.&quot;

Jose Mourinho didn't really settle the situation down. In a very Jose way, he was nice but there was always a 'but'. Did that affect things at all?

&quot;No. When the window is not open, there can only be talk. There cannot be anything concrete. I think Mourinho did well. He could have said 'he wants to leave, so he is not going to play any more'. He didn't do that.

&quot;After I told him where my feelings were and what I would like to do, he told me just to be happy and if I was needed I would play. I was needed in a few games where I did make a difference. It was more as an extra rather than in the starting XI of course.&quot;

When you talk about Tottenham, it does seem to have unravelled very quickly after finishing last season on such a high...

&quot;Yes. It did. The Champions League final was such a special moment. In the history of Tottenham, it was the first time. To be there was so nice and beautiful. But you lose and the next day it is the end of the world. That is how it goes.

&quot;Afterwards it was difficult. People were still sad from the Champions League final when the season started. After you get a few bad results, then you go into a spiral you are not used to and it was difficult to come back up.

&quot;But if you look at the Premier League, there is only one team that is really flying. All the others are trying to find their place, not only Tottenham. Some seasons are like that.

&quot;The history of the last five years is of Tottenham being where they have not been before for a long time. It was not a time to end but, in a way, it just came along which was something we didn't expect and didn't want.&quot;

So we get to January. When did you find out, when did you think, you would be leaving?

&quot;Not until it got serious. In the end it comes down to what Tottenham wants to have and what Inter, or any other club, want to pay.

&quot;In the end you are controlled by Tottenham. You are controlled by [chairman Daniel] Levy. He says yes or no. You try to be as professional as you can be and not to force anything through in any way.&quot;

Was it always Inter Milan? There were a few clubs mentioned. Manchester United were routinely mentioned...

&quot;For a few years but it was never really likely. We did speak to them of course and we did hear what was possible and what wasn't possible. But, in the end, me personally, I wanted a new challenge. To stay in the Premier League would have been an easy solution.

&quot;Of course, staying at Tottenham would also have been a solution but, for me, it just came down to wanting to try a new challenge in a new country. Once Inter came up it really wasn't a difficult choice.&quot;

It is amazing how many former Premier League players are here...

&quot;Yes. And a bit of the English culture straightaway and a bit of the English language. I am not the only one who can't understand everything in Italian. It is funny that so many players have come over - and also at the same club.

&quot;That doesn't happen often. I don't know if it makes it easier. You can speak with them about where you are going to live, what kind of house you are going to look for, what has happened, what hasn't happened. You speak more with them and you can speak the language with them.

&quot;But it doesn't really matter. It depends on the group you come into. So far, it is a very nice group of people and players.&quot;

It is an exciting time to join Inter Milan. They are challenging for the title, have got Europe are still in the Coppa Italia...

&quot;Yes. Historically, it is not that easy to come in January. Everyone is at the same fitness level because they have trained together all season. I need to fit in with how they play and learn the different things they do.&quot;

And this weekend, you couldn't have a much bigger game to play in and any team with Zlatan Ibrahimovic has a bit of star quality about it...

&quot;He brings a name with him of course. And there is (fellow Dane) Simon Kjaer. I have spoken to him, even before, when he was over here and we were speaking to Inter back then.

&quot;He was not that far away at Atalanta. It will be the first time I have played against him so that will be fun. Hopefully we will show where we are in the league.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51380652</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Scottish Premiership team news, stats &amp; selectors - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scottish Premiership</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/4AA4/production/_108180191_fridaypreviews.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Leaders Celtic travel to third-place Motherwell in the pick of Wednesday's six Scottish Premiership fixtures.

Title rivals Rangers host Hibernian, looking to avoid dropping points for the third time in four games.

Aberdeen are hopeful of closing the gap on third when they host St Johnstone, while bottom of the table Hamilton could move level on points with 10th-place St Mirren should they beat the Paisley men.

Second-bottom Hearts bid to make it six games unbeaten when they welcome Kilmarnock, while Livingston seek a sixth straight victory at a Ross County side winless in eight.

Catch up with the team news and statistics for all six of the fixtures and choose your team's preferred XI.
• How Livingston's Lions have found their roar

Motherwell could hand a debut to on-loan Newcastle winger Rolando Aarons, but Charles Dunne, David Turnbull and Barry Maguire remain out.

Celtic's Jonny Hayes will be assessed before the game, while Mohamed Elyounoussi and Jozo Simunovic are back in contention.

Motherwell manager Stephen Robinson: &quot;We have nothing to lose. We are a good side, we have to believe that.&quot;

Celtic manager Neil Lennon: &quot;It's been a good response for the second half of the season. In terms of the goals we're scoring, we're scoring them from different places and we've been ruthless at times.&quot;

Did you know? Celtic have picked up 45 points from the last 48 on offer in the Scottish Premiership (P16 W15 D0 L1), with the only dropped points during this run coming against Rangers back in December (a 1-2 loss).

Rangers captain James Tavernier is set to return to Steven Gerrard's starting line-up, while Greg Stewart is also available. Florian Kamberi will not be allowed to face his parent club, while Greg Docherty is also unavailable to for Hibs for the same reason.

Hibernian will have Adam Jackson back from illness.

Rangers manager Steven Gerrard: &quot;We're ready for Hibs. We're aware they are a good team but they are a side that in the last five weeks we've beaten quite comfortably. The players know what it takes.&quot;

Hibernian forward Marc McNulty: &quot;The manager here, I played for him before, he has confidence in me and hopefully I can repay him. That was another big factor, he took me there and I love working with him and big Pottsy (John Potter).&quot;

Did you know? Rangers have won each of their last three league games against Hibernian by an aggregate score of 10-1.

Aberdeen have no fresh injuries. Craig Bryson has started light training this week.

St Johnstone defender Liam Gordon has been ruled out with concussion. Isaiah Jones has joined the Saints squad following his loan move from Middlesbrough. Drey Wright, Liam Craig and Scott Tanser are all doubts.

Aberdeen defender Ronald Hernandez: &quot;It would be nice to make my debut against St Johnstone. I am waiting for the opportunity. The coach has the final decision.&quot;

St Johnstone defender Jamie McCart: &quot;That's why you want to play in the Premiership, going to places like Pittodrie, better atmosphere, bigger crowds, better standard of football.&quot;

Did you know? St Johnstone have only lost twice in their last nine visits to Aberdeen in the Scottish Premiership (W4 D3), avoiding defeat in their last two such meetings (W1 D1).

Michael Smith has resumed training for Hearts, but fellow full-back Aaron Hickey is less likely to return. Deadline-day signing Marcel Langer could get his first taste of action.

Kirk Broadfoot could make his first start for Kilmarnock since returning to the club on transfer deadline day.

Hearts forward Liam Boyce: &quot;I like playing with my back to goal, getting flicked balls and one touch round the corner, that's how I take advantage of defenders who expect you to hold it up and slow it down and get it wide.

Kilmarnock manager Alex Dyer: &quot;It's important that we go there and show that attitude that we can win the game, especially on the back of the win on Saturday.&quot;

Did you know? Hearts have lost each of their last three league matches against Kilmarnock without scoring a single goal.

Ross County are expected to have an unchanged squad. Callum Morris is working his way back from injury, while Ross Stewart and Michael Gardyne remain out with hamstring injuries.

Boss Gary Holt will assess his Livingston squad ahead of the trip to Dingwall. Dolly Menga, the Angolan forward who was recalled from a loan spell, has started back training this week.

Ross County midfielder Iain Vigurs: &quot;It has been a difficult period but everybody is doing their best. Trying to get that confidence back is key. It's work hard, that's all we can do.&quot;

Livingston manager Gary Holt: &quot;I think they [Ross County] play excellent football, they score goals and they are finding the little risks they are taking sometimes is not getting the rewards they are meriting.&quot;

Did you know? This will be only the third Scottish Premiership contest between Ross County and Livingston, with the Lions winning both of the first two while scoring exactly four goals in each victory.

Forward Seifedin Chabbi, who signed on loan until the end of the season from Turkish Super Lig side Gaziantep, is available for St Mirren.

Defender Jamie Hamilton is suspended for the visitors following his red card against Celtic, and will also miss the Motherwell game on 22 February. George Oakley is out, while Mickel Miller and Brian Easton are doubts.

St Mirren manager Jim Goodwin: &quot;In this particular game, it's that old cliche, a six-pointer. If we go and win it we open up a six-point gap between us and Hamilton, if they come and win then it's game on again, they level up with us on points. So there is no need for us to remind the players or anyone else, how important this game is. It is huge.&quot;

Hamilton midfielder David Templeton: &quot;Everyone is up for the fight and come Wednesday it is a massive game for us so hopefully we can start picking up points and get ourselves up the table to safety.&quot;

Did you know? St. Mirren are unbeaten in four league matches against Hamilton (W2 D2), keeping a clean sheet in each of the last three.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51378175</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>David de Gea: Name the players with 300 Premier League appearances for a single club - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12F4A/production/_110724677_degea_index.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The goalkeeper made his 300th Premier League appearance for Manchester United on Saturday, as they drew 0-0 with Wolves at Old Trafford.

Below is a list of 35 players who have also achieved 300 starts in the top flight of English football with a single club during their career.

All you have to do is read the clues and try to name as many players as you can in four minutes.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51330931</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Hearts: Fans group to take ownership by 'end of April' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Hearts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/CF5F/production/_110778035_15003712.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Foundation of Hearts expects to take over ownership of the Scottish Premiership club by &quot;around the end of April&quot; after confirming it has repaid the £2.5m loan owed to Ann Budge.

The fans' group will take control when Budge hands over her 75.1% stake.

Budge joined forces with the Foundation when she paid £2.5m to take Hearts out of administration in 2014.

Since then, the Foundation's continued financial backing to the club includes £3m towards a new main stand.

Last August, Budge announced she intends to stay on as Hearts' chairwoman and chief executive until at least summer 2021 to assist in the transition to fan ownership.
• Stendel says 'more to come' from Clare
• Budge to stay on as Hearts CEO</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51383726</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Why a potential Saudi takeover holds no issue for many Newcastle fans - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Newcastle</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/EE06/production/_110743906_newcastle.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Billy Cann was a season-ticket holder at Newcastle United for 35 years before he decided he'd had enough.

He had been watching his team since 1969 but when owner Mike Ashley sacked Chris Hughton in 2010 the 63-year-old decided not to renew and many fans have since followed.

Their issues are numerous, but chief among them is an owner who they feel does not match their ambition.

&quot;I don't want to give Mike Ashley any more of my cash,&quot; Cann tells BBC Sport en route to a goalless draw with bottom-of-the-table Norwich City for which he has borrowed a ticket.

That is why news of a potential £340m takeover featuring Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund has been greeted on the streets of Tyneside with excitement rather than any moral outcry.

Newcastle fans have have been promised a new dawn many times before, so they are sceptical about whether it might even happen.

But instead of worrying about a country's human rights record, which Amnesty International calls &quot;appalling&quot;, many of them see it as a chance to rid the club of Ashley, who has been in charge for 13 years.

As Cann, who works on a gas rig in the North Sea, asks: &quot;Were Manchester City's fans complaining when their Abu Dhabi owners took over the club? Now look at their success.&quot;

It is a common view among Newcastle fans, who see football as a religion and feel their club has been left behind as others have tapped into wealth and ambition from across the globe.

The thread that binds the majority of Newcastle fans is their desire to see Ashley leave the club.

Even those who have reservations about a Saudi takeover - and it is a minority view - still want Ashley out.

The final straw for many was the departure of manager Rafael Benitez last summer.

For them, the Spaniard, who has won the Champions League and the Europa League twice with previous clubs, represented a route back to the top and, more importantly, hope for the future.

He walked away, however, because Ashley did not provide him with financial backing he wanted and, as a result, thousands of fans did not renew their season tickets this season. That led to Ashley dishing out 10,000 free half-season tickets in December in order to keep the stadium full.

Ashley will point to record signings in consecutive transfer windows (£20m for Miguel Almiron in January 2019 and £40m signing Joelinton last summer) and the fact manager Steve Bruce almost spent a reported £35m on Lille's Boubakary Soumare two weeks ago before the midfielder changed his mind.

The owner also said in a rare interview last July that he offered Benitez an eight-year contract and &quot;couldn't have done any more&quot; to keep him at the club.

But down at the Dog and Parrot, a stone's throw from St James' Park, host of the NUFC matters podcast Steve Wraith says the way Ashley treated Benitez was &quot;the ultimate act of treachery&quot;.

He says losing so many fans will cost Newcastle not only next term but in seasons to come.

&quot;Fans voted with their feet and think of all those kids whose parents or uncles or aunties have turned their backs on the club,&quot; Wraith says.

&quot;It has the potential to cut out a new generation of supporters. You see a lot of kids now wearing shirts of other teams in the city rather than Newcastle.&quot;

Asked whether that financial loss could trigger Ashley to sell, Wraith says: &quot;You would think so, but I don't think he's a willing seller.

&quot;He's quite happy to milk Newcastle United for every penny he can and to build his sports brands globally. The only thing that will push him out is a ridiculous offer.&quot;

The Saudi bid, which has been led by financier Amanda Staveley and includes the billionaire Reuben brothers, is not short of money.

Yet not all Newcastle fans believe the takeover should come at any cost.

Norman Riley of the True Faith fanzine says some fans will feel &quot;conflicted&quot; by talk of a Saudi-financed takeover whatever the issues with Ashley.

Riley says he finds a lot of Saudi government policy &quot;abhorrent&quot; and would have to &quot;re-assess his relationship with the club&quot; if the deal goes through.

Those who have no issue often mention how Manchester City are backed by Abu Dhabi, which Amnesty also says is guilty of &quot;sports-washing&quot; their country's &quot;deeply tarnished image&quot; by pouring money into the Premier League champions.

It said the country &quot;relies on exploited migrant labour and locks up peaceful critics and human rights defenders&quot;.

Others mention how Sheffield United are owned by Saudi Prince Abdullah bin Mosaad bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, who took full control from Kevin McCabe last year, although he has not been accused of anything similar to the Saudi government.

Lori, who is sat at the back of the Dog and Parrot with her family, can see both sides to the argument.

&quot;Talk of Saudi human rights abuses might not be the first thing that comes to mind, but it does make you think when you look at it in more detail,&quot; she says.

&quot;The fact it doesn't matter for most fans shows the level of animosity towards Ashley.&quot;

As kick-off for the Norwich game is approaching, Alex, a teacher and mother of one, explains how she is also &quot;anti-Ashley&quot; and keen on new investment.

But she also recognises some of the issues raised about Saudi Arabia, including rights for women and the LGBT community.

&quot;It's a difficult one,&quot; she says. &quot;But similar to what happened at Manchester City, if it brings more investment to the local economy and jobs then it's a positive.

&quot;You also have to question our own government's record given recent wars in the world.

&quot;I totally respect people's rights, but perhaps more links with our country might have a positive impact on their culture and society?&quot;

Do most fans feel the same way as Newcastle's?

Wraith says that for many Newcastle supporters, the team's success would override any lingering doubts over the source of a potential Saudi investment.

&quot;That's an issue for the Premier League or the authorities to work out, not for the fans on the terraces,&quot; he adds.

He also says supporters of other clubs would feel the same way, before referencing Manchester City and Sheffield United.

Choosing between Ashley and a Saudi-backed bid must seem a world away for fans of Norwich City, who are owned by former television chef Delia Smith and her partner Michael Wynn-Jones.

Newcastle are a club on a different scale to the Canaries, but it shows it is possible to have wealthy owners who do not cross any moral boundaries.

Norwich supporter Dan said: &quot;I do like the fact we have Delia and Michael in charge. They are big Norwich fans and care what happens. It's a nice family, community club.

&quot;It would be nice to have more money but it's not the be all and end all. Fans mainly care that the team is winning and how much there is to spend, but it's quite concerning what is going on at some clubs and what else owners are involved in.&quot;

Perhaps that is easier to say if you've not been at loggerheads with your owner for the past decade.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51349042</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Sportscene Predictor: Steven Thompson v Jamie Gillan - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scottish Premiership</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/2E98/production/_110682911_dafsd.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Steven Thompson ended the last round against former Ryder Cup golfer Stephen Gallacher with a draw, with both scoring 20 points each.

This week, the Sportscene pundit takes on American football punter Jamie Gillan, who plays for Cleveland Browns.

A correct result (picking a win, draw or defeat) is worth 10 points. The exact score earns 40 points.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51348739</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Tottenham 2-0 Man City: This was no Jose Mourinho masterclass - Jermaine Jenas - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/64A4/production/_110746752_spursbossjosemourinhoandstrikersonheung-min.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The statistics behind Tottenham's win on Sunday might suggest it was another Jose Mourinho masterclass. In reality it was more a story of Manchester City's missed chances.

Yes, in the early stages Spurs looked quite solid and strong, which is the way Mourinho likes to set his sides up in these big games, but City did what they always do and broke them down.

Spurs showed character and hung in there thanks to a couple of big moments - the biggest one being Hugo Lloris' first-half penalty save, which is when they might have started believing this could be their day.

But if City were anything like as clinical in front of goal as they usually are, they would have put the game to bed long before Steven Bergwijn put Tottenham ahead with their first shot at goal after 63 minutes.

I have been involved in games like that before, where my team have ended up winning despite being outplayed for long periods.

You come off thinking 'yes, we worked hard, dug deep and we really deserved to get something' then, after the dust settles and you maybe watch it back, you realise you got away with one, like Spurs did here.

The reality was they were hugely fortunate not to be at least a couple of goals down before Oleksandr Zinchenko's red card gave them a way back into the game, and even then their first goal came out of absolutely nothing.
• 'The VAR has too many mistakes, too many'

Tanganga got told 'you are going nowhere'

I don't blame Jose for playing the way he did against City, because of the way results went when he first took charge of Spurs.

He knew he had goals in his team so he went out and just let them play, and they had some crazy results in the first few weeks when they were winning by all sorts of scores.

That was never going to last. I could feel it coming where, in his mind, he went 'enough is enough'.

He could not trust his team to go out and score goals, especially when Harry Kane got injured, so instead he started setting them up not to be beaten. That was clearly Tottenham's approach against City on Sunday.

Look at Japhet Tanganga at left-back, for example. He was basically told 'you are not going anywhere today', so he had to stay back all game.

It paid off for Mourinho in the end, but Spurs fans will not allow that kind of negativity in every home game.

So he still needs to work on his side's style of play, but of course getting a result this way still has plenty of positives.

Mourinho has been talking a lot about how his players lack confidence, which he probably did not expect when he arrived at the club.

Well, getting through games like this one will give the players lots of belief, and we saw some other important signs too.

Mourinho has sorted out Christian Eriksen's situation, by selling him to Inter, while Jan Vertonghen, another player whose future is uncertain because he is out of the contract at the end of the season, was on the bench.

I looked out on the pitch and there was not a Spurs player out there whose focus I would be concerned about any more. Everyone was playing for the shirt, and giving everything.

Red card will annoy Guardiola more than the misses

I honestly think City just have to write this game off.

From their perspective, I had plenty of experiences like it in my career too, when we did everything we needed to do to win a game. Normally that means you do, and it is especially rare that this City side don't.

Pep Guardiola's teams look to play in a certain way, and they did that. They executed his gameplan to perfection apart from every time they got in the box, which is where it matters most.

Some of their misses were inexplicable, and from players as good as Kevin de Bruyne, Sergio Aguero or Raheem Sterling, who over-hit a simple pass in front of goal.

You could see Guardiola was infuriated by all of that, but at the same time he will understand that it happens. Essentially his team's effort and character and the way they performed was good, and they created enough chances to win the game. They just could not score.

It is Zinchenko's red card that I think will annoy him more, because that is what cost City.

If City had stayed with 11 men, I don't think they would have been beaten. They might not have gone on to win it, but I don't see them losing the game.

Race for top four is wide open

This defeat saw City lose more ground on leaders Liverpool, and the only real race left at the top of the table is the one for the top four.

It is wide open at the moment - one minute Wolves look like they might be serious contenders, then Sheffield United and now Tottenham. Manchester United might come back and have another run at it too.

They are all having a go, but essentially it all depends on Chelsea and Leicester now. The Foxes have had a bit of a wobble but I still think they are too far ahead of fifth place to be caught.

Chelsea, however, have a genuine problem. They seem unable to hold on to leads, home or away, and we have seen the first bit of friction from their manager Frank Lampard with regards to the transfer window and him not getting what he wanted.

Suddenly, Lampard has got a few players at the club who do not appear to be happy - Kepa Arrizabalaga, Olivier Giroud, Marcos Alonso, Willian and Pedro - which is going to have an impact on things.

They all have a big influence in the dressing room, and that could be a problem for Lampard. How much are they behind him to go and get a top-four finish now?

He has backed his young players so far - which is fine - but have they got enough to get him in the Champions League places from here?

I am not sure, so the next few weeks are going to be very interesting.

Results like this will give Mourinho and Spurs more confidence and increase the pressure on Chelsea, who are now only four points above them.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51351514</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Ronaldo, Neymar, Tevez &amp; Hagi: Why 5 February is a birthday jackpot - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/2D75/production/_110773611_5th-feb-bday_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>If you were born on 5 February and you're not a professional footballer, you could be in the wrong job.

It just so happens this particular day is a birthday jackpot in the world of football.

There are not just a couple of big football names who share this birthday, there are actually quite a few.

We'll start with easily one of the best in the business, ever...

Five-time Ballon d'Or winner Cristiano Ronaldo is celebrating his 35th birthday on Wednesday... just days after scoring his 50th goal in 70 appearances for Juventus.

We're used to his routine brilliance but his CV is still stunning to consider - 623 goals in 830 club appearances, plus five Champions Leagues, six league titles and captaining Portugal when they won Euro 2016. And that's just some of his achievements.

And there's no sign of any slowing down.

From one birthday boy to another who's arguably almost as famous...

Neymar, 28 - aka the most expensive player of all time (222m euros)

You might have seen in the news that Neymar has already celebrated his birthday.

The Paris St-Germain striker hosted a lavish white-themed party at Parisian nightclub Yoyo, on Sunday, with a host of celebrities and fellow players including Edinson Cavani, Marco Verratti, Angel di Maria, and Memphis Depay among those on the guestlist.

A day later it was announced he would miss PSG's match with Nantes because of a rib injury.

From one South American forward to another...

Boca Juniors and Argentina striker Carlos Tevez is 36 on Wednesday.

Once part of the 'golden triangle of attacking talent' at Old Trafford alongside Ronaldo and Wayne Rooney, he became the 'Welcome to Manchester' poster boy (literally) for Manchester City just two years later.

Wonder if he'll be getting a birthday card from both sides of Manchester this year?

Former Barcelona, Real Madrid and Steaua Bucharest playmaker Gheorghe Hagi is widely regarded as Romania's greatest ever player.

With 124 appearances for his country between 1983 and 2000, some might argue he deserves a national holiday in his honour.

Now owner and manager of Romanian club Viitorul Constanta, he'll always be remembered for a stunning strike for his country in their 3-1 win over Colombia at USA '94.

He might be visiting Britain this year, as his son Ianis has just joined Rangers on loan from Genk.

The Sheffield United striker is next on the list of people who share a 5 February birthday. Yes, the list is still going.

Last week, Sharp played a role in the side's transfer announcement when the Blades confirmed the club record signing of Sander Berge from Genk.

Here he is playing a game of 'Honesty Cards' with team-mate John Fleck (and he does a good impression of another team-mate).

And we're not finished there, it's 'Sven, Sven, Sven'....

The former England manager celebrates his 72nd birthday on 5 February.

Responsible for taking the Three Lions to the quarter-finals of the 2002 and 2006 World Cups and Euro 2004, as well taking charge of Benfica, Lazio, Manchester City and Leicester, to name just a few, in a 43-year coaching career.

And even now, that's not all. Inter Milan's Stefan de Vrij, ex-Arsenal and Barcelona midfielder Giovanni van Bronckhorst, former Manchester United winger Adnan Januzaj, Sheffield Wednesday's Jordan Rhodes and ex-Tottenham defender Vedran Corluka all celebrate their birthdays on 5 February.

So if you're ever asked to pick a five-a-side using people who were born on your birthday, and your birthday is today, you've probably won.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51358322</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Quiz: Can you name the 12 biggest transfer fees paid by British clubs? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1322B/production/_110697387_quizindex.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Another transfer window has come and gone with Premier League clubs shelling out millions of pounds to secure new signings.

However, while British clubs have paid some big transfer fees this past month, none of them came close to surpassing the £89m paid to Juventus by Manchester United for Paul Pogba in 2016.

So the Red Devils midfielder still holds the record for the highest fee paid by a British club - can you name the previous 11 players to hold the record? You get Pogba for free to start you off.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51302545</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Tottenham Hotspur v Southampton - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>FA Cup</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1157D/production/_110773017_shutterstock_editorial_10543245gb.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Dele Alli has &quot;a chance&quot; of featuring in Tottenham's FA Cup fourth-round replay at Southampton, says Spurs boss Jose Mourinho.

England midfielder Alli was injured by a Raheem Sterling tackle during Sunday's 2-0 win over Manchester City.

He was able to play on before being replaced but Mourinho, who believes Sterling should have been sent off, said Alli could play against Saints.

&quot;Dele Alli was very lucky,&quot; said the Spurs boss on Tuesday.

&quot;Did Sterling want to injure him? I don't think so. I don't believe that.

&quot;Respect to Sterling. But the intention doesn't count and what counts is the action. It's a red card.&quot;

Son Heung-min put Spurs 1-0 up at St Mary's on 25 January before substitute Sofiane Boufal's late equaliser forced a replay at Tottenham Hotspur Stadium.

The winners of Wednesday's replay will host Norwich City in the fifth round.

New signing Steven Bergwijn, who scored on his Spurs debut against City, is ineligible for the tie while defender Ben Davies, who has not featured since 23 November, has returned to training after an ankle injury.

However, this tie has come too soon for Davies although he could feature for the eight-time FA Cup winners at Aston Villa on 16 February.

Southampton midfielder Stuart Armstrong has made good progress from the hip injury he suffered in the original tie against Spurs but is unlikely to feature.

Saints boss Ralph Hasenhuttl is unhappy the replay is eating into his side's winter break although he does not plan to follow the lead of Liverpool manager Jurgen Klopp.

Klopp opted to field a team of youngsters for his club's replay with Shrewsbury on Tuesday.

&quot;It's not the best but we have to accept it,&quot; added Hasenhuttl. &quot;For us it's not as hard as teams playing in the Champions League and continuing playing three games a week all season.

&quot;My personal opinion is I'm not a friend of these replays, first because it minimises the chances of the smaller teams to maybe make these big miracles and go through to the next round.

&quot;The second thing is the schedule. We were all accepting that we would have this replay in the winter break.

&quot;Maybe next year we should think about if it is really necessary to make it exactly in this week.&quot;

Southampton, 13th in the Premier League table, do not play again after the replay until 15 February when Burnley are the visitors to St Mary's.
• Since losing 1-0 to Crystal Palace in February 2016, Tottenham have won each of their last seven home FA Cup matches, scoring 25 goals across these victories.
• Spurs have won eight of their last nine home games against Southampton (L1), with all games coming in the Premier League - they won 2-1 against the Saints earlier this season.
• This is the first time an FA Cup tie between Spurs and Southampton has gone to a replay since 1994-95, when Spurs won 6-2 in a fifth-round replay after a 1-1 draw.
• Southampton have been beaten in just one of their last 11 away FA Cup matches (W7 D3 L1), losing 1-0 at Sunderland in February 2014.
• Spurs' Son Heung-min has been directly involved in 18 goals in 20 FA Cup appearances (11 goals, 7 assists), scoring their goal in the 1-1 draw at St. Mary's in the original tie.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51377830</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Celtic and Hamilton to face Scottish FA charge for not acting in 'orderly fashion' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scottish Premiership</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1300E/production/_110783877_19825380.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Celtic and Hamilton Academical will be charged by the Scottish FA for failing to act &quot;in an orderly fashion&quot; during Sunday's Scottish Premiership game.

It relates to a first-half incident when players from each team surrounded referee Nick Walsh after Leigh Griffiths stood on Accies' Sam Woods.

The clubs face a hearing at Hampden on 20 February.

Celtic have also been charged with the same offence in their Scottish Cup tie at Partick Thistle on 18 January.
• 'No debate Griffiths should have had red'

If found guilty, each could face a fine ranging from £2,500 to £20,000.

The clubs will be charged under disciplinary rule 204 which states players and staff must &quot;conduct themselves in an orderly fashion at all times&quot; and refrain from &quot;confrontation&quot; and &quot;conduct likely to lead to or to exacerbate or prolong a hostile or argumentative situation&quot;.

Premiership leaders Celtic won the match 4-1 at Hamilton's Fountain of Youth Stadium, with Griffiths avoiding further punishment for his tangle with Woods, which happened when the game was goalless.

The Griffiths incident was referred by Scottish FA compliance officer Clare Whyte to a three-man panel of former referees, who did not agree it was a red-card offence.

Hamilton were later reduced to 10 men in the first half when Jamie Hamilton received a straight red for a last-man foul on Griffiths.

Celtic won the cup tie with Thistle 2-1 to progress to a meeting with League One Clyde on Sunday.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51387705</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Scottish Cup: Last-16 kick-offs delayed by minute to promote mental health awareness - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scottish Cup</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/10656/production/_110785176_13447529.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>This weekend's Scottish Cup ties last-16 ties will kick off a minute late to promote mental health awareness.

It is part of the Scottish FA's 'Heads Up' campaign which aims to remove the stigma around discussing mental health.

The delayed kick-offs will begin with Hamilton Academical v Rangers at 12:31 GMT on Saturday.

The initiative follows research which shows male fans are three times more likely to discuss football than mental health with friends.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51390311</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Can the WSL deal with pressures of growing visibility? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Women's Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12095/production/_110777837_sophie_ingle_beth_england_getty_01.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Crowds are up, television coverage has increased and sponsorship deals are becoming more lucrative - but there are side-effects to the growth of top-level women's football.

Players in the Women's Super League are having to deal with greater levels of expectation, and with that can come stinging criticism.

England boss Phil Neville has suggested in the past that such scrutiny comes with the territory. But how do players cope when they have not been used to it?

And are Women's Super League clubs equipped to support them?

Neville said last June that his team should be &quot;brave enough&quot; to accept criticism in the build-up to the World Cup, at which his team reached the semi-finals.

&quot;There's always been this real 'nicey nicey' approach to the women's game and I'm of the opinion that if you win, you get praise, but if you do a bad pass, then you are going to get criticised,&quot; he said.

A record-breaking 28.1m people watched BBC coverage of the 2019 World Cup on television and online.

But Manchester City and England midfielder Keira Walsh told the Guardian in January she &quot;probably underestimated how much attention was going to be on the games&quot;.

She said: &quot;I really did struggle with the criticism off the back of [the World Cup]. There were times when I thought: 'Is this actually for me? Do I want to play football any more?'

&quot;Sometimes people are very critical of me, which is fine, I can learn to deal with it, but people do tend to forget that I've still got time to improve and this isn't the finished product by any means.&quot;

It is a product, though, that is attracting ever more attention - which will bring scrutiny and criticism along with a major financial lift.

Atletico Madrid forward Toni Duggan told BBC Breakfast in May last year that the game had been &quot;screaming out for sponsorship, interviews and brands coming on board&quot;.

Both the sponsors and the fans are doing just that. Last year, Barclays agreed a multi-million sponsorship deal with the Women's Super League. And after the publicity generated by the World Cup, England played in front of a record crowd of 77,768 against Germany at Wembley in November.

&quot;The product on the pitch has become better which makes fans come in and want more,&quot; departing Manchester City boss Nick Cushing told BBC Radio Manchester.

Has this level of pressure always been there?

Manchester United manager Casey Stoney, a former England captain, says &quot;the women's game isn't used&quot; to the visibility.

Asked if there is more criticism of players now, she replied: &quot;I think there is, and I think that should be what we want, because we want visibility and we want people to judge the game for the game, rather than saying: 'Oh, unlucky.'&quot;

Wales international Hayley Ladd added &quot;a little bit of criticism is normal&quot;.

&quot;You see what the men have to put up with in their side of the game,&quot; she said. &quot;If things do turn a bit negative then we have to stay focused on our jobs, so we might not read that.&quot;

A number of clubs in the WSL provide social media training in order to help players manage criticism online. They also carry out media training sessions at the start of the season.

Mental health support is provided at Everton, who employ a club chaplain, a performance psychologist and a lifestyle adviser. The Toffees' players can also use a club doctor and external clinical psychologists.

Liverpool invited a consultant in leadership, team culture and elite performance to speak to the players before the Merseyside derby at Anfield in November.

Manchester United have an external wellbeing coach, who comes into the club every day.

They have also had someone come in to talk about social media and the club provides one-to-ones with players every six weeks to discuss personal issues, as well as their football development.

Players also receive support from the Football Association.

Every club is visited by FA officials during pre-season to discuss how to report abuse or discrimination and players are made aware of self-referral mental health support programmes.

WSL academies are given workshops on mental health and there are plans in place to introduce a mental health first aider at every club.

Assistance in dealing with publicity is given too, as a BBC documentary showed last June; the programme showed the England squad taking part in media training and team bonding sessions in Qatar before the World Cup.

All of those programmes can help players deal with the criticism that comes their way.

&quot;It's not about patronising people - it's a football game, and we don't want to be treated any differently from the male players,&quot; Stoney said.

&quot;You're going to get the same judgement. The difference is: the male players are used to it. The women's game isn't used to it, and it's a big wake-up call for a lot of [the players] because they read it.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51106078</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Premier League has to try and make VAR better, says chief executive Richard Masters - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/15925/production/_110775388_var_sign_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Premier League has to &quot;try and make the video assistant referee better&quot;, says chief executive Richard Masters.

More than two-thirds of Premier League fans questioned believe VAR has made the game less enjoyable, a YouGov survey has found.

There have been several controversial decisions involving VAR since it was introduced to the league this season.

&quot;I don't think VAR has been damaging but I accept it needs improvement,&quot; Masters told BBC Sport.

&quot;Scrapping it is not an option - what we have to do is try and make VAR better.&quot;

VAR has been brought in to the Premier League to decide on goals, penalties, red cards and offside decisions.

Masters, who was appointed on a permanent basis in December after being in temporary charge for more than a year, said the Premier League would discuss changes to VAR with the clubs in April.

&quot;We are going to have a debate about what sort of VAR they would like next season and what improvements can be made to the system,&quot; he said.

&quot;It's going to be a work in progress this season and next as we try to rebalance it so you get the positives of better decision-making and fewer of the perceived negatives about delay and sometimes confusion.&quot;

The Premier League has previously promised to improve VAR's consistency and speed and increase communication with fans.

Six out of 10 of those fans surveyed by YouGov felt the system was working badly.

Masters said that VAR is delivering on the &quot;principal reason&quot; for its introduction in improving the accuracy of decision-making.

&quot;In key match incidents we are up to 94% accuracy with officials, 97% with their assistants, so we are seeing an impact on results and a positive impact on the league table,&quot; he said.

&quot;Obviously there are issues with consistency of decision-making and delays, which people don't like.

&quot;But I don't think VAR is harming the product - attendances are up, TV audiences are up, the health of the Premier League is very good.&quot;

'More to be done' on racism

Statistics compiled by anti-discrimination campaigners Kick It Out suggested there had been a 43% increase in reports of racist abuse in English football in 2018-19 from the previous season.

In December, the government said it would not rule out taking &quot;further steps&quot; if football authorities fail to deal with racism following several high-profile cases this season.

Masters said there is &quot;always more to be done&quot; by the Premier League in helping to combat racism in football.

&quot;Football has a big role to play - we are part of society and can play a role in promoting all the right messages and will continue to do that,&quot; he said.

On Monday, a fan who shouted racial abuse at players during Brighton's home Premier League game against Tottenham Hotspur in October was jailed.

&quot;One incident of racism is unacceptable and one too many,&quot; added Masters.

&quot;Ultimately we can't stop individuals harbouring racist or homophobic thoughts coming into our grounds or sharing them with people around them.

&quot;It's our responsibility to make sure people who do that know there are consequences and also to put proper systems in place to deal with it when it happens.

&quot;We need to make sure there are proper reporting mechanisms, trained stewards in place, and police if necessary, and that when perpetrators are caught they are banned from football, which we are now seeing more regularly, as well as possible criminal proceedings.&quot;

Sports minister Nigel Adams MP told BBC Sport last month that football has &quot;far too much dependency&quot; on sponsorship from gambling companies.

Half of Premier League clubs are sponsored by bookmakers and there are concerns about the potential impact on young fans and vulnerable people.

The Betting and Gaming Council chair, Brigid Simmonds, told a parliamentary committee on Tuesday that bookmakers are &quot;considering&quot; a voluntary ban on football shirt sponsorship and pitchside advertising, expanding on the whistle-to-whistle ban on television gambling adverts introduced last year.

Masters said the Premier League &quot;welcomes&quot; the government's upcoming review of the 2005 Gambling Act and that the league will be &quot;willing and active participants&quot; in it.

&quot;Betting is a legitimate pastime - sport and betting have a long history,&quot; he added.

&quot;The Premier League don't have any betting partnerships and ultimately it is the clubs' decision.

&quot;I don't think if you are looking at solving the issue of vulnerable people and betting that the answer should be that the clubs can't have betting partnerships anymore - I don't think one follows the other.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51377663</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Transfer rumours: Pogba, Sane, Dembele, Stones, Gabriel, Grealish, Maddison, Bale - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/2735/production/_110773001_paul_pogba_reuters.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>France midfielder Paul Pogba, 26, has told his Manchester United team-mates he still wants to leave the club in the summer. (Manchester Evening News)

Juventus are considering making a move for Manchester City and Germany winger Leroy Sane in the summer, with the 24-year-old also a target for Bayern Munich. (Calcio Mercato, via Inside Futbol)

Chelsea are prepared to give manager Frank Lampard £150m to spend in the summer with Lyon's French striker Moussa Dembele, 23, his top target. (Evening Standard)

Manchester City boss Pep Guardiola wants to sign two centre-backs this summer in a move that casts fresh doubt over the future of England defender John Stones, 25. (Times, subscription required)

Manchester United will prioritise a move for Aston Villa midfielder Jack Grealish, 24, in the summer with fellow Englishman James Maddison, 23, moving closer to signing a new deal with Leicester City. (Mirror)

Atletico Madrid are monitoring the availability of former Tottenham manager Mauricio Pochettino should they part company with Diego Simeone in the summer. (Telegraph)

Arsenal are interested in Feyenoord and Turkey Under-21 midfielder Orkun Kokcu, 19. (Mail)

Arsenal and Everton made offers for Lille's Brazilian defender Gabriel Magalhaes, 20, in January, but did not meet his club's valuation. (Le10 Sport, via Team Talk)

Leicester City and Newcastle United are prepared to pay £15m for Brentford and Algeria winger Said Benrahma, 24, in the summer. (Sun)

Gareth Bale's agent has denied reports that Tottenham made an offer for the 30-year-old Real Madrid and Wales forward during the January transfer window. (Talksport)

Athletic Bilbao are keeping an eye on the situation of former keeper Kepa Arrizabalaga after the 25-year-old Spain international was dropped by Chelsea manager Frank Lampard for the game against Leicester City. (Sun)

Crystal Palace boss Roy Hodgson, 72, could leave the Selhurst Park side in the summer unless he is given assurances over the club's summer transfer plans. (Times - subscription required)

Matej Vydra's agent has claimed Rangers and Aston Villa had bids rejected for the 27-year-old Czech Republic and Burnley striker during the January transfer window. (Sport24, via Sport Witness)

Manchester United are expecting Argentina goalkeeper Sergio Romero, 32, to leave in the summer, along with English third-choice keeper Lee Grant, 37. (Sun)

Leicester City's head of senior recruitment Lee Congerton watched Turkey and Trabzonspor goalkeeper Ugurcan Cakir, 23, over the weekend. (Fotospor, via Leicester Mercury)

Bournemouth face a battle to persuade Norway forward Josh King, 28, to sign a new contract following the collapse of his deadline-day move to Manchester United. (Telegraph)

German goalkeeper Loris Karius is in trouble at Besiktas as the club believe the 26-year-old, who is on loan from Liverpool, has spent too much time partying of late. (Star)

Manchester City are monitoring Red Bull Salzburg's Austrian 'wonderkid' Luka Reischl, with Juventus also interested in the 16-year-old striker. (Calcio Mercato, via Talksport)

Former West Ham manager Manuel Pellegrini has claimed the poor form of 33-year-old Spanish goalkeeper Roberto contributed to his sacking. (Evening Standard)

Chelsea could be set to re-sign French winger Jeremie Boga, 23, from Sassuolo this summer, according to the Italian club's president Giovanni Carnevali. (Goal, via Independent)

West Ham have announced they plan to have new seating at London Stadium in place for the start of next season to bring the fans closer to the pitch. (Evening Standard)

Crystal Palace are unable to recall Norway striker Alexander Sorloth, 24, from his two-year Trabzonspor loan, despite him scoring 16 goals in 19 games for the Turkish side this season. (Sutton and Croydon Guardian)

Leicester City and Algeria striker Islam Slimani, 31, was &quot;very close&quot; to joining Italian side Inter Milan during the January transfer window. (Calcio Mercato, via Leicester Mercury)
• Download and listen to the latest Football Daily podcast</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51376893</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>Livingston: How has Gary Holt created a formidable force in the Premiership? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Livingston</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/949F/production/_110774083_19807894.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Five wins on the bounce, six straight games undefeated at the home fortress of the Tony Macaroni Arena, and the best goalscoring record in the league outwith Celtic and Rangers.

By rights, Livingston should be toiling for survival in the lower reaches of the top flight. They have the division's second lowest average attendance - just 3,664 last season - and the second-lowest wage bill.

Yet they sit comfortably in fifth - four points above Hibernian and eight clear of seventh-place Kilmarnock - and are on course for their best top-flight finish in 18 years since coming third in 2002.

So how have the Livi Lions defied the odds and found their roar? BBC Scotland takes a look at the numbers behind their success.

The robust, direct style of Livingston is not always pleasing on the eye, but is ruthlessly effective - and much of the team's success this season is down to their home form. The modest Tony Macaroni Arena and its plastic pitch has become a Lion's den where opponents are chewed up and spat out.

Livingston's haul of 24 points from 12 home games - compared to just 10 from 12 away matches - is a record bettered only by Celtic and Rangers, and their defensive stats are enough to make a Catenaccio coach envious.

No side in the Premiership has a more miserly backline on home soil than Livingston.

They have not conceded in their last six Premiership home matches, winning five on the spin, and have kept clean sheets in nine of 12. In comparison, Celtic have mustered just seven clean sheets in 12 and Rangers seven in 11.

In total, Holt's men have lost just five goals at home, one fewer than Celtic and level with Rangers despite having played a game more than the Ibrox side.

Livingston finished ninth last season on their return to the top flight, but the building blocks of that solid campaign were soon reduced to rubble.

Goalkeeper Liam Kelly, centre-backs Craig Halkett and Declan Gallagher, and midfielder Shaun Byrne - all with more than 35 appearances each last term - moved on. Loan striker Ryan Hardie, who had finished as the side's top scorer with seven goals, also departed and Holt had a huge rebuild on his hands.

He has plugged the gaps with canny recruitment. Jon Guthrie has been a stand-out at centre-back - and contributed an impressive four-goal haul at the other end - while fellow defender Aaron-Taylor Sinclair only arrived in November but has quickly established himself.

Marvin Bartley has become a tenacious mainstay in midfield, Aymen Souda brings bustle in attacking areas and goalkeeper Matija Sarkic impressed in his six-month loan spell. Robby McCrorie has since been drafted in from Rangers to fill the gloves - and Holt labelled the performance in his recent debut against St Johnstone as &quot;exceptional&quot;.

The pick of the signings, though, are in forward positions - and the stats have reflected that.

Livingston scored 1.10 goals per game last season, a statistic that had them the joint-seventh top-scoring team in the league alongside Hearts. That has significantly improved this season - so much so that only Celtic and Rangers have outscored Gary Holt's side and their 1.50 goals per game.

Lyndon Dykes has taken the step up from second-tier Queen of the South in his stride. The Australian already has 11 goals and his physical attributes make him a nuisance to defenders while putting him on the international radar and reportedly attracting interest from Rangers.

Steven Lawless' goal tally is also into double figures - three more than any Livingston player netted last season - and he has assisted five on top of that in the Premiership.

Livingston have attracted criticism for their style of play and physicality - but are they committing more offences than other teams? The numbers indicate the Lions are all roar and no bite in disciplinary matters.

Despite being third-highest in the league for fouls conceded, Gary Holt's men are like kittens in comparison to Hamilton Accies, who have seven red cards to Livingston's two.

They are not among the highest offending teams when it comes to cautions either - they are fifth in the league with 42 yellow cards compared to the likes of Motherwell and Ross County who have seen their players booked 50 times each.

Livingston have made their home a Lion's den, have shown physical prowess and defensive tenacity, but they have an attacking punch too now, making them a formidable force well beyond their means.

We are trying to implement things, show them things and educate them with the analysis that we do.

The training sessions we do is painting pictures for them to try to implement and I felt on Saturday [1-0 home win over Motherwell] that more and more what we have been doing in the week came out.

The movement off the ball, movement beyond the ball, supporting the team-mates when the ball went forward was really pleasing to see.

It was good and you just hope it is another wee building block for them to see how good they are and what they can achieve with, first and foremost, hard work.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51368590</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>James Milner: Liverpool midfielder watches youngsters in the FA Cup - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Liverpool</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/651F/production/_110778852_gettyimages-1198663261.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Goalkeeper Alisson was in Rio de Janeiro. Striker Roberto Firmino was in The Maldives. Midfielder Georginio Wijnaldum was in Dubai. And right-back Trent Alexander-Arnold was in Miami.

Just some of the sunshine destinations Liverpool's superstars found themselves in as the club's youngsters played Shrewsbury in an FA Cup tie on Tuesday night.

James Milner? The veteran of over 800 career matches was sitting on a bench at a chilly Anfield, supporting Curtis Jones and co in their replay against the mid-table League One side.

The former England midfielder, who is recovering from a hamstring injury, didn't just turn up five minutes before kick-off and watch the match either.
• Was Klopp correct to miss tie with Shrewsbury?

The 34-year-old trained with the team in the build up to the game and gave the kids - with an average age of 19 years and 102 days - a pre-match pep talk.

'I think he was desperate to get on'

According to Under-23 manager Neil Critchley, who was in charge with Jurgen Klopp staying away as the replay fell during the Premier League's winter break, he was even eager to play.

&quot;He trained with us [the day before] and he asked whether he could come along. I think the answer is 'Yes, of course you can'. It was very respectful to ask,&quot; Critchley said.

&quot;He was giving words of advice, he was getting right behind the players. He was vocal in the dressing room. He was animated. He was vocal behind me, I could hear him.

&quot;I don't think he's available [fit] yet... but he was jumping up and down behind me so I think he was desperate to get on.&quot;

Milner made his senior debut with Leeds at the age of 16, so knows what it is like to play on the big stage at a young age.

After the match, he tweeted: &quot;Outstanding performance from the boys, Critch and his staff &amp; fantastic turn out from the fans.&quot;

&quot;He was genuinely delighted at how the boys performed and I can't thank him enough,&quot; added Critchley.

&quot;He was buzzing. We've given him a game against Chelsea away to look forward to.&quot;

With Klopp likely to recall at least some of his senior players for the fifth-round tie against Chelsea, there's every chance Milner will be in action at Stamford Bridge thanks to the efforts of the youngest line-up in Liverpool's history.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51384244</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>Garth Crooks' team of the week: Lloris, Henderson, Bergwijn, Fernandes, Salah - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/03C4/production/_110746900_son.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Liverpool continued their march towards the Premier League title this weekend by beating Southampton 4-0.

The chasing pack dropped points as Tottenham beat Manchester City 2-0 while Leicester drew 2-2 with Chelsea.

Elsewhere, Bournemouth claimed a narrow 2-1 win against Aston Villa, Everton fought back from two goals down to win 3-2 at Watford and West Ham and Brighton played out a thrilling 3-3 draw.

Sheffield United won 1-0 at Crystal Palace, while there were goalless draws between Newcastle and Norwich and Manchester United and Wolves.

Here's my team of the week - have a read and then select your own below.

Hugo Lloris: Regular readers will know that I am not a huge fan of Spurs' Hugo Lloris but credit where credit is due.

The France World Cup winner was the difference between the two teams on the day. The penalty save by Lloris was one of the many turning points in this game against a Manchester City side that seemed to be in control from start to finish. However, from the moment Lloris saved the penalty and speedily recovered to stop Raheem Sterling from getting the rebound, his performance got better and better.

His overall handling was clean and decisive while his decision-making was excellent. I'll be very interested to see if he can retain this form and for how long.

Did you know? Lloris has saved three of the last four penalties he has faced in the Premier League.

Antonio Rudiger: Chelsea got away with this result having been let down, not on one occasion but two by Willy Caballero in the Chelsea goal. The Blues have a keeper problem having already dropped Kepa Arrizabalaga. Fortunately Antonio Rudiger was on hand to rescue Chelsea and Caballero from defeat.

Rudiger's second goal was one of the best headed goals I've seen this season. Meanwhile the London club have gone from having Petr Cech and Thibaut Courtois - two world-class goalkeepers - to Kepa and Caballero, who both look like they've only recently been introduced to the game. If Chelsea are serious about a top-four place they need to get a top-class goalkeeper. They should take a serious look at Newcastle's Martin Dubravka.

Did you know? Rudiger became the first Chelsea centre-back to score twice in a Premier League match since John Terry against Fulham in April 2013.

Yerry Mina: It's rather unusual to pick a defender for scoring goals rather than his team coming away with a clean sheet. Nevertheless I have decided to go with Yerry Mina simply due to his persistence. Every time the ball went into the Watford penalty area at set plays their defence fell to pieces. The sheer presence of Mina (who is a lump by the way) sent Watford into meltdown.

What a result this was. Everton scoring three goals away from home is about as crazy as Barcelona wanting to buy Richarlison for £75m! To think both happened in the space of a week suggests the Carlo Ancelotti effect is starting to work.

Did you know? Mina had taken 24 shots without scoring in the Premier League this season before putting away consecutive chances against Watford.

Nathan Ake: When Nathan Ake plays for Bournemouth things usually happen. The Dutch defender has been an excellent purchase for Bournemouth and they need him now more than ever. Ake is a defender who is not afraid to put his body on the line for his team, or afraid to get among the goals if he has to, which is just as well because Bournemouth needed this result.

Aston Villa on the other hand seem to be suffering from a Carabao Cup semi-final victory hangover. It took them far too long to get going. The Villans had better understand quickly that EFL Cup success is not a solution to Premier League survival.

Did you know? Since Ake joined Bournemouth for his first spell there in the summer of 2016, he has scored 11 Premier League goals - the most of any centre-back.

Steven Bergwijn: What a start for the lad. To make your Premier League debut against the 'outgoing' champions and to score the goal that changes the game is one thing. To do it with such a wonderful piece of skill is something else entirely. The chest control by Steven Bergwijn and the volley that followed was the stuff of boyhood dreams.

How Manchester City didn't put this game to bed in the first half is a complete mystery to me. However, once City went down to 10 men there was only one team that was going to win this match.

Did you know? Bergwijn became the 250th player to score on his Premier League debut.

Jordan Henderson: You can't beat the first-time ball. Certainly not the way Jordan Henderson provided the pass for Mohamed Salah to score his second goal. In fact there aren't many players who are prepared to deliver a pass on the run without taking a touch first.

However, Henderson is in such blistering form I think he's capable of anything at the moment. I've said repeatedly in this column that the Liverpool captain is playing the football of his life and a shoo-in for Footballer of the Year.

Did you know? Henderson has both scored and assisted twice in his last three Premier League matches, as many times as he had done so in 131 games prior to this run.

Bruno Fernandes: This was a game Manchester United manager Ole Gunnar Solskjaer will want to forget in a hurry. The only glimmer of light for the beleaguered United boss was the performance of his new Portuguese signing Bruno Fernandes. The midfielder only arrived two days before they played Wolverhampton Wanderers and if this performance is a taste of what is to come from him, then things might be looking up for United.

What a pity executive vice-chairman Ed Woodward wasn't there to see his new signing make his league debut. I can't see what can be possibly more important than seeing your £47m purchase come through his first major test for his new club - can you? Read what I have to say about Manchester United in The Crooks of the Matter below.

Did you know? Fernandes had 110 touches of the ball against Wolves - only two players had more touches this weekend in the Premier League (Aaron Wan-Bissaka, 119 and Fernandinho, 113).

Robert Snodgrass: The Scottish international is probably playing the best football of his career at the moment. He's certainly scoring more goals than I can remember. What a pity his team is struggling. West Ham cannot afford to let two-goal leads slip from their grasp. Such carelessness at this stage of the season could be catastrophic.

In the meantime the Hammers have to make sure Snodgrass remains fit. They have enough quality in the team not to get relegated but where have we heard that before?

Did you know? Snodgrass scored twice and provided one assist against Brighton - the last West Ham player to score at least twice while providing at least one assist in the same Premier League game was Andy Carroll against Swansea over six years ago.

Mohamed Salah: It looks like Mohamed Salah has got that golden scoring touch back. All those little dinks and chips over the advancing goalkeeper seem to be coming off again.

Earlier in the season he appeared to be trying too hard to score and not allowing chances to come naturally. This was the cause of a little tension between Salah and Sadio Mane in one game in particular but not anymore.

Liverpool's second-half performance was as good as I've seen for some time. Much more relaxed and no longer battling the spectre of winning the Premier League title. At one stage Liverpool were just getting the job done, now it looks like they are having a party.

Did you know? Salah has scored more goals on home soil than any other player in the Premier League this season (12 goals in 12 matches at Anfield).

Roberto Firmino: The Brazilian played half this game as though the ball was stuck to his feet. The touch he displayed when he took the ball out of the sky and placed it perfectly in his path, prior to playing an inch-perfect pass for Henderson to score was pure genius.

He had just done something similar when he set up Alex Oxlade-Chamberlain to score moments earlier with the most gorgeous backheeled flick. Yes, Southampton should have had a penalty when Fabinho brought down Danny Ings, but Liverpool also had a claim turned down when Firmino was 'hauled down' by Shane Long in the box.

This was a game full of errors by referee Kevin Friend but at least he made the errors and not a sophisticated toy.

Did you know? Firmino became the fifth Liverpool player to record three assists in a single Premier League match, after (most recent first) Trent Alexander-Arnold, Alberto Aquilani, Vladimir Smicer and Stan Collymore.

Son Heung-min: If ever Tottenham needed a performance out of Son Heung-min, then this was it. In the absence of Harry Kane, Spurs are struggling up front. Son is a runner and not a natural striker with his back to goal, which leaves Spurs lacking someone who can hold and retain the ball.

Nevertheless Son ran himself into the ground against Manchester City and was rewarded with a well-deserved goal for his efforts.

Did you know? Son has scored five goals against Pep Guardiola's Manchester City in all competitions - only Jamie Vardy (six) has scored more goals against them since the Spaniard took over in 2016.

Now it's your turn

You've seen my selections this week. But who would you go for?

The Crooks of the Matter

Who sells Romelu Lukaku and replaces him (if only in the short term) with Odion Ighalo? Manchester United it would appear. Ole Gunnar Solskjaer sold the Belgium international to Inter Milan and now finds himself in the middle of a striker crisis having lost Marcus Rashford, his most valued goalscorer, to a rather unfortunate but avoidable back injury.

Ighalo is a proven striker made very much in Solskjaer's image. Professional, a team player and most importantly just happy to be at the club of his dreams. But the Nigerian is not in Lukaku's class, even if he is only on loan.

This latest signing comes at a time when United fans have become increasingly frustrated by their team's lack of impact on the Premier League title race. They are playing second fiddle to their noisy but very successful neighbours City and having their noses rubbed in it by arch enemy Liverpool, who are running away with the title. It just doesn't get any worse than that.

Such extraordinary indifference by those who own the club to what is clearly a crisis as far as United fans are concerned is starting to grate. This perceived contempt by the owners to the concerns of fans has erupted into threatening behaviour towards executive vice-chairman Ed Woodward, when in fact the Glazer family are to blame - and guess what? Solskjaer and Woodward have been left holding the baby.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51351685</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>Liverpool 1-0 Shrewsbury: Absent Jurgen Klopp 'delighted' with FA Cup win - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Liverpool</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/3D8D/production/_110775751_hi059717721.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Absent Liverpool manager Jurgen Klopp was &quot;delighted&quot; as the youngest team in the club's history beat Shrewsbury to reach the FA Cup fifth round.

Klopp decided to miss the fourth-round replay because it fell during the Premier League's winter break.

A Reds side with an average age of 19 years and 102 days set up a tie at Chelsea with a 1-0 win.

&quot;There was a message at half-time and at full-time [from Klopp],&quot; said under-23s boss Neil Critchley.

&quot;There was a message before the game that Chelsea away could be an opportunity for one or two of them and they put in a performance tonight.&quot;

There was at least one of Klopp's senior players in the sell-out 52,399 crowd, with James Milner offering his support sat behind the home dugout.

&quot;He trained with us yesterday and he asked whether he could come along,&quot; added Critchley, who oversaw the game for Liverpool.

&quot;He was giving words of advice, he was getting right behind the players. He was vocal in the dressing room. He was animated. He was vocal behind me, I could hear him.&quot;

Ro-Shaun Williams' own goal was enough to send a Liverpool side containing seven teenage outfield players through against their League One opponents.

Liverpool right-back Neco Williams, whose long ball forward led to the goal, said it was a night that his team-mates would remember for &quot;a long time&quot;.

The result means the Reds are still in the chase for three additional trophies, having already won the Club World Cup and Super Cup.

They have a 22-point lead at the top of the Premier League and are in the last 16 of both the Champions League and FA Cup.

&quot;The lads were excellent and hopefully we will do the same against Chelsea in the next round,&quot; said 18-year-old Williams.

&quot;Our aim is to win the FA Cup. I think the [senior] lads will have been extremely proud of us and hopefully us young players will get a chance again.&quot;

Aged 19 years and five days, Toxteth-born Curtis Jones became the youngest first-team captain in Liverpool's history.

&quot;All the boys went out there and showed belief, character, showed everything that the manager looks for in his players,&quot; said Jones.

&quot;I was grateful to become the youngest captain of the team but most importantly we came away with the win with a great performance.

&quot;The boys showed heart, character and a hard decision for the next game.&quot;

'Klopp should have been there'

Former England captain Alan Shearer said &quot;it doesn't sit right with me&quot; that Klopp missed Tuesday's match.

The German said last week he &quot;decided three weeks ago we would have a mid-season break based on a letter we got [from the Premier League] in April 2019&quot;.

Top-flight teams were all due to have two weeks off in February but the 2-2 draw in the original tie meant the replay fell within that period, prompting his decision to miss the match, along with his entire senior squad.

&quot;I understand Jurgen's point in terms of his players having the break they were told they'd have,&quot; said Shearer on BBC One.

&quot;He is the manager so he can put whichever team he wants but it doesn't sit right with me - he should be there. He should be at the ground giving the support to those young players.&quot;

Former England keeper Rob Green, speaking to BBC Sport, said Klopp's decision not to field his senior players and stay away was &quot;clever mind games&quot;.

&quot;Coming from Germany, he thinks we're crazy playing all these games, so it's a really interesting quandary and one where you're thinking he's got the upper ground here,&quot; added Green.

Former Birmingham and Crystal Palace striker Clinton Morrison also believes Klopp should have been present.

&quot;If I was one of those youngsters, I would've liked Jurgen Klopp to have been there, win, lose or draw, to have put an arm around me and say I had done well,&quot; said Morrison.

&quot;But he's made his decision and he's one of those managers that has credit in the bank because he's been so good.&quot;

'This tie had the potential to be a real legacy for the club'

Shrewsbury boss Sam Ricketts said before the replay that the League One club missed out on making more money from it.

The Reds cut ticket prices to £15 for adults and £1 for children while the game was not shown live on television.

&quot;We're going to generate some money from this but nowhere near what it could've been,&quot; Ricketts told BBC Radio 5 Live.

&quot;It had the potential to be a real legacy for the club and for us to put some infrastructure in place but it's still more then what we would've got without a replay, so we'll look at that on the positive side.&quot;

Speaking about the game, Ricketts said his players &quot;could not get near&quot; Liverpool &quot;to impose ourselves&quot;.

He added: &quot;It is game 39 for us and it caught up with us. We could not get up to the physicality level.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51380211</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>When can Liverpool win Premier League title? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/13174/production/_110569187_hi059262932.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Premier League title moved closer into Liverpool sights on Sunday without Jurgen Klopp's side even kicking a ball.

Tottenham's 2-0 victory against Manchester City means the Reds are an incredible 22 points ahead of second place.

After 30 years of slip-ups and near misses, Reds fans - or a decent number of them - now believe a first title since 1990 is tantalisingly within their grasp, even if manager Jurgen Klopp is refusing to celebrate just yet.

But just when Liverpool fans thought their season could not get any better, the prospect of sealing the title at the home of their nearest rivals Everton, is now a very real one.

BBC Sport has crunched the numbers to work out when and where Liverpool could become champions again.

Can Liverpool win the title in February?

No is the simple answer to this.

Even if Liverpool win all their games this month Manchester City only play twice in the Premier League so mathematically would not be out of the title race by the start of March.

When is the earliest Liverpool can win the league?

Liverpool could, in theory, win the title against Bournemouth on 7 March. That would require Liverpool to win all their matches in that time while Manchester City slip up.

The only guarantee the Reds know is that just six wins from their remaining 13 games will be enough to be crowned champions, regardless of what their rivals do.

The Reds' sixth game from this point of the season is against Crystal Palace at Anfield on 21 March.

What needs to happen for Liverpool to win the title at Goodison Park?

To put it simply, Liverpool need to keep winning while Manchester City keep slipping up.

If City lose one of their four Premier League games between now and 14 March then a win in the Merseyside derby at Everton on 16 March will clinch the title.

The triumph would be extra sweet for Reds fans given it was a goalless draw at Goodison Park last year that was one of the matches that proved critical in their failure to snatch the title from Manchester City.

The stalemate in early March was the last time Liverpool dropped points, with nine successive wins still not enough to overhaul Guardiola's men, who claimed the title by a single point on the final day of the season.

What's the earliest a team has won the Premier League?

Manchester United hold the record for the earliest Premier League title win, with Sir Alex Ferguson's men claiming victory in 2000-01 on 14 April.

The earliest Premier League title win by games remaining, rather than by date, is five - a record also set by United in 2000-01, as well as Manchester City in 2017-18.

Liverpool have rewritten the record books on several occasions already this season and their current lead of 22 points after 25 games is the biggest in Premier League history.

What is the biggest lead a team has had WITHOUT going on to win the title?

&quot;I'd love it if we beat them, love it.&quot;

Who can forget Kevin Keegan's famous on-screen rant as his Newcastle side saw their lead slowly chipped away by Manchester United during the second half of the 1995-96 season?

Keegan's swashbuckling Magpies team led the table by 12 points at the start of 1996, but finished the campaign four points behind Manchester United in second. That remains the biggest lead a side has had in the Premier League without going on to win the title.

Now that is a record Liverpool do NOT want to break.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51163821</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-24</ID>
      <TITLE>FA Cup fifth-round draw: Wayne Rooney to face former side Man Utd - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>FA Cup</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/B41B/production/_110670164_rooney_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Wayne Rooney will face his former side Manchester United in the fifth round of the FA Cup after Derby beat Northampton in their fourth-round replay.

Chelsea will host Liverpool after they overcame Shrewsbury in a replay, while Arsenal travel to League One Portsmouth.

All eight ties will be played across three midweek nights from 3-5 March.

Rooney, who is United and England's all-time record goalscorer, joined Championship club Derby County as a player-coach in January from MLS side DC United.

Now 34, he played 559 times for United, scoring 253 goals.

He won five Premier League titles and each of the Champions League, Europa League and FA Cup once after joining from Everton for £27m in 2004.

Since leaving Old Trafford he has faced his former employers twice, losing both games during the 2017-18 season, while in a second spell at Everton.

Tottenham play Southampton in the remaining fourth-round replay on Wednesday, with the winners at home to Norwich.

Why are fifth-round ties being played in midweek?

In a change to the usual format, all eight ties will be played across three midweek nights from 3-5 March, with no replays.

If any of the ties are level after 90 minutes there will be 30 minutes of extra time and, if necessary, penalties to determine a winner on the night.

It is the second season running that fifth-round replays have been removed from the competition in an attempt to alleviate fixture congestion.

In addition, the Premier League is having a mid-season break in February, with each team getting a weekend off.
• Premier League winter break: All you need to know

Four Premier League matches will take place on the opening weekend of the inaugural winter break, with six more the following weekend.

All 10 matches have different kick-off times, meaning none of the games will be played at the same time.

The schedule was agreed in June 2018 between the Football Association, the Premier League and EFL.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51271468</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-03 00:00:00-25</ID>
      <TITLE>Quiz: Name the British &amp; Irish players to have played in Serie A - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/17EB4/production/_110727979_young_index.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The January transfer window has closed for business for another year.

One player to make the switch from the Premier League to Serie A was Ashley Young.

The former Manchester United defender signed for Italian giants Inter Milan for £1.28m on an initial six-month deal, with an option to extend for a further season.

Young, 34, joins a long list of British and Irish players to make the jump from English football to Italy's top division.

For the quiz below, we've picked out 15 players - past and present - who also played in Serie A at some point in their careers.

All you have to do is read the clues and try to name as many as you can in three minutes.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51334223</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
