<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Nasa investigates shuttle failure</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The US space agency had to scrub Wednesday's launch attempt when a fuel tank sensor started to play up.

The orbiter was all set to make the first flight since the loss of Columbia and its crew of seven in February 2003.

Discovery's astronauts had all been strapped into the shuttle and were preparing for blast-off when the order came through to stand down.

Nasa says the launch will now take place no earlier than Saturday.

However, it is considered more likely lift-off will be delayed until Monday.

The agency's administrator, Dr Mike Griffin, told reporters he did not know whether the problem could be fixed at the launch pad or would require the shuttle to be rolled back into its hangar.

The latter would mean a lengthy delay to Discovery's mission to the International Space Station (ISS).

&quot;All I can say is aw shucks,&quot; said the shuttle's deputy programme manager Wayne Hale.

&quot;It is an unexplained anomaly. We changed every wire, every electronics box. We thought we had a good system.&quot;

Nasa officials said that from the troubleshooting done so far, the problem could be down to suspect transistors in the box that supplies the sensors with power.

Mr Hale said the shuttle team would now implement a troubleshooting plan to track down the source of the problem.

&quot;This system goes from an avionics box in the back of the orbiter to these sensors in the external tank, so we'll start looking from end to end to try to isolate what the problem is,&quot; Nasa manager Scott Thurston told the BBC News website.

This type of sensor has caused problems before, during the first &quot;tanking test&quot; of STS-114 in April.

Then, the external fuel tank was rolled back into the Vehicle Assembly Building. But Discovery is now using an entirely different tank.

Earlier, senator and former presidential candidate John Kerry and senator and astronaut John Glenn had turned up at Kennedy Space Center's press complex.

&quot;It's good that they detected this ahead of time. This is a complicated business, this is one of the most complex vehicles ever designed by human beings,&quot; said Mr Kerry.

The faulty sensor is one of four in the shuttle's external tank responsible for making sure the spacecraft's engines shut down at the proper point during the ascent.

The sensors ensure the engines are not suddenly starved of propellants and are switched off in a controlled fashion.

The current launch window runs until the end of July, after which Discovery would have to wait until September to get airborne.

The long wait results from the need to have the ISS in the right position in orbit and Nasa's desire to launch during daylight hours so it can photograph all aspects of the ascent.

Discovery's mission will be the first for a space shuttle in two and a half years.

The agency says it has learnt the lessons of the Columbia accident.

Improvements to Discovery include a 50ft-long (15m) robotic arm that will inspect parts of the orbiter for damage once in orbit.

The giant external tank has undergone modifications that should ensure it sheds little of its insulation foam on blast-off.

It was a suitcase-sized chunk of this material that crashed into Columbia's left wing, punching a large hole and leaving the orbiter open to the destructive super-heated gases of re-entry.

More cameras than ever before will be trained on Discovery during launch, to watch for any debris that could damage the spacecraft.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4681327.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Astronomers detect '10th planet'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The largest object found in our Solar System since Neptune in 1846, it was first seen in 2003 - but important details have only now been confirmed.

Designated 2003 UB313, it is about 2,800km across - a world of rock and ice and somewhat larger than Pluto.

Scientists say it is three times as far away as Pluto, in an orbit at an angle to the orbits of the main planets.

Astronomers think that at some point in its history, Neptune probably flung the small world into its highly inclined 44-degree orbit.

It is currently 97 Earth-Sun distances away - more than twice Pluto's average distance from the Sun.

Its discoverers are Michael Brown of Caltech, Chad Trujillo of the Gemini Observatory in Hawaii, and David Rabinowitz of Yale University.

&quot;Brought to the same distance from the Sun as Pluto, it would be brighter. So today, the world knows that Pluto is not unique. There are other Plutos, just farther out in the Solar System where they are a little harder to find.&quot;

It was picked up using the Samuel Oschin Telescope at Palomar Observatory and the 8m Gemini North telescope on Mauna Kea.

Chad Trujillo told the BBC News website: &quot;I feel extremely lucky to be part of a discovery as exciting as this. It's not every day that you find something Pluto-sized or larger!&quot;

&quot;The spectra that we took at the Gemini Observatory are particularly interesting because it shows that the surface of 2003 UB313 is very similar to that of Pluto.&quot;

The object was first observed on 21 October 2003, but the team did not see it move in the sky until looking at the same area 15 months later on 8 January 2005.

This gives them an upper limit of its size of 3,000 km, they say. The lower limit still makes it larger than Pluto.

The discovery of 2003 UB313 comes just after the announcement of the finding of 2003 EL61, which appears to be a little smaller than Pluto.

The discoveries will once again ignite the debate about the qualifications of an object to be called a planet, an issue the International Astronomical Union is wrestling with as the official naming organisation for this area of science.

Modern techniques have revealed several far-off objects that approach Pluto's size, such as Quaoar (detected in 2002) and Sedna (found in 2004); and the promise of Brown and his colleagues is that more will soon be detected.

Some researchers suspect there could even be Mars-sized objects lurking in this region of the Solar System known as the Kuiper belt.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4730061.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Shuttle set despite 'loose ends'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The US space agency officials have been holding &quot;spirited discussions&quot; ahead of this week's planned lift-off.

There were some loose ends, said one official, but these would probably not prevent the shuttle from flying.

This will be the first shuttle mission since the loss of Columbia and its seven astronauts in February 2003.

&quot;We have a couple of loose ends to tie up,&quot; deputy shuttle programme manager, Wayne Hale, said.

Mr Hale said these issues related to a tanking test carried out in April, when two of four sensors that detect when the hydrogen tank is full failed to work properly; and a pressure relief valve operated more often than expected.

He said they were having trouble passing data from a weather balloon test added since the Columbia accident.

&quot;They're nothing major, but I would say we have to resolve these issues,&quot; Mr Hale said.

The Columbia accident was triggered by a suitcase-sized piece of foam insulation that broke off the external fuel tank during lift-off and damaged the vehicle's left wing.

When the crew attempted to return through the atmosphere, superheated gases entered the wing and tore the orbiter apart.

Discovery's launch is scheduled for 1551 EDT (2051 BST; 1951 GMT) on Wednesday, when the chances of weather being acceptable for launch are 70%.

If lift-off is delayed for 24 or 48 hours, this figure is forecast to drop to 60%. One concern for shuttle officials is &quot;tropical depression number five&quot;, a weather system which could yet turn into Hurricane Emily.

However, First Lieutenant Mindy Chavez, a shuttle launch weather officer from the US Air Force, said tropical depression number five was not expected to start causing problems until Monday.

The mission is scheduled to last 12 days, with landing set for 1101 EDT (1601 BST; 1501 GMT) on 25 July at the Kennedy Space Center.

The mission will carry spare parts and other equipment to the International Space Station (ISS).</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4674947.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Red Planet scientist battles MS</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Professor Colin Pillinger, from the Open University, said he had been diagnosed with a progressive form of the neurological condition in May.

The planetary scientist underwent tests after having difficulty walking for the past two years.

He now uses crutches when he is away from the security of his home or Milton Keynes laboratory.

Beagle 2, a robot designed to search for life, should have landed on Mars in 2003 but vanished without trace.

The last anyone saw of it was in an image snapped from the Mars Express mothership as it hurled its baby towards the Red Planet.

Since the disappointment, Professor Pillinger has been working to persuade space agencies to take a follow-up mission back to Mars.

He told me his condition would not affect his efforts to get British technology back on the surface of the fourth planet.

&quot;The work is mostly about meetings and I can always reach you with a crutch if I need to prod you, you see!&quot;

Professor Pillinger then gleefully demonstrated the various uses of his new &quot;bargaining tool&quot; on me. It graphically illustrated that he has lost neither his sense of fun nor fire.

He submitted his latest plans to explore Mars to the European Space Agency in April, and has also asked the US space agency (Nasa) if it would be willing to put a Beagle &quot;pod&quot; on its Mars Science Laboratory probe in 2009.

&quot;We have unfinished business on Mars. The science is more important now than it ever was because of discoveries made with Mars Express, the Nasa rovers and ground-based astronomy.

Professor Pillinger is 62. It is highly unusual for someone his age to get the disease. It is more common for people to get the disease between the ages of 20 and 40. There is no effective treatment for the condition.

So is he interested in diverting his efforts away from space and toward medical research?

&quot;I've thought as to whether or not I should suddenly become a champion for MS research. I think that would be a little bit selfish because I believe that by doing the things we do in space, we encourage people to take science and technology careers.

&quot;It's actually those people who'll be running the instruments in the hospitals that do the diagnostics. So I think I can do better championing all science rather than just one cause.&quot;

The Open University scientist has stepped down as head of department in order to concentrate on his latest Mars venture.

&quot;This is a question which has fascinated people for centuries. I think we're so close to finding out the answer.

&quot;I'd still very much like the team behind Beagle to be the one to answer that question. Unless you find whether there is or isn't life on Mars I don't think it's fair to start sending astronauts to explore the place.&quot;

Professor Pillinger concedes that the MS will slow down his efforts to get back to Mars.

&quot;But,&quot; he says, &quot;it's not going to stop me!&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4671941.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Discovery blasts off from Florida</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Space shuttle Discovery blasted off on its 12-day flight at 1039 local time (1539 BST) from the Kennedy Space Center in Florida.

It roared up into a bright blue sky to the cheers of spectating astronaut families and US space agency staff.

Discovery's crew will test safety measures brought in after the Columbia accident in 2003 and resupply the International Space Station.

US space agency officials said they were happy with the launch, despite the sighting of what appeared to be some debris falling around the vehicle during the flight to orbit.

They said they would wait for detailed photo analysis to be done before coming to any conclusions about the structural integrity of Discovery.

&quot;On behalf of the many millions of people who believe so deeply in what we do, good luck, God speed and have a little fun up there,&quot; Nasa launch director Mike Leinbach told Commander Eileen Collins and her crew just before lift-off.

An earlier attempt on 13 July had to be scrubbed because of the failure of a fuel sensor; but the problem did not recur on Tuesday and the countdown proceeded without interruption.

Collins and her crew were strapped in and the hatch closed as launch controllers went through the pre-flight checks.

On cue, the orbiter raced skyward leaving a huge exhaust plume in its wake.

The separation of solid boosters and external tank all occurred without incident; and after eight-and-a-half minutes, Discovery shut down its engines to enter the planned preliminary orbit.

A series of thruster firings will gradually raise its altitude over the next couple of days.

&quot;We know that the folks back on the planet Earth are just feeling great right now and our thanks to everybody for all the super work that's been done over the past two-and-ahalf-years to get us flying again,&quot; Collins told mission control in Houston not long after launch.

&quot;Take note of what you've seen today,&quot; said Nasa chief Dr Mike Griffin.

Nasa says it has learnt the safety lessons of the Columbia disaster, which cost the lives of seven astronauts, and has made this the most scrutinised shuttle flight ever.

Columbia broke up as it attempted to re-enter Earth's atmosphere.

Super-heated gases entered a hole punched in the wing during take-off by a suitcase-sized chunk of foam from the external tank, tearing the vehicle apart.

Shuttle managers expect to have all the imagery in and checked over by day six of the flight. If there is an issue over the debris sighted at launch, engineers should have ample information to judge the seriousness of the situation.

US President George W Bush watched the launch on television.

&quot;I thank the men and women of Nasa who have dedicated themselves to putting our space programme back on track,&quot; he said in a statement.

&quot;Our space programme is a source of great national pride, and this flight is an essential step toward our goal of continuing to lead the world in space science, human spaceflight, and space exploration.&quot;

Discovery will take parts and supplies to the ISS and test new safety features such as a repair-kit for heatshield tiles and a 15m-long robotic arm that will inspect the shuttle for damage in orbit.

Discovery is due to touch down at Kennedy Space Center on 7 August at 0546 EDT (0946 GMT; 1046 BST).</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4716463.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Snag won't hold up shuttle launch</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The falling cover damaged two heatshield tiles on the panel near the rear of the shuttle.

But engineers say they have already replaced the panel, which is said to be a routine procedure.

This week's mission would be the first since the loss of Columbia and its seven astronauts in February 2003.

Discovery is due to lift off from Kennedy Space Center at 1551 EDT (2051 BST; 1951 GMT) on Wednesday.

US space agency (Nasa) engineers said they still do not know why the cover was not attached properly.

&quot;Right now [there is] no impact to tomorrow's time and date,&quot; said shuttle vehicle manager Stephanie Stilson.

The incident is likely to be mildly embarrassing for Nasa on the eve of what it hopes will be the safest shuttle flight ever.

Nasa officials said the &quot;soft&quot; cover had fallen off by itself at about 1700 EDT (2200 BST; 2100 GMT) on Tuesday during routine work at launch pad 39B, where Discovery is being readied for launch.

The Oms pod houses an engine and propellant for the shuttle to manoeuvre in orbit. The carrier panel seals the Oms pod to the rest of the orbiter.

&quot;When we discovered the damage, we went ahead and pulled a spare carrier panel. The Oms pods are interchangeable, so the carrier panels are as well,&quot; said Ms Stilson.

&quot;We found that it fitted perfectly.&quot;

The repair procedure takes about an hour to complete.

The soft window cover which fell is made of plastic with a foam edge and is taped in place to protect the windows and keep them clean before launch.

Earlier, Nasa administrator Dr Mike Griffin had given a frank press conference outlining the importance of launching the shuttle.

&quot;There is no recovery from the mistakes we've made, whether it's going back to the Apollo fire, the loss of Challenger, or the loss of Columbia; going back to go through 100 years of flight, the lessons that we who fly know are written in other people's blood,&quot; he told reporters at Nasa's Kennedy Space Center in Florida.

&quot;Obviously, it is utterly crucial for Nasa, for the nation, for our space programme, to fly a safe mission,&quot; Dr Griffin added.

&quot;We have done everything that we know to do.&quot;

Its mission is scheduled to last 12 days, with landing set for 1101 EDT (1601 BST; 1501 GMT) on 25 July at the Kennedy Space Center.

The mission will carry spare parts and other equipment to the International Space Station.

Columbia and its crew of seven perished as they flew home for landing, the result of undetected damage from a debris impact during lift-off that had no effect on the ship in space.

One final obstacle to Wednesday's launch may be stormy weather forecast for the area.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4677495.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Discovery restocks space station</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The transfer has been given added urgency by Nasa's decision to ground the shuttle fleet after this mission.

The astronauts had planned to give the station 13.6 metric tons (15 tons) of items stored in a cargo unit.

They are now also transferring computers, office supplies, food, water and other items from Discovery.

The US space agency has extended Discovery's mission by a day to allow time to unload the extra cargo, with the shuttle's return to Earth now set for 8 August.

The Discovery mission is the first shuttle trip to the ISS since 2002, and the first mission since the Columbia disaster.

Nasa announced it would ground the shuttle fleet once again last week after videos showed insulating foam from Discovery's external fuel tank breaking loose as the shuttle launched from Florida.

Loose foam from the fuel tank was blamed for the damage which caused the loss of the Columbia and its seven crew on re-entry to the Earth's atmosphere in February 2003, and was not supposed to happen again after Nasa spent $1bn and two and a half years attempting to solve the problem.

Discovery suffered minor damage to its protective tiles at launch because of the flying debris, but Nasa says laser and television scans of the orbiter show no major problems.

The Discovery astronauts are working with space station astronauts Sergei Krikalev and John Phillips to unload the Italian-made cargo unit, named Raffaello.

&quot;It is kind of just like working in your closets and your garage,&quot; station flight director Mark Ferring said. &quot;It's a lot of work.&quot;

During the moratorium on shuttle flights, Russian spacecraft were used to ferry supplies to the space station but they cannot transport as much cargo - or the large modules used to piece together the unfinished outpost.

Discovery astronauts Steve Robinson and Soichi Noguchi made a spacewalk of nearly seven hours to test heat shield repair techniques developed since such damage led to the disintegration of Columbia.

The tests were made not on Discovery itself but on damaged heat shield tiles carried into space for that purpose.

They also carried out some overdue repairs to the space station, restoring power to a failed gyroscope and replacing a broken positioning antenna.

Robinson and Noguchi are due to make another spacewalk on Monday.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4732225.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Problem delays US shuttle launch</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>No new launch date has been set, but Nasa managers say the most optimistic possibility for the next attempt could be as early as Saturday.

The US space agency aborted Wednesday's launch shortly before lift-off when a fuel sensor started to play up.

The orbiter was set to make the first flight since the loss of Columbia and its crew of seven in February 2003.

All seven members of the crew died in the accident.

Discovery's astronauts had all been strapped into the shuttle and were preparing for blast-off when the order came through to stand down.

Nasa's chief administrator Mike Griffin told reporters he did not know whether the problem could be fixed at the launch pad or would require the shuttle to be rolled back into its hangar.

The latter would mean a lengthy delay to Discovery's mission to the International Space Station.

The faulty sensor is one of four in the shuttle's external tank responsible for making sure the spacecraft's engines shut down at the proper point during the ascent.

The sensors ensure the engines are not suddenly starved of propellants and are switched off in a controlled fashion.

Nasa said it appeared that one sensor was showing a low level on the part of the tank containing the hydrogen propellant - even though the tank had been fully topped up ready for launch.

The sensors &quot;for some reason did not behave today and so we're going to have to scrub this launch attempt,&quot; launch director Mike Leinbach informed colleagues.

&quot;So appreciate all we've been through together, but this one is not going to result in a launch attempt today,&quot; he added.

The current launch window runs until the end of July, after which Discovery would have to wait until September to get airborne.

The long wait results from the need to have the International Space Station in the right position in orbit and Nasa's desire to launch during daylight hours so it can photograph all aspects of the ascent.

Discovery's mission will be the first for a space shuttle in two and a half years.

The agency says it has learnt the lessons of the Columbia accident.

Improvements to Discovery include a 50ft-long (15m) robotic arm that will inspect parts of the orbiter for damage once in orbit.

It was a suitcase-sized chunk of this material that crashed into Columbia's left wing, punching a large hole and leaving the orbiter open to the destructive super-heated gases of re-entry.

More cameras than ever before will be trained on Discovery during launch, to watch for any debris that could damage the spacecraft.

&quot;It is utterly crucial for Nasa, for the nation, for our space programme, to fly a safe mission,&quot; Dr Griffin said on Tuesday.

&quot;We have done everything that we know to do.&quot;

Discovery's 12-day mission to the International Space Station will deliver spare parts and essential supplies.

It will also test out new safety procedures and kits that have been designed to repair in orbit and damage sustained by the shuttle on launch.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4680687.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Nasa to give Discovery all-clear</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Orbiter managers have said the heatshield tiles and insulation blankets are in good shape for the fiery re-entry to Earth's atmosphere.

A six-and-a-half-hour spacewalk to test repair techniques for heatshield tiles was completed successfully by two of Discovery's astronauts on Saturday.

Nasa has decided to extend the mission by one day.

Heatshield panels that line the shuttle's wing leading edge are expected to be cleared on Monday.

But some outstanding issues are preventing managers from giving Discovery 100% clearance to return.

Mission managers have also formally approved extension of Discovery's 12-day mission by a single day, at the request of International Space Station officials.

Discovery's damage assessment is based on data from inspections of the shuttle in space using a 15m-long boom.

These showed some pockmarks on the shuttle's underside and one gouge near the nose landing gear doors.

They also found that a thermal insulation blanket had billowed out just under the commander's window.

&quot;All of those items have been formally assessed through rigorous engineering models in great detail and found acceptable to fly home as is,&quot; shuttle deputy programme manager Wayne Hale told reporters in Houston, Texas.

But two gap fillers are known to be sticking out from the shuttle's underside just aft (rear) of the nose landing-gear doors.

When gap fillers protrude, they can disturb the aerodynamic flow under the shuttle as it re-enters the atmosphere. This can raise temperatures on heatshield tiles downstream of the protrusion by as much as 200 degrees.

It can also have implications for flight control.

Shuttle managers have been mulling whether to send an astronaut out on a spacewalk to physically trim the fabric fillers.

&quot;That is not completely off the table,&quot; said Mr Hale.

The deputy programme manager said he believed experts assessing images of the reinforced carbon-carbon panels lining the wing leading edge would formally clear those for re-entry on Monday.

&quot;Once we get that clearance we will be able to tell you the heatshield of Discovery is completely ready for re-entry,&quot; he said.

But Mr Hale said he thought the team now understood this phenomenon, which was probably down to a form of surface blistering and did not have important implications for the return to Earth.

Shuttle experts think the protruding gap fillers may have be shaken out by vibrations during the climb to orbit.

All the other minor damage to the shuttle is thought to be caused by the impact of foam debris from the external tank.

Early on Saturday, astronauts Steven Robinson and Soichi Noguchi carried out the first of three spacewalks scheduled for the STS-114 return-to-flight mission.

They tested repair techniques for the heatshield tiles and carried out maintenance tasks for the International Space Station (ISS), including the restoration of power to a failed control moment gyroscope, replacing a GPS antenna and recovering materials experiments mounted outside the station.

Discovery will transfer more hardware and supplies during the day-long extension to its period docked to the ISS in case another shuttle does not return for some time.

Despite Discovery sustaining far less damage than the average for previous shuttle flights, Nasa has grounded its fleet until the problem of foam debris from the external tank has been solved, placing a scheduled September launch in doubt.

Multiple chunks of debris were shed during Discovery's climb to orbit, the largest of which weighed about one pound - slightly smaller than the debris that hit space shuttle Columbia in 2003, tearing a hole in its wing that allowed superheated gases to enter the orbiter on re-entry, ripping it apart and killing seven astronauts.

Despite the foam problem, Nasa administrator Mike Griffin has said he is optimistic the agency can solve it and fly another shuttle mission this year.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4732003.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Distant object found orbiting Sun</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Details of the object are still sketchy. It never comes closer to the Sun than Neptune and spends most of its time much further out than Pluto.

It is one of the largest objects ever found in the outer Solar System and is almost certainly made of ice and rock.

It is at least 1,500km (930 miles) across and may be larger than Pluto, which is 2,274km (1,400 miles) across.

The uncertainty in estimates of its size is due to errors in its reflectivity.

It might be a large, dim object, or a smaller, brighter object. Whatever it is, astronomers consider it a major discovery.

In 2004 scientists discovered Sedna, a remote world that is 1,700 km across.

Two groups of scientists will be claiming the latest discovery.

It was picked up by astronomers of the Institute of Astrophysics in Andalusia as part of a survey of the outer solar system for new objects that they have been carrying out since 2002.

&quot;We found a bright, slow moving object while checking some older images of our survey for Trans-Neptunian Objects,&quot; Jose-Luis Ortiz, one of the objects co-discoverers, told the BBC News website.

However, American astronomers also appear to have detected it.

The same team that found Sedna have designated it K40506A after it was picked up by the Gemini telescope and one of the twin Keck telescopes in Hawaii.

They are due to present their findings at a conference in Cambridge in September.

Because the object is relatively bright, astronomers are frantically checking other observations that may have picked it up, particularly robotic sky surveys.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4726733.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Shuttle may launch despite glitch</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Engineers have raced to isolate the glitch, and have come up with two likely candidates.

The current launch window is open until 31 July, but may be widened into the first week of August.

Discovery's 12-day mission to the International Space Station (ISS) marks Nasa's first shuttle launch since the loss of Columbia on 1 February 2003.

Dr Mike Griffin, the US space agency's administrator, said he hoped the problem would recur during countdown tests, so engineers could resolve the problem once and for all.

&quot;What you want of Nasa is that we make the right technical decisions, that we do the right thing, to the extent that we can figure that out, which is hard,&quot; he explained.

&quot;We can't restrict the range of our options to those things that are going to present well.&quot;

The launch attempt on 13 July was scrubbed when one of four identical engine cut-off (Eco) sensors failed a routine countdown check. The sensors act as fuel gauges, monitoring the volume of cryogenic hydrogen in the shuttle's external tank.

For Tuesday, the wiring between sensors number two - which played up last time - and number four has now been switched, to try to isolate the glitch.

If engineers see a failure in either of these sensors, managers say they will understand the problem well enough to fly Discovery.

However, if an unforeseen problem with the other sensors arises, they will have to abort the launch.

Engineers have so far identified and fixed three electrical grounding issues in the sensor wiring system and also suspect electromagnetic interference from other hardware could be the root cause of the problem.

Mr Hale brandished an example of the sensor involved at a news conference here at Kennedy Space Center.

Though engineers have completed a battery of &quot;ambient&quot; tests on the sensor system, they have to wait until the early hours of Tuesday to check how they perform with a full tank of cryogenic liquid hydrogen.

Mr Hale countered suggestions that Nasa carry out a &quot;tanking&quot; test, in which the external tank is filled up with cryogenic propellants, before attempting launch.

&quot;I think we're all still struggling a bit with the ghosts of Columbia, so we want to make sure we do this right,&quot; said Mr Hale.

&quot;Are we taking care enough to do it right? Based on the last 10 days' worth of effort, the huge number of people and the tremendous number of hours that have been spent testing and analysing - I think we're coming to the right place.&quot;

At the right time

The sensors at the heart of Nasa's troubleshooting operation ensure the orbiter's three main engines shut down before its fuel runs out, avoiding the potentially catastrophic scenario of the motors running with empty tanks.

But the agency also needs to be sure that the sensor glitch does not lead to the alternative and equally unwelcome scenario in which the engines shut down too early because the system believes wrongly all the tanks are empty.

An engine shutdown before Discovery reached its intended orbit could force the crew to abort the mission and make an emergency landing.

The US space agency has set Tuesday's launch for 1039 EDT (1439 GMT; 1539 BST).

Discovery's 12-day mission will deliver parts and supplies to the ISS. It will also give the astronauts a chance to test new safety features on the shuttle brought in following the loss of Columbia.

If Tuesday's launch goes ahead as planned, the shuttle will return to Earth on the morning of 7 August, landing at Kennedy Space Center.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4714063.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Nasa to continue shuttle checks</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The agency has suspended all future orbiter flights until it can find an effective way to stop foam sliding off the vehicle's external tank on launch.

The images taken from the International Space Station suggest Discovery has suffered no major harm on its lift-off.

Nasa chief, Dr Mike Griffin, said the shuttle looked to be &quot;a clean bird&quot;.

And part of Friday has been set aside for astronauts to take a closer look at &quot;areas of interest&quot; - places on the tiled surface which may have chips or nicks.

The concern about Discovery's structural integrity stems from video footage of Tuesday's spectacular launch that showed foam falling about the vehicle a few minutes into its ride to orbit.

Before arriving at the space station, Discovery performed an unprecedented 360-degree flip. It allowed the crew on the ISS the chance to train long lenses on the vehicle's underside.

&quot;The team is employing all of their tools to go look at that. The team has a lot of information. They have a lot of data. And we'll work to understand that,&quot; flight operations manager John Shannon said during a media briefing.

&quot;Some good news is, it looks like all of the foam loss that we had from the tank did not hit the orbiter.&quot;

Discovery's docking with the ISS was completed at 0718 EDT (1218 BST; 1118 GMT) above the South Pacific just west of Chile.

The ISS crew, American John Phillips and Russian Sergei Krikalev, warmly greeted Discovery's seven-member team, led by Commander Eileen Collins.

&quot;We are ready to get on with a mission that the station has been waiting to see for two-and-a-half years,&quot; said flight director Paul Hill.

Nevertheless, Nasa is having to grapple with the disappointment of seeing the foam issue raise its head again.

It was a suitcase-sized chunk of the material that led to the loss of Discovery's sister craft, Columbia, and its crew of seven in February 2003.

During Tuesday's launch, at least three pieces of foam came off the Discovery, including one about 80cm (31 inches) by 35cm (14 inches), slightly smaller than the piece which caused Columbia's destruction.

&quot;We will simply never be able to get the amount of debris shed by the tank down to zero,&quot; Dr Griffin told NBC television. &quot;We are trying to get it down to a level that cannot damage the orbiter.&quot;

Nasa will want to establish if these areas have been compromised in a way that might prohibit a safe return to Earth for Discovery. That landing is currently scheduled for 7 August.

Three spacewalks are planned for the mission.

The first on Saturday will test repair kits designed to deal with small damage areas on the shuttle's heatshield tiles.

The two other spacewalks will repair and install critical hardware outside the space station.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4726177.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Foam 'might have struck shuttle'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>But they said they were confident the craft would make a safe return.

Nasa deputy programme manager Wayne Hale said new photographic evidence appeared to suggest an impact with one of the wings.

But he stressed there was a &quot;divergence of opinion&quot; at Nasa on whether the foam had actually made contact.

&quot;There are 11 indications of potential impacts,&quot; said Steve Poulos, manager of the orbiter project office.

&quot;We might have four areas of the wing leading edge where there might have been an impact.&quot;

Mr Hale said he did not believe the impact had caused any damage to the shuttle.

But in January 2003, the Columbia shuttle broke up as it re-entered the Earth's atmosphere after a piece of insulating foam struck its wing.

Although officials said the shuttle Atlantis could be launched as part of a rescue operation and was being held &quot;on readiness&quot;, they stressed they were &quot;nowhere near doing that&quot;.

The agency has suspended all future orbiter flights until it can find an effective way to stop foam sliding off the vehicle's external tank on launch.

The concern about Discovery's structural integrity stems from video footage of Tuesday's spectacular launch that showed foam falling about the vehicle a few minutes into its ride to orbit.

Before arriving at the space station, Discovery performed an unprecedented 360-degree flip. It allowed the crew on the ISS the chance to train long lenses on the vehicle's underside.

The digital images were sent down to Nasa's Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas, for engineers to work over.

The ISS crew, American John Phillips and Russian Sergei Krikalev, warmly greeted Discovery's seven-member team, led by Commander Eileen Collins.

Work was immediately started to allow the 15 tonnes of supplies ferried up by the shuttle to be moved across to the station.

During Tuesday's launch, at least three pieces of foam came off the Discovery, including one about 80cm (31 inches) by 35cm (14 inches), slightly smaller than the piece which caused Columbia's destruction.

&quot;We will simply never be able to get the amount of debris shed by the tank down to zero,&quot; Dr Griffin told NBC television. &quot;We are trying to get it down to a level that cannot damage the orbiter.&quot;

Nasa will want to establish if these areas have been compromised in a way that might prohibit a safe return to Earth for Discovery. That landing is currently scheduled for 7 August.

Three spacewalks are planned for the mission.

The first on Saturday will test repair kits designed to deal with small damage areas on the shuttle's heatshield tiles.

The two other spacewalks will repair and install critical hardware outside the space station.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4726543.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Shuttle links with space station</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The manoeuvre allowed the crew on the ISS to take photographs of the shuttle's exterior.

They will be used to assess any damage which may have been caused when foam insulation broke off the orbiter's external fuel tank during the liftoff.

Nasa is concerned enough about the issue to suspend all future launches.

It was a similar fault that led to the loss of Discovery's sister craft, Columbia, and its crew of seven in February 2003.

But Nasa administrator Dr Mike Griffin said it would be wrong to over-dramatise the current situation with Discovery.

&quot;Everything that we see at this point says that the orbiter is in fact a clean bird,&quot; he told the ABC's Good Morning America programme.

Just before docking, Discovery performed a three-quarter-of-a-degree per second, 360-degree backflip to allow Russian cosmonaut Sergei Krikalev and US astronaut John Phillips - the ISS crew - a good view of its belly.

The images were transmitted from the space station for analysis at Nasa's Johnson Space Center, in Houston, Texas.

Initial reports indicated there were no areas that had been obviously or seriously impacted.

Managers announced the suspension of all shuttle flights on Wednesday evening EDT after more than a day analysing video and still images of Discovery's spectacular ascent from Florida.

The Discovery astronauts themselves also fed into the investigation the results of their own inspection of the orbiter's exterior using a boom with sensor and camera attachments.

From the evidence, it is clear a 61-84cm (24-33 inch) piece of foam tore away from the external fuel tank's Protuberance Air Load (Pal) ramp.

A 15cm (six-inch) piece of foam also came away from the tank bipod area, where engineers carried out important modifications post-Columbia, and smaller pieces from the acreage foam just below it.

None of the foam is thought to have hit Discovery but it does mean Nasa will have to revisit the whole issue of foam insulation on the external tank.

The foam prevents the formation of ice on the fuel tank while it is standing on the launch pad.

&quot;We have got to go take a look at this, and we have got to go find a solution to this problem. And we will,&quot; shuttle programme manager Bill Parsons said.

Nasa will want to establish if these &quot;areas of interest&quot; will compromise in anyway a safe return to Earth for Discovery. That landing is currently scheduled for 7 August.

The astronauts expect to get a close look at the two tile areas on Friday.

Three spacewalks are planned for the mission.

The first on Saturday will test repair kits designed to deal with small damage areas on the shuttle's heatshield tiles.

The two other spacewalks will repair and install critical hardware outside the space station.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4725179.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Nasa looks into shuttle 'debris'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The events were captured in onboard video and the agency says it now needs to consider their significance.

In one case, a heatshield tile seems to have been affected on the underside of the shuttle.

Discovery's astronauts are to use a 15m-long robotic arm to inspect the orbiter's exterior.

The arm is equipped with sensor and camera attachments. A full sweep of the shuttle's key surfaces will take several hours.

It appears the tip of the shuttle's external fuel tank also hit a bird as it launched from Kennedy Space Center on Tuesday.

John Shannon, STS-114 mission operations representative, pointed out video frames apparently showing a piece of heatshield tile breaking off from the underside of the shuttle.

&quot;We're very interested in that,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;That's something we're going to get better pictures of on flight-day three.&quot;

Mr Shannon said it could simply be that part of the black covering on the orbiter's underside was damaged exposing the heatshield tile.

But he added that it was equally possible the tile itself had been dented or sheared.

The missions operations representative also showed journalists video footage of a dark object falling from the external tank.

Experts cannot yet determine its size, but it did not appear to hit the shuttle, they said.

News outlets had reported details of this piece of debris falling off the tank earlier in the day.

Tuesday's successful launch was Nasa's second go at a lift-off in the current launch window.

Nasa says it has learnt the safety lessons of the Columbia disaster, which cost the lives of seven astronauts, and has made this the most scrutinised shuttle flight ever.

Columbia broke up as it attempted to re-enter Earth's atmosphere.

Nasa had positioned more than 100 cameras, both on the ground and in the air, to capture as much detail as possible on Discovery's ascent into orbit.

Discovery will take parts and supplies to the ISS and test new safety features such as a repair-kit for heatshield tiles and a 15m-long robotic arm that will inspect the shuttle for damage in orbit.

Discovery is due to touch down at Kennedy Space Center on 7 August at 0546 EDT (0946 GMT; 1046 BST).</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4719847.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Space check for shuttle damage</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Discovery's belly tiles were imaged by cameras on the International Space Station (ISS) as it moved into dock.

Video footage caught foam peeling off Discovery's external tank on launch and Nasa wants to be sure there are no holes on the vehicle's underside.

Until the foam issue can be fixed, shuttles will not lift-off, Nasa says.

Tuesday's shedding foam is not thought to have hit Discovery, but two heatshield tiles do appear to be broken underneath the vehicle.

However, the first reports of the ISS investigation indicated there were no major areas of damage to contend with.

It was a suitcase-sized piece of foam that fell off the Columbia shuttle during its launch and punched a hole in the wing.

The damage did not present problems in orbit, but as the vehicle tried to re-enter Earth's atmosphere on 1 February 2003, super-heated gases entered the wing and tore the orbiter apart.

Managers announced the suspension of all shuttle flights on Wednesday evening EDT after more than a day analysing video and still images of Discovery's flight to orbit.

A 15cm (six-inch) piece of foam came away from the tank bipod area, where engineers carried out important modifications post-Columbia, and smaller pieces from the acreage foam just below it.

&quot;You have to admit when you're wrong and we were wrong. We have to do some more work here,&quot; said shuttle programme manager Bill Parsons.

&quot;Until we fix this, we're not ready to go fly again.&quot;

Shortly after 0600 EDT (1100 BST; 1000 GMT) on Thursday, Discovery performed a three-quarter-of-a-degree per second, 360-degree backflip as it closed in on the ISS.

Russian cosmonaut Sergei Krikalev and US astronaut John Phillips, who were positioned in the station's Zvezda service module, took digital images through 400mm and 800mm lenses.

The pictures should have provided resolution of up to 2.5cm (one inch), good enough to &quot;read the serial numbers on the tiles,&quot; according to flight director Paul Hill.

Discovery's docking with the ISS was completed at 0718 EDT (1218 BST; 1118 GMT) above the South Pacific just west of Chile.

On Wednesday morning EDT, Discovery crew members used the Orbiter Boom and Sensor System (OBSS) to inspect the shuttle's wing and nosecone leading-edge panels.

The OBSS is expected to further inspect &quot;areas of interest&quot; on Friday. These will likely include the two damaged shielding tiles. A rectangular tile near the nose landing-gear doors and a square &quot;chine&quot; tile further toward the aft (back) end of Discovery both appeared to be damaged.

Luckily, the shuttle was nearly out of the atmosphere when the foam broke free, so there was not enough air to accelerate the debris to dangerous speeds.

Nasa spent months changing the way the insulation was applied to the tank. It was thought only small pieces of debris would come off during Discovery's launch.

Mission controllers have since played back astonishing footage shot from Discovery's flight deck by astronaut Soichi Noguchi of the external tank tumbling to Earth after separation.

Discovery is due to touch down at Kennedy Space Center on 7 August at 0546 EDT (0946 GMT; 1046 BST).</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4723869.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | US agrees climate deal with Asia</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>China, India, South Korea, Japan and Australia and the US account for nearly half of world greenhouse gas emissions.

The US-led initiative would tackle global warming with new technology supplied to countries most in need.

Critics say the new compact undermines Kyoto and is likely to be ineffective because it is non-binding.

The pact will allow signed-up countries to set their goals for reducing greenhouse gas emissions individually, with no enforcement mechanism.

The signatories argue it complements, rather than weakens, the 1997 Kyoto agreement, which imposes targets on industrialised countries to cut their emissions.

Australian Prime Minister John Howard said: &quot;The fairness and effectiveness of this proposal will be superior to the Kyoto protocol.

&quot;It demonstrates the very strong commitment of Australia to reducing greenhouse gas emissions, according to an understanding that it's fair in Australia and not something that will destroy Australian jobs and unfairly penalise Australian industries.&quot;

US Deputy Secretary of State Robert Zoellick agreed the six nations &quot;view this as a complement, not an alternative&quot; to Kyoto.

Both the US and Australia have refused to ratify Kyoto, which came into effect earlier this year, partly, they say, because big developing countries like India and China escape emissions limits.

They have also made clear their concern that climate change should only be addressed without harming development or economic growth.

Australian Foreign Minister Alexander Downer told BBC Radio 4's Today programme: &quot;Our view is you really need to focus on technological change to solve the climate change problem... and you do have to involve the major developing countries, which are very substantial emitters.&quot;

The UK government's chief scientific adviser, Sir David King, told the BBC's Today radio programme he doubted the new deal could work without setting caps on emissions.

But, he added, the surprise announcement should be seen as a sign of progress on climate change.

Environmental campaigners have criticised the new pact as ineffectual and serving the interests of industrialised nations.

The Geneva-based Worldwide Fund for Nature (WWF) said: &quot;A deal on climate change that doesn't limit pollution is the same as a peace plan that allows guns to be fired.&quot;

Bob Brown, leader of Australia's opposition Green party, dismissed the agreement as a &quot;coal pact&quot; involving four of the world's largest coal producers - China, the US, India and Australia.

The new group's first summit will be held in Adelaide, Australia, in November.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4723305.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Nasa probe strikes Comet Tempel 1</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The washing machine-sized &quot;impactor&quot; collided with Comet Tempel 1 at a relative speed of 37,000km/h, throwing up a huge plume of icy debris.

The probe's mothership, the Deep Impact spacecraft, watched the event from a safe distance, sending images to Earth.

&quot;We hit it just exactly where we wanted to,&quot; said an ecstatic Dr Don Yeomans, a Nasa mission scientist.

&quot;The impact was bigger than I expected, and bigger than most of us expected. We've got all the data we could possibly ask for.&quot;

Comets - giant &quot;dirty snowballs&quot;, as some have called them - are believed to contain materials that have remained largely unchanged since the formation of the Solar System 4.6 billion years ago.

Scientists hope that by getting &quot;under the skin&quot; of Comet Tempel 1, they can gain new information on the Solar System's original composition and perhaps even how life emerged in our corner of the Universe.

Agency staff working on the $333m mission cheered, clapped and hugged when the first pictures of the impact came through to the control room at Nasa's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) in California.

Dr Charles Elachi, director of JPL, said: &quot;From the beginning, I said this was one of the most daring missions and now we have success.&quot;

&quot;We are in the business of opening new frontiers in the exploration of space. When we analyse the data, we will have a whole new insight into the Universe.&quot;

The collision occurred at just after 0550 GMT at a distance of about 133 million km from Earth.

In the moments before impact, the probe itself relayed pictures of the looming 14km-wide mass of ice, dust and rock. Large circular craters could be seen on the comet's surface.

The impactor's last image was sent just three seconds before impact.

It will take a few days for all the data from Deep Impact's observations to download, and scientists will then spend several months interpreting it.

Researchers were uncertain as to the size of scar their impactor would leave on the comet. It was conjectured to be anywhere from the size of a large house to a football stadium and between two and 14 storeys deep.

Some of the biggest and most expensive instruments were deployed, including the Hubble space observatory in its orbit above the planet, and the world's largest optical telescope facility, the VLT in Chile.

UK planetary scientist Dr Monica Grady, from the Open University, watched a feed of the Deep Impact images sent down to Earth.

&quot;It's absolutely fantastic to see this,&quot; she said. &quot;Before we knew so little about the comet nucleus; we had little idea of what the surface looked like.

And Professor Iwan Williams, from Queen Mary, University of London, who is working on Europe's Rosetta mission to a comet, was also taken aback by the scale of the event.

&quot;It was like a mosquito hitting a 747. What we've found is that the mosquito didn't splat on the surface; it's actually gone through the windscreen.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4647673.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | EU pushes binding climate deal</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A spokeswoman's comments came after the announcement of a voluntary pact, based on new technology, between the US and five Asia-Pacific states.

She also told BBC News that the new pact was unlikely to bring a significant reduction in emissions.

The EU's intention to pursue further legally binding reductions could lead to political disputes later this year.

The new pact will allow signed-up countries - currently the United States, Australia, China, India, South Korea and Japan - to set goals for reducing greenhouse gas emissions individually, with no enforcement mechanism.

The signatories argue it complements, rather than weakens, the 1997 Kyoto agreement, which imposes targets on industrialised countries to cut their emissions.

Speaking at the announcement, which came during the Regional Forum of the Association of South-East Asian Nations (Asean) in Laos, US Deputy Secretary of State, Robert Zoellick, said the six nations &quot;view this as a complement, not an alternative&quot; to Kyoto.

Both the US and Australia have refused to ratify Kyoto, which came into effect earlier this year - partly, they say, because big developing countries like India and China escape emissions limits.

But environmental groups argue that the new agreement undermines the Kyoto Protocol, and will make the process of agreeing a successor treaty more difficult. The Geneva-based Worldwide Fund for Nature (WWF) said: &quot;A deal on climate change that doesn't limit pollution is the same as a peace plan that allows guns to be fired.&quot;

The European Commission's environment spokeswoman Barbara Helferrich told the BBC News website that Europe remained committed to further legally binding reductions in emissions.

&quot;We welcome any initiative that can combat climate change, but this has to be seen in a global context,&quot; she said.

&quot;If it is simply technology and clean coal, it is no substitute for agreements like the Kyoto Protocol and we do not expect it to have a real impact on climate change.

&quot;There will have to be binding global agreements, but on what scale and what basis is yet to be decided.&quot;

The designated forum for making those decisions is the next round of United Nations climate negotiations, which opens in Montreal in November - shortly after the Asia-Pacific grouping holds its first meeting in Adelaide.

There is concern in environmental circles that the United States and Australia will present the new pact as evidence that a &quot;son-of-Kyoto&quot;-style treaty is not needed.

Europe, which for many years has been the leading pro-Kyoto force, is unlikely to agree.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4724877.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Discovery given new launch date</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Nasa engineers have still not fixed the troublesome fuel sensor that stopped an earlier launch attempt but feel they are now getting on top of the issue.

Agency officials said they would start the countdown clock on Saturday for what will be the first shuttle mission since the loss of Columbia in 2003.

Discovery's 12-day venture into orbit will take it to the space station.&quot;

We have a great amount of work to do to get us through this but we all agree that this work is doable to take us to a launch on the 26th (of July),&quot; shuttle programme manager Bill Parsons told reporters.

At issue is the performance a low-level fuel cut-off sensor, which failed to give a correct reading during a routine pre-launch check last week.

The sensor is one of four that warn the shuttle computers if the external tank is about to run dry.

This allows the computers to shut down Discovery's three main engines and its fuel pumps in an orderly fashion - neither too soon nor too late; both scenarios have potentially disastrous consequences.

Exhaustive work by hundreds of engineers suggests that an electrical grounding problem lurking somewhere inside the spacecraft is the most probable cause of the sensor's faulty behaviour.

Shuttle officials said some further tests still needed to be done but that they felt confident now to proceed to a countdown.

If the sensor worked properly during the final hours before launch, Discovery would fly, Bill Parsons said.

If the problem reoccurred but was well understood, then the go-ahead would likely be given to launch the orbiter anyway, he added.

&quot;If anything goes not per the plan that we've laid out in front of us, then we'll have a scrub and we'll have to talk about it.&quot;

Including the first launch attempt on Tuesday, there are at least four opportunities for Discovery to launch during the current launch window, which extends until 31 July; although Nasa managers are now also looking at the possibility of additional launch opportunities in the first week of August.

It would be a controversial move to fly Discovery with a low-level fuel sensor still malfunctioning.

Nasa used to permit launches with only three of the four sensors working properly but then insisted on a four-out-of-four approach after the 1986 Challenger explosion.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4702651.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Astronauts finish long spacewalk</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The two shuttle crew members tested repair techniques for heatshield tiles during the first spacewalk of the Discovery's mission.

It was the first spacewalk for either astronaut, and the first for the US since the 2003 Columbia accident.

Nasa is currently considering extending the mission by one day.

Discovery's crew were woken up this morning with a recording of Noguchi's children singing in a choir.

&quot;What a view!&quot; the Japanese Space Agency astronaut said as he stepped outside the airlock at 0946 GMT while the International Space Station (ISS) was over south-east Asia.

&quot;We were a little late getting out the hatch but during the EVA, they finished the timeline within the appointed time and picked up a couple of extra activities,&quot; said mission operations representative Phil Engelauf.

Using a box containing a sample of heatshield panelling with artificial damage, Steve Robinson tested a gun that dispensed a rubbery sealant called Noax (Non-oxide Adhesive Experimental), which he described as &quot;liquorice-vapour pizza dough&quot;.

Robinson forced the sealant into the cracks with a tool like a putty knife.

Noguchi used &quot;a shoe-polish like dauber&quot; to test a so-called emittance wash which appeared to transfer well despite some bubbling.

During the spacewalk, the Japanese Space Agency astronaut made his way over to the Destiny docking module of the International Space Station (ISS) to photograph the port-side cabin of Discovery.

Mission managers have reported that insulation blanket may have come loose in this area just under the commander's window.

&quot;Each spacewalk is filled with complex, highly choreographed procedures,&quot; Dave Wolf, an astronaut who has flown on previous shuttle missions, told the BBC News website.

He agreed the EVA would have been a baptism of fire for the two first-time spacewalkers.

&quot;Rarely does an image and a feeling grip one than your first time stepping out of the vehicle on a spacewalk and looking down 250 miles and moving at 18,000mph. But the main task is keeping your mind on the job,&quot; Mr Wolf added.

Cindy Begley, Nasa's officer for spacewalks, said: &quot;I've had a lot of crews come back and say that the handrail above the [airlock] hatch is dented from people holding on to it so hard.&quot;

The EVA lasted approximately six hours and 50 minutes, ending as the shuttle-ISS complex orbited above Australia.

The astronauts restored power to a failed Control Moment Gyroscope on the ISS, which maintains the space station's correct position in space, bypassing a faulty power breaker.

They also retrieved space station experiments and moved a stowage-platform attachment device.

Meanwhile, mission specialist Charlie Camarda and pilot Jim Kelly have been continuing to inspect the shuttle for damage sustained during the climb to orbit, using the shuttle's 15m-long boom to photograph and scan Discovery's port wing.

The shuttle sustained about 25 impacts during launch on Tuesday, shuttle managers said, compared with an average of roughly 150 for most shuttle launches.

Nevertheless, all shuttle flights are currently grounded while Nasa tries to fix the problem of foam debris peeling off the external tank during lift-off.

Multiple pieces of foam flew off the tank during Tuesday's launch, the largest of which weighed about one pound, slightly smaller than the chunk that doomed space shuttle Columbia in 2003.

The debris came from an area of the tank called the Protuberance Air Load (Pal) ramp, which was not modified following Columbia.

Nasa administrator Dr Mike Griffin said on Friday that he was optimistic Nasa could launch another shuttle this year &quot;by being smart and working hard&quot;.

An extra day is expected to be added to the mission at the request of International Space Station managers in order to carry out extra tasks on the station.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4730129.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Nasa grounds space shuttle fleet</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Although none is thought to have hit the orbiter, two shielding tiles on Discovery do appear to be damaged.

Managers described the findings as &quot;unacceptable&quot; and said other orbiters would not be safe to fly until changes were made to the launcher system.

&quot;Until we fix this, we're not ready to go fly again,&quot; said Bill Parsons.

&quot;I am personally disappointed that this happened, but it didn't harm the orbiter and we learned something,&quot; the space shuttle programme manager added.

Experts have been poring over video and still images of the launch. Discovery's astronauts, too, have been examining the structural integrity of their orbiter with sensor and camera attachments on the end of a long robotic arm.

They also took images from their cockpit of the external tank immediately after it was jettisoned and was beginning its fall back to Earth.

A six-inch (15cm) foam chunk also fell from an area of the tank called the liquid hydrogen intertank flange. This was an area where several modifications were made after the Columbia disaster.

Officials stressed there was no evidence that either piece of foam had hit Discovery itself.

Mr Parsons said it was too early to say what implications this had for plans to send the Atlantis orbiter into space in the event that Discovery's crew needed to be rescued; but he vehemently denied suggestions that the orbiter system was inherently unsafe.

Of the two heatshield tiles apparently damaged during launch, deputy programme manager Wayne Hale said: &quot;Are we concerned about it? We're treating it very seriously, but we're not losing sleep yet.&quot;

A rectangular tile near the nose landing gear doors appeared to be chipped and a square &quot;chine&quot; tile further toward the aft (back) end of Discovery also seemed to have broken away.

On Thursday, Discovery will do a flip manoeuvre before docking with the International Space Station. This will allow the ISS crew to photograph the underside of the spaceship.

Discovery's mission is the first shuttle flight since the loss of Columbia and its crew of seven in February 2003.

Nasa spent months changing the way the insulation was applied to the tank. It was thought only small pieces of debris would come off during Discovery's launch.

&quot;Perfection is our goal in this business; you seldom get perfection in anything you do. We need to do better than this,&quot; said Mr Hale.

&quot;This is a very difficult business, it's not for the faint-hearted and it's not to be undertaken lightly.&quot;

Discovery is due to touch down at the Kennedy Space Center on 7 August at 0546 EDT (0946 GMT; 1046 BST).</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4723109.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-02 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Science/Nature | Probe on course for comet impact</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science/Nature</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A washing machine-sized 372kg (820lbs) &quot;impactor&quot; is due to smash into Comet Tempel at 0552 GMT on Monday.

The aim is to blast out material frozen inside the comet since the Solar System was formed 4.6 billion years ago.

Scientists hope to get new insights into the Solar System's composition and the chemical building blocks of life.

The impactor itself will shatter as the comet crashes into it at a relative velocity of 37,000 km/h (23,000 mph), but an onboard camera will record the approach in the last minutes before collision.

Deep Impact, the spacecraft which carried and ejected the impactor, will take pictures and gather data from the collision and its aftermath, 133 million kilometres (83 million miles) from Earth.

The Hubble, Chandra, Spitzer and XMM Newton space observatories will be trained on Tempel 1 for the collision, as will ground-based telescopes worldwide.

The impact is expected to excavate a crater more than 25m (80ft) deep and 100m (330ft) across, ejecting ice, dust and gas and exposing &quot;pristine&quot; material.

Rick Grammier, Deep Impact project manager, likened the mission to &quot;a bullet trying to hit another bullet with a third bullet in the right place at the right time&quot;.

But despite the complexities, team members are confident they will not miss.

&quot;The spacecraft are perfectly healthy and where they are supposed to be,&quot; Andy Dantzler, head of Nasa's solar system program, told a news conference on Sunday.

Comets are porous balls of ice and rock hailing from the frigid outer boundaries of our Solar System. Periodically, some journey inwards, looping around the Sun.

Like other comets, Tempel 1 contains pristine material unchanged since the Solar System formed. This is hidden beneath an outer crust.

&quot;These materials have not seen the light of day for 4.6 billion years,&quot; mission scientist Jessica Sunshine said.

&quot;Like any good geologist would, we want to hit it (Tempel 1) with a hammer and see what's inside,&quot; Dr Sunshine added.

Cometary impacts early in Earth history are thought to have first brought water to our planet.

They might also have seeded it with the chemical building blocks required for life. &quot;We want to find out what those materials were,&quot; explained Mr Grammier.

The Deep Impact mission has been named after the Hollywood film in which a comet hits the Earth with devastating effect.

Nasa says there is no risk of the impacter knocking the comet into a dangerous orbit, likening it to a mosquito hitting an airliner. But scientists say information from this mission could inform future strategies for deflecting a comet.

&quot;If you are worried about defending Earth from possible impactors, it's a whole lot easier to change the course of something if you know what it is you're changing the course of,&quot; said Dr Mike A'Hearn, Deep Impact principal investigator.

This week, astronomers got a preview of the pyrotechnics to come when Tempel 1's nucleus released a short-lived blizzard of particles and gas.

These outbursts seem to occur as comets heat up when approaching the Sun.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/4642845.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
