<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>'I swapped Chelsea FC for the City': From goalie to Goldman Sachs - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/15053/production/_108099068_mediaitem108099067.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When Chelsea Women open their season against Tottenham Hotspur Women in front of a full Stamford Bridge this Sunday, one ex-Blues player will be watching with mixed feelings.

Lizzie Durack quit as a Chelsea goalkeeper this summer to follow a new financial career in the City of London, and many of her friends will be in action as the FA Women's Super League kicks off.

And, while they have been taking part in pre-season training, she has been getting her feet under the table at Goldman Sachs in their Prime Brokerage Division, working with wealthy hedge fund clients.

So why - at the age of 25 - has she quit one of England's top teams, with arguably the best years of her playing career still ahead of her?

&quot;I made my decision for a lot of reasons, and obviously it was a difficult one to make.&quot; says Durack, who has a degree in economics and neurobiology, and had previously served an internship at Goldman Sachs when she was a student.

&quot;The main one was - I had come to a point in my football career where I had achieved a certain amount that I was happy with. In order to take the next step and be one of the best in the game, it would have taken five years or so - if I was ever going to be fortunate enough to actually achieve that top level.&quot;

During the 2018-19 season, Durack found herself behind two other goalkeepers in the Chelsea pecking order, and by the end of the season there were four goalkeepers at the club vying for places.

&quot;I had to make this big decision, and take on board the realisation that opportunities for a young goalkeeper are hard to come by,&quot; she says.

&quot;I had thrown myself into football since my teens. It got so I was wondering if I should start a financial career further years down the line, or just say 'it has been a great time, now is the moment I should invest my energies into the world of finance'.&quot;

Durack - who now works in &quot;capital introduction and consulting&quot; at Goldman Sachs - talked things over with her parents who said they would support whatever decision she made.

Similarly, she said Chelsea women's goalkeeping coach Stuart Serle was supportive, asking her to think again, believing she had potential and could kick on in football.

Born in Australia, she was the only girl in her school football team, went on to study at Harvard in the US for four years, won a full international cap for her mother's homeland England, and played professionally for both Everton and Chelsea.

But a different career was never far from her thoughts, and during her last two years as a player she found time to study for the Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) programme for investment professionals, and has passed her CFA Level 1 and 2 exams.

&quot;It was starting to annoy me to see my academic peers getting on with their careers,&quot; says Durack, whose father is from Sydney and mother from Doncaster, &quot;I felt I was missing the intellectual stimulation that a career in finance could give me.&quot;

Durack had joined Chelsea in 2018 after a second spell of playing at Everton, where she says she had a rather &quot;volatile period as a professional&quot;.

&quot;I did enjoy my year at Chelsea, it helped me to see what I really wanted,&quot; she says. &quot;I was grateful for the opportunity at Chelsea.&quot;

&quot;We didn't have a great season last year, it was not a successful season by Chelsea standards, it wasn't ideal, but those things come in waves, and in sport you have to deal with the ups and the downs.&quot;

Durack played three first team games for Chelsea last season and kept three clean sheets, in the FA Women's Continental Tyres League Cup against Crystal Palace, Yeovil Town and Tottenham Hotspur.

Now Durack is getting to grips with what she calls &quot;a huge lifestyle change&quot;, with her typical working day doubled from the six hours spent as a football pro, to ones of 12 hours or more.

&quot;I am going into a very client facing role,&quot; she says. &quot;I am immersed in a very intense environment - I wanted to replicate sport.

&quot;I have always found, in any role, that the people you work with can make or break the experience.&quot;

Her salary will be more than in football, but she says more money &quot;is a consequence, rather than a reason&quot;, of the change. If cash was her motivation, she would &quot;not have gone into football otherwise&quot;.

&quot;I was very much on a living wage at Chelsea, I wasn't rolling in money,&quot; she says.

She says that in her first spell as a player with Everton in 2013 she was not paid much more than expenses. During her second period at Everton in 2017-18 she was on what she calls &quot;a semi-professional wage&quot;, and at Chelsea she was on &quot;a professional wage&quot;.

Durack, who also played for Australia at Under-17 level, and England at numerous age levels, says sport and business have a number of similarities which will stand her in good stead in her new job.

&quot;In both you need to be disciplined, confident, and resilient,&quot; she observes. &quot;Both are a roller-coaster existence, and things can get heated at times.

&quot;But there is some more control of your life in finance. In the City although the hours are long and intense, but you have the ability to book a week of holiday, In contrast when the football season starts you are locked in for 10 months.

&quot;Also luck plays a bigger part generally in football, and work-rate does not always mean winning success or even being selected for the team - sport is more subjective.&quot;

She says this summer's Women's World Cup was a great success, and that the sport in the UK should be trying to piggyback more on the men's game to continue building awareness.

&quot;Getting some of the men players at clubs on board to promote the women's side of the game would be a great help,&quot; she says.

&quot;And, groundsmen won't thank me for saying this, but I think they should have a women's game opening for the men's games. It should be considered a 'one club' thing, if you are a Chelsea fan, you are a women's team supporter too.&quot;

Looking ahead she says: &quot;I hope to go along on the opening day, and follow Chelsea this season. The saddest thing for me is leaving some of my good friends and team-mates behind, and I still feel keenly about what they do.

&quot;But any full time athlete will tell you about the sacrifices. I have made them, and it has been worth it, but all the hours add up and you often can't enjoy being a 25-year-old. I couldn't travel with freedom, or go and see my family in Australia with freedom. I am now looking forward to this new chapter in my life.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49393728</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Ines Geipel: East German sports doping tore lives apart - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Europe</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/339D/production/_107731231_p07fvvs2.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When the Berlin Wall collapsed in 1989 a systematic, coercive administration of performance-enhancing drugs to thousands of young athletes in East Germany was exposed.

It was meant to make them into world beaters and paid no regard to any damage to their health. Many athletes have said they were not told what they were taking.

A compensation fund was set up by the unified German government and a Berlin court case ended with suspended sentences for the head of the East German Sports Ministry, Manfred Ewald, and the chief doctor, Manfred Hoeppner.

Former East German sprinter Ines Geipel told Hardtalk's Stephen Sackur how her youth was shattered by a state sponsored programme of steroids and male hormones which destroyed her health and made her medals worthless.

Watch the full interview on Wednesday 3 July 2019 on BBC World News. Watch again on BBC iPlayer (UK only)</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-48856570</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Rugby World Cup: No clubhouse but there is karaoke - the club game in Japan - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/15556/production/_109328378_tgrfc20yamanashi20tour202019.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Matches played in driving rain, mud everywhere and spectators with cold toes on the touchline. Then, all is made better by a warm shower followed by food and drinks with team-mates in the clubhouse after.

This will be the scene in rugby clubs across the UK as we get deeper into the season. But not so in Japan.

There is still rain, sometimes typhoons, but it is much warmer, with temperatures around 20C. Mud is nowhere to be seen on artificial pitches and the clubhouse after? There is no clubhouse, although karaoke could be on the cards later.

Rugby has been front-page news in the country after the Brave Blossoms' historic run to a first World Cup quarter-final.

Japan proved their ability against tier-one teams in the pool stage, powering past Ireland and Scotland to reach the last eight.

That fairytale was ended by South Africa on Sunday, but afterwards Japan head coach Jamie Joseph said Japanese rugby was in a good place now. It does not, however, seem quite like that at grass-roots level.

There are around 80 amateur clubs registered with the Japanese Rugby Football Union (JRFU) in Tokyo, but very few can afford a permanent home because of high property prices. Instead they rent pitches from the local council once a week.

A culture of long working days means there is rarely time to train and, with sports such as baseball much more popular, only a few clubs can field more than one team.
• What next for Japan's Brave Blossoms?
• How Japan became a force to be reckoned with

Tokyo Gaijin Rugby Football Club is a team of ex-pats and Japanese players - Gaijin means foreigner - based in the city.

On the Sunday after Japan's pool-stage victory against Samoa, they gathered at a train station in Yokohama, about half an hour from the city centre.

Due to a lack of players they were combining with another team, Odawara, to take on a touring side from Beijing, but they had to make it to the ground first.

After queuing behind a crowd of schoolchildren for a public bus, the players eventually squeezed on and made their way up the hill to the sports complex where the match would be played.

Many were playing together for the first time, including a United States fan who had come to Japan for the World Cup and found the team on social media, so they used the journey to get to know each other.

This match-day routine is perhaps why Tokyo Gaijin's club president Tommy Nasuno describes Japanese rugby as &quot;primitive&quot;.

Although the national side has impressed on the world stage, the club game seems to be a labour of love for individuals such as 29-year-old Nasuno. There is hope that could change, though.

&quot;Union support is the biggest issue,&quot; Nasuno said. &quot;There's not enough funding.

&quot;I haven't been able to gauge the effect of Japan's run yet. That being said, it has definitely lit a fire in everyone's eyes, especially the Japanese, bringing hope for the future.

&quot;If the JRFU invests into youth rugby, we will be able to sustain this momentum and actually fight with the best and secure tier-one status?

&quot;Only time will tell. The Rugby World Cup in four years' time will determine if it was a fluke or the real deal.&quot;

Rugby may not be as established at an amateur level as it is in the UK, but there are of course benefits to playing in Japan.

David McElhinney, a freelance rugby and travel writer from Belfast who lived in Tokyo for two years and plays for Nasuno's team, cites matches at the base of Mount Fuji as one.

And then there is the social side to the sport. The team never miss post-match drinks, although the location is slightly different to the clubhouse he is used to back home.

&quot;We always play on Sundays, but win or loss, rain or shine, we go for drinks,&quot; the 25-year-old said.

&quot;We do just drink on the street outside the train station. You go in the convenience store and then sit around doing after-match things like picking man of the match.

&quot;Sometimes you might go to karaoke if it stays on really late. It always starts at the train station but sometimes we'll go elsewhere.&quot;

There are differences on the pitch too. At full-time, teams bow to each other then form a circle where the captains give a short speech and exchange gifts.

Japanese people are usually reserved and boisterous behaviour is not encouraged in society as a whole.

Sometimes a fight will happen in games, but McElhinney says there is slightly different etiquette in Japanese teams.

&quot;Any time there's a bit of a scuffle, the Japanese will never start it and they'll always try and calm it down straight away,&quot; he explains.

&quot;There definitely is more of an element of respect. I guess there is back home but the way we show it is going for a drink after.&quot;

'Universities are more important than clubs'

One reason Japanese club rugby has such meagre resources could be that it is seen as much less important than the university game.

In January, Meiji University won the All-Japan University Rugby Championship in front of a crowd of more than 20,000 and at its peak in the 1980s the competition's final attracted more than 60,000 fans.

But club rugby does not benefit from the same prestige and McElhinney had hoped the World Cup might have provided the impetus needed to improve the situation.

&quot;University level definitely seems more important than the club set-up,&quot; he explains.

&quot;You can tell just from playing rugby here with the lack of funding, energy and resources to develop the grass-roots sport that there's not too much of an interest on making it a big thing.

&quot;The pitch leaves a lot to be desired. They're mostly artificial but the worst pitches are grass because it's not tended to. There's a patch of basically gravel in front of the posts.

&quot;Japan has known it was going to host the World Cup for a long time so they had time to get grass-roots systems in place and it hasn't happened.&quot;

'There's not enough interest to field school teams'

Rugby may be popular in some Japanese universities but Nasuno says it rarely is in schools, except for in certain regions like Osaka.

Having spent four years playing rugby while at Exeter university in England, Nasuno is well-placed to examine the differences between the British and Japanese approaches to the sport.

He explains that Japanese schoolchildren can only choose one activity to do for the whole academic year; they do not change depending on the season as in the UK.

For this reason, rugby loses out to more popular sports like baseball or football and a lot of schools do not have enough interested students to field a full team.

&quot;In the UK you get into rugby really young,&quot; Nasuno added. &quot;Here it's common for people to start rugby when they're on a year abroad.

&quot;In schools, you have to make sure you have the numbers. If you don't have the interest, you can't start the club.&quot;

Has that interest been ignited by Japan's inspiring run to the World Cup quarter-finals?

Japanese fans have embraced the tournament, giving local amateur players hope that club rugby could soon be more than a select few teams playing on rented pitches in the suburbs on a Sunday afternoon.

Who knows? Maybe one day Nasuno and his side might even get a clubhouse.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/50122934</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Why a potential Saudi takeover holds no issue for many Newcastle fans - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Newcastle</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/EE06/production/_110743906_newcastle.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Billy Cann was a season-ticket holder at Newcastle United for 35 years before he decided he'd had enough.

He had been watching his team since 1969 but when owner Mike Ashley sacked Chris Hughton in 2010 the 63-year-old decided not to renew and many fans have since followed.

Their issues are numerous, but chief among them is an owner who they feel does not match their ambition.

&quot;I don't want to give Mike Ashley any more of my cash,&quot; Cann tells BBC Sport en route to a goalless draw with bottom-of-the-table Norwich City for which he has borrowed a ticket.

That is why news of a potential £340m takeover featuring Saudi Arabia's Public Investment Fund has been greeted on the streets of Tyneside with excitement rather than any moral outcry.

Newcastle fans have have been promised a new dawn many times before, so they are sceptical about whether it might even happen.

But instead of worrying about a country's human rights record, which Amnesty International calls &quot;appalling&quot;, many of them see it as a chance to rid the club of Ashley, who has been in charge for 13 years.

As Cann, who works on a gas rig in the North Sea, asks: &quot;Were Manchester City's fans complaining when their Abu Dhabi owners took over the club? Now look at their success.&quot;

It is a common view among Newcastle fans, who see football as a religion and feel their club has been left behind as others have tapped into wealth and ambition from across the globe.

The thread that binds the majority of Newcastle fans is their desire to see Ashley leave the club.

Even those who have reservations about a Saudi takeover - and it is a minority view - still want Ashley out.

The final straw for many was the departure of manager Rafael Benitez last summer.

For them, the Spaniard, who has won the Champions League and the Europa League twice with previous clubs, represented a route back to the top and, more importantly, hope for the future.

He walked away, however, because Ashley did not provide him with financial backing he wanted and, as a result, thousands of fans did not renew their season tickets this season. That led to Ashley dishing out 10,000 free half-season tickets in December in order to keep the stadium full.

Ashley will point to record signings in consecutive transfer windows (£20m for Miguel Almiron in January 2019 and £40m signing Joelinton last summer) and the fact manager Steve Bruce almost spent a reported £35m on Lille's Boubakary Soumare two weeks ago before the midfielder changed his mind.

The owner also said in a rare interview last July that he offered Benitez an eight-year contract and &quot;couldn't have done any more&quot; to keep him at the club.

But down at the Dog and Parrot, a stone's throw from St James' Park, host of the NUFC matters podcast Steve Wraith says the way Ashley treated Benitez was &quot;the ultimate act of treachery&quot;.

He says losing so many fans will cost Newcastle not only next term but in seasons to come.

&quot;Fans voted with their feet and think of all those kids whose parents or uncles or aunties have turned their backs on the club,&quot; Wraith says.

&quot;It has the potential to cut out a new generation of supporters. You see a lot of kids now wearing shirts of other teams in the city rather than Newcastle.&quot;

Asked whether that financial loss could trigger Ashley to sell, Wraith says: &quot;You would think so, but I don't think he's a willing seller.

&quot;He's quite happy to milk Newcastle United for every penny he can and to build his sports brands globally. The only thing that will push him out is a ridiculous offer.&quot;

The Saudi bid, which has been led by financier Amanda Staveley and includes the billionaire Reuben brothers, is not short of money.

Yet not all Newcastle fans believe the takeover should come at any cost.

Norman Riley of the True Faith fanzine says some fans will feel &quot;conflicted&quot; by talk of a Saudi-financed takeover whatever the issues with Ashley.

Riley says he finds a lot of Saudi government policy &quot;abhorrent&quot; and would have to &quot;re-assess his relationship with the club&quot; if the deal goes through.

Those who have no issue often mention how Manchester City are backed by Abu Dhabi, which Amnesty also says is guilty of &quot;sports-washing&quot; their country's &quot;deeply tarnished image&quot; by pouring money into the Premier League champions.

It said the country &quot;relies on exploited migrant labour and locks up peaceful critics and human rights defenders&quot;.

Others mention how Sheffield United are owned by Saudi Prince Abdullah bin Mosaad bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, who took full control from Kevin McCabe last year, although he has not been accused of anything similar to the Saudi government.

Lori, who is sat at the back of the Dog and Parrot with her family, can see both sides to the argument.

&quot;Talk of Saudi human rights abuses might not be the first thing that comes to mind, but it does make you think when you look at it in more detail,&quot; she says.

&quot;The fact it doesn't matter for most fans shows the level of animosity towards Ashley.&quot;

As kick-off for the Norwich game is approaching, Alex, a teacher and mother of one, explains how she is also &quot;anti-Ashley&quot; and keen on new investment.

But she also recognises some of the issues raised about Saudi Arabia, including rights for women and the LGBT community.

&quot;It's a difficult one,&quot; she says. &quot;But similar to what happened at Manchester City, if it brings more investment to the local economy and jobs then it's a positive.

&quot;You also have to question our own government's record given recent wars in the world.

&quot;I totally respect people's rights, but perhaps more links with our country might have a positive impact on their culture and society?&quot;

Do most fans feel the same way as Newcastle's?

Wraith says that for many Newcastle supporters, the team's success would override any lingering doubts over the source of a potential Saudi investment.

&quot;That's an issue for the Premier League or the authorities to work out, not for the fans on the terraces,&quot; he adds.

He also says supporters of other clubs would feel the same way, before referencing Manchester City and Sheffield United.

Choosing between Ashley and a Saudi-backed bid must seem a world away for fans of Norwich City, who are owned by former television chef Delia Smith and her partner Michael Wynn-Jones.

Newcastle are a club on a different scale to the Canaries, but it shows it is possible to have wealthy owners who do not cross any moral boundaries.

Norwich supporter Dan said: &quot;I do like the fact we have Delia and Michael in charge. They are big Norwich fans and care what happens. It's a nice family, community club.

&quot;It would be nice to have more money but it's not the be all and end all. Fans mainly care that the team is winning and how much there is to spend, but it's quite concerning what is going on at some clubs and what else owners are involved in.&quot;

Perhaps that is easier to say if you've not been at loggerheads with your owner for the past decade.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51349042</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Pep Guardiola visits Salvation Army football tournament - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Manchester</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/8167/production/_108972133_p07pbw0g.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The event, which was launched nine years ago, brings together more than 25 teams from the Salvation Army's hostels.

BBC pundit and former Liverpool and Preston player Mark Lawrenson also attended to show his support.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-lancashire-49833656</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Saracens Q&amp;A: What is going on and what does relegation mean? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1473E/production/_110547738_saracenslogo_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Why are Saracens, one of England's most successful rugby union clubs, being relegated from the Premiership at the end of the season?

In the past five years they have dominated both domestically and in Europe, with Sarries winning England's Premiership four times and being European champions three times.

Six Saracens players started for England in the Rugby World Cup final defeat by South Africa in November, including captain Owen Farrell.

But the north London club were hit by a massive fine and points deduction late last year for breaking salary cap rules.

And Premiership Rugby has now confirmed Saracens will be relegated to the Championship at the end of the 2019-20 season.

In November, Saracens were given a 35-point deduction and a £5.4m fine for breaching salary cap regulations for the previous three seasons.

Initially, the club insisted they had done nothing wrong and said they would appeal - this was later withdrawn and the punishment accepted.

It was not until Nigel Wray resigned as chairman and Edward Griffiths returned as chief executive that the club admitted culpability and announced plans to trim down their squad in order to comply with the cap this season.

On Tuesday, 14 January, Premiership bosses met in London at a board meeting.

Given Saracens had not been able to show evidence they were going to comply with the cap this season, it was decided they should face further punishment.

According to Exeter chairman Tony Rowe, Saracens were given a choice: either open up their books for a forensic audit, or accept relegation. Sarries went down the latter route.

Have Saracens released any players this season?

Despite Griffiths' intentions, no players have yet left Saracens, either permanently or on loan.

Saracens are thought to have exceeded the cap by well in excess of £1m last season, and other Premiership clubs were determined to see the champions make major changes to their operation this campaign.

However, simply terminating players' contracts is difficult, with any compensation paid out also counting towards the cap.

While one solution would have seen the players taking a pay-cut across the board, this didn't materialise, and with players being paid since July, it would have been a case of too little, too late.

How have the other clubs reacted?

Exeter have been the most vocal opponents - not surprisingly given how they have lost three Premiership finals in recent seasons to the men in black.

Shortly after Christmas, the Chiefs beat Sarries in an ill-tempered clash at Sandy Park, with director of rugby Rob Baxter strongly reiterating his disillusionment in an interview with the BBC.

Furthermore, Rowe went on BBC Radio Devon minutes after the relegation was confirmed.

&quot;Every club just wants the same opportunity and chances and let's hope we get back to that,&quot; he said.

What happens after relegation?

Saracens' situation is complicated by Wray's retirement as chairman and resignation from the board. He has financed Saracens for decades, reclaiming full control in April 2018. Although Wray's family remain heavily involved, it isn't clear what long-term plans they have for the club.

While Sarries will remain Premiership shareholders, relegation for the club will lead to regrettable redundancies on the non-playing side.

As for the impact on the playing squad…

What happens to the players?

While relegation will almost certainly lead to the break-up of the star-studded squad, it is a complicated situation.

Unlike in football, where there is not a salary cap and there are set transfer windows, rugby clubs tend to finalise their squads for the new season at the start of the calendar year.

While some clubs may have room in the cap for a big name who suddenly becomes available, many will now have started to finalise their playing group for the 2020-21 season.

So either Saracens' players go on the market as free agents, or they take considerable pay cuts elsewhere, or they stay at Sarries - especially as it is unlikely they would have relegation clauses in their contracts.

Like with Mark Wilson and Newcastle, season-long loan deals are a distinct possibility, while players moving abroad is another option.

However, French clubs also have salary cap restrictions, many Pro14 sides are not flush with extra money, and operating overseas would mean players would not be eligible to play for England because of Rugby Football Union regulations.

The dismantling of the squad will start immediately. It's understood a handful of players will leave the club at the end of January.

Could England players play in the Championship?

Yes. There are no rules precluding selecting Championship players for England. While playing a significantly poorer standard of rugby in the second tier would be far from ideal preparation for international rugby - let alone the Lions in 2021 - there could even be benefits for the national side. For example, if a star name stays at Saracens in the event of relegation, he may be able to focus more on being fit and available for England, without the week-to-week grind of Premiership and Champions Cup action.

Can Saracens play in next season's Champions Cup?

As it stands, no. While the winners of the Champions Cup qualify for next season's tournament - and Saracens are still in contention - European organisers have confirmed to the BBC that only teams from the Premiership, Top 14 and Pro14 are eligible to play in European competitions. The only exceptions are the teams from emerging nations who play in the Challenge Cup.

What does it mean for the Premiership?

This episode will serve as a line in the sand. An independent review into the salary cap regulations - conducted by former government minister Lord Myners - is already under way.

It has not just hit the integrity of Saracens as a club - but the Premiership as a whole.

Now it is time to start to repair reputations.
• 'The most remarkable scandal in the domestic game'</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51149035</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Firms urged to crack down on office football chat - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/BEFF/production/_110659884_annfrancke.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Chat about football or cricket in the workplace should be curtailed, a management body has warned.

Chartered Management Institute head Ann Francke said sports banter can exclude women and lead to laddish behaviour such as chat about sexual conquests.

&quot;A lot of women, in particular, feel left out,&quot; she told the BBC's Today programme.

&quot;They don't follow those sports and they don't like either being forced to talk about them or not being included.&quot;

&quot;I have nothing against sports enthusiasts or cricket fans - that's great,&quot; she said.

&quot;But the issue is many people aren't cricket fans,&quot; she added, arguing bosses should crack down on sports banter.

Ms Francke is concerned that discussing football and, for example, the merits of video assistant refereeing (VAR) can disproportionately exclude women and divide offices.

&quot;It's a gateway to more laddish behaviour and - if it just goes unchecked - it's a signal of a more laddish culture,&quot; she said

&quot;It's very easy for it to escalate from VAR talk and chat to slapping each other on the back and talking about their conquests at the weekend.&quot;

Nevertheless, Ms Francke does not think sports chatter should be banned, just moderated.

She said that good managers should be inclusive and ensure that everyone in their team feels comfortable.

But sports journalist Jacqui Oatley thinks cracking down on sports chatter would be a &quot;terrible idea&quot;.

&quot;If you ban football chat or banter of any description, then all you're going to do is alienate the people who actually want to communicate with each other,&quot; she told the Today programme.

&quot;It would be so, so negative to tell people not to talk about sport because girls don't like it or women don't like it, that's far more divisive.&quot;

She said the secret was to discuss sport in an inclusive way and to notice if people were blankly &quot;staring into space&quot; during the conversation.

A majority of people responding to a LinkedIn post from the BBC and on Twitter appear to agree with Ms Oatley.

Former sports, gambling, charities and loneliness minister Tracey Crouch called the Chartered Management Institute's advice &quot;a load of nonsense&quot;.

And others agreed with her on Twitter.

Office manager Debra Smyth worries that other topics such as Love Island, EastEnders and Game of Thrones could also be censored if sport chatter is banned.

&quot;I personally think companies should not dictate what people talk about, as not talking about it will alienate those with similar interests,&quot; she said.

&quot;Where would it end? Banning people with children talking about them so as not to alienate people without children. Certainly not!&quot;

Recruiter Peter Ferguson said: &quot;I have seen managers and staff build a more direct bond over a shared love of sport which has excluded those who don't share that interest.

&quot;The answer is not to ban the conversation, it is to ensure managers and staff are trained to understand that those shared interests should not get in the way of management decisions or working collaboratively.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51261999</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>A football fan explores the dark side of sports betting in Africa - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Africa</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/9589/production/_108918283_p07p3jzj.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sports betting has exploded across Africa. But are the betting companies playing it straight? Do the punters really understand the odds they’re up against? And who is getting rich from the thrill of the beautiful game?

BBC Africa Eye follows one young football fan on a journey across Uganda, to find out what happens when global companies target some of the poorest and most vulnerable people on the continent.

If you have been affected by any of the issues in this video, you can seek further information and support here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-49796438</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>What baseball parks tell us about US cities - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>US &amp; Canada</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1BA6/production/_107187070_p07bx5t4.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Baseball 'on the rise' in London

The London Mets are playing the Essex Arrows this weekend in the National Baseball Finals at a time when the sport has never been more popular in the UK.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-48454118</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Saracens relegation 'is most remarkable scandal in the domestic game' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1334A/production/_110566687_allianzparkgeneralreuters.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Relegations are a familiar and routine part of every sporting landscape. Do not for a moment think Saracens' demotion from English rugby's Premiership has anything to do with that.

This is the most remarkable scandal the domestic game has ever seen.

The dominant team at home and the multiple champions of Europe. A club that has provided more players to England over the past four years than any other. The club that gave England their captain, Owen Farrell. The club that gave England their icon, Maro Itoje. The club that gave England the entire spine of the pack.

It is as momentous to rugby union as it would have been to football had the same happened to the Manchester United of Sir Alex Ferguson.

This is not inadvertent financial mismanagement, which has taken down plenty of great sporting institutions in the helter-skelter dash for glory and its monetary rewards. It is deliberate and clandestine circumvention of the rules, over a significant period of time. It is cheating.

Four Premiership trophies, three Champions Cups. That is a lot of iconic moments, a lot of trophies being hoisted, a lot of laps of honour, garlands and awards, for many rivals to consider forever tainted.

Money in itself guarantees nothing in sport. Saracens still had great players playing at their peak as a relentless unit. They had fine coaching and an ethos that ran through much of the club, from the academy to the Saracens Foundation, that deserves considerable praise. Underpinning it all was a support that would buttress any club.

There have always been flaws and loopholes in the salary cap, a system maybe deliberately set up to sit in the grey area between window-dressing and a genuine attempt to protect clubs from the hubris of their own ambitions.

In the reaction of some others in the game is visible both another form of self-interest - if they suffer, we do better - and a certain unedifying schadenfreude. Success has bred jealousy elsewhere as well as a culture at the top of Saracens that sought to meet each fresh allegation with a new denial.

But without the money some of those players would not be there. Without the chicanery some of the funds to support the more admirable initiatives would be diverted elsewhere.

There will be sympathy for the supporters and sympathy for the players. Those players' futures are now a mess of confusion, of one-season loan deals or a strange sabbatical in the second tier against teams like Ealing, Ampthill and Jersey, and of what all that might mean for their places with England or the British and Irish Lions tour at the end of next season.

It is harder still on the staff who had nothing to do with the subterfuge and took no benefit from the inflated salaries enjoyed by the star players. Pruning at the top mean serious cutbacks lower down.

It is a collapse where almost everyone has lost something profound in the detritus.

Saracens have accepted relegation rather than returning their Premiership trophies for 2018 and 2019 or letting independent auditors at their books. Neither is a pretty look for a club who claimed to represent the best values that rugby has to offer.

The Premiership is weaker as a competition this season, with the impetus of relegation removed from the other clubs, and weaker next term without one of its traditional giants.

The Heineken Champions Cup will be without its dominant side. Sarries supporters who cherished the memories of great victories and away days will now wonder if they hold the same magic they once did.

But what's the alternative? Premiership Rugby has to enforce its own rules. No club can be too big or successful to fall. Someone has to try to keep a grip on the financial side of the elite game.

Every scenario is bad, but the alternative - doing nothing, looking away, accepting a half-hearted apology - is far worse.

And this is where professional rugby union continues to teeter: on a permanent knife-edge, desperate to grow audiences and revenues but with no proven strategy to do so, determined to ape the success of Premier League football but with nowhere near the same clout or means.

Everywhere you look in the game you see financial conundrums and hazardous, long-range punts at trying to solve them.

Private equity group CVC is about to acquire a 27% stake in the company that owns the Pro14, having taken a 27% stake in Premiership Rugby a year ago. It closing in on another deal to buy a £300m stake in the Six Nations.

Private equity firms are not benign entities whose interest is in protecting the traditional structures of the assets they take over. It is about profit, everywhere, at all times.

As one deputy team principal said as CVC's 11-year period owning Formula 1 came to an end: &quot;All their actions have been taken to extract as much money from the sport as possible and put as little in as possible.&quot;

At the same time, the value of title sponsorship of both the Six Nations and the Heineken Champions Cup has fallen dramatically in the past two years. World Rugby's big plans to revitalise the international game through their World League proposal also fell apart, when it could not reach its own agreement with CVC.

Meanwhile, Scottish Rugby is paying chief executive Mark Dodson £933,000 this year, despite finishing the last Six Nations with just one win and going out of the World Cup at the group stage.

Punts and speculation and mistakes. Some 25 years on from the slow death of the old amateur structures, it is as uncertain a future as ever.

Big teams do return from catastrophe. Rangers are challenging Celtic again at the top of the Scottish Premiership, eight years after being demoted to the fourth tier. Juventus were stripped of one league title and relegated to Serie B after the Calciopoli scandal of 2006, but were back in the top flight a year later.

Saracens will be back even if, like Juve, many of their superstars will end up elsewhere. So too will the wider financial conditions which persuaded them to chance their arm in the first place.

The sums in professional rugby union too often do not add up. And no-one can agree on how they should.
• Saracens to be relegated from Premiership
• Q&amp;A: What is going on and what does relegation mean?
• Stars can still play for England despite relegation</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51168926</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Professional Golf League faces challenges but could shake up status quo - Iain Carter - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Golf</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/D6AC/production/_110665945_tourflagscollage_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Rarely have golf's leading professional tours been more tightly aligned, and their united front has good cause given the threat of a rebel world circuit trying to sign up the biggest names in the game.

The so-called Professional Golf League has ambitious plans to reshape the sport. It wants a big-money, television-friendly, grand prix-style 18-event world tour, featuring 48 top players with individual and team dynamics involved in the competition.

It is proposing a series of 54-hole tournaments, with shotgun starts - when groups of players tee off simultaneously on different holes - for the first two rounds to limit the television window to under five hours. There would be no cut at each of these $10m events.

It is difficult to envisage it succeeding against the might of the PGA and European Tours, who would see their current business models ripped apart were the proposals to come to fruition.

Yet those behind PGL are bullish and published releases over the weekend suggesting their aim is to be up and running as early as January 2022.

They say they want to work with the establishment, not against it. Cooperation of this sort is likely to be in short supply.
• Leishman wins by one from Rahm at Torrey Pines

The American-based PGA Tour is the world's most lucrative circuit and routinely makes multi-millionaires of the world's best golfers. It would be a huge surprise were it to grant releases for members to play a rival circuit.

The tour also operates a very successful pension and players would be reluctant to risk the security afforded by the scheme.

And how could the PGL function without the blessing of the official world rankings? These are run by an amalgamation of all the established tours and governing bodies.

Even so, bosses are taking the threat seriously. There was a striking similarity in dismissive messages coming from both the PGA and European Tours when details of the proposed PGL emerged.

&quot;We don't comment on the business of other tours, real or hypothetical,&quot; said the Florida-based PGA Tour.

When I spoke to European Tour chief executive Keith Pelley, he said: &quot;We are not really in the business of commenting on other tours whether they are real or whether they are fictional.&quot;

Asked about the potential impact on his circuit, Pelley added: &quot;You are speaking with hypothetical thoughts and I don't speak from a hypothetical perspective, I speak from reality. And our business has a tremendous amount of momentum right now.

&quot;We are excited about our recent partnership with the LET [Ladies European Tour] and our relationship is getting closer and closer with the PGA Tour so that is what our focus is right now.&quot;

Pelley was speaking at last Friday's launch of the LET's record £15m schedule for 2020.

Mike Whan, head of the LPGA, was also at the launch. He called it &quot;the age of collaboration&quot;.

The rival golfing bodies, undoubtedly, see the upside of closer ties and, as Pelley intimated, the relationship between his Wentworth-based operation and the PGA Tour is becoming ever more closely aligned.

But despite the success of the current set-up - with spiralling purses, massive sponsorship and TV deals in the United States - there is a degree of fascination among leading players about the PGL, which has been working on its model for the past six years.

&quot;I'm curious but I don't know enough about it,&quot; said five-time major winner Phil Mickelson. &quot;I'm listening to it. I think it is intriguing but I don't know enough about it to comment publicly, but I hope to learn more.&quot;

Rory McIlroy confirmed he was first approached in 2014.

&quot;I certainly wouldn't want to lose what's been built in the last 40 to 50 years,&quot; the Northern Irishman said.

But he did say the challenge of these outsiders could prompt a remodelling of the current structure.

&quot;It might be a catalyst for some changes on this tour,&quot; said the four-time major winner. &quot;That can help it grow and move forward and reward the top players the way they should be, I guess.&quot;

Those behind the PGL project have maintained a degree of mystery. There are rumours of Saudi Arabian money being involved and it is known that the boutique investment bank, the Raine Group, is a key stakeholder.

One of the Raine Group's partners is golf fanatic Colin Neville, who has brokered major sporting deals including a $400m Chinese investment in Manchester City and who, according to a 2016 interview in the Sports Business Journal, would most like to swap jobs for a day with McIlroy.

PGL's backers believe the current golf set-up is outdated.

&quot;If you want the world to watch, you have to showcase your best product, week-in week-out. Golf doesn't do that currently,&quot; it said in a press release.

&quot;If you had the chance to start again you wouldn't create professional golf as it exists today. The league is that chance.

&quot;We believe we'll succeed because the league is what fans, sponsors and broadcasters want - and the best players deserve. It will revitalise the sport for this and future generations.&quot;

The established tours are compromised by being member organisations. They have to act in the best interests of their players and sometimes that is contrary to creating an ideal spectacle.

For example, the European Tour's elite Rolex Series would be far more impactful if it were a set of limited-field tournaments, with the best-of-the-best chasing the big money.

But try selling that to the bulk of your membership; you could not get it through. The rank-and-file players want their chance of winning the largest cheques.

Things may have to change, though. There is now talk that the Australian Open could be part of the rebel circuit, with a women's version as well.

Make no mistake, PGL faces massive challenges to muscle in at the top of professional golf but the fact it is agitating could be enough to shake the status quo.

Expect the establishment to come together to fight off the outsiders. Indeed, there is evidence aplenty that this is already happening.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/51267311</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Davos 2020: Can Formula 1 really go 'carbon neutral' by 2030? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12220/production/_110627247_8fbd9c4a-877e-4550-b085-fa8dbf542679.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It is no secret that Formula 1 racing is a polluting sport, or that its previous owner Bernie Ecclestone wasn't particularly interested in sustainability.

But things have changed since the elite motor-racing series was taken over by US media giant Liberty Media in 2017. Last year F1 announced its first ever sustainability plan, with an ambitious goal to make itself &quot;carbon neutral&quot; by 2030.

When I meet Yath Gangakumaran - the man responsible for leading the plan - at the World Economic Forum in Davos, he is keen to distance himself from sport's old guard, although he won't comment on Mr Ecclestone's tenure.

&quot;Up until 10-15 years ago sport wasn't run in a mature way - typically by ex-players not business professionals. It's become much more professional and is catching up with other industries, and that includes on sustainability.&quot;
• Lewis Hamilton on his mission to be 'carbon neutral'

Formula 1's carbon footprint is &quot;material&quot;, he says, but it has little to do with the cars, which are among the most fuel efficient on the planet thanks to their lightweight design and innovative hybrid engines.

The main problem are the races themselves - 22 in total this year - which require large amounts of equipment, cars and people to be shipped around the world, often by aircraft. In 2019, the sport's 10 teams each notched up an average of 110,000 air miles.

Then there is the huge amount of C02 emissions generated by F1's 500 million fans globally who will travel far and wide to see the sport.

It makes the 2030 target seem wildly ambitious, but as F1's director of strategy Mr Gangakumaran is bullish: &quot;There is no point just throwing out a target and having it as a marketing gimmick. Ultimately you will be held accountable, and so you should.&quot;

The former Sky Sports executive, who is only 31, seems sincere, but there are parts of Formula 1's plan that raise questions.

First to note is that the plan will only target emissions generated by the activities of the F1 business - which manages the series - and the individual teams who compete.

That amounts to some 256,000 CO2 equivalent tonnes per year, according to Liberty Media, which calculated F1's carbon footprint for the first time ever last year.

But the plan won't cover emissions generated by fans - the much bigger part of the problem. When they are accounted for, F1's footprint rises to some 1.9 million CO2 equivalent tonnes.

&quot;We think it is just too difficult to control what our fans do because they are ultimately their own custodians. So we think it is most appropriate and achievable to focus on what we do have control over,&quot; says Mr Gangakumaran.

That said, Liberty will encourage fans to use public transport to get to Formula 1 events, or to offset their air travel if they fly. It has also pledged to make races sustainable by 2025, including banning single-use plastics.

The sport will also continue to fly its operation around the world, and while Mr Gangakumaran says its absolute carbon footprint will decrease, it will have to rely on some carbon offsetting.

This may anger the fiercest environmental campaigners, who view offsetting - for instance, by planting trees to compensate for your emissions - as a cop out.

But Mr Gangakumaran says the business will keep it to a minimum and has to be realistic. &quot;We are a global sport and we have fans around the world who want to see F1. That requires travel.&quot;

The business also plans to spend more on transferring its own sustainable technologies to the wider world - something it has a strong record of.

In its 70-year history, Formula 1 has pioneered ground-breaking aerodynamics and efficient brake systems that have found their way into everyday road cars.

Other industries have benefited too. Take the way an F1-inspired aerofoil attached to chiller cabinets has cut refrigeration costs by about 15% in some supermarkets.

The strip, the result of a collaboration between Williams Advanced Engineering and Aerofoil Energy, was rolled out by Sainsbury's across its 1,400 supermarkets and convenience stores in 2017.

Professor Mark Jenkins, an F1 expert at Cranfield University, says Liberty Media's 2030 goal is highly ambitious and should be lauded. &quot;But whether it is achievable is another question.&quot;

He notes that Formula 1 has increased its number of races from 21 to 22 this year, while Mr Gangakumaran concedes there are plans for several more.

Prof Jenkins says: &quot;One of the obvious ways to reduce the carbon footprint would be reduce the number of races. But F1 also needs to increase its sales so there is a tension there.&quot;

In addition, the sport will introduce a cost cap in 2022 as it looks to even out competition between teams. The three that dominate - Mercedes, Red Bull and Ferrari - will be hit the hardest.

&quot;It will limit what they can spend at a time when they are also being asked to become more sustainable. Is that really wise?&quot; says Prof Jenkins.

Liberty Media's contracts with its F1 teams are up for renewal at the end of this year.

But Mr Gangakumaran says the firm is in advanced discussions and he is quietly confident the teams will re-sign.

He adds that Liberty has factored in the growing number of races into its carbon reduction plan, and that there will only one or two more. Becoming more sustainable could actually save F1 money, he adds.

All eyes will be on F1 as it works towards its goal. It also faces stiff competition in the sustainability stakes from events such as the World Cup, which could become carbon neutral by 2022.

&quot;You can't say anything is 100% but we wouldn't be putting these targets out there if they weren't ambitious enough or we didn't think we could achieve them,&quot; Mr Gangakumaran says. &quot;Most importantly our fans are totally behind us on this.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51226066</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Twitter and Facebook accounts for 15 NFL teams hacked - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/111E5/production/_110671107_gettyimages-1201136323.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>More than a dozen teams in the US National Football League have had their social media accounts hacked.

The teams included the San Francisco 49ers and Kansas City Chiefs, who will compete in the Super Bowl Championship on 2 February.

The hacking group OurMine took responsibility for the attack, which said it was to show internet security was &quot;still low&quot; and had to be improved.

The NFL did not respond to a request for comment about the attack.

The Twitter, Facebook and Instagram accounts for 15 teams were compromised.

Twitter confirmed the accounts were hacked by a third-party platform.

&quot;As soon as we were made aware of the issue, we locked the compromised accounts and are working closely with our partners at the NFL to restore them.&quot;

Many accounts had the same message posted: &quot;Hi, we're back. We are here to show people that everything is hackable.&quot;

Some of the accounts had their profile pictures or headers changed or deleted.

The OurMine Twitter account was taken down on Monday.

OurMine told the BBC it reached out to the NFL ahead of the attack to offer its services in improving the league's security but received no response.

OurMine says it is currently based in Dubai.

In the past, the group has hacked companies and well-known individuals to offer its private cyber security services.

It has hacked the Twitter accounts of Netflix, Marvel, Google's chief executive Sundar Pichai, and Twitter's founder Jack Dorsey. It has also hacked Buzzfeed's website and multiple Facebook and YouTube accounts.

The first attack occurred early on Sunday morning with a tweet on the Chicago football team the Bears. A post on the team's Twitter account said it had been sold to a Saudi Arabian official. Later a tweet said the team was trading a prized player for just $1 (£0.76).

Throughout Monday the hacking group targeted the NFL's own Twitter account along with the accounts of the Kansas City Chiefs, Green Bay Packers, Dallas Cowboys, Denver Broncos, Indianapolis Colts, Houston Texans, New York Giants, Philadelphia Eagles, Tampa Bay Buccaneers, Los Angeles Chargers, San Francisco 49ers, Cleveland Browns, Arizona Cardinals and Chicago Bears.

The Instagram pages of the Minnesota Vikings and Dallas Cowboys were also compromised.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-51275786</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: LPGA Tour's Blue Bay event in China cancelled - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Golf</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/4652/production/_110720081_gettyimages-1059803248.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The LPGA Blue Bay golf event, due to take place in China, has been cancelled because of the coronavirus outbreak.

The women's competition was scheduled to begin on 5 March.

Organisers of the event, due to be staged on Hainan Island, said the health and safety of players, fans and staff was their &quot;highest priority&quot;.

The start of China's domestic football season and the World Indoor Athletics Championships in Nanjing had already been postponed.

&quot;Any time you cancel an event, it is a difficult decision and we appreciate how hard our partners, the China LPGA and the China Golf Association have worked to host an incredible event,&quot; a statement from the LPGA on Friday said.

&quot;While we are disappointed that the tournament won't take place this season, we look forward to going back to Blue Bay in 2021 and for many years to come.&quot;

The chief medical officer for England confirmed on Friday that two people in the UK have tested positive for coronavirus.

At least 213 people in China have died from the virus, mostly in Hubei, with almost 10,000 cases nationally.

There have also been 98 cases of the virus in a further 18 countries around the world.

The World Health Organisation declared the outbreak a global emergency on Thursday.

Other sporting events in China have also been affected by the crisis.

The men's alpine skiing World Cup races in China, scheduled for 15 and 16 February in Yanqing, have been cancelled.

Formula 1's governing body has also admitted the Chinese Grand Prix in Shanghai from 17-19 April could be at risk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/golf/51323865</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Sonny Bill Williams: Toronto Wolfpack cross-code star allowed to cover gambling logos - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/14B19/production/_110616748_williams.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sonny Bill Williams will be allowed to cover up the logo of Super League sponsors Betfred on his Toronto Wolfpack jersey for religious reasons.

The cross-code star, who converted to Islam in 2009, previously covered up the logos of banking sponsors while at Super Rugby union side Auckland Blues.

Super League and the title sponsors came to a compromise over the issue.

&quot;I think the matter has been resolved in satisfactory fashion,&quot; said Super League chief executive Robert Elstone.

&quot;I have say a big 'thank you' to Betfred for the way they've managed this. We suspected it might be an issue but it only really surfaced five or six days ago and Betfred have taken it on, considered it and come up with the right answer and one that works for all parties.

&quot;I'm really pleased, they showed a progressive, pragmatic approach to this.&quot;

French clubs Catalans Dragons and Toulouse do not carry the sponsorship logos on their shirts at home games, as French laws prohibit the advertising of gambling, alcohol and tobacco products.

The 2020 Super League season kicks off on Thursday, 30 January when Wigan Warriors host 2019 Challenge Cup winners Warrington Wolves.

'You've got to be true to it'

Sponsorship is one area of sport which Williams has been public in how his faith is affected, with alcohol as well as banking and gambling among the industries he will not promote.

The 34-year-old is passionate about his beliefs and ensuring he can adhere to them within his rugby life.

&quot;Whatever walk of life or purpose you stand for, you've got to be true to it,&quot; he told BBC Sport at Friday's Super League season launch.

&quot;People's convictions change throughout their life, they get stronger in their beliefs and that's through knowledge and knowledge of oneself.

&quot;You learn from past experiences and mistakes, and I'm no different.&quot;

The spotlight will shine brightly on the former All Black when he finally takes to the field for the Wolfpack.

Having been away from rugby league since departing Sydney Roosters in 2014, Williams' re-conditioning for the 13-man code is an ongoing process.

&quot;I'm still getting into it, still working my way back to full fitness in the sense of being a rugby league player,&quot; he added.

&quot;I've been playing rugby (union) for the past four or five years so that will take a bit of a process, but with patience and hard work I'll get back to where I need to be.&quot;
• Sign up for live match notifications on the BBC Sport app</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-league/51221254</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>The robo racing cars accelerating driverless tech - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/142A6/production/_108389528_roborace-onthehillclimb.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Johannes Betz is not your typical racing car driver.

For a start, he doesn't get in the vehicle - it's driverless. As a post-doctoral researcher, he is in charge of the Technical University of Munich's entry in the Roborace motorsport competition, now in its first competitive season.

All these cars are electric and self-driving. &quot;We started in early 2017, when my professor saw this in a newspaper,&quot; he says.

&quot;Each month, we have to develop our software a little further, and then go to an event - yeah, like Formula 1,&quot; he laughs.

Each team - the University of Pisa and electric van start-up Arrival also compete - writes software for an identical racing car, currently the DevBot 2.0, which is capable of speeds over 200mph (322km/h).

It is guided by six cameras, two radars, 18 ultrasound sensors, and five lidar [light detection and ranging] sensors. The onboard computer processor is capable of 24 trillion operations a second.

It was the first racing car to establish a fully autonomous official record at the Goodwood Hill Climb, an important motorsport event in England's West Sussex, on 13 July.

And DevBot navigated it in 66.96 seconds - eight seconds faster than an unofficial attempt last year.

Now &quot;there's around twelve seconds left for the AI (artificial intelligence) to find&quot; before it can match the best human drivers, says Bryn Balcombe, Roborace's chief strategy officer.

Of that, &quot;six seconds we think is easily gained, and then you're starting to get into the unknowns.&quot;

But what is the point of racing driverless cars?
• The people policing the internet's most horrific content
• 'How I lost £25,000 when my cryptocurrency was stolen'
• Could Facebook’s new currency be stopped in its tracks?
• Making classic cars go faster with old Tesla motors
• If one drone isn't enough, try a drone swarm

It's an important way to assess the quality of the sensors and cameras which autonomous vehicles (AVs) will rely on, explains Mr Balcombe.

And &quot;testing performance limits on real roads is not something, as a member of society, I'm 100% comfortable with,&quot; he says.

He plans to introduce obstacles for the DevBots to navigate, such as slower-moving lorries and tractors. Overtaking is the hardest race course task to automate, says Dr Betz.

The ultimate aim is to find out whether driverless cars can eventually &quot;perform at a level so you can't detect it's an AI,&quot; Mr Balcombe says.

This is the Turing Test for AVs: to see if they can drive &quot;as naturally as a human but without the mistakes&quot;.

Your ability to be autonomous &quot;is based on your ability to see the world around you&quot;, explains Glen de Vos, chief technology officer at Aptiv, a car electronics company headquartered in Dublin.

So sensors are getting most of the attention these days.

Tesla's Elon Musk insists cameras can do the job alone. Mobileye, owned by the giant chipmaker Intel, is making a camera-only AV, too.

But most automotive experts think you need lots of other kit, too - lidar, radar, ultrasound, inter-car wireless communication and so on - in case cameras alone aren't up to the job.

Lidar is &quot;really good at short distance, but gets really interfered with by weather&quot;, says Wael Elrifai, vice president of Hitachi Vantara, a subsidiary of the Japanese electronics multinational.

Cameras are &quot;really good at managing shapes and colours to identify objects, and can even work at long distance&quot;, but rain and fog frustrate them, too.

And radar is &quot;low resolution but works at long distances in bad weather, and is also good at determining the relative speed of something coming towards you&quot;, he says.

To be completely reliable, cameras would have to &quot;match the ability of the human eye&quot;, argues Charles Boulanger, chief executive of Quebec lidar company LeddarTech. And cars would need &quot;human brain&quot; processing power to analyse all the images in real time.

But six lidars could add €15,000-20,000 (£13,700-18,300) to the price of a car today, says Mr De Vos, so it's more likely this tech specification level will be reserved for driverless ride sharing, shuttle buses, automated deliveries and robo-taxis.

Once you remove the cost of the driver and can use the vehicle 24-hours-a-day, the sensors start looking affordable. And once commercial AVs become more common - within the next five years some technologists predict - sensor manufacturing costs will fall.

&quot;Optimising design, materials and manufacturing, this hasn't really begun in earnest,&quot; says Mr De Vos.

A big move forward, in cost and performance, will come from lidars on a chip, or solid-state lidars, says Raffi Mardirosian, vice president of San Francisco-based lidar-maker Ouster. When technology systems can be built on a single silicon chip, it opens the door to making them much more cheaply.

You might have seen bulky lidars on top of prototype driverless cars, spinning round scanning the environment. Solid-state lidars won't have moving parts, so one solution is flashing an entire area with laser light, says Mr Boulanger.

Other sensor technologies besides lidars are also emerging.

Like far infrared heat sensing, useful for spotting pedestrians, says Kirsty Lloyd-Jukes, chief executive of Latent Logic, an Oxford autonomous systems spin-off.

But there is a long way to go to make all these sensors reliable and cheap enough to please regulators and manufacturers, particularly when a simple sticker or bit of spray paint can fool AI into confusing a stop sign for a speed limit sign.

There is also the issue of how to maintain and repair all this complex sensor technology.

&quot;We're used to yearly MOTs,&quot; says Ms Lloyd-Jukes, &quot;but the existing ecosystem isn't going to be enough.&quot;

Insurers, repairers, and regulators will need to adapt to this new autonomous world.

At the moment, humans collectively drive for at least eight million hours on average before misidentifying something that leads to an accident. Currently, AVs can only manage 10,000-30,000 hours.

&quot;When you have a number like that, it's sending big flashing signals there's a lot of work to be done,&quot; warns Hitachi Vantara's Wael Elrifai.

But robo racing cars are at least accelerating development of this autonomous future.
• Follow Technology of Business editor Matthew Wall on Twitter and Facebook</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49420570</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Aston Martin: F1 billionaire owner leads rescue deal - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12694/production/_110421457_ai87rasy.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A consortium led by billionaire Lawrence Stroll will put in £182m, with the rest of the money coming from existing investors.

Mr Stroll partly owns the Racing Point Formula 1 team, which will be branded Aston Martin from 2021 under the deal.

The move comes hours after a board meeting held to discuss how to prop up the ailing firm.

Aston Martin's best known customer is fictional spy James Bond and the company recently revealed that four of its cars will feature in the next Bond movie, No Time To Die.

The carmaker said its latest financial moves were aimed at strengthening its balance sheet after its &quot;disappointing performance&quot; in 2019.

Mr Stroll's consortium will take a 20% stake in the company and he will become its executive chairman.

As a result, Penny Hughes will be stepping down as Aston Martin's chairman once the deal is completed.

It's all very well to build James Bond's company cars, but Aston Martin can't rely on a flashy brand alone.

Many of its troubles can be traced to the decision to build a new factory at St Athan in South Wales, where it will produce its long-anticipated sports utility vehicle, the DBX.

An ambitious move, it could have big long-term benefits for the carmaker.

But in the short term, it has been struggling to generate enough cash to pay its bills, including the costs of setting up the factory.

Dealers have been reducing stock rather than ordering new cars, while average selling prices have been falling, weighing on profits.

Last year, the company was forced to borrow £120m at a steep interest rate in order to prop up its operations. It had been facing the prospect of borrowing even more.

The new funding from Lawrence Stroll will give Aston Martin some much-needed stability. It now has breathing space in which to get the DBX into production, and implement a cost-cutting programme.

Meanwhile the Canadian billionaire will be able to put an Aston Martin badge on his F1 cars - opening up new opportunities both to burnish the brand and to exploit its petrol-scented cachet.

She said: &quot;The difficult trading performance in 2019 resulted in severe pressure on liquidity which has left the company with no alternative but to seek substantial additional equity financing.

&quot;Without this, the balance sheet is not robust enough to support the operations of the group.

&quot;Notwithstanding recent weak trading, the strength of the Aston Martin brand and our expanding portfolio of cars has allowed us to attract a strong new partner in Mr Stroll to support the turnaround of the business.&quot;

Earlier this month, the 106-year-old firm issued a profit warning, saying annual earnings were expected to fall by nearly half from a year earlier.

It said core retail sales - which covers sales from Aston Martin dealers to consumers - were up 12% from a year earlier. However, wholesale volumes - which covers how many cars the dealers are ordering from Aston Martin itself - were down 7% to 5,809.

The company said it was expecting earnings of between £130m and £140m, well below the £247.3m it reported last year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51323241</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Saracens salary cap breaches: Ashton says co-investment 'completely separate to rugby' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/11177/production/_110670007_gettyimages-1189968958.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former Saracens wing Chris Ashton says he did not understand that the club was breaching the salary cap when owner Nigel Wray invested in a property with him.

The 32-year-old was named in a leaked report into relegated Sarries' misdemeanours on Thursday.

Ashton, a presenter on BBC Radio 5 Live's Rugby Union Weekly podcast, has spoken to a lawyer about the leak.

&quot;[The investment] was completely separate to the rugby for me,&quot; he said.

&quot;Nigel was never involved in any negotiations of contracts or anything like that so I saw Nigel as a businessman outside of rugby that I went to see to get a loan, like I would from the bank.

&quot;It was completely separate to my contract. Nigel likes property, he invests in property. He came along to the house to see it with me, we had a look round and he gave some thoughts on what we could do.

&quot;I can completely understand why people are annoyed about it because it is a benefit that you don't get at other clubs. Now I do understand. I do see it. At the time, I didn't.&quot;
• Saracens salary cap breaches: What we have learned from Premiership Rugby report?

Ashton joined Saracens in 2012 and stayed for five years, moving to French side Toulon in 2017 before signing for Premiership team Sale in 2018.

The wing says he has now paid Wray back, but that at one time the former Saracens chairman owned 20% of his house.

Although confidential information was redacted in the version of the Saracens report published by Premiership Rugby, the identities of some players were in the public domain after the full report was leaked.

&quot;My name got brought up with the Saracens leaks, which I'm not too happy about at all,&quot; Ashton added on Rugby Union Weekly.

&quot;Whoever I spoke to about it told me it was going to be completely confidential so I was pretty upset that that was broken. It's pretty frustrating.

&quot;I've spoken to a lawyer who works with us all through the Rugby Players' Association to see how we go about this.

&quot;We did have confidentiality agreements and that has been thrown out the window. We'll see if there is anything in it.&quot;

'I asked Nigel if he would help me buy a family home'

Ashton says he was two years into a four-year contract at Saracens when he entered into the co-investment with Wray.

His wife Melissa was pregnant and they &quot;wanted to find a place to stay in forever and make a family home&quot;.

&quot;I knew Nigel had done it previously with some players and staff - he invests in a lot of property in and around London,&quot; explained Ashton.

&quot;I went along to ask him. We'd found a house we liked that needed some work doing to it. I went along to ask Nigel if he would help me buy it and help do the house up.

&quot;So we'd invest in it together. We'd both put the same deposit in. I got the mortgage and we lived in it, did the house up and I still have it.

&quot;We had a solicitors drawn-up contract to say that Nigel owned his percentage of the house and when the house was sold he would receive all his money back. I've paid that back.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51272146</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>2022 Commonwealth Games: Alexander Stadium revamp approved - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Birmingham &amp; Black Country</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/130C6/production/_110722087_alex_1_crop.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Plans to almost quadruple the size of Birmingham's Alexander Stadium for the 2022 Commonwealth Games have been approved.

Permanent capacity will increase to 18,000, with temporary seating taking it up to a limit of 40,000 spectators.

New 400m relay and warm up tracks will be built, along with extra parking and bus provision.

The cost of the 11-day sporting event is £778m, with £184m paid by Birmingham City Council and partners.

There will also be a new throwing area, access road and office and teaching accommodation under the plans approved by the city council.

Birmingham was named as the host city for the games in December 2017, and it will be the UK's costliest sporting event since London 2012.

The stadium in Perry Barr, which currently has a 12,700 capacity, will host the opening and closing ceremonies as well as athletics events, which are expected to take place between 27 July and 7 August 2022.

The Labour-run council has said it wants to &quot;create a legacy asset the city and its residents can be truly proud of&quot;.

The authority does not yet know how much of its share of the overall cost of the games would be paid by partners including West Midlands Combined Authority, local enterprise partnerships, other local authorities under the banner of the Midlands Engine, the NEC and others.

In June, the council's Tory opposition leader said he was concerned about how a £50m loan by the authority would affect residents in years to come.

The council said day-to-day services would not be affected.

Follow BBC West Midlands on Facebook, on Twitter, and sign up for local news updates direct to your phone.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-birmingham-51312190</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-06 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>Saracens salary cap breaches: What we have learned from Premiership Rugby report? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/150E2/production/_110624268_gettyimages-1189526085.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Premiership Rugby has released the report into Saracens' breaches of the league's salary cap that led to their 35-point deduction and £5.36m fine, and paved the way for their subsequent relegation.

Saracens said they were &quot;keen&quot; for the report to be published, with chairman Neil Golding saying it would &quot;provide much-needed context and clarity&quot;.

Premiership Rugby (PRL) chief executive Darren Childs said: &quot;We are pleased to be able to finally publish the full judgement.

&quot;Now that everyone can see the details, the decision will show that Premiership Rugby has taken firm action to enforce the regulations and our management of the salary cap has been endorsed by the panel.&quot;

So what have we learned from the 103-page document, which covered the last three seasons? Here is a summary of what has emerged.
• 'We should have been far better' - Wray sorry for Saracens approach to salary cap

Although confidential information is redacted in the version published by PRL, the identities of those involved in the deals are in the public domain because of the full report having been leaked.

There are several new pieces of information revealed in the judgement:
• Saracens' overspend was more than £1.1m in 2016-17; £98,000 in 2017-18; and £906,000 in 2018-19.
• PRL initially wanted each breach to be treated separately but the panel decided this would have led to a 'disproportionate' sanction of 70 points. It decided 35 points was the right decision, which PRL accepted.
• Former chairman Nigel Wray made almost £924,000 of contributions to property co-investments with players
• Part of the breaches surrounded image-rights deals and hospitality payments relating to a player
• A previously unknown property-sharing arrangement between the club's former owner and Wray and another player is revealed

More on those £924,000 contributions

The total contribution to property co-investments with players was £923,947.63. The names of the players are redacted, but the figures are £451,188.92, £219,932.36 and £252,826.35.

In this section of the report, the starkly contrasting positions of PRL salary cap manager Andrew Rogers and Wray are detailed.

Rogers says there was a &quot;misconceived&quot; and &quot;concerted and deliberate attempt&quot; to take those contributions outside of the salary structure.

Wray contested this view, saying he entered into &quot;bona fide commercial transactions&quot; - not for &quot;an additional reward&quot; for players.

He said: &quot;While it is important to me to help the club's players prepare for a life outside rugby and it is certainly the case that where I know and trust an individual, I am more favourably disposed to an idea they pitch to me and to entering into a business relationship with them, my motivations when making investment decisions are ultimately always commercial.&quot;

Having regarded both positions, the panel ruled that &quot;we are satisfied that these capital contributions were salary&quot;, relying on its finding that the loan from Wray was not repayable in the salary cap year.

In the report, it emerges part of the overspend in the 2018-19 salary cap year related to the image rights valuation of a player.

It says Rogers identified £800,000 of salary &quot;on the basis of an alleged overpayment by Mr Wray, Mr Silvester [Saracens director Dominic Silvester] and Mr Leslau [Nicholas Leslau, a director of Saracens until September 2019]&quot; - for &quot;30% of the shares in [redacted]&quot;.

Rogers disputed the purchase price, but Wray and Leslau both defended the valuation they had used.

The panel decided &quot;Mr Rogers was reasonably entitled to conclude that the purchase price for the [redacted] shares was above the true market value to the extent of £800,000&quot;.

The report also looks at the activity of a hospitality business called MBN Promotions - which has since become Premier Team Promotions Ltd and is owned by Wray's daughter Lucy and her husband Tony. Lucy Mercey - formerly Lucy Wray - was, until Thursday, a director of Saracens.

MBN paid a player £30,000 in 2016-17, £30,000 in 2017-18 and £35,000 in 2018-19, but details of these payments or the relevant agreement between MBN and the player were not disclosed.

The report also states &quot;no evidence was provided by Saracens to show any events that [player] had in fact attended&quot;.

Saracens accepted this was an &quot;oversight&quot; and apologised for the non-disclosure. However, the club's position was these payments were &quot;arm's length commercial transactions&quot; and should not be deemed salary.

The panel rejected Saracens' challenge that the three payments should not be included in the salary cap.

Co-owned £1.35m property to be lived in by player

This section of the report concerns a sum of £319,600.76 relating to a 20% stake in a £1.35m property lived in by a player.

It states Wray and fellow Saracens director Silvester each provided 10% of the purchase price, equating to £135,000. They also contributed £234,223 for refurbishment work on the property.

In May 2019, Saracens disclosed to PRL a &quot;Declaration of Trust in respect of the property&quot;.

Rogers made the case that there had been &quot;a payment of salary of £319,600&quot; in the 2017-18 salary cap year, because it was a benefit in kind. In outlining this position, he said the sum deferred was a loan, that it was &quot;doubtful&quot; the player would have been able to secure such a loan elsewhere, and he had immediate use of the property.

Saracens disputed this, saying that this was an &quot;entirely arm's length commercial bargain&quot;.

A considerable portion of the Saracens judgement concerns the club's challenge &quot;that the salary cap provided for by the regulations is illegal on the grounds that it is contrary to competition law&quot;.

How did the panel reach the penalty decision?

In reaching its decision on what the penalty for the breaches should be, the panel heard evidence from salary cap manager Rogers and Saracens.

Rogers said he disagreed with the suggestion Saracens had been &quot;open and transparent&quot; and said the club had been &quot;reckless in its approach to the salary cap&quot;.

In this section, the panel notes Saracens' breaches were &quot;not deliberate, but in our view they were reckless&quot;, that Saracens had not admitted any of the breaches, that they were charged with a failure to co-operate in 2015 (leading to a settlement and sanctions) and that they had not fully cooperated with Rogers.

It uses the analogy that Saracens were issued with a &quot;yellow card&quot; in 2015, and therefore &quot;the repeated failure to disclose breaches, which it has admitted, make the position all the more stark&quot;.

Saracens argued that to deduct points for &quot;technical&quot; breaches was &quot;unfair punishment and is contrary to the spirit and underlying purpose of the regulations&quot;.

The panel disagreed with this view.

Despite viewing the breaches as &quot;very serious&quot;, the panel ultimately decided that imposing a 70-point deduction would be &quot;disproportionate&quot; and that a 35-point deduction would be &quot;sufficient to mark the seriousness of the breaches&quot; over the three seasons covered by the report.

Saracens were subsequently handed automatic relegation for next season as they would not have not been in compliance with the salary cap this season as well. There was no panel decision for this, as it was a Premiership Rugby decision which Saracens agreed to.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51222415</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
