<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Tiny PCs goes into administration</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lancashire-based Granville Technology Group has been making monthly losses of up to £2m since the start of the year.

All directors of the company, except its non-executive chairman, left ahead of Wednesday's announcement.

Many customers are believed to have paid for goods in recent days but have yet to receive them.

A helpline has been set up to provide information to customers and creditors: 0870 830 3288. E-mail address is: enquiries-time@gtuk.com.

Customers and creditors now face an uncertain future as computers were sold with warranties and deals with schools and colleges included service contracts.

Administrators Grant Thornton have said they will maintain a customer support operation and plan to make a further announcement soon.

About two million Tiny and Time PCs are used in homes and schools around the UK.

Granville's financial situation worsened in recent days, leading to the closure of all its Computer Shop stores across the UK on Tuesday - shoppers had been told the closures were for stocktaking.

Grant Thornton said the scale of the company's losses meant that it could not continue trading making redundancies &quot;inevitable&quot;.

&quot;The group has fallen victim to the continued price deflation in the personal computer market,&quot; said joint administrators Andrew Hosking, Martin Ellis and Les Ross.

Granville employs about 1,600 staff, with most employed at its headquarters in Simonstone, near Burnley. Only about 100 will keep their jobs for the time being.

Staff were told about its financial position on Wednesday, but many complained that they had been left completely in the dark about its problems.

Unions said the job cuts were &quot;devastating&quot;.

The GMB union said it had sought urgent talks with the firm in the past few days but had not been able to gain any information.

It is to ask the Department of Trade and Industry to investigate the company's collapse and the role played by its directors.

Two directors quit the company last month leaving just two executives - headed by non-executive chairman Bill Davies - to run the business.

&quot;The GMB is angry that the management have let the company run down to this point without saying anything,&quot; said Graham Coxon, GMB organiser in Lancashire.

&quot;We will be seeking immediate talks with the administrators to see if there are any viable options to save jobs and to get proper compensation for those who have lost jobs.&quot;

Nigel Evans, MP for Ribble Valley in which the company's offices are situated, called for a &quot;full investigation&quot; into the firm's collapse.

&quot;I would like to know who knew how bad it was for the company and why action wasn't taken at any earlier date,&quot; he told the BBC.

The company's profitability has been affected by falling PC prices and intense global competition.

According to Grant Thornton, Granville has not filed any accounts since June 2003 when it recorded a £2.5m profit and sales of £207m.

However, it said the company had been making monthly losses of between £1m and £2m since January.

The company is owned by British businessman Tahir Moshan, who resigned as managing director last year.

I work as an independent computer repairer, and fixing Time and Tiny branded computers makes up a large part of my business. Most of them come to me with a support horror story; many of them are still under warranty, but their owners are just sick of being passed from pillar to post by Tiny's 'support'.

Mark Saunders, Bath

It's tragic that we find out from the media about this! Staff were speculating about what was going on but the company management did not have the decency to inform them about what was going on!

Salma, Blackburn

Having worked for Time computers, the news came as no surprise. The company was on Watchdog a few times so I thought they would have gone into administration long before now.

Hema, Bromley, Kent

I managed a Tiny showroom in Seattle, until July 2001, when Tiny abruptly closed all its stores in the US. I was one of the lucky few who, as a manager, received his final pay, plus severance. However, none of the hourly commissioned employees received their final month's pay. I hope the UK employees will be more fortunate.

Ivan Smith, Seattle, WA

I ordered a laptop from Tiny three days ago, and am now bracing myself for getting neither computer nor my money back. It's an unfortunate situation, but nothing compared to the hardship of the employees made redundant, already owed a month's salary. They should never have been put in this position.

Nicholas Horne, London

Just been informed that we are not getting paid on Friday at all. We've got to go through the DTI.

Jason Nicholson, Hull

I placed an order for a Home Cinema system on Monday (25th July), I just found out that Tiny has gone bust today, the very same time the money was taken out of my bank. If the union have known about the situation for some days, why didn't they inform the purchasers before an order was placed?

Les Bell, Stavanger, Norway

I work for the Computer Shop which is the retail outlet for the company. We have been left totally in the dark as to what is going on. All the directors have left. We don't know if we are going to get paid or not. We have families to feed and mortgages to pay. If we do not get paid on Friday I don't know what I am going to do.

Anonymous, Wales

My husband has worked 6 years for Time Computers, and the last 2 months hasn't been paid on time. I called my husband at work this morning to update him on the situation of what the media was saying and I find it absolutely disgusting that the media knew what was going on before the staff did.

Jayne, Blackburn

I have been affected by the job losses at Time, I have worked for the company for 5 years and 3 months in total and I was informed of my job loss by text message. I have no idea if I will be able to pay my mortgage on Monday as pay has not been confirmed. My chances of keeping my house are completely shattered.

Manager, Middlesbrough

I worked there for a couple of years and to be honest I thought this would have happened sooner. I feel sorry for all the people who will lose their money as a result of the ineptitude of the management of Time.

Ex Employee, York

I am one of the employees actually in the building. We have not been informed of any such statements about the severity of the situation. Yesterday we were informed of the stores closing for 1-2 days, but was told it was due to a credit card transaction problem and the stores were to put a notice on the windows telling the public that we where having a stock check and it would be business as usual.

Anon, Simonstone

Time and Tiny were brands associated with some of cheapest budget computers on the market. Their products regularly got slated in reviews for having many corners cut on their specifications and build quality. This news should really be seen as sign that consumer can no longer be fobbed off with substandard goods and will use the power of they're wallets to prove it.

Arthur, London

I was made redundant at the end of March 2004. The problems that Time/Tiny finds itself in now are of no surprise to me as it has been struggling since Christmas 2003/2004 when its sales were not at the expected level.

Justin, Accrington

Speaking as a manager of one of the retail stores, I have not heard any official comment so far and heard about the situation first on a website. We have been kept in the dark the whole way through, I was told to put a sign on the door saying &quot;closed for stock take&quot; and I do not even know if I will get paid on Friday - never mind redundancy.

Anon

I purchased a Tiny laptop on the 17th July - the salesperson gave no indication that they were in financial difficulties, maybe he did not know. I have paid £600 for a machine I am unlikely to obtain.

Richard Thomas, Birmingham

After 7 years working with Time we are experiencing one of many problems that has hampered production and customer service in the past - a total lack of communication between management and staff. There has been no news of what is happening - the staff are in the dark and totally demotivated. So much so that any news has come from internet news sites such as yourself. It's a disgrace.

Gary Shaw, Burnley

As a person affected by the demise of Tiny ( I am awaiting delivery of an order paid for on 23rd May 2005) I thought I would check the Tiny website today. Amazingly, at 1.35pm the web site is still accepting credit card orders with no indication of the companies financial troubles.

 Steve Wooldridge, UK

I didn't know about the closing of my store until yesterday morning. And many customers have bought PCs but won't get them. They've waited until three days before payday to lay us off, and we still don't know if we are getting paid for it. I hope whoever is responsible will get their comeuppance.

Stuart Keane, United Kingdom

I bought a computer in Nov 2004 from Tiny which gave lots of problems. I had taken Tiny to the Small Claims Court regarding the computer which ultimately completely broke down. They agreed to reimburse me and I sent the computer back last week. They sent a cheque for my court fees but now I have nothing for the costs of the computer.

Brian Hughes, Swansea

After working for Time Computers in 1999-2000 this news come as no surprise to me. The sad thing is that the customers will pay the price for the managements incompetence.

Richard, London

I was one of the first retail employees of the company and was with them for over 5 years. It all started going wrong 4 years ago, when we were seen as too expensive and were replaced by much cheaper staff who did not have the commercial skills to make money.

Dave Watson, Horton Heath, Hants</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4719833.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Pensionable age 'ought to be 67'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The higher age for payments should be introduced between 2020 and 2030, according to the Institute of Public Policy Research report.

The think tank said that government and employers must first win the public's trust before they can make the change.

Ministers say there are no plans to raise the pension age, while the Tories say incentives would be needed.

The report's author, Peter Robinson, said: &quot;Raising the state pension age is vital if the UK pensions system is to remain sustainable and cope with the pressure of an ageing population.&quot;

He said the public is reluctant to accept that life expectancy is rising, and the institute's focus groups showed people wanted to retire at or before 65.

The IPPR believes that, unless there is a clear political consensus on pensions, it will be difficult to bring about change.

&quot;One way to build a consensus on increasing the state pension age is to link it with an increase in the basic state pension,&quot; said Mr Robinson.

Minister for pension reform, Stephen Timms, said the government was &quot;committed to achieving consensus&quot; on pensions.

He said: &quot;The government has no plans to raise the state pension age but welcomes giving people increased choice as they plan for their retirement.&quot;

But the Trade Unions Congress warned that &quot;work-till-you-drop&quot; policies would hit poor people hardest.

Conservative pensions spokesman Nigel Waterson called for more flexibility to allow those who want to work for longer to do so.

&quot;If the government expects people to work longer, they need to provide incentives,&quot; he said.

The Pensions Commission is due to publish its final report in the autumn.

In October last year, the commission estimated that more than 12 million people in the UK were not saving enough towards their retirement.

The commission's interim report said that some mixture of higher taxes, more saving or a higher average retirement age was needed to solve the UK's pension crisis.

But the Chancellor, Gordon Brown, has said that there will have to be a cross-party consensus before any major changes to the UK pension system are made.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4712983.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Ex-ECB chief found dead in pool</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He drowned following cardiac problems at his home in the town of Faucon, a regional prosecutor says.

The former Dutch finance minister was the ECB's first president, and oversaw the introduction of the single European currency, the euro.

The 70-year-old had stepped down in 2003 after five years in the job.

Under Mr Duisenberg, the euro evolved from being only a market-traded currency into coins and notes in the pockets of 300 million people in 12 European countries.

Born in 1935, Mr Duisenberg worked for the International Monetary Fund before serving as his country's finance minister from 1973 and 1977.

A member of the Dutch Labour Party, his views on responsible economic management changed. Later in life, he preferred strong fiscal discipline rather than a strategy of promoting growth through major public spending.

Germany and France - the two biggest eurozone economies - wrangled over Mr Duisenberg's appointment in 1998, and over who should succeed him.

Mr Duisenberg became first ECB president with strong German backing - with Mr Trichet being named as his successor at the same time as part of a Franco-German deal to share power.

The shift to euro notes and coins took place on 1 January 2002, and was feted with firework displays and street parties in some European cities.

The ECB cut interest rates in the euro countries to their lowest level since the World War II under Mr Duisenberg.

But critics said the slowdown in the eurozone would not have been so severe if he had cut rates sooner and more aggressively.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4733081.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Byers wished to 'kill' Railtrack</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The evidence came from handwritten minutes of crucial Whitehall meetings the week before Railtrack went into administration in 2001.

Notes from the meetings also reported Mr Byers saying Railtrack should be given &quot;no options&quot; to avoid collapse.

One possible escape route for Railtrack was a plan to bring forward payments worth millions of pounds to the company, but in the meeting notes Mr Byers' response to that was &quot;got to kill it off&quot;.

Keith Rowley, acting for the Railtrack shareholders, told the High Court that the government took a secret and malicious decision to destroy the company.

The case revolves around whether the government plotted Railtrack's demise in 2001 by refusing it extra money.

About 50,000 Railtrack shareholders have launched a claim for £157m in compensation from the government.

They allege &quot;misfeasance&quot; - that the government and the then Transport Secretary Stephen Byers acted within the law but in bad faith - and a breach of human rights for confiscation of assets.

The government has always said the firm was not capable of running the railways and was insolvent without its support.

The critical question in the case is whether the company - since replaced by the state-backed Network Rail - simply ran out of money or whether the government plotted its downfall.

The case is being led by the Railtrack Private Shareholders Action Group (RPSAG), which has raised £2.4m to bring the matter to court.

If the High Court finds in favour of the shareholders, then there will be a second trial to quantify damages.

Railtrack was formed in April 1994 after the privatisation of the UK railway network by the then Conservative government of John Major.

It was floated on the London Stock Exchange in 1996.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4648923.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | G8 leaders agree $50bn aid boost</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The debt of the 18 poorest nations in Africa is also being cancelled. On trade, there was a commitment to work towards cutting subsidies and tariffs.

On climate change, Prime Minister Tony Blair said an agreement had always been unlikely, but that the US now accepted global warming was an issue.

But reaction was mixed, with some calling it &quot;vastly disappointing&quot;.

&quot;The people have roared but the G8 has whispered,&quot; said Kumi Naidoo, chair of the Global Call to Action against Poverty.

&quot;Never before have so many people forced a change of policy onto a global agenda. If anyone had said eight weeks ago will we get a doubling of aid, will we get a deal on debt, people would have said 'no',&quot; Mr Geldof said.

He added that he gave the G8 summit &quot;10 out of 10 on aid, eight out of 10 on debt&quot;.

Irish rock star and fellow anti-poverty campaigner Bono, praised the agreement to give universal access to Aids drugs.

&quot;600,000 Africans, mostly children, will remember this G8 summit at Gleneagles because they will be around to remember this summit, and they wouldn't have otherwise,&quot; said Bono.
• Mr Blair said trade discussions in Hong Kong later this year should yield an end date to agricultural subsidies.
• Britain is to host a 1 November meeting on climate change, to assess progress.
• Mr Blair said &quot;only people who can change Africa ultimately are the Africans&quot;.
• $3bn agreed for Palestinian Authority for investment in infrastructure.
• Nigeria's President Olusegun Obasanjo described the deal as a &quot;success&quot;.
• African leaders to commit to democracy and good governance as part of the deal.
• Debts of the 18 poorest countries to be forgiven.
• Universal access to anti-HIV drugs in Africa by 2010.

Summing up the G8 meeting, Mr Blair acknowledged: &quot;It isn't all everyone wanted, but it is progress.&quot;

UN Secretary General Kofi Annan said the G8 deal represented a &quot;good day&quot;, but that it was only &quot;a beginning&quot;.

&quot;The fight to end poverty is just starting,&quot; said Mr Annan.

On climate change, Mr Blair said: &quot;If it is impossible to bring America into the consensus on tackling the issue... we will never ensure the huge emerging economies, who are going to consume more energy than any other part of the world... are part of the dialogue.&quot;

He said however that agreement had been reached that climate change was a problem, human activity contributed to it and it had to be tackled with urgency.

Earlier the prime minister had said that in the wake of Thursday's attacks, the communique was the &quot;definitive expression of our collective will to act in the face of death&quot;.

&quot;It has a pride and a hope and a humanity that can lift the shadow of terrorism,&quot; he added.

Some described the talks on climate change as a &quot;significant lost opportunity&quot;.

G8 leaders have indicated the statement represents progress but Stephen Tindale, a spokesperson for Greenpeace, said: &quot;The G8 has committed to nothing new but at least we haven't moved backwards on the environment.&quot;

The Sustainable Energy and Economy Network, a worldwide coalition of environmental and development campaigners, said: &quot;Urgent action is now required to substantially reduce emissions, reduce fossil fuel dependence and to protect people around the world, especially the vulnerable, the poor and disappearing nations.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4662297.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Union votes on Rolls-Royce strike</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Some 400 workers at the plant which makes military jet engines took action after Amicus official Jerry Hicks was sacked over allegations of misconduct.

Amicus said ballots would be sent out on Monday and warned industrial action could spread to Rolls-Royce's five other sites across the UK.

A company spokesman said Rolls-Royce had not been informed of any ballot.

He added &quot;virtually everyone&quot; was working normally at the plant on Friday, and that there had been no talks between the union and management.

Earlier, the trade union said any action - if approved - was likely to take place in four weeks' time.

Mr Hicks, who was a convener at the Bristol plant that makes engines for military jets, was dismissed on Wednesday after a disciplinary panel hearing.

The panel heard he had been accused of gross misconduct after organising an unofficial strike in support of two members of staff who faced the sack.

Amicus said in a statement that there was &quot;a meeting of union convenors from all the UK Rolls-Royce sites...at which they all pledged their support&quot; for Mr Hicks.

Rolls-Royce said it had been &quot;regrettable&quot; that staff had decided to down tools on Thursday.

&quot;This is not about the trade unions, this is about the gross misconduct of one of our employees that undermined the lawful and legitimate legal process for the handling of issues involving other employees,&quot; Tony Wood, managing director of Rolls-Royce's Defence Aerospace division said.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4706169.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Asda planning to shed 1,000 jobs</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A total of 185 management posts are to go at its main head office in Leeds and 15 at its second centre in Lutterworth.

A further four to five management positions are to go at each store, affecting 1,200 people, but the company expects 400 of these to be redeployed.

Asda, the UK's second largest supermarket, is owned by US giant Wal-Mart, the world's largest retailer.

The job cuts were part of &quot;a number of wide-ranging changes designed to simplify, re-focus and re-energise the business for future success&quot;, said Asda in a statement.

Asda chief executive Andy Bond added that the changes were designed to &quot;re-ignite our business over the next 12 to 18 months&quot;.

&quot;Whilst it's the right thing to do for our business, we say goodbye to some great colleagues this week and I thank them for all they have done for ASDA,&quot; he said.

&quot;While our sales have slowed in recent months as the economy's tightened, ASDA is no retail straggler.&quot;

Neil Derrick from the GMB union in Leeds said there had been insufficient consultation with staff over the job cuts.

He said junior managers in particular had &quot;certainly [been] left feeling that they have been treated without the respect they deserve&quot;.

Asda today employs 140,000 people, but has recently lost ground to Tesco, the UK's largest supermarket.

It has also been affected by a resurgence at number three supermarket Sainsbury's.

In addition to the job cuts, Asda also announced on Tuesday that two former directors are to rejoin its board.

David Cheesewright is to take on responsibility for trading and logistics following his return from a 12-month attachment as chief operating officer for parent company Wal-Mart in Canada.

And Andy Clarke is to return to Asda after a three-year gap to be retail director, the position he left in 2002 to work at Matalan and Iceland.

Founded in 1965, and bought by Wal-Mart in 1999, Asda now has 279 supermarkets across the UK.

In addition it has nine stand-alone stores of its George clothing subsidiary, and three Asda Living general merchandise outlets.

While Asda is headquartered in Leeds, George is based in Lutterworth, Leicestershire, where 15 positions are to go.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4651305.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | China launches currency shake-up</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The announcement on Thursday was widely seen as the first step towards the liberalisation of China's currency.

The yuan will no longer be pegged to the dollar, but will float against a basket of currencies.

It will also appreciate against the dollar, mollifying critics who say a cheap yuan has helped Chinese exports.

&quot;I welcome China's announcement today that it is adopting a more flexible exchange rate regime,&quot; said US Treasury Secretary John Snow in a statement.

&quot;As we have said, reform of China's currency regime is important for China and the international financial system.&quot;

Mr Snow said the US would watch China's implementation of its new system, which will see the yuan float against a basket of currencies, rather than linking it at a fixed rate to the US dollar.

China's currency had been pegged at 8.28 against the dollar, but the new move effectively strengthens it by 2.1%, to 8.11 to the dollar.

&quot;The Chinese have now put in place a system to allow their currency to move in tune with the global economy,&quot; Mr Snow said.

Meanwhile the International Monetary Fund (IMF) said it was ready to &quot;work with the authorities on the continuing evolution for the exchange rate system&quot;.

After the announcement the euro came under pressure from a rallying Japanese yen, which rallied sharply across the board - including against the US dollar.

Japanese officials welcomed the yuan's revaluation, saying it would benefit both the economies of China and Japan.

The dollar dropped against several Asian currencies following the Chinese announcement, sinking from 112.50 yen to 110.38 yen, its lowest level since 30 June.

Criticism had been strongest in the US, where many blame China for the decline of domestic industry.

However the White House also welcomed the move, with presidential spokesman Scott McClellan saying: &quot;We are encouraged by China's announcement today that they are adopting a more flexible market-based currency system.&quot;

And Thomas C Dawson, director of external relations at the IMF said: &quot;The change in China's exchange rate regime announced today represents a move in the direction of greater exchange rate flexibility.

&quot;Greater flexibility is very much in China's best interest, as it would provide more room for monetary independence, enhancing the government's ability to manage the economy.

&quot;We would encourage the authorities to utilise fully the scope for flexibility in the new exchange rate arrangement.&quot;

In an announcement on state television, the Chinese government said that from Friday the yuan would be allowed to trade in a tight range of 0.3% against a basket of foreign currencies.

However, it did not indicate which currencies they would be.

In a move that seems to be coordinated with the Chinese decision, Malaysia has also scrapped its currency's link with the dollar.

The Malaysian ringgit had been pegged at 3.8 to the dollar since September 1998, in the aftermath of the Asian financial crisis.

Malaysia's central bank said it did not expect the currency to deviate widely from its current level against the dollar.

The Chinese revaluation came a day after US Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan warned that China faced a &quot;very serious&quot; risk to its economy if it did not allow its currency to rise in value.

Senior US politicians had threatened to impose tariffs against China if it did not revalue the yuan.

However despite the warm reactions, some analysts reacted with some caution to Beijing's decision.

&quot;This looks like a very minimalist move,&quot; said Mark Cliffe, an economist with ING. &quot;It maybe relieves the pressure from the US with tariffs on the table in Congress but it remains to be seen if it is enough politically and economically.&quot;

The shake-up of the way the yuan is valued was &quot;clearly more symbolic than anything else&quot; said John Ip, a senior economist with Morley Fund Management.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4703477.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Helping poor 'a lifetime's work'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He told the BBC: &quot;It is a lifetime's work where we empower the people of Africa and the developing countries to make decisions for themselves.&quot;

But he said agreement on two key areas - a doubling of aid for poor countries and 100% debt relief had been reached.

And he said the Live 8 events were an example of Britain at its best.

They were proof that &quot;people can have power if they make their views felt&quot;.

G8 leaders are due to begin their three-day summit in Gleneagles in Scotland next Wednesday, with poverty and climate change high on the agenda.

&quot;We have already seen an agreement in the last few days for 100% debt relief for the poorest countries,&quot; Mr Brown told BBC News 24's Sunday programme.

European aid for poorer states was also set to double.

Mr Brown added: &quot;We've now got 13 European countries that have accepted a timetable for moving to 0.7% of their income spent on aid - something we've never achieved for 30 years despite all sorts of attempts.&quot;

&quot;So, on one or two of the major issues there has indeed been a great deal of progress,&quot; he said.

But he stressed: &quot;It is not a week's work at the G8 that is going to determine the long-term future of Africa or the developing countries.&quot;

The Pope has also joined in calls for world leaders to take action to stamp out poverty in Africa.

He urged them to take concrete measures to eradicate starvation and help poorer countries to develop.

Following talks with Russia's Vladimir Putin and German Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder, French President Jacques Chirac expressed hope for a possible deal on climate change. &quot;We are waiting to know the American position,&quot; he said.

The G8 summit will be chaired by British Prime Minister Tony Blair.

The UK government is promoting proposals, which came out of a report produced by the Commission for Africa, which he established.

The commission recommended: 100% debt cancellation for the poorest nations, the doubling of aid to Africa, the removal of barriers to trade with African nations, and improved governance.

While commitments have already been made on aid and debt relief, little concrete has been achieved on fair trade - which many African leaders and poverty campaigners see as crucial if the continent is to develop.

EU Trade Commissioner Peter Mandelson said that trade was the only way to convert humanitarian assistance into economic sustainability in Africa.

But he added: &quot;It's not a simple we throw a switch, we pull a lever and we have reform overnight for the benefit of all developing countries.

&quot;Different developing countries have different interests and different needs and we have to accommodate them all.&quot;

Last week, President George W Bush proposed doubling US aid to Africa over the next five years, a move which would see US aid rise to $8.6bn by 2010.

He said this would happen if African leaders made a commitment to honest government and the rule of law.

&quot;We are still no where near a deal that will effectively tackle global poverty. So far the UK government is largely serving up spin and hype. On the eve of such a crucial summit, Africa deserves more,&quot; said Steve Tibbett, head of policy and campaigns at ActionAid UK.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4646045.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | G8 leaders condemn London blasts</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>They said violence would not halt the summit, where talks would continue &quot;in the interests of a better world&quot;.

It was read by UK Prime Minister Tony Blair who is travelling to London for police briefings before returning to Gleneagles this evening.

It called the blasts &quot;an attack on civilised peoples everywhere&quot;.

Earlier, Mr Blair said it was the will of all the G8 leaders that the summit should continue in his absence.

It was &quot;particularly barbaric&quot; that this should occur when people are meeting to tackle poverty, he said.

Mr Blair said it was &quot;reasonably clear&quot; the explosions were designed to coincide with the opening of the G8.

The joint condemnation came from all the countries represented - including China, India and African states - and international agencies like the World Bank and International Monetary Fund.

It has now been announced that Foreign Secretary Jack Straw will chair the G8 summit while Mr Blair is in London.

Earlier, the US and UK leaders called for a new consensus on how to tackle climate change as the opening session of talks got underway.

They said it was time to replace a focus on Kyoto-style curbs on greenhouse gas emissions with research into clean technology.

President Bush said fast-developing nations must take a role, and welcomed India and China's attendance at the G8.

Along with climate issues, G8 leaders are due to discuss global trade.

With more than 10,000 police deployed, the summit is at the centre of one of the biggest security operations in UK history.

&quot;Now is the time to get beyond the Kyoto period and develop a strategy forward that is inclusive of the developing nations,&quot; said US President George W Bush.

UK Prime Minister Tony Blair said there was &quot;no point in going back over the Kyoto debate&quot; and it was preferable to &quot;bring people back into consensus together&quot; on global warming.

For many protesters and observers, the G8 summit is a defining moment in current world politics, amid increased calls for the world's richest countries to act now to help the world's poorest.

Demonstrations and Live8 concerts over the last four days sought to highlight the need for action on the issues of African aid, trade and climate change.
• 160 arrests as police and protesters clashed on Wednesday.
• Financier George Soros says the US is in &quot;total denial&quot; over climate change.
• UK Chancellor Gordon Brown hails US acceptance that &quot;human activity&quot; is causing global warming
• Mr Blair says there is &quot;no point going back over the Kyoto debate.

After the climate change talks, the G8 leaders are timetabled to discuss Middle East tensions, and hear from James Wolfensohn, the international envoy on Israel's pull out from Gaza.

African aid and trade will dominate the talks on Friday.

Some countries, notably Germany, have pressed for high oil prices and global economic imbalances to have a bigger place in the talks.

Frictions on climate change have emerged as high-level officials from the G8 nations have battled to hammer out an agreement ahead of the talks.

France is pushing for an agreement to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, whereas Mr Blair has called for &quot;sensible compromise&quot; and backed the US focus on fuel-efficient technology.

Some critics think the UK is too willing to seek a compromise. International financier George Soros said &quot;looking for common ground&quot; would &quot;merely...water down the seriousness of the situation&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4658427.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | G8 statements delayed to Friday</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The world leaders paused to condemn what they called &quot;an attack on civilised peoples everywhere&quot;.

Talks then resumed in Tony Blair's absence as he travelled to London for police briefings.

Soon after his departure, developing nations called for action on climate change and for reduced trade barriers.

Before leaving for London, Mr Blair said it was &quot;reasonably clear&quot; the explosions were designed to coincide with the opening of the G8 and insisted it was the will of all the G8 leaders that the summit should continue regardless.

It was &quot;particularly barbaric&quot; that this should occur when people are meeting to tackle poverty, Mr Blair said.

UK Foreign Secretary Jack Straw travelled from London to Scotland to chair the talks until Mr Blair returns sometime on Thursday night.

Mr Straw was greeted by a joint declaration issued by the so-called G5 developing countries Brazil, China, India, Mexico and South Africa, who called for trade barriers to be removed as part of efforts to eradicate poverty.

&quot;Trade distorting domestic support for agriculture in developed countries must be substantially reduced and all forms of export subsidies must be eliminated,&quot; the statement said.

The G5 also urged the G8 to take a lead in international action to combat climate change, insisting there is an urgent need to develop policies to help overcome &quot;the inevitable adverse effects of climate change on the poor&quot;.

Ahead of the attacks in London, Mr Blair and US President George W Bush had called for a new consensus on how to tackle climate change.

The two leaders said it was time to replace a focus on Kyoto-style curbs on greenhouse gas emissions with research into clean technology.

President Bush said fast-developing nations must take a role, and welcomed India and China's attendance at the G8.

Along with climate issues, G8 leaders are due to discuss global trade.

&quot;Now is the time to get beyond the Kyoto period and develop a strategy forward that is inclusive of the developing nations,&quot; said President Bush.

UK Prime Minister Tony Blair said there was &quot;no point in going back over the Kyoto debate&quot; and it was preferable to &quot;bring people back into consensus together&quot; on global warming.

With more than 10,000 police deployed, the summit is at the centre of one of the biggest security operations in UK history.

Demonstrations and Live8 concerts during the last week have sought to highlight the need for action on the issues of African aid, trade and climate change.

For many protesters and observers, the G8 summit is a defining moment in current world politics, amid increased calls for the world's richest countries to act now to help the world's poorest.

After the climate change talks, the G8 leaders are timetabled to discuss Middle East tensions, and hear from James Wolfensohn, the international envoy on Israel's pull out from Gaza.

African aid and trade talks are scheduled to dominate the talks on Friday.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4660831.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Government defends G8 aid boost</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Prime Minister Tony Blair insisted &quot;very substantial progress&quot; had been made in helping developing countries.

International development secretary Hilary Benn said: &quot;This is politics demonstrating its capacity to make a difference.&quot;

And campaigner Bob Geldof was satisfied the measures agreed on Africa would save 10 million lives.

Mr Blair acknowledged the shortcomings in what the summit had achieved saying: &quot;We do not, simply by this communique, make poverty history.&quot;

But he said the G8 had demonstrated a &quot;political will &quot; to end global poverty and to tackle the effects of greenhouse gas emissions.

On climate change, Mr Blair said an agreement had always been unlikely, but that the US now accepted global warming was an issue.

Environment Secretary Margaret Beckett said claims the G8 offered nothing new on climate change were &quot;absolute rubbish&quot;.

Some aid agencies and environmentalists have described the outcome of the summit as &quot;vastly disappointing&quot;.

&quot;The people have roared but the G8 has whispered,&quot; said Kumi Naidoo, chair of the Global Call to Action against Poverty.

&quot;Never before have so many people forced a change of policy onto a global agenda. If anyone had said eight weeks ago will we get a doubling of aid, will we get a deal on debt, people would have said 'no',&quot; Mr Geldof said.

He added that he gave the G8 summit &quot;10 out of 10 on aid, eight out of 10 on debt&quot;.

Irish rock star and fellow anti-poverty campaigner Bono, praised the agreement to give universal access to Aids drugs.

&quot;600,000 Africans, mostly children, will remember this G8 summit at Gleneagles because they will be around to remember this summit, and they wouldn't have otherwise,&quot; said Bono.
• Mr Blair said trade discussions in Hong Kong later this year should yield an end date to agricultural subsidies.
• Britain is to host a 1 November meeting on climate change, to assess progress.
• Mr Blair said &quot;only people who can change Africa ultimately are the Africans&quot;.
• $3bn agreed for Palestinian Authority for investment in infrastructure.
• Nigeria's President Olusegun Obasanjo described the deal as a &quot;success&quot;.
• African leaders to commit to democracy and good governance as part of the deal.
• Debts of the 18 poorest countries to be forgiven.
• Universal access to anti-HIV drugs in Africa by 2010.

Summing up the G8 meeting, Mr Blair acknowledged: &quot;It isn't all everyone wanted, but it is progress.&quot;

UN Secretary General Kofi Annan said the G8 deal represented a &quot;good day&quot;, but that it was only &quot;a beginning&quot;.

&quot;The fight to end poverty is just starting,&quot; said Mr Annan.

On climate change, Mr Blair said: &quot;If it is impossible to bring America into the consensus on tackling the issue... we will never ensure the huge emerging economies, who are going to consume more energy than any other part of the world... are part of the dialogue.&quot;

He said however that agreement had been reached that climate change was a problem, human activity contributed to it and it had to be tackled with urgency.

Earlier the prime minister had said that in the wake of Thursday's attacks, the communique was the &quot;definitive expression of our collective will to act in the face of death&quot;.

&quot;It has a pride and a hope and a humanity that can lift the shadow of terrorism,&quot; he added.

Some described the talks on climate change as a &quot;significant lost opportunity&quot;.

G8 leaders have indicated the statement represents progress but Stephen Tindale, a spokesperson for Greenpeace, said: &quot;The G8 has committed to nothing new but at least we haven't moved backwards on the environment.&quot;

The Sustainable Energy and Economy Network, a worldwide coalition of environmental and development campaigners, said: &quot;Urgent action is now required to substantially reduce emissions, reduce fossil fuel dependence and to protect people around the world, especially the vulnerable, the poor and disappearing nations.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4666743.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Credit card advice site launched</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The site, called &quot;choosing and using&quot;, advises people what sort of credit card best suits their spending behaviour.

It also offers help for people already experiencing credit card debt, but it does not compare specific cards.

With around 1,500 credit cards available in the UK, choosing the right one is not always an obvious decision.

The site was set up by Apacs, the UK payments association, which represents all of the major UK credit card issuers

The website gives the type of features people should be looking for depending on their spending behaviour.

For example people who clear the balance each month are advised that the interest rate is less important, and that they should concentrate on whether there is an annual fee and any rewards programme.

There is also advice on what to do if people have run up too much debt on their credit card.

But the website does not look at specific cards. BBC personal finance reporter Richard Scott says people are still likely to need comparison tables in newspapers or on the internet in order to make their choice.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4705899.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Ex-minister denies Railtrack plan</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mr Byers said that he put public interest first and did not abuse his position or act unlawfully.

About 50,000 shareholders want £157m in compensation after the firm in charge of running the UK's rail infrastructure collapsed in 2001.

They allege that the government deliberately allowed the firm to fail.

&quot;These are very serious allegations without foundation in fact and are simply wrong,&quot; Mr Byers said.

Answering questions from the shareholders' lawyer, Mr Byers said that he was &quot;prepared&quot; to reverse the privatisation of Railtrack if it was in the best interests of the public and rail travellers.

&quot;But in doing that, I did not abuse my position, I did not act unlawfully,&quot; he said.

Mr Byers added that he &quot;had regard to the interests of Railtrack shareholders&quot;.

The court case, the UK's largest ever group action, is in its second week.

It is a complex wrangle, with disgruntled shareholders alleging &quot;misfeasance&quot;, whereby the government and Mr Byers are said to have acted within the law but in bad faith.

They also claim a breach of human rights for confiscation of assets.

At the heart of the case is whether Railtrack - since replaced by the state-backed not-for-profit Network Rail - ran out of money or whether the government took a secret and malicious decision to destroy the company.

Critics complain that by withholding state support, Railtrack was renationalised by the backdoor.

The government has always said the firm was not capable of running the railways and was insolvent without its support.

It denies killing off Railtrack and said it withdrew financial support and rescue plans because the financial state of Railtrack had deteriorated.

Last week, Railtrack's former chairman John Robinson denied that he had told Mr Byers, during a meeting, that the firm was in a worsening financial situation.

He also pointed out that Railtrack was asking for less support than is currently given to its successor, Network Rail.

Mr Byers has a different recollection of the meeting, and points to it as a key moment when he was made aware of how serious Railtrack's situation had become.

The BBC's transport correspondent Tom Symonds says the trial is an &quot;an unprecedented case, and one which includes evidence from the secret heart of Whitehall&quot;.

Small shareholders are angry that the value of their investment in Railtrack, formed in April 1994 after the privatisation of the UK railway network by the then Conservative government of John Major, plummeted.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4674475.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Warning on Channel rail link cost</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A National Audit Office (NAO) report found passenger revenue forecasts for the £5bn project - made in 1998 and 2001 - had been &quot;too optimistic&quot;.

As a result taxpayers could be forced to make up the shortfall for the London to Kent link, the NAO added.

&quot;The economic justification for the project remains marginal,&quot; it said.

The uncertainties remained despite &quot;encouraging developments&quot; linked to regenerating areas around London's King's Cross, Stratford in east London and Kent, the NAO said.

It called on the government to take measures to minimise potential risks to taxpayers by reviewing costing forecasts more regularly.

Such a move would allow the Department of Transport to make &quot;realistic predictions of the value and timing of future lending&quot; to London and Continental Railways who are building the link.

However, the NAO did acknowledge that Section 1 and 2 of the scheme had come in on time and to cost.

Section 2 - from north Kent to St Pancras in north London - is expected to be completed in 2007.

Edward Leigh, chairman of the House of Commons Public Accounts Committee called on the Department of Transport to keep a close eye on the scheme.

&quot;This project is a sorry tale of something that started off in the expectation that all the risks would be borne by the private sector and has ended up today as one where they are all backed financially by the government,&quot; he said.

However, Mr Leigh did add that the plans to provide a fast link between London and the Channel Tunnel in Folkestone were &quot;bold and prestigious&quot; and had helped the UK secure the 2012 Olympics.

Part of the link will be used to carry spectators from central London to Olympic sites in east London.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4701801.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Brown 'cheating' claim on budget</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Treasury is planning to stretch the economic cycle to nine years to avoid breaching its &quot;golden rule&quot; on balancing the budget over the cycle.

Shadow Chancellor George Osborne said the move was &quot;a smokescreen to conceal his fiddling of the golden rule&quot;.

Mr Brown said the change was driven purely by revised economic data.

The effect of the change is to add an extra £10bn-£12bn to the chancellor's coffers - by adding two more years to the cycle when the budget was in surplus.

The opposition say the move has damaged Mr Brown's reputation as the Iron Chancellor.

Mr Brown has insisted that he would meet his self-imposed rules even without this change.

But, with the Chancellor in danger of breaching his rule in the current financial year, the adjustment will reduce pressure to raise taxes next April.

Under the &quot;golden rule,&quot; the current budget must be in balance over the economic cycle as a whole.

The news, announced by Mr Brown in testimony to the Treasury Select Committee, is the most significant revision of the fiscal rules since Mr Brown gained his reputation for prudence by publishing them in 1998.

The Chancellor now says that the current economic cycle began in 1997, not 1999 as previously thought.

Mr Brown does not have to formally announce the change until he delivers the government's economic forecast in the pre-Budget report in November.

The move comes as many independent forecasters warn that the government is in danger of breaching its own rules this year, as tax receipts have been falling below expectations, while spending continues to grow.

Mr Brown told MPs that the change was fully justified given the significant revisions to GDP data made by the Office for National Statistics.

But he denied that the change of definition had anything to do with his budget difficulties.

&quot;We would meet the Golden Rule irrespective,&quot; he told the committee.

Mr Brown's plan was criticised by the opposition parties and independent commentators.

Liberal Democrat Treasury Spokesman Vince Cable said the move &quot;makes a mockery of the Golden Rule.&quot;

Martin Weale, head of the respected economic think tank NIESR, said that the golden rule now &quot;should be replaced by an independent expert assessment of whether the current budget is expected to be in balance or surplus in the medium term&quot;.

Chief CBI economist Ian McAfferty added the move was simply a way to delay tough decisions about tackling the &quot;structural deficit&quot; of public finances.

&quot;The Treasury announcement that the fiscal goalposts have been shifted reflects the mounting problems with the Government's finances,&quot; he said.

And Peter Spencer, who analyses trends in public spending for Ernst &amp; Young's ITEM club, said: &quot;The chancellor's big problem is that he will start the next cycle in serious structural deficit with no obvious political window of opportunity for correction.&quot;

Some experts warned that the shift could lead to tax rises or spending cuts in the coming year as Mr Brown will be forced to start the next economic cycle from a weaker position.

Mr Brown compounded the impression that the public finances are in difficulty by announcing that he was postponing the next spending review for one year, from 2006 to 2007.

And he said it would be &quot;zero-based,&quot; and departments should not assume that they will be funded at the same level as before.

The effect of this move will be to ensure that the planned squeeze on public spending, scheduled to start in 2006, cannot be challenged by government departments.

The Chancellor had already announced substantial jobs cuts to the civil service in 2004.

Mr Brown will now have a chance to assess more fully the state of the public finances before departments begin planning for spending in 2008-11, a period that will cover spending through the next General Election..

That spending review will now come as Tony Blair is celebrating 10 years as Prime Minister, and during the period that Mr Brown is widely expected to put his hat in the ring as his successor.

Mr Brown has staked his reputation as a New Labour chancellor on his absolute commitment to fiscal prudence.

By effectively moving the goalposts, he will be more confident that he will be able to meet his fiscal rules - at a time when their breach would have damaged his chances of succeeding Mr Blair.

Mr Brown has also effectively postponed for several years making any tough decisions about raising taxes or cutting spending, which might have been necessary if he had been in danger of breaching his borrowing rule.

However, he may have won a Pyrrhic victory if his actions reduce the Labour government's hard-won credibility in financial markets.

This could lead to higher borrowing costs for government debt.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4695823.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Rover sold to Nanjing Automobile</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It was one of two Chinese companies trying to buy the assets of MG Rover, the other being Shanghai Automotive.

Although Nanjing was the smaller firm it secured a deal with administrators PriceWaterhouseCoopers (PwC) on Friday.

&quot;Nanjing will now begin to take control of the assets and develop its plans for the future,&quot; said Tony Lomas of PwC.

The news is a blow for UK businessman David James, whose Kimber group had put in two bids to buy parts of Rover.

Earlier this week Mr James, the company-recovery specialist who helped revive the Millennium Dome, told the BBC the combined value of his bid would be about £40m.

Joint administrator Mr Lomas said Nanjing intended to relocate the engine plant and some car production plant to China but to &quot;retain some car production plant in the UK&quot;.

He added that Nanjing, China's oldest carmaker, also planned to develop an R&amp;D and technical facility in the UK.

It is still not known how many workers Nanjing will employ. But according to the BBC's Nils Blythe if Nanjing's proposed long-term plans come to fruition it could create 2,000 jobs in the UK.

Geoffrey Robinson, Labour MP for Coventry North West and former boss of Jaguar, told BBC Radio 4's Today programme the deal &quot;seems fraught with difficulties&quot;.

&quot;We can only wish them luck but they are a very small company and they will face formidable difficulties.&quot;

For a transitional period a rump workforce will continue to be employed by MG Rover Group and engine maker Powertrain.

They will assist the administrators as they have for the last three-and-a-half months, following the demise of Rover in early April when it ran out of money after a proposed tie-up with SAIC collapsed.

&quot;In the meantime Nanjing Automobile (Group) Corporation intends to begin to hire staff to assist it in implementing and developing its strategy,&quot; Mr Lomas said.

Nanjing had been close to winning the bidding war a week ago, but SAIC then came back with another offer, and Mr James put in his offers this week.

&quot;It is not really a surprise that one of the Chinese bidders has won as they were looking to buy the whole operation,&quot; Dr David Bailey, of the University of Birmingham's business school told the BBC.

&quot;However some had thought that Shanghai was the front runner given the previous proposed tie-up with Rover and the fact they had bought some of the copyrights.&quot;

Nanjing had earlier said it wanted to restart car production in the West Midlands, but may look to use other sites as well as the former Rover site at Longbridge in Birmingham.

Cars will be built under the MG marque and may include sports models and small and medium sized vehicles.

However, it also previously expressed plans to shift production of small and medium-sized cars to China, and then export kits to the UK for final assembly.

That has lead the T&amp;G union to fear the Chinese company may not maintain substantial production in the UK.

&quot;Having viewed both the Nanjing and SAIC bids, there is no doubt in our mind that on first viewing the SAIC proposals appeared to suggest more jobs for Britain, &quot; Tony Woodley, general secretary of the union said on Friday.

He said the union would now look to make &quot;urgent contact&quot; with Nanjing for talks on jobs.

Nanjing has indicated before it plans to use MG as its main marque in Europe while developing other MG Rover brands, such as Austin, elsewhere.

Arup has been advising Nanjing on the proposed deal and chairman John Miles said: &quot;The fact that Nanjing has bought the entirety of MG is an indication of their bigger intention to become a global automotive company.&quot;

SAIC bought the intellectual property rights to sell the Rover 25 and 75 models in China during a previous attempt to take over the carmaker.

Nanjing had previously rejected any claims that SAIC's ownership of the rights to the Rover 25 and 75 engines would affect its plans.

And Honda - which owned the rights to some of MG Rover's technology - has repossessed equipment and blueprints, making it more difficult for any buyer to restart production of the Rover 45 - based on the Honda Civic - or MG ZS models.

&quot;It is an interesting legal position, maybe Nanjing think they can make MG models of the 25 and 75,&quot; said Dr Bailey.

&quot;There could still be some tie-up between the two Chinese firms. After all, earlier in the year when MG Rover and SAIC were having talks Nanjing had planned to be a joint partner in that.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4708739.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | African leaders urge debt action</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Meeting in Libya, African Union heads of state said G8 leaders must act quickly to cancel debt at their summit in Scotland, which starts on Wednesday.

The summit will be dominated by issues of global trade, aid for Africa, debt relief and climate change.

Anti-poverty protests continued on Tuesday but passed off peacefully.

AU leaders - headed by Nigerian president Olusegun Obasanjo - called on Tuesday for the G8 group of nations to endorse the recommendations of the UK-backed Commission for Africa - which include 100% debt relief for all African countries - and &quot;to act expeditiously on them&quot;.
• Police have said they will deal robustly with further protests expected on Wednesday near the summit venue.
• Up to 100 protesters arrested on Monday have appeared in court in Edinburgh
• Live8 organiser Bob Geldof has called violent protesters &quot;idiots&quot; and said Monday's clashes were a side issue
• South African Finance Minister Trevor Manuel questioned G8 leaders' commitment to Africa as the continent does not pose a threat to their future or security.
• Breakthroughs have been reached on debt cancellation and aid ahead of the meeting, but progress has yet to be made on fair trade and climate change.

Police have set out their plans to ensure a peaceful protest in the town of Auchterarder, near the summit venue, on Wednesday.

Tayside chief constable John Vine said months of preparation had taken place for the march, which will be licensed for only 5,000 people. He said the police would take &quot;robust action&quot; if they encounter people who are prepared to break the law.

In Edinburgh, three anti-poverty activists chained themselves to the top of a crane to highlight their objections to Mr Brown's promotion of free-market solutions for Africa.

About 150 environmental activists staged a peaceful protest at an oil refinery in Grangemouth, about 30 kilometres from Edinburgh.

For many, the meeting is a defining moment in current world politics, as an upswell of popular support is calling on the G8 leaders to make fundamental changes to the way rich countries deal with poorer nations.

Some breakthroughs have been made, with G8 nations agreeing to double aid for poor countries and offer 100% debt relief.

Other key topics are fair trade and climate change and leaders are also likely to talk about the impact of high oil prices and exchange rates on economic stability.

President George W Bush downplayed expectations over trade deals and climate change in an interview with ITV on Monday.

Mr Bush said a deal on dropping its farm subsidies - which African states say is vital for fair trade - would only happen if the EU ditched its Common Agricultural Policy (CAP).</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4653713.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Blair will not 'flinch' on Africa</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The prime minister said he thought &quot;substantial progress&quot; could be made at the summit and that the US and UK were in broad agreement over the aid issue.

Anti-poverty campaigners led by Bob Geldof and fellow singer Bono said a deal on extra aid was not yet secured.

Mr Geldof urged the prime minister to stand firm on aid or run the risk of a &quot;terrible human failure&quot;.

Mr Geldof held meetings with Mr Blair and other world leaders including President George Bush and Chancellor Gerhard Schroeder, who have arrived in Scotland for the two-day summit.

One hundred people were arrested on Wednesday following a day of protests in Edinburgh and near the summit venue at the Gleneagles Hotel.

The Queen hosted a dinner for world leaders on Wednesday evening ahead of the start of formal talks on trade, aid and climate change.

Before attending the banquet, President Bush received treatment for minor injuries sustained when he collided with a police officer during a bike ride around the Gleneagles estate.

Mr Bush suffered scrapes on his hands and arms while the officer, who suffered minor ankle injuries, was taken to hospital as a precaution.

Speaking on Wednesday, Mr Blair said he would not flinch on trying to secure a deal at the summit.

&quot;I'll push them (the G8 leaders) the whole way,&quot; he told the BBC.

&quot;Do you ever get everything you want in negotiations like this? No. But can we make very substantial progress, can we change the terms of the debate on Africa? Yes we can.&quot;

Mr Blair acknowledged international differences over climate change but said he wanted &quot;a firm understanding to end the trade distorting subsidies&quot; - one of the more controversial issues and one on which many divisions remain.

Pop singer Bono urged the leaders to consider extra measures, such as the education of girls and the fight against malaria.

The prime minister had the &quot;biggest democratic mandate in history&quot; to press for an African aid deal, Mr Geldof added.

About 4,000 protesters gathered around the perimeter fence at Gleneagles during a day of tension between the march's organisers and police.

A small group of protesters breached the fence, prompting police to bring in reinforcements by helicopter.

Earlier, groups of protesters smashed car windows, attacked police and disrupted traffic by dragging branches onto the road, prompting police to temporarily revoke the permission to march.

With up to 4,000 police on duty, the summit is at the centre of the biggest security operation in UK history.
• The final Live 8 concert has taken place at Edinburgh's Murrayfield stadium
• The UK insists the final summit communique will contain detailed commitments to help Africa, not just warm words.
• The European Commission pledges 1bn euros a year in extra aid for trade.
• President Bush insists African leaders must end corruption in return for debt cuts.
• Mr Bush also says he wants to move to the &quot;post-Kyoto&quot; era on global warming - with the emphasis on new technologies not cutting emissions.
• Scuffles broke out during a series of protests in Edinburgh, police making 18 arrests

For many protesters and observers, the G8 summit is a defining moment in current world politics, amid increased calls for the world's richest countries to act now to help the world's poorest.

The leaders of Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, Russia, and the US are present at Gleneagles with the leaders of China, Brazil, India, Nigeria and South Africa also due to attend.

Pressure is on to reach deals on debt relief and aid for Africa, address global trade issues and adopt a unified stance in the fight against climate change.

Commitments to 100% debt relief for African countries and a doubling of aid for the continent are at the centre of discussions although it is thought that a firm deal has yet to be agreed.

Discussions over trade liberalisation and how to tackle global warming are likely to prove far more contentious.

President Bush has made clear he will not sign up to Kyoto-style limits on greenhouse gas emissions, highlighting strong differences with France.

Mr Blair is trying to reach a compromise by stressing commitment to eco-friendly technology to cut greenhouse gases.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4654483.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Positive signal on Rover pensions</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The comments come after pensioners were told that their payments would be adjusted lower because of overpayment.

Trustees moved to calm fears saying that the cut was needed to prepare for entry into the Pension Protection Fund.

The fund will cover 90% of benefits, and entry will be a matter of weeks rather than months, trustees said.

Rover, the last British mass-produced car maker, collapsed in April at a cost of almost 6,000 jobs.

Financial problems meant that the company's two employee pension schemes had a deficit of £495m, raising concerns that workers would either lose benefits or have to live on reduced payments.

Trustees and the government have been negotiating to safeguard as much of the pension schemes as possible.

&quot;We are now confident that we are very close to being able to have both schemes enter the Pension Protection Fund (PPF),&quot; said Chris Martin, managing director of Independent Trustee Services, which is looking after the rights of Rover pensioners.

&quot;I would imagine it would be a matter of weeks, rather than months.&quot;

Trustees will now have to finalise talks with Phoenix Venture Holdings, the company that owned and ran Rover, about how much debt they will pay off.

Once those talks are finished, the government will clarify entry requirements to the PPF.

Mr Martin told the BBC's Today programme that getting ready for entry into the PPF meant that they would have to cut pension payments to those people who had taken early retirement by 10%.

There also would be a readjustment to rectify three months of overpayment.

Mr Martin was keen to point out, however, that despite the cut in payments, pensioners are likely to be in a stronger position.

At best, Rover's pension schemes would have been able to pay out only 63% of their obligations. Once the schemes join the PPF, 90% of the pension payments will be guaranteed.

&quot;The vast majority of pensioners will find themselves in a better position than the scheme would have afforded,&quot; Mr Martin told the BBC's Today programme.

&quot;And all those 6,000 or so other workers that have not retired will have confidence that their benefits will be safe in the future.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4674303.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Markets recover from UK bombings</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>London's FTSE 100 added 73.9 points, or 1.4%, to 5,232.2. Paris's Cac 40 and Frankfurt's Dax both rose over 1.5%.

The British pound, however, continued to slide, hitting an 19-month low against the US dollar and taking its decline to 5% in the past two weeks.

The London Metal Exchange did not open its trading floor for business on Friday because it is within a police exclusion zone.

The commodities exchange, which was one of a number of City buildings evacuated on Thursday, can also trade electronically.

As news of the bombings emerged on Thursday, the FTSE 100 tumbled as much as 3.5% in 90 minutes, its steepest fall since the start of the Iraq war.

The slump wiped more than £44bn off the value of the stocks in London.

For a time the London Stock Exchange asked its member firms to switch off all automated trading systems.

&quot;It was manic yesterday when the electronic trading systems were turned off,&quot; said one trader at HSBC.

&quot;We had to trade manually and the phones went berserk.

By Thursday afternoon the FTSE bounced back from its worst levels to close just 1.4% lower at 5,158.

Despite initial concerns about the economic impact of the London attacks, traders and investors said that any market decline was likely to be short-lived as the threat passed and the extent of damage became clearer.

&quot;People cope okay with good and with bad news, but they don't cope well with uncertainty, and that was the problem on Thursday,&quot; said David Buik at financial bookmaker Cantor Index.

&quot;Now there is a feeling that there is some level of control,&quot; he added.

Industries that were hardest hit on Thursday led the rally on Friday, with insurance firms and airlines bouncing back.

Analysts said that the economic effect of the bomb blasts was likely to be limited and companies were well prepared to deal with any disruption.

&quot;Unfortunately, we expected it to come,&quot; said Andrea Williams, head of European equities at Royal London Asset Management.

&quot;It came and it doesn't really affect economic growth. This is something which you have to price into the markets.&quot;

Share indexes in the US were little changed overnight, with the S&amp;P 500 and Dow Jones indexes both adding 0.3%.

In Asia, the Tokyo's Nikkei 225 index lost 0.2%, Hong Kong's Hang Seng slid 0.5% and Sydney's main index shed 0.1%.

The UK pound fell 0.5% to $1.7363 on Friday as investors bet that the Bank of England was likely to cut interest rates in August.

It left the key interest rate at 4.75% on Thursday, resisting increasing calls from retailers and business leaders to cut borrowing costs amid evidence that consumer were spending less and the economy was slowing.

Also impacting the pound were unfounded rumours that the Bank of England planned to hold a crisis meeting to consider an emergency rate cut in response to the London bombings.

&quot;It's important to see how these events affect the British economy and global security in the longer term,&quot; said Kikuko Takeda, currency analyst at Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi.

European bonds fell in early trading on Friday as many investors moved out of the so-called havens they had sought safety in on Thursday.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4663125.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | BA ex-chief Lord King dies at 87</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Dubbed Mrs Thatcher's favourite businessman, he was chosen to prepare the loss-making nationalised flag carrier for privatisation.

He was chairman of BA from 1981 to 1993 and was later given the honour of president emeritus.

Reports said he died peacefully in his sleep at noon at his 2,000-acre estate in Wartnaby, Leicestershire.

&quot;John King was an industrial trail-blazer. He was one of a handful of bold business leaders who helped turn round the British economy in the 1980s,&quot; Baroness Thatcher said.

&quot;I shall miss him a very great deal.&quot;

Lord King began his business career working for a number of small engineering firms as a salesman. Soon he was running his own company, Whitehouse Industries, which managed to prosper through securing defence contracts.

After the war, at the age of 28, he bought Yorkshire-based ball bearing company Pollard Bearings and built it up to be the third biggest UK company in the field.

His numerous business interests included the chairmanship of engineering firm Babcock and Wilcox, as well as posts at British Nuclear Associates, Dennis Motor Holdings and BA.

He has also held directorships at the Daily Telegraph, The Spectator and engineering firm Short Brothers.

In 1979 he was knighted and two years later was appointed chairman of BA by Margaret Thatcher.

Lord King hired Colin Marshall as chief executive and the airline was floated on the London Stock Exchange in 1987. The initial share offering was 11 times oversubscribed.

Other actions taken to turn the ailing airline around included 23,000 job losses and an overhaul of the fleet and route map.

Lord King recognised the importance of Concorde to BA's business strategy and used the charismatic airliner to win business customers by guaranteeing a certain number of Concorde upgrades in return for corporate accounts with BA.

During his reign at BA, Lord King courted controversy with the emergence of Richard Branson's Virgin Atlantic - which posed a serious threat to some of BA most lucrative routes.

When Virgin first came on the scene, there seemed little threat to BA, the established, traditional national carrier, but a bitter battle for customers ensued.

A &quot;dirty tricks&quot; row ended with each suing the other for libel.

Richard Branson sued Lord King and BA for libel in 1992. BA countersued and after the case went to trial in 1993 the court found in favour of Mr Branson and Virgin.

Lord King and BA were ordered to pay damages of £500,000 to Richard Branson and £110,000 to his airline. BA also had to foot a legal bill of about £3m.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4676661.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | James poised to launch Rover bid</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mr James hopes to resurrect Rover as a niche car manufacturer but his plans depend on him finding a buyer for the engine design business Powertrain.

Administrators are understood to have given Mr James a couple of days to put forward a firm proposition.

Bids have already come from Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation and from Nanjing Automobile Corporation.

SAIC is teaming up with former Ford of Europe chief Martin Leach.

Mr James said his consortium had the funds in place to bid for Rover.

However, he stressed that his plans hinged on finding an immediate buyer for Powertrain.

&quot;We believe that we can build the MG side of it into a niche car category,&quot; he told the BBC.

Mr James said he believed he could persuade other British and international car makers to develop small-scale production at Longbridge, leading to a &quot;very big escalation in employment&quot;.

&quot;We don't believe in the mass production concept. We believe in niche products and that is exactly where we are going with our bid,&quot; he said.

Administrators PricewaterhouseCoopers are already studying two detailed offers to buy MG Rover, both of which are likely to see production resume at Longbridge.

A decision on a sale is expected within the next week.

SAIC submitted a bid reported to be worth £60m on Monday.

It is working in partnership with Magma Corporation, a company set up by Mr Leach, the former head of Ford's European operations. If successful, SAIC aims to establish a manufacturing, distribution and research centre at Longbridge.

It wants to resume production of the MG TF sports car and the Rover 75 saloon and develop new models from 2007 onwards.

It is not known how many jobs the SAIC-Magma bid would create, although it has been reported that it could employ up to 1,600 staff.

Under Nanjing's proposals, production of MG sports cars would restart in the west Midlands - probably at Longbridge - as would the design and manufacturing of high-value saloons.

Nanjing plans to use MG as its main marque in Europe while developing other MG Rover brands, such as Austin, elsewhere.

It is understood that both bids would result in some MG Rover assets being shipped to China.

SAIC could relocate engine design and production to China while Nanjing is expected to use Rover's production line to produce small and medium sized cars in its home country.

&quot;Nanjing is bidding for the complete assets of MG Rover and a core part of their global strategy is to retain a strong design and manufacturing capability here in the UK,&quot; a source close to Nanjing told the BBC.

MG Rover collapsed in April with the loss of more than 5,500 jobs.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4695443.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-24</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Boots hit by 'difficult' trading</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Like-for-like sales at Boots the Chemist outlets fell by 0.8%.

The retailer is the latest to report that consumer demand is sputtering. On Wednesday GUS and Clinton Cards said retail conditions were &quot;challenging&quot;.

Increased competition, higher interest rates and more expensive petrol are all taking their toll, analysts have said.

&quot;Conditions on the High Street are difficult, competition is intense and there is nothing to suggest this will change in the coming months,&quot; said Richard Baker, chief executive of Boots.

&quot;This is a reasonable performance in a tough market, against our strongest trading period last year.&quot;

Overall sales at Boots the Chemist rose 1.5% during the fiscal first quarter. For the Boots Group as a whole, revenues were up 1.9% on a year earlier.

Boots said that &quot;the quarter saw good performance in Beauty, with particularly good growth in cosmetics&quot;, adding that it planned to invest more money in that part of its business.

&quot;Toiletries also performed well,&quot; the company said, though &quot;sales were weaker in the Lifestyle categories, with continued decline in the photo market and a slow start to summer ranges&quot;.

The company said it expected to complete the sale of its Boots Healthcare International division by the end of this year.

Analysts have valued the healthcare division, which makes Strepsils sore-throat pastilles and Nurofen pain killers, at just over £1bn.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4702361.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-25</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | MG Rover 'white knight' drops out</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Speculation has been rife recently about a possible rescue for Rover, which went bankrupt earlier this year at a cost of more than 5,500 jobs.

Mr James is part of a consortium that had hoped to buy Rover and keep making cars at the firm's Longbridge plant.

For that to happen, Mr James needed China's Shanghai Automotive (SAIC) to agree to buy key Rover businesses and assets, which it refused to do.

Without SAIC's agreement, Mr James and his group could not raise the money that they needed to buy Rover.

Under the terms of their rescue plan, Mr James wanted to break up Rover and create a new MG car firm. The MG brand is seen as one of Rover's most valuable assets.

Under his plan, SAIC would have acquired Rover's profitable Powertrain engine-making division, and undertaken to buy the firm's remaining assets a year later.

Mr James said that over the weekend it became clear that SAIC was not willing to commit to the plan.

&quot;I thought they would accept it, because it would be such a logical step,&quot; he told the BBC's Today programme.

&quot;We would have put them on our board and given them 25% of our new MG company as a gift,&quot; he explained.

&quot;It would have been a very logical progression towards an eventual time when SAIC would have owned everything.&quot;

He said that it would have given SAIC access to the UK car market as well as providing the Chinese firm with the assets they already had expressed an interest in.

SAIC had already held lengthy discussions with Rover's management about the possibility of a partnership, but eventually ruled itself out of making a bid.

Analysts said that the firm may have decided it can get the assets cheaper once all hopes of a rescue have evaporated.

Speculation has swirled about Rover and its chances of finding a white knight.

The Mail on Sunday carried news of Mr James' talks, while The Sunday Telegraph reported that another firm, Nanjing Automobile, had been awarded preferred bidder status, enabling it to conduct negotiations on an exclusive basis.

Rovers' administrators PricewaterhouseCoopers have set an October deadline for reaching a deal.

Mr James said that his deal could only be resurrected if PwC made it clear it would not accept bids from SAIC or Nanjing for parts of MG Rover, or if the UK government promised to step in as a guarantor for Mr James's proposed deals.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4670753.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-26</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Possible legal action over Rover</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It secured a deal with administrators PriceWaterhouseCoopers (PwC) on Friday.

But fellow Chinese firm Shanghai Automotive Industry Corporation (SAIC) is unhappy with the &quot;discriminatory&quot; decision and may take legal action.

And UK businessman David James, who put in two bids to buy parts of Rover, may consider tabling another bid.

But administrator Tony Lomas of PwC said the deal with Nanjing, Chinese oldest carmaker, was rock solid.

&quot;Nanjing has paid a non-refundable deposit and there will be a letter-of-credit payment in respect of the rest of the money,&quot; he told the BBC. &quot;It is an unconditional contract.&quot;

He said there were a number of characteristics which differentiated the Nanjing bid from its rivals.

&quot;One of them was the price they paid, and also nobody else, including SAIC, was at such an advanced stage in their contract discussions,&quot; said Mr Lomas.

He said administrators had judged that if they did not take up the offer there was no prospect of getting any of the other offers &quot;up to a level that matched Nanjing's&quot;.

However there could be legal wrangles ahead when Nanjing begins car production, which it plans to do under the MG marque in Europe.

SAIC bought the intellectual property rights to sell the Rover 25 and 75 models in China during a previous attempt to take over the carmaker.

On Monday SAIC said it would consider taking legal action against Nanjing if it found that its Chinese rival had violated its intellectual property rights (IPR) in the deal to buy MG Rover.

Late on Sunday an SAIC spokesman said it was examining all its options in reaction to the way the MG Rover sale was carried out, including the possibility of legal action.

SAIC believed its bid was superior to Nanjing's.

&quot;The process has not been handled fairly or in the best interests of creditors and employees,&quot; a spokesman said.

&quot;Our offer gave a firm guarantee of substantial employment at Longbridge. It was at least equal and probably superior to Nanjing's. We believe the process has been discriminatory and unfair.&quot;

Mr Lomas said he was used to dealing with disappointed losers in bidding battles but there had been &quot;an entirely level playing field&quot;.

Meanwhile, union leaders are calling for urgent talks with Nanjing over how many UK jobs it will create.

Rover collapsed in April after a mooted tie-up with SAIC fell through, with the loss of more than 5,000 jobs.

Tony Woodley, T&amp;G general secretary, has called on the two Chinese firms to work together in building cars at Rover's Longbridge plant in Birmingham.

Mr Woodley had earlier said the &quot;prize&quot; of resuming mass car production in the West Midlands had been missed because of the sale of the company to Nanjing.

He said SAIC should have been given more time by PwC to complete its bid and a &quot;fantastic opportunity&quot; could have been missed.

But Mr Lomas said all three bidders had talked in &quot;similar terms&quot; about the level of employment.

&quot;Our judgement - on the jobs front, cash flow, and the prospects for suppliers and distributors - was that Nanjing offered the best way forward.&quot;

Mr Lomas said Nanjing intended to relocate the engine plant and some car-production plant to China but to &quot;retain some car production plant in the UK&quot;.

He added that Nanjing, China's oldest carmaker, also planned to develop an R&amp;D and technical facility in the UK.

Early indications are that Nanjing could eventually create up to 2,000 jobs in the UK.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4713901.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-27</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Markets bounce back after blast</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>In New York, the Dow Jones index rose to close up 0.31% after assurances from homeland security.

The UK's FTSE 100 index fell 1.36% to 5,158, having earlier slid 3%. Markets in France, Germany, Holland and Spain also bounced back to trade 1% lower.

&quot;Five years ago, the market would have been down much more. Now we see it as a buying opportunity,&quot; said one trader.

The pound dipped as investors bought Swiss franc and gold, while the price of crude oil also dropped in London before recovering from lows.

Despite the huge disruption caused by the explosions, dealers reported no major panic selling.

&quot;Frankly, things are remarkably resilient if you think the FTSE is actually only at levels where it was last week,&quot; said Will Armitage at IG Index.

&quot;There's not the panic we saw on 9/11 when we had people ringing up and saying 'get us out of everything'.&quot;

The BBC's business editor, Jeff Randall, reported that people in the City had stayed in their offices and remained calm.

&quot;Traders had been expecting something like this for some time because of the world situation,&quot; he said.

&quot;Clearly the emergency services acted very quickly. Very few people have tried to leave. It's business as usual. That's what they're hoping for.&quot;

In the US, where stocks initially slipped, confidence recovered after the homeland security secretary said there is no &quot;specific credible evidence&quot; of a similar attack in the US at this time.

European Central Bank president Jean-Claude Trichet said that he had been in talks with counterparts in the US and UK about the level of interest rates.

After speaking with Alan Greenspan and Mervyn King, Mr Trichet said that &quot;we are alert, we are vigilant&quot;. After their scheduled meetings on Thursday, the ECB left its borrowing costs unchanged 2%, while the Bank of England also kept its interest rate at 4.75%.

A number of City buildings were evacuated following the blasts. The London Clearing House was evacuated but transferred its operations to a disaster recovery site.

The London Metal Exchange cancelled dealing on its trading floor for the day, although it said electronic trading was continuing.

The explosions took place on the Underground network and on a double-decker bus in London.

London's police chief Sir Ian Blair said there had been &quot;many casualties&quot; and the latest figures showed that more than 30 people had died.

British Transport Police originally said some of the explosions had been caused by power surges.

But speaking from the G8 summit in Gleneagles, UK Prime Minister Tony Blair said London had been &quot;hit by a series of terrorist attacks&quot;.

The financial shockwaves were felt as far away as South Africa, where shares dropped nearly 3% before recovering to stand 0.6% lower.

&quot;This is all on the back on the London underground incidents, and particularly the bus blast,&quot; said one Johannesburg trader.

Insurers, transport and leisure stocks bore the brunt of the sell-off in London. Shares in British Airways fell 4.2%, while travel group First Choice fell 2.8% and cruise operator Carnival was down 2.2%.

&quot;Insurers are always first to get hit in a situation like this, in addition to the tourism industry,&quot; said Guiseppe Amato, analyst at Lang &amp; Schwarz.

Sterling fell to a 19-month low against the dollar and sank 1% to a 6-week low against the euro.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4659349.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-28</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | G8 summit battle lines are drawn</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>In Scotland, where the G8 leaders will meet from Wednesday, hundreds of demonstrators clashed with police as they called for fairer global trade.

Police said they had arrested about 30 protesters in Edinburgh.

African leaders, meanwhile, met in Libya to discuss how to capitalise on a high-profile poverty campaign that was boosted by pop concerts at the weekend.

Africa and global poverty are set to dominate the three-day meeting in Gleneagles, which will be chaired by British Prime Minister Tony Blair.

Doubling aid to poor nations and cutting debt are among the summit's declared goals.

Another key topic will be climate change, though US President George W Bush seemed to rule out any new climate control treaty.

Leaders also are likely to take in the impact of both high oil prices and exchange rates on economic stability.

In Edinburgh, police in riot gear and on horseback clashed with several hundred black-clad anarchists and anti-capitalist protesters.

Small skirmishes were still going on Monday evening, the BBC's home affairs correspondent Andy Tighe said.

&quot;The agenda in Edinburgh today simply seems to be to disrupt the life of the community,&quot; said Chief Superintendent Charles Michie of Lothian and Borders police.

&quot;It's certainly not clear that they are genuine protesters, that they have legitimate concerns.&quot;

Demonstrators have hit back, saying the police were heavy-handed and pushed and punched people.

Amid the violence there also were peaceful protests with demonstrators dressed as clowns and some even stripping naked.

&quot;We're anti-capitalists, we're for trade justice,&quot; said one woman in a clown costume calling herself General Lovely.

On the west coast of Scotland, about 700 protesters gathered outside the Faslane nuclear submarine base to highlight the fact that wealthy nations are still selling weapons to developing countries.

In Libya, leaders of the 53-member African Union, joined by UN Secretary General Kofi Annan, have been calling for real change, not hollow words.

&quot;Africa will lose hope&quot; if rich nations break their promises to the continent, said Rene N'Guettia Kouassi, the AU's economic director.

UK Chancellor Gordon Brown said on Sunday that G8 leaders had already made &quot;a great deal of progress&quot; on &quot;one or two of the major issues&quot; of poverty reduction.

He said that:
• European aid for poorer states was also set to double, with 13 European countries accepting a timetable to increase aid to 0.7% of their annual income.

 The US also has been taking steps to address the poverty issue. President Bush has proposed doubling US aid to Africa over the next five years, lifting it to $8.6bn by 2010, as long as African leaders tackled corruption. The UK has said it will promote ideas put forward by the Commission for Africa, established by Mr Blair. The commission recommended 100% debt cancellation for the poorest nations; the doubling of aid to Africa; the removal of barriers to trade with African nations, and improved governance. US resistance to curbs on greenhouse gas emissions means a breakthrough on climate change is unlikely. President Bush said the fact that the G8 meeting was being chaired by the UK, his close ally in Iraq, would not in itself bring concessions. &quot;I really don't view our relationship as one of quid pro quo,&quot; he told broadcaster ITV. He ruled out US backing for any Kyoto-style deal on climate change involving legally-binding reductions of carbon emissions, while defending US efforts to tackle climate change. &quot;The Kyoto treaty would have wrecked our economy if I can be blunt,&quot; he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4647639.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-29</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Shoppers drive brisk retail sales</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Retail sales rose 1.3% in June, the Office for National Statistics (ONS) said, raising the annual growth rate to 1.6%, up from 1.3% in May.

Retailers said the growth was driven by stores bringing summer sales forward.

On a three-monthly basis, sales were up 0.7% on the previous quarter, the highest such rate since November 2004.

However, compared with the same period a year ago, sales in the three months to June were up 1.6%, the lowest annual growth since February 1999.

In addition to early price cutting, a pick-up in sales of summer fashions and sportswear, triggered by the heatwave in late June, also played a part, the ONS said.

Clothing and food stores led retail sales growth on a three-monthly basis, up 3.5% and 2.5% respectively.

All retail sectors reported a rise in sales in June with the exception of household goods sales which were still flagging, a trend that could be blamed on a slowdown in the housing market.

Analysts said that the monthly figures should ease fears that the UK consumer spending has come to an abrupt halt, but warned that the apparent surge in monthly sales volumes should be treated with caution.

&quot;The housing market remains flat, wage inflation fell in May to 4.1%, the lowest since October 2004, and claimant count unemployment is rising slowly,&quot; said Dominic Walley, economist at the Centre for Economics and Business Research.

&quot;Today's data may be just a blip.&quot;

And the latest figures are unlikely to have a strong enough impact to influence the Bank of England's expected cut in interest rates next month.

&quot;It gives the Bank of England more food for thought at August's meeting but nevertheless our view is still that rates will come down by a quarter-point,&quot; said Philip Shaw, chief economist at Investec.

Other analysts believe that if consumer demand is recovering, however, the Bank's Monetary Policy Committee (MPC) may hold off from further rate cuts later in the year.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4702763.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-30</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Consumer slowdown hits UK growth</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Provisional data from the Office for National Statistics (ONS) showed GDP grew just 0.4% between April and June.

As a result year-on-year growth stood at 1.7% - its weakest rate since the first three months of 1993.

The slowdown is likely to raise fears that Chancellor Gordon Brown could miss his target of 3% - 3.5% growth in 2005.

Analyst Howard Archer of Global Insight said he expected growth to hit just 1.8% this year.

Mr Archer warned a weak manufacturing sector, subdued exports and business investment as well as the recent London bombing attacks would all take their toll.

He also warned that despite upbeat retail sales figures on Thursday, weakening confidence over job prospects could also unsettle the economy later this year.

&quot;Despite the surprisingly strong growth in retail sales in June, we remain dubious that consumer spending is going to see sustained marked improvement in the near term at least, given that a weakening labour market is now threatening to add to add to the already significant pressures facing the consumer,&quot; he added.

Adding to the gloom was news that the manufacturing sector moved into recession during the period. Manufacturing output contracted 0.7% in the second quarter - following a 0.9% fall in the previous three months.

Meanwhile service industry growth slowed to 0.6% during the quarter, from 0.7% between January and March.

The slowdown underlines a drop in confidence in the sector revealed by the British Chamber of Commerce earlier this month.

&quot;Today's release again highlights the deteriorating economic situation in the UK and should reinforce the view that the Bank of England will cut interest rates next month despite yesterday's stronger than expected retail sales figures,&quot; James Knightley at ING Financial Markets said.

Earlier this month the Bank voted narrowly to keep rates on hold in July despite a slowing housing market.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4706749.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-31</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Sanyo shake-up cuts 14,000 jobs</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sanyo said it would close or sell off 20% its factories in Japan, where more than a third of its workforce is based.

It aims to shave costs by 70bn yen ($626m; £355m) and has set aside a 90bn yen budget for restructuring costs.

Loss-making Sanyo plans to diversify from digital cameras and mobile phones into a new range of eco-friendly items.

Solar panels and rechargeable batteries are among the products it wants to focus on more.

Last week it reported that weak sales of digital cameras and mobile phones had pushed losses to 171.54bn yen ($1.55bn; £860m) in the year to March 2005.

The restructuring programme, and the job cuts, will be spread across three years.

Sanyo is not the only electronics firm to suffer from falling prices for mobile phones, digital cameras, and the computer chips that operate them.

Sony, Fujitsu, Toshiba and Hitachi have all suffered financial pain in their core electronics and chip-making businesses.

Sanyo's revamp will be guided by its newly appointed chief executive Tomoyo Nonaka, a former TV anchorwoman with little experience in the electronics industry, and its new president, Toshimasa Iue, a member of Sanyo's founding family.

The company aims to restore profit margins to 5% in its 2007 financial year, and cut its debts by 600bn yen.

Sanyo is pushing the eco-friendly theme to the fore in its restructuring, saying it wants &quot;symbiotic evolution&quot; of the company to &quot;restore a beautiful earth to the children of the future&quot;.

Its investors certainly appear to like the idea of the financial shake-up.

Sanyo's shares have risen every day since Friday, when news of the restructuring leaked out. The shares were up 1.3% after Tuesday's announcement.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4651111.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-32</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | British Gas to cut 2,000 UK jobs</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Up to 1,000 of these back office jobs will be outsourced to India, a British Gas spokesman told BBC News.

&quot;With new billing systems, we will not need anything like the number of back office data processors,&quot; the spokesman added.

The Unison union called the cuts &quot;completely unacceptable&quot; and warned that they may lead to strike action.

&quot;No-one should be fooled that these savings will go towards reducing customer's bills or improving services,&quot; the union said.

&quot;This is a devastating blow for the North West and West Midlands,&quot; the GMB union added.

Job losses are unlikely this year, the company said in a statement, adding that it was still in consultations with unions.

This will be the company's first move to outsource work to India, but British Gas - owned by Centrica - was keen to stress that its customer service division would not be affected.

The British Gas spokesman said: &quot;We have no plans at all to offshore any of our call centre work, we remain entirely committed to existing UK call centres.&quot;

In recent years, thousands of UK jobs, particularly call centre posts, have been shifted to low-cost, offshore centres such as India.

But in British Gas' case inquiries from its 18 million customers will continue to be handled from the UK.

In its statement, the energy company said a number of data processing and administrative jobs are likely to become redundant as it switches to a more streamlined customer billing system at a cost of £430m ($750m).

&quot;We have an agreement with British Gas that they must consult the unions on their plans before any final decisions are made,&quot; said Unison.

The union added that it would fight management all the way to stop the job cuts.

British Gas currently employs about 26,000 workers across the UK.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4686219.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-33</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Fresh calls for interest rate cut</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Optimism and output are improving but are still weak, the BDO Business Trends report said, and interest rates should start to &quot;come down soon&quot;.

BDO believes a cut is &quot;justified&quot;, but the report indicates that rates are likely to remain on hold until August.

The Bank of England's monetary policy committee (MPC) meets this week for its latest rate-setting meeting, amid speculation that rates have peaked.

The MPC raised rates five times between November 2003 and last August, with the base rate now at 4.75%. Its aim was to cool the UK housing market and try to slow consumer borrowing.

Last week's release of slower-than-expected first-quarter UK growth figures increased pressure for lower rates.

An abrupt slowdown in consumer spending meant the UK economy grew by just 0.4% in the first three months of the year, slower than previously thought.

With the release of the BDO report, the firm's partner Peter Hemington said: &quot;With inflation under control, we believe that a cut in interest rates is justified and that the MPC should act now.&quot;

The BDO output index - which predicts GDP movements a quarter ahead - slipped from 100 in May to 99.4 in June.

The outlook for the manufacturing sector - though improving - remained bleak, the report said. Despite increasing by 0.8 points to 97.7 points in June, it failed to recover the ground lost in May, it said.

Its optimism index - an indicator of GDP growth two quarters ahead - rose from 100.5 in May to 100.9 in June - an improvement but still below the levels recorded in the first quarter of 2005, the report said.

However, a separate report from the CBI and PricewaterhouseCoopers highlighted optimism in the financial services sector.

Growth was expected to resume in the next three months after a &quot;static&quot; quarter, the quarterly financial services report said.

It added that more firms are expecting profits, output prices and employment levels to rise.

Doug Godden, head of economic analysis of the CBI, said: &quot;The expectations of growth and increasing profits, although modest by past standards, are nevertheless encouraging, following a period of stagnation.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4646881.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-34</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Coca-Cola still world's top brand</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It estimated that Coca-Cola's brand was worth $67.5bn (£39bn; 55bn euros). US firms dominated the top 10 and made up more than half of those listed.

The biggest non-US company was Finnish mobile phone group Nokia at number six, valued at $26.5bn.

Only five UK names made it into the top 100, with banking group HSBC ranked the highest at 29 and worth $10.1bn.

The other UK firms to make a showing were news and information company Reuters at 74, oil giant BP at 75, Diageo-owned vodka label Smirnoff at 88, and petroleum firm Shell at 90.

All five of the UK brands managed to boost their value - HSBC increased the most with a 20% gain.

Interbrand's survey showed that little has changed in the top five since 2001.

Qualifying for the list is tough, with US supermarket giant Wal-Mart, payment card group Visa and confectionery firm Mars all missing out on a place.

That was because they failed to qualify in at least one of the following criteria:
• The brand value must be worth at least $2.1 billion.
• It must derive at least a third of its income outside of its domestic market.
• Its marketing and financial data must be publicly available.

Despite the status quo at the top of the tree, interesting global developments could be seen lower down the rankings

Evidence of Asia's increasing power as a carmaker saw Japan's Toyota increase its brand value by 10% to $24.8bn.

US rival Ford only managed to feature at 22 in the list, slipping two places from last year - in 2001 it was placed at number eight.

Elsewhere, several new companies managed to push into the top 100, including delivery group UPS, internet search engine Google, drugs firm Novartis, Spanish fashion chain Zara, vehicle maker Hyundai, luxury goods company Bulgari and electronics group LG.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4706275.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-35</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Bank vote points to UK rate cut</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Growth and consumer spending worries prompted four members of the Bank's rate-setting body to vote for a cut.

However, the monetary policy committee (MPC) minutes show that the other members argued it was still unclear how severe the consumer slowdown was.

The news pushed sterling to a four-month low against the euro.

The 5-4 vote in favour of keeping rates on hold followed a 7-2 split in June.

The four MPC members who voted for a rate cut were Kate Barker, Stephen Nickell, and David Walton, and the Bank of England's chief economist Charles Bean.

A number of industry bodies have called for an interest rate cut to help stimulate the UK economy.

Most analysts now think the MPC will shave rates by a quarter percentage point next month, bringing rates down to 4.5%.

&quot;With four members of the MPC voting for lower interest rates this month, a 25 basis point cut in August still seems highly probable,&quot; said Howard Archer at Global Insight.

Last month, the Office for National Statistics revised the UK's growth for the first three months of the year down to 0.4% from a previous estimate of 0.5%.

Figures due out later this week are expected to show that the slowdown is continuing into the second quarter.

&quot;Given the way the growth is slowing right now, the Bank of England must act quickly to stop consumer-led slowdown turning into a consumer-led recession,&quot; said David Brown at Bear Stearns.

&quot;We think the Bank's rate target should be 4% by mid-2006,&quot; he added.

Last year, the Bank raised interest rates, partly in order to cool the over-heated housing market.

The Bank will also produce its quarterly inflation forecast in August.

The last rate decision was announced on 7 July, the same day as bombers hit the London transport network.

However, the minutes show that although the MPC members were aware of the blasts they did not influence the committee's decision.

&quot;The decision on interest rates was reached solely on the economic merits, and no committee member argued that it should be altered to reflect unfolding events,&quot; the minutes said.

In contrast, in the United States the Federal Reserve reduced interest rates several times to keep the economy going after the 9/11 attacks on the World Trade Center.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4699251.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-36</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Vista opens on Microsoft Windows</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The software, until now known by its code name Longhorn, is due for release towards the end of 2006, half a decade after the launch of Windows XP.

To hit the deadline Microsoft has already taken out a number of features it had promised for the system.

A test version will be released by 3 August, the Seattle-based firm said.

Once Vista hits the market it will be the longest gap between releases of Windows systems.

On Thursday Microsoft announced fourth-quarter net profits of $3.7bn (£2.11bn) for the three months up to 30 June 2005.

Chief financial officer Chris Liddell said Microsoft would benefit greatly in the next financial year from new products.

Microsoft's flagship software already runs on about 90% of personal computers worldwide.

The firm has promised that Vista will take what for Microsoft is a completely new approach to computing, with security not an add-on but an integral part of the operating system.

But to meet the autumn 2006 deadline, Vista will be launched with some key components missing. Once they have been released - probably in the form of so-called service packs - the operating system will have a much-improved filing system, a new way to render graphics and much higher internet connectivity.

One of its most important features could be the promised seamless integration with a vast range of computing devices - from media centres to wireless music players.

According to Brad Goldberg, general manager of Windows product development at Microsoft, the renaming is in the interests of &quot;communicating the idea of clarity&quot;.

&quot;That lets users focus on the things they need to focus on,&quot; he added.

A video of the launch showed the Vista brand name alongside the slogan &quot;Clear, Confident, Connected; Bringing clarity to your world&quot;.

Microsoft has previously said that Vista will make malicious software that gets onto computers without the users' knowledge &quot;a thing of the past&quot;.

Executives at the firm have said Vista, which is likely to run on high-specification computers only, has been designed with security as &quot;part of the design, not a bolt-on&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4708177.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-07 00:00:00-37</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Business | Protesters in court ahead of G8</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Live8 organiser Bob Geldof has called violent protesters &quot;idiots&quot; and said Monday's clashes were a side issue.

The summit starts on Wednesday, with climate change, global trade, aid for Africa and debt relief on the agenda.

African leaders meeting in Libya have appealed to G8 leaders for full cancellation of Africa's debts.

A resolution, approved by African Union heads of state, calls on G8 leaders to &quot;fully embrace&quot; the recommendations of the UK-backed Commission for Africa - which include 100% debt relief - and &quot;to act expeditiously on them&quot;.
• British Prime Minister Tony Blair opened a London business event, saying &quot;the private sector is the engine for growth in Africa&quot;.
• South African Finance Minister Trevor Manuel questions G8 leaders' commitment to Africa as the continent does not pose a threat to their future or security.
• UK Chancellor Gordon Brown said the summit will be a chance to bring the whole world together - but acknowledged to the BBC that campaigners might be disappointed with the results.
• Breakthroughs have been reached on debt cancellation and aid ahead of the meeting, but progress has yet to be made on fair trade and climate change.
• President Bush has said the US will not agree to a Kyoto-style deal on climate change as it will damage the US economy.

Earlier on Tuesday police set out their plans to ensure a peaceful protest in the town of Auchterarder, near the summit venue, on Wednesday.

Tayside chief constable John Vine said months of preparation had taken place for the march, which will be licensed for only 5,000 people. He said the police would take &quot;robust action&quot; if they encounter people who are prepared to break the law. Earlier, there was a brief bomb scare in Auchterarder.

In Edinburgh, three anti-poverty activists chained themselves to the top of a crane to highlight their objections to Mr Brown's promotion of free-market solutions for Africa.

About 150 environmental activists are staging a peaceful protest at an oil refinery in Grangemouth, about 30 kilometres from Edinburgh.

On Monday, demonstrators fought running battles with 1,000 police in Edinburgh. Nearly 100 protesters were arrested and are now appearing in court, facing charges related to breach of the peace, alleged drugs and weapons offences and obstructing the police.

It is unclear who caused the violence and while the police have been accused of using &quot;heavy-handed&quot; tactics, they insist their response was &quot;proportionate&quot;.

For many, the meeting is a defining moment in current world politics, as an upswell of popular support is calling on the G8 leaders to make fundamental changes to the way rich countries deal with poorer nations.

&quot;We have got to bring the whole of the world together. What Britain says is one thing; what we can persuade the rest of the world to do together is what we will get, is the outcome from Gleneagles,&quot; Chancellor Gordon Brown said ahead of the meeting.

Some breakthroughs have been made, with G8 nations agreeing to double aid for poor countries and offer 100% debt relief.

Other key topics are fair trade and climate change and leaders are also likely to talk about the impact of high oil prices and exchange rates on economic stability.

President George W Bush downplayed expectations over trade deals and climate change in an interview with ITV on Monday.

Five big developing countries will take part in the talks on climate change - China, India, Brazil, Mexico and South Africa.

Mr Bush said a deal on dropping its farm subsidies - which African states say is vital for fair trade - would only happen if the EU ditched its Common Agricultural Policy (CAP).</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/business/4650783.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
