<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Ian Paterson: Redditch MP Rachel Maclean among patients operated on - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>England</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1364C/production/_110763497_paterson.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>An MP who was operated on by disgraced surgeon Ian Paterson says she has been left with &quot;doubts about her health&quot;.

Rachel Maclean, MP for Redditch, said she was now concerned about the procedure she underwent years ago.

On Tuesday, an independent inquiry into Paterson's malpractice recommended the recall of his 11,000 patients for their treatment to be assessed.

Health Secretary Matt Hancock has pledged to introduce improvements within a year.

In a tweet, Conservative Ms Maclean said: &quot;The extent of the malpractice he carried out is shocking, and the response from authorities was woefully lacking.&quot;

It comes after the inquiry found a culture of &quot;avoidance and denial&quot; which allowed Paterson to perform botched and unnecessary operations on hundreds of women.

The inquiry also revealed five health professionals have been referred to either the General Medical Council or Nursing and Midwifery Council and one case has been sent to police.

But police have since said the referral was in relation to Paterson himself.

&quot;A report of a sexual assault against Ian Paterson was referred to the force by West Midlands Police in May 2018,&quot; Staffordshire Police said.

&quot;The complainant was visited by detectives in June 2018 and after speaking to her she did not wish to pursue a complaint. There were no further safeguarding issues as Ian Paterson was in prison.&quot;

Paterson, of Altrincham in Greater Manchester, who grew up in County Down, Northern Ireland, is serving a 20-year jail term for 17 counts of wounding with intent.

He worked with cancer patients at NHS and private hospitals in the West Midlands over 14 years.

His unregulated &quot;cleavage-sparing&quot; mastectomies, in which breast tissue was left behind, meant the disease returned in many of his patients.

Others had surgery they did not need - some even finding out years later they did not have cancer.
• 'I am sad that so many women are dead'

Judy Conduit had 23 unnecessary operations and said she almost died due to complications during surgery.

&quot;He [Paterson] told me I would have to have a bilateral mastectomy,&quot; she said.

&quot;Because I had so many surgeries already I agreed, reluctantly in a way, because I didn't really want it done but I knew I couldn't keep putting my body through all these general anaesthetics.

&quot;Unfortunately I developed complications, I was told I had blood clot in the artery next to the heart.&quot;

The inquiry made 15 recommendations, and Mr Hancock has vowed to introduce improvements.

&quot;There's a whole series of recommendations but the central one is about information-sharing because the authorities that inspect different parts of the health system, the information wasn't being shared properly,&quot; he told BBC Breakfast on Wednesday.

&quot;That absolutely can be fixed, it will be fixed.&quot;

Jeremy Hunt MP, former Health Secretary and current chairman of the Commons Health Select Committee, has also pledged it will look at how to change NHS culture following the inquiry.

&quot;What we will look at is how we change the culture so that doctors who see something going wrong, maybe a mistake they themselves make, how we make it so that it is easy for them to talk about it openly so that mistake isn't repeated,&quot; he said.

Follow BBC West Midlands on Facebook, on Twitter, and sign up for local news updates direct to your phone</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-51384609</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Ad-targeting should be made transparent, data ethics body says - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EC7A/production/_110783506_mediaitem110778662.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Major online companies should be required to host publicly accessible archives of certain targeted adverts, a government-commissioned report says.

Political ads and those for housing, credit, jobs and age-restricted products should be included, it says.

It follows controversy over the targeting of political adverts during the 2019 general election.

Web users want &quot;meaningful control&quot; over how their data is used to target advertising, the report says.

The Centre for Data Ethics and Innovation (CDEI)'s report also suggests the forthcoming online harms regulator should have the power to:
• give independent experts secure access to online businesses to audit their use of people's data
• compel online companies to give access to independent researchers &quot;for research of significant potential importance to public policy&quot;
• make companies take steps to protect vulnerable people and be accountable for the effects of ad-targeting systems

This regulator should also establish a code of practice for businesses that buy or sell targeted ads online, the reports says.

&quot;We have reviewed the powers of the existing regulators and conclude that enforcement of existing legislation and self-regulation cannot be relied on to meet public expectations of greater accountability,&quot; it says.

The background to the ad-targeting debate

Online political advertising has been a hot topic in the UK since 2015, with Facebook ads also playing a key role in the 2016 EU referendum and 2017 general election.

After criticism over transparency, in 2018 Facebook unveiled an &quot;ad library&quot;, which means anyone can browse the ads that politicians, parties and political campaign groups use to target voters. Google has a similar tool.

This meant online ads were covered extensively during the 2019 general election campaign.

However, while there is more transparency than before, it has limits - some observers have called Facebook's tool &quot;inadequate&quot;.

The ad archive shows broad information like age and gender but does not reveal the far more sophisticated targeting tools political advertisers have at their disposal.

Today's report goes further, suggesting transparency for non-political advertisers, such as those marketing credit, or housing, or age-restricted products.

A spokeswoman for the UK's Internet Advertising Bureau said: &quot;We welcome the CDEI's recognition that online targeting is an important driver of economic value and a core element of many business models, as well as the fact that people do value the benefits of targeting.&quot;

She added that the bureau, for one, was committed to increasing ad industry transparency.

The report showed there was strong public demand for the government to take action over ad-targeting, said Jeni Tennison, chief executive of the Open Data Institute, a non-profit organisation based in the UK.

&quot;It's particularly welcome that they highlight the impact of 'opportunity' ads such as for jobs, credit and housing, alongside more familiar concerns about political advertising,&quot; she said.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-51384858</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC: TV licence fee decriminalisation consultation launches - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13F17/production/_110778618_new-comp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Culture Secretary Nicky Morgan has launched a public consultation on whether non-payment of the TV licence fee should remain a criminal offence.

Currently, anyone who watches or records live TV or uses iPlayer without a TV licence is guilty of a criminal offence and could go to prison.

Baroness Morgan said it was time to think about keeping the fee &quot;relevant&quot; in a &quot;changing media landscape&quot;.

The BBC said a 2015 review found the current system to be the fairest.

The consultation, which will last eight weeks with the government publishing its response this summer, will also look at the viability of an alternative enforcement scheme.

Decriminalisation would not mean non-payment would become voluntary. It could instead mean it would become a civil offence similar to non-payment of council tax or electricity bill.

In a speech on Wednesday, Baroness Morgan said many people thought it wrong that &quot;you can be imprisoned for not paying the TV licence and its enforcement punishes the vulnerable&quot;.

&quot;We are launching a public consultation to make sure we have a fair and proportionate approach to licence fee penalties and payments, that protects those most in need in society,&quot; she added.

The culture secretary also announced a new flexible payment scheme, called the Simple Payment Plan, to help those struggling to pay, including the over-75s.

It will allow people to spread the fee out into a number of manageable instalments.

&quot;This will help prepare the BBC and public service broadcasting for the future and make sure it continues to work for our society, our economy, and the public which funds it,&quot; said Baroness Morgan.

Last year, Treasury minister Rishi Sunak said the Prime Minister Boris Johnson had ordered a review of the sanction for non-payment of the £154.50 charge, which funds the BBC.

Confirmation of the consultation comes two days after it was announced the fee is to increase by £3, from £154.50 to £157.50, from 1 April 2020.

It also follows the controversy last year over the decision to scrap free licences for some over-75s, a decision which saw a number of celebrities joining the call for the decision to be overturned.

From June, only over-75s who are claiming pension credit will be eligible to a free TV licence.

Baroness Morgan said her plans should not be seen as &quot;any kind of attack on the BBC&quot;.

The broadcaster is an &quot;incredibly important organisation in the UK and around the world&quot;, she said.

But it was the government's &quot;duty&quot; to look into the issue of funding.

In a statement, the BBC said &quot;a detailed government-commissioned review (in 2015) found the current system to be the fairest and most effective&quot;.

&quot;It did not recommend change - in part because the current system is effective in ensuring payment with very few people ever going to prison.

&quot;If there are changes, they must be fair to law abiding licence fee payers and delivered in a way that doesn't fundamentally undermine the BBC's ability to deliver the services they love.&quot;

In 2018, more than 121,000 people were convicted and sentenced for evasion and issued with an average fine of £176.

There were around 26 million TV licences being used in the UK last year, generating £3.69bn in income for the BBC.

If decriminalisation of the TV licence fee were to go through, it would have a considerable impact on BBC funding.

The DCMS (Department for Digital, Culture, Media and Sport) said the government would take into account the impact on the corporation in the context of the overall licence fee settlement, for which negotiations begin later this year.

A previous government review in 2015 looked into whether a fine for non-payment could be issued under civil law instead, similar to the fees for breaking parking, bus lane and congestion charge rules.

The review also examined whether unpaid TV licence fees should be considered a civil debt in the same way as unpaid utility bills or council tax.

However, it recommended against changing the criminal sanctions regime, saying decriminalisation could bring with it an increased risk of evasion.

A consultation is a process used by public bodies that invites the public to provide their views and feedback on a particular proposal.

The members of the public who are asked are individuals and organisations that would be affected directly or indirectly by a project or a decision.

They include those who have the ability to influence the decision, both positively and negatively. They can also be people who simply have an interest in the project.

There is no maximum or minimum number of respondents; It's open to anyone over 16.

Consultations last for a proportionate amount of time and consist of a limited number of clear, concise questions.

Follow us on Facebook or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51373372</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Ministers back bill aiming to cut school uniform costs - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1EE4/production/_110780970_8018c7ad-eb5f-45e5-8df9-2868081eebad.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The government intends to back a bill from a Labour MP designed to cut the cost of school uniforms in England.

The legislation, drafted by Weaver Vale MP Mike Amesbury, would aim to strengthen existing guidance encouraging schools to keep down costs.

It could also force schools to keep compulsory branded items, like blazers, to a minimum.

An inquiry last year heard items like blazers embroidered with school logos can cost up to three times more.

The bill, whose details have yet to be finalised, will be debated in March and stands a much better chance of approval with government support.

The draft law has already received the backing of Tory MPs Huw Merriman and Kevin Hollinrake, as well as Lib Dem education spokesperson Layla Moran.
• How can you cut the cost of school uniform?
• Children 'asking Santa for new school uniform'

It understood that Mr Amesbury's bill would aim to make government uniform guidance statutory, meaning schools would be legally required to follow it.

The government does not force English schools to have a uniform, but they are strongly encouraged to do so by the Department for Education.

Current guidance from 2013 encourages schools to opt for clothing available in supermarkets, and generally avoid having uniform supplied by a single company.

The move would bring the English school system into line with Wales, where new statutory guidance came into force in September last year.

Despite a pledge to do so first being made in 2015 under the premiership of David Cameron, the government has yet to introduce compulsory guidance in England.

Mr Amesbury told the Daily Mirror, which first reported the story, that the government's decision to back his bill was &quot;absolutely brilliant&quot;.

He added: &quot;It is a victory, though we're not quite there yet. We need to keep pushing to get it through Parliament.&quot;

Schools Minister Nick Gibb said: &quot;School uniforms should always be affordable and should not leave pupils or their families feeling that they cannot apply to a particular school.

&quot;That is why we will be supporting the progress of this bill through Parliament, in order to make our guidance on the cost considerations for school uniform statutory at the earliest opportunity.&quot;

Last year, a Children's Society survey of 1,000 parents saw nearly one in six families blame uniform costs for having to cut back on food and other basic essentials.

A joint inquiry by Parliament's education and work and pensions committees last September also heard evidence that schools could cuts costs for parents by choosing to have non-branded uniforms.

In Scotland and Northern Ireland, low-income families can claim support towards the cost of school uniforms. A similar scheme, based on whether pupils are eligible for free school meals, also exists in Wales.

Mr Amesbury will get the chance to introduce his bill after he topped a ballot allowing MPs to suggest ideas for new laws, known as private members' bills.

While only a small number of these bills have ever become law, some have effected significant change, including the abolition of the death penalty in 1965 and change to the abortion laws in 1967.

More recently, a 2019 private member's bill extended the availability of civil partnerships to opposite-sex couples.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51385214</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Is the government avoiding the media and does it even matter? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Newsbeat</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/9265/production/_110777473_borisjohnson976.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The media and the government have always had a frosty - or far too cosy - relationship depending on who you want to believe.

However, have things taken a turn for the worst?

This week, there was a mass walkout by political journalists after senior reporters say they weren't allowed into a meeting at Number 10.

This is denied by those working for the Prime Minister.

They argue this is the most open and transparent government in decades.

The government is being accused of avoiding tough questions and selecting who it gives background information to.

A minister told Parliament: &quot;We reserve the right to brief journalists which we choose whenever we wish to, and that is not something abnormal.&quot;

That's what some critics think.

The government hasn't been interviewed on some national BBC news programmes after major news events, like the recent terror attack in London.

It has always been normal for journalists to get invited in groups for background chats about stories by government departments - which are called briefings.

Journalists walked out of one at Downing Street this week after it's claimed they were put on two sides of the room - with one group asked to leave.

Instead of letting this happen, all the reporters walked out in solidarity.

They have collectively decided not to give long interviews about what happened, but one has told Radio 1 Newsbeat that &quot;our actions speak for themselves and it's for the government to explain its actions&quot;.

The Prime Minister's team deny this is how it happened.

Newsbeat contacted Downing Street for a comment and was told to watch MPs sitting in the House of Commons when a minister would give the government's version of events.

The Cabinet Office minister Chloe Smith told MPs that no journalists are barred from official briefings hosted by the Prime Minister's spokesman.

&quot;It is entirely standard practice for the government to host additional technical specialist briefings, as was the case,&quot; she said.

Is this really new?

Governments of all parties have always given information to parts of the media more likely to give them better coverage.

However, journalists who have reported on politics for years feel we have seen a big shift recently.

We've seen lots of stories of how Boris Johnson's close team are preventing ministers from appearing on BBC 2's Newsnight and the BBC Radio 4's Today programme.

Presenters on ITV's Good Morning Britain also say they are being ignored and senior ministers have refused to appear on Channel 4 since before the election.

Some say this a deliberate tactic to avoid scrutiny, something President Trump is accused of in America.

Donald Trump gave Boris Johnson his backing as Prime Minister at the last election and some journalists, who were at the briefing, say that this event feels like something that could happen under the American leader.

Is the government just changing how it gets its message across?

There has been a big shift in how any government gets its message to voters and a lot of that is about politicians of all parties using social media to directly connect with its audience.

Labour had success with this at the 2017 election. A strong social media strategy is central to modern politics.

Boris Johnson faces questions once a week from MPs at Prime Minister's Questions - or PMQs for short - in the House of Commons.

It's an event loved by Westminster geeks but not that popular with the rest of the country.

Boris Johnson and his team have started an event to follow it called People's PMQs where he answers questions sent in on Facebook.

The government say this is about answering questions that matter to voters, but critics say the questions are selected by his team and can be quite easy to answer.

Not just the government?

We mentioned that Labour under Jeremy Corbyn has been seen as good at using social media but it has also been criticised for how it deals with the big media organisations.

Some political observers say the party's leader has been reluctant to appear on mainstream media outlets.

So when Labour's spokesperson on the media, said the government was behaving like President Trump critics of Jeremy Corbyn were quick to highlight what they see as inconsistency.

We asked Labour for an official comment and so far they've not given us one.

Does any of this matter?

Some will say this is all a bit inward-looking and it's just big, established media organisations getting angry and feeling left out.

There could be truth in that but others say this is a big issue because how the country works relies on the government being held to account and being scrutinised.

Currently the main opposition party Labour are in a weak position. They lost the recent election and are a long way from power.

Critics of the government will be hoping the media is able to do a lot of the questioning instead and anything that pushes the press out prevents this.

The Prime Minister's team insist it is open to scrutiny.

Listen to Newsbeat live at 12:45 and 17:45 weekdays - or listen back here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-51371760</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>What is a 'Canada-style' trade deal? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/C68B/production/_103572805_gettyimages-481599449.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Prime Minister Boris Johnson has said when it comes to trade with the EU after Brexit: &quot;We want a comprehensive free trade agreement, similar to Canada's&quot;.

The EU's agreement with Canada is called the Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement, or Ceta for short.

The EU began negotiating with Canada in 2009, and Ceta provisionally came into force in 2017, although it has not yet been signed off by all the EU member states.

What does Ceta do?

We've heard a lot about wanting a &quot;zero-tariff, zero-quota&quot; deal between the UK and the EU. Ceta does not do that.

Ceta gets rid of most, but not all, tariffs (that's taxes on imports) on goods traded between the EU and Canada. Tariffs remain on poultry, meat and eggs.

It also increases quotas (that's the amount of a product that can be exported without extra charges) but does not get rid of them altogether. For example, quotas on EU cheese exports to Canada increase from 18,500 tonnes to 31,972 tonnes a year.

It does little for the trade in services and in particular almost nothing for the trade in financial services, which is very important for the UK economy.

It also does not remove border checks, so there is still a possibility that goods have to be examined at ports to make sure they meet regulatory requirements, and their paperwork is in order.

What does it say about standards?

Ceta protects EU &quot;geographical indications&quot;, meaning for example that you can only make Parma ham in Italy and camembert cheese in France, and Canada can't import something that calls itself camembert from any other country.

They have also agreed to open up government contracts to each other, so Canadian companies could bid to build French railways, for example.

There is also co-operation between the two countries on standards, so a piece of equipment made in an EU country can go through all its safety and quality checks there, without needing to have them repeated in Canada - and vice versa.

Ceta also allows professional qualifications to be recognised both in Canada and the EU, making it easier, for example, for architects or accountants to work in both places.

And it aligns Canadian rules in some areas of copyright and patents with those of the EU.

Is the UK's trade with the EU like Canada's?

Countries that are closer to each other tend to trade more, especially in goods, and this is the case with the UK and the EU.

The UK exported £291bn of goods and services to other EU countries in 2018, which was 45% of all UK exports.

It imported £357bn of goods and services from the EU, which was 53% of all UK imports.

On the other hand, Canada exported 46.2bn Canadian dollars (£26.7bn) of goods and services to the EU in 2017, which was 7.9% of its exports.

It imported 63.6bn Canadian dollars of goods and services to the EU, which was 10.5% of its imports.

What is an Australian-style deal?

The prime minister also mentioned having an arrangement with the EU similar to Australia's.

The EU does not have a free trade deal with Australia. They are in negotiations for one, but they currently operate mainly on World Trade Organisation (WTO) rules.
• Reality Check: What does a 'WTO Brexit' mean?

There was an EU-Australia Partnership Framework agreed in 2008, which reduces barriers to trade, but was not a free trade agreement.

So, trading on a similar basis to Australia would be largely the same as trading under WTO rules. In other words, it's another way of saying the UK would leave with no trade deal in place.

What claims do you want BBC Reality Check to investigate? Get in touch</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-45633592</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Beckbury residents vent pothole anger - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Shropshire</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/118C6/production/_110387817_p07zgr20.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Residents in a Shropshire village say potholes are so common they amount to &quot;tax&quot; on rural drivers.

Businessman Ian Field, who lives in Beckbury, says he has spent £6,000 on vehicle repairs in the last two years.

He has written to the government with a dossier of photographs showing a dozen large potholes.

He says they are strewn across all major routes into the village and many of them are deep, posing a danger to vehicles.

&quot;I’d go as far to say that this is akin to an additional tax for residents or a small business operating in a rural area – you simply wouldn’t have this in a major town,&quot; he said.

A Shropshire Council spokesman said the local authority was &quot;working hard to identify and tackle potholes and other defects&quot;.

He said the number of potholes typically increase by about a fifth at this time of year and the recent weather had &quot;amplified the problem&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-shropshire-50988823</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Ex-PM David Cameron's bodyguard 'left gun in aeroplane toilet' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/932D/production/_110777673_gettyimages-98809871-1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A bodyguard for David Cameron is being investigated after he reportedly left his gun in a toilet on a transatlantic jet.

A &quot;terrified passenger&quot; found the gun and gave it to staff on a British Airways flight from New York to London on Monday, according to the Daily Mail.

As a former prime minister, Mr Cameron is entitled to continued security provided by the Metropolitan Police.

The Met said the officer involved has been removed from operational duties.

Mr Cameron's team said it could not comment on security matters.

The gun, believed to be a 9mm Glock 17 pistol, is said to have been left by a close-protection officer from the Met's Specialist Protection unit, who took off his holster while in the toilet.

Mr Cameron's passport - and that of the officer - were found with the weapon, according to the Sun.

A Metropolitan Police spokesperson said: &quot;We are aware of the incident on a flight into the UK on 3 February and the officer involved has since been removed from operational duties.

&quot;We are taking this matter extremely seriously and an internal investigation is taking place.&quot;

British Airways said it had adhered to Civil Aviation Authority rules allowing UK police &quot;to carry firearms on board in specific, controlled circumstances&quot;.

&quot;Our crew dealt with the issue quickly before departure and the flight continued as normal,&quot; the airline added in a statement.

Mr Cameron was the UK prime minister for six years until July 2016, when he stepped down following the result of the EU referendum.

Were you on the flight? If you have any information email haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk.

Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist. You can also contact us in the following ways:
• Please read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51383104</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit trade: What do the UK and EU want? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Reality Check</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F650/production/_110765036_mediaitem110757008.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Trade negotiations tend not to begin with two sides in agreement - otherwise there would be nothing to negotiate.

So it's not surprising to see the UK and EU set out rather different positions before talks begin in earnest.

In fact, the two sides agree they want a free-trade agreement, with no tariffs (border taxes on goods) or quotas (limits on the amount of goods). They are also keen to include as much of the service sector as possible.

But that's the easy bit and this is likely to become a bruising experience for all involved.

Terms and conditions always apply and the EU says it has two main conditions.

First and foremost, the EU wants the UK to sign up to strict rules on fair and open competition so if British companies are given tariff-free access to the EU market, they cannot undercut their rivals.

These are known as level-playing-field guarantees and they have been a constant theme in the EU's negotiating position for nearly two years.

Most importantly, its draft negotiating mandate says a future partnership must &quot;ensure the application&quot; in the UK of EU state-aid rules on subsidies for business.
• What are the EU rules about state aid?

The UK would also be required to stay in line with the EU's rules on environmental policy and workers' rights.

But Boris Johnson has publicly ruled out any such commitment and said he would create an independent system that would uphold the UK's international obligations and not undermine European standards.

&quot;There is no need for a free-trade agreement to involve accepting EU rules on competition policy, subsidies, social protection, the environment or anything similar,&quot; Mr Johnson said in his speech in London.

He also pointed out the UK spent far less money on state aid than Germany or France.

The EU says without a level playing field, it cannot offer any kind of basic free-trade agreement along the lines of the one it has negotiated with Canada.

The UK's response? A Canada-style deal would be its preference. But if that is not available, it will settle for what Australia has with the EU. In other words, no free-trade deal at all.

Either way, says Mr Johnson, a new relationship will begin on 1 January.

His critics accuse him of recklessness but the prime minister says he has &quot;no doubt that in either case the UK will prosper&quot;.

The EU's second condition is a free-trade deal must include an agreement on fisheries - because UK fishing waters are among the best in Europe.

The UK says it's happy to consider a deal on fisheries but it must be based on the notion &quot;British fishing grounds are first and foremost for British boats&quot;.

Its draft mandate says a future deal should &quot;aim to avoid economic dislocation for [European] Union fishermen that have traditionally fished in United Kingdom waters&quot;.

That's a lot of access and the EU seems prepared to link it to the UK's ability to sell its fish in the EU market.

Fishing is a tiny part of the UK economy - well below 1% - but it has always been an emotional issue. And coastal communities depend on it on both sides of the Channel.

When it comes to product standards and other regulations, the EU is more flexible.

&quot;We're not asking for alignment, I know it's a red rag to the UK, so I won't really mention it,&quot; the EU's chief negotiator, Michel Barnier said.

&quot;What I am looking for is consistency.&quot;

The UK says it must have the right to diverge from EU rules when it chooses to do so but it won't do that just for the sake of doing things differently.

The more it diverges, the more checks there will be and the more barriers to trade will emerge.

That's true for both goods and services. UK financial services companies, for example, will lose the passporting rights that gave them unfettered access to the rest of the EU.

Instead, the UK is hoping for a system of what's known as enhanced equivalence, which would give companies plenty of notice if the rules were about to change.

But talk in government circles of frictionless trade has gone. The UK now accepts that will not be possible outside the EU single market and customs union.

The EU's negotiating mandate recalls a statement made back in 2018, in which the other 27 member states agreed Gibraltar would not be included in any post-Brexit agreement between the UK and the EU.

It doesn't rule out a separate deal between the UK and the EU that does cover Gibraltar, but that in turn would have to be agreed by the UK and Spain.

This is another hot-button issue pretty much guaranteed to generate tabloid headlines.

Mr Johnson said he would be negotiating for what he called the whole UK family, including Gibraltar.

Gaining independence from the rulings of the European Court of Justice (ECJ) was an important part of the argument for Brexit.

Now, the EU is demanding the ECJ be given a legal role in policing any free trade agreement.

It wants the court to be able to issue binding rulings on disputes between the two sides, when they &quot;raise a question of interpretation of [European] Union law&quot;.

But the government's written statement says a future agreement cannot include &quot;any jurisdiction for the [ECJ] over the UK's laws&quot;.

The ECJ does play a limited role in the withdrawal agreement, both in the special arrangements for Northern Ireland and in resolving any disputes over citizens' rights for the next few years.

But a future trade deal is a different matter.

Devising a dispute-resolution system that satisfies both sides will not be easy.

It's not just about trade, it's about internal security cooperation and access to databases too.

&quot;Where a partnership is based on concepts derived from European law,&quot; Michel Barnier said, &quot;obviously the ECJ should be able to continue to play its role in full.&quot;

The EU's draft mandate also says there should be &quot;automatic termination&quot; of law enforcement and judicial cooperation in criminal matters if the UK were to opt out of the European Convention on Human Rights.

The bottom line for the UK? The ECJ and the EU's legal order &quot;must not constrain the autonomy of the UK's legal system in any way&quot;.

So there are some big divides to be bridged.

Both sides say they would settle for a free-trade agreement but they have to work out how to get there and how to implement it.

It is also worth recalling the government's own internal analysis from November 2018 suggested a Canada-style deal would leave the economy 4.9% smaller after 15 years than if the UK had stayed in the EU.

There is a long way to go in a short period of time.

What claims do you want BBC Reality Check to investigate? Get in touch</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/51357589</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: Five things the UK needs to resolve after leaving the EU - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12D06/production/_110726077_hi059601273.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The UK might have left the EU but many questions remain unanswered.

Here are just some of the hurdles facing the UK after Brexit.

This legal departure from the EU means the UK can finally start formal trade negotiations - both with the EU and countries around the world, like the US.

The government is determined not to extend the post-Brexit transition period - to discuss the future relationship with the EU - beyond the end of 2020. This means the timetable for getting an agreement with the EU is extremely tight.

Formal talks are expected to begin in March, once the remaining 27 EU countries have agreed on instructions for their negotiators.

Getting any agreement finally signed off and put into practice will take a couple of months towards the end of the year. So, realistically, that only leaves time for a fairly basic free trade deal to emerge, with plenty of issues still up for discussion once the transition period is over.

The government talks about getting a &quot;zero tariff, zero quota&quot; deal on goods, with no border taxes and no limits on exports and imports.

But there are a host of issues to be dealt with if the aim is to keep trade flowing as smoothly as possible, and that is before we mention the services sector.

From financial and business services to the food and drinks industry, this accounts for more than 80% of UK jobs.

It is of course in the interest of both sides to get a deal done, but it remains a massive task. Expect disputes about fisheries, fair competition, the role of the European Court of Justice and more.

It is possible that no deal will be done in time, which will generate a fresh crisis in UK/EU relations as 2020 draws to a close.

If the challenge to get a trade deal within 11 months is not hard enough, the UK must also agree a treaty to paper over legal cracks in the way countries work together on security.

Policing and security experts in the UK and the EU agree that things will become harder after Brexit.

For instance, the UK no longer has a place on the team that manages Europol, the agency that co-ordinates major investigations into Europe-wide organised crime.

This means the UK's priorities - such as concerns about smuggling people or arms across the English Channel - may, slowly, fall down the pecking order.

British police officers can, for now, still use EU systems to check criminal records of foreign nationals, or alerts on wanted people from around the continent.

But access to that information could either end or become harder, because many member states have their own specific laws governing data-sharing beyond the EU.

The government is trying to think ahead.

It has, for instance, pledged to pass laws to ensure the same fast service the UK has enjoyed from the European Arrest Warrant - which allows suspects to be sent to another country for trial - if a deal cannot be struck. Everyone, on both sides, wants that.

The question is whether it is legally doable - and if so, can it be done by January 2021?

3. Making sure the food keeps coming

From farming and fishing to manufacturing and retail, the UK's food and drink sector adds £460bn to the UK economy every year, employing more than four million people.

It represents a fifth of UK manufacturing, by far the biggest chunk of the sector.

So there is some nervousness about what will happen to the complicated way that food and drink makes its way to consumers after the end of the transition period.

A third of people in the industry are from outside the UK, with many from Eastern Europe. What happens if the number of such workers is restricted because of the introduction of a minimum salary being imposed for migrants?

When it comes to trade, there is the prospect products may have to be opened and checked at borders which could add expense and cut the shelf life of fresh food.

And the Food and Drink Federation, a body representing food manufacturers, says the most complex challenge is around trying to get a trade deal with Europe that satisfies what are called &quot;rules of origin&quot;.

UK manufacturers use a mixture of domestic and internationally-produced ingredients, which would not be allowed under rules included in recent EU trade deals.
• Brexit: What will change after Friday, 31 January?
• What is the transition period?

4. Building a new role in the world

The government has a huge task ahead to establish the UK's place in the world after leaving the EU.

Ministers have to work out what the government's slogan &quot;Global Britain&quot; actually means.

The traditional role of providing a transatlantic bridge between Europe and the US will be put to one side.

Instead, ministers must develop a more independent foreign policy. That could mean less automatic support from the UK for the US, as it focuses more on domestic issues and less on its relations with other countries.

It will mean a new relationship with European allies, not through EU structures, but through smaller existing groups. These include the E3, an informal group made up of the UK, Germany and France, which has worked together on issues like relations with Iran.

The biggest foreign policy challenge will be how to navigate a path between an increasingly stronger China and a defensive US, without the protective membership of the EU.

To that end, Boris Johnson has ordered what he calls an 'integrated review&quot; of the UK's security, defence and foreign policy which is expected to report later this year.

5. Showing that all the arguing was worth it

The protesters who turn up on Westminster's College Green are a lonely bunch these days.

Even the most ardent fan of the EU would have to admit that the heat has gone out of the passionate, and often vicious, political fight of the last few years.

The challenge for Mr Johnson is now to show to the public that all the disruption, all the arguing, was actually worth it.

That will not be easy. Brexiteers are keen to make the most of the powers that will come back to the UK from Brussels as soon as possible.

But now we are in the departure lounge - the transition period where the status quo will stay pretty much the same.

Even if you popped champagne on Friday night to celebrate the UK leaving the EU, when you woke up on Saturday morning not much would have actually felt very different.

Can the enthusiasm and excitement on that side be managed?

And even though the stay or leave debate is now at an end, some voters still believe we are setting off on a path of folly. And there are big fears that a trade deal No 10 wants simply is not doable by the end of the year.

Mr Johnson would be perfectly happy if after Friday, the B-word was never heard again, but he needs to show to the public on both sides it was worth it.

He has already found a place in the history books, but the chapter is not yet complete.

What questions do you have about Brexit and how it will affect you in the future?

In some cases your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy.

Use this form to ask your question:</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51267987</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Minister defends dealings with media amid No 10 briefing row - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/17E0F/production/_110770879_mediaitem110770878.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The government has insisted it is &quot;committed to being open&quot; with the press amid a row over the official system for briefing journalists.

A group of leading reporters decided not to attend a Downing Street briefing on Monday when other journalists - who hadn't been invited - were turned away.

Labour said this threatened democracy, while the SNP said it was &quot;sinister&quot;.

But Cabinet Office minister Chloe Smith said it was &quot;routine&quot; for select titles to be given &quot;additional&quot; briefings.

Responding to an urgent question in the Commons, she said there was a clear distinction between the twice-daily briefings by the PM's official spokesman open to all accredited members of the parliamentary lobby and extra briefings given by special advisers, political appointees handpicked by ministers.

Journalists from the BBC and ITV were among those to walk out of a briefing due to be given by the PM's chief Brexit adviser David Frost after No 10 advisers reportedly said publications such as the Mirror, the i and Huffington Post were not welcome.

Raising the issue in Parliament, shadow culture secretary Tracy Brabin suggested it was &quot;not an isolated incident&quot; and there was a trend for the government to decide who had access to information.

She asked who had drawn up the criteria for inviting journalists, whether civil servants had been present at the time, and whether those responsible had violated the code of conduct for special advisers.

&quot;The ability of the lobby to have access to briefings without favour is a longstanding tradition and one which is vital to the health of a functioning democracy,&quot; she said.

&quot;Yesterday certain publications were barred from a briefing on future trade talks.

&quot;The code of conduct for special advisers' states that special advisers must not ask civil servants to do anything which is inconsistent with their obligations under the civil service code.

&quot;If that decision was made by a special adviser, are they in violation of the code for special adviser and the civil service code.&quot;

In response, Ms Smith said there was nothing unusual in what had gone on and the government strongly supported a free and open press.

&quot;No journalists are barred from official media briefings hosted by the prime minister's official spokesman. It is entirely standard practice for the government to host additional specialist or technical briefings as was the case yesterday.&quot;

She said the planned session with Mr Frost was designed to &quot;increase understanding&quot; of the UK's stance in the next stage of Brexit talks.

She urged Labour &quot;to look in the mirror&quot;, suggesting the opposition wanted to introduce a Soviet-style licensing of the newspaper industry.

Conservative MP Damian Green said while &quot;better arrangements&quot; were needed for such lobby briefings he detected &quot;the faint air of fake outrage&quot;, while his colleague Sir Peter Bottomley said under the last Labour government certain editors had been banned from briefings.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51375580</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Tracy Brabin: MP hits back at Twitter 'keyboard warriors' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Leeds &amp; West Yorkshire</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13E0A/production/_110781418_mediaitem110780797.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A Labour MP who faced criticism on social media for her off-the-shoulder dress said people needed to &quot;listen to what we say not what we wear&quot;.

Tracy Brabin, the shadow culture secretary, said she had been &quot;startled by the vitriolic nature&quot; of some comments.

She told BBC Breakfast it was her responsibility to &quot;call it out&quot;.

&quot;Women around the world... are being demeaned everyday because of what they wear,&quot; she said.

The Batley and Spen MP had been raising a point of order in the House of Commons on Monday about journalists being asked to leave a Downing Street press briefing on the next stage of Brexit talks, when her shoulder appeared.

She said her slightly off-the-shoulder dress had slipped a little as she leant forward to speak.

Ms Brabin said she had been to a music event earlier in the day and was not expecting to be called to the dispatch box.

&quot;But, the context of this is frankly pretty absurd,&quot; she said.

&quot;I am here talking about a shoulder when it is an important time for the media,&quot; she told viewers to BBC Breakfast.

Ms Brabin, who played Tricia Armstrong in Coronation Street for three years in the 1990s, said she tried not to take the comments too seriously, especially as they were likely from &quot;keyboard warriors sat in their mum's back bedroom eating Pot Noodles and having a pop at people they don't know anything about&quot;.

However, she said: &quot;This is everyday sexism where women are continually judged for what they wear, how they look and not what they say.&quot;

&quot;Why is that? It's a way to silence us,&quot; she told BBC Radio Leeds.

She said there were examples of things that happened in the Commons that were worthy of discussion, including Jacob Rees Mogg &quot;asleep on the front benches with his legs up&quot;.

&quot;That is disrespectful,&quot; she added.

She said she was also thankful for the many positive comments she had received.

Former Strictly star Stacey Dooley was among those supporting Ms Brabin on Twitter.

Dr Hannah Barham-Brown, from the Women's Equality Party, said the focus should be on Ms Brabin calling out the prime minister for &quot;trying to block out the media&quot;.

&quot;That's what we need to be concentrating on, [and] frankly, I don't really care what she was wearing.&quot;

&quot;We've seen female MPs leaving because they have suffered harassment and death threats - they have suffered incredible abuse, and that's the context these comments are being made in,&quot; she added.

Those responsible should &quot;find something better to do with their time&quot;.

More news from across Yorkshire

Follow BBC Yorkshire on Facebook, Twitter and Instagram. Send your story ideas to yorkslincs.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-leeds-51386155</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Former Black Rod says ex-speaker unfit for Lords - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/A331/production/_110777714_p082bgyj.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>David Leakey says John Bercow's &quot;explosive behaviour&quot; makes him unfit for the House of Lords.

He says he spoke out against Mr Bercow on behalf of colleagues, and is doing so again now because Mr Bercow has been nominated for a peerage by Jeremy Corbyn.

John Bercow says David Leakey's allegations are &quot;total and utter rubbish&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51386674</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Mobile operators clash on 'notspots' costs - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/6E6A/production/_110766282_mobilemast2.gif</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>An agreement to share network equipment in order to improve phone coverage in rural areas has hit a stumbling block over costs.

Rival operators are unhappy at the price BT-owned EE is asking them to pay to share its equipment.

O2's chief said the fees being sought by its rival &quot;may undermine the viability of the project&quot;.

BT said the costs were based on the value of the masts and other investments it had made over the years.

A key meeting is due to take place on Wednesday to hammer out the details, the BBC has learned.

The £1bn Shared Rural Network (SRN) agreement was announced in October and aims to get the mobile operators working together to extend the geographic coverage of 4G to 95% of the UK by 2025.

Many rural areas have only patchy service, and some have none at all.

The government is contributing £500m towards the costs, with the other half of the bill being footed by the mobile operators.

The Conservatives want the deal done as soon as possible - ideally in time for the Budget on 11 March - and has threatened to intervene if the operators cannot reach agreement.

The BBC understands that if the mobile operators do fail to agree, the government will consider other ways of achieving its 95% coverage goal.

It will, said one industry insider, make delays to improving rural mobile coverage inevitable.

The Financial Times reported that BT wants to include 320 yet-to-be-built masts in the agreement and to charge 250% more than the existing commercial rate for rivals to access them.

One insider told the BBC it would be cheaper for operators to build their own masts.

BT has not revealed the commercial agreements it is hoping to sign with other operators but it is believed it will offer rivals a cheaper rate for masts on its emergency service network, which was partially funded by the government. There are several hundreds of these in rural locations.

Previously BT's chief executive Marc Allera has said the costs of sharing equipment needed to reflect the fact that EE has 4G coverage in &quot;significantly more places than any other network&quot;.

&quot;Finding an analogy here is tricky because this is complex, but I sometimes think of it like Sainsbury's building a new superstore in a rural area and being made to give away shelf space to Tesco, Lidl and Asda,&quot; he said in a blog.

Of the meeting this week BT told the BBC that it was &quot;ready to go&quot;.

&quot;We've proposed a far simpler and more pragmatic way for SRN to succeed, plus a way to reduce any taxpayer money by also including new sites that are being built by us in the future.

&quot;It's now down to the industry to finalise the deal to get it done.&quot;

All the operators said they were committed to getting an agreement.

In a blog, O2 chief executive Mark Evans said: &quot;The SRN requires all four mobile network operators to deliver additional investment and an unprecedented level of infrastructure-sharing; it requires the government to deliver planning policy reform and a modest level of funding.&quot;

Dave Dyson, chief executive of Three, said: &quot;Enhancing mobile connectivity for the 9.3 million living in the UK's countryside requires a joined-up approach between the industry and government.

&quot;A Shared Rural Network is the best way to do that, bringing mobile coverage to more places in the UK and giving people in rural areas a similar choice to those living in towns and cities.&quot;

And Vodafone told the BBC: &quot;We remain committed to the Shared Rural Network scheme and are working towards reaching a final agreement.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-51372017</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Caption mix-ups 'show lack of respect' for black MPs - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13CE7/production/_110772118_gettyimages-1195207481.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The media keeps mistaking black women MPs for each other because it does not respect them as much as their white counterparts, a Labour MP has said.

The Evening Standard used a picture of Bell Ribeiro-Addy in a story about fellow Labour MP Marsha de Cordova.

The story was about BBC Parliament captioning Ms de Cordova as Labour deputy leadership hopeful Dawn Butler.

Ms Ribeiro-Addy told BBC News: &quot;We are not given the same respect as our white counterparts and that's not right.&quot;

The MP, who has represented Streatham, in south London, since last year's general election, said she accepted that &quot;everybody makes mistakes,&quot; but added: &quot;It happens all the time with us.
• Election 2019: Six charts on Britain's most diverse Parliament

&quot;It is hard enough for us to get elected here but when we do get here we are not treated as individuals.&quot;

She said she used to get mistaken for Dawn Butler when she worked as the chief of staff to shadow home secretary Diane Abbott, &quot;because I must be the other one&quot;.

The BBC Parliament channel's mistake came during a Commons debate on the Agriculture Bill on Monday.

Tweeting a photo of the incorrect caption, Ms Butler said: &quot;I love my sister @MarshadeCordova but we are two different people.

&quot;Marsha is amazing and deserves to be called by her own name. Diversity in the workplace matters and it also helps to avoid making simple mistakes like this.&quot;

Ms de Cordova, who is Labour's shadow minister for disabled people, said the BBC's mistake was &quot;not OK at all&quot;.

Part of the problem was the lack of diversity in most newsrooms, Ms Ribeiro-Addy said, and the tendency of journalists to treat Black, Asian and minority ethnic (BAME) MPs as part of a homogenous group.

&quot;Why do so many MPs get to be individuals and we just get to be part of a group that gets confused with each other?&quot;

The BBC &quot;sincerely apologised&quot; to Ms Butler and Ms de Cordova for the mistake.

A spokesperson said: &quot;Sometimes we incorrectly identify MPs at the moment when they stand to speak. This error was immediately corrected on screen.&quot;

The Standard blamed picture agency Getty Images, which also supplies images to the BBC, for incorrectly captioning an image of Ms Ribeiro-Addy as Ms de Cordova.

Getty Images &quot;sincerely apologised&quot; for incorrectly captioning the image of Ms Ribeiro-Addy and issued an &quot;unreserved apology&quot; to the two MPs &quot;for any offence this may have caused&quot;.

A Getty spokeswoman said: &quot;As soon as we were made aware of the error by the Evening Standard, we corrected the caption information on our website and in a notice sent to customers.

&quot;Getty Images holds itself to a high standard of editorial integrity and has robust measures in place to ensure our content ingestion process reflects these standards.

&quot;Although these errors are relatively rare, we, like all news agencies, regret when these measures fail to capture inaccuracies.&quot;

Tottenham MP David Lammy, one of the longest-serving black MPs, tweeted: &quot;This cannot go on. Black people are not all the same. We need more diversity in our newsrooms.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51374401</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Tory MP Daniel Kawczynski faces suspension calls for speaking at 'far-right' conference - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10A33/production/_110774186_mediaitem110770885.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Conservative MP Daniel Kawczynski is facing calls to be suspended for sharing a platform with some of Europe's leading far-right politicians.

Labour said he should lose the whip for speaking at the same event as Hungary's nationalist PM Viktor Orban and Italy's populist leader Matteo Salvini.

The party said it was &quot;disgraceful&quot; that he was associating with &quot;anti-Semites, Islamophobes and homophobes&quot;.

But the Polish-born MP said the reaction to his trip was &quot;hysterical&quot;.

He said Mr Orban, who has been prime minister of Hungary since 2010 and Mr Salvini, a former deputy prime minister of Italy, &quot;represent serious ideas and concerns, some of which are shared by many citizens of the UK&quot;.

Both politicians are strongly Eurosceptic and hostile towards immigration, particularly from Muslim countries. Mr Orban has won three successive elections while Mr Salvini remains an influential figure in Italian politics despite his League Party quitting government last year.

Mr Kawczynski was among 22 speakers at the National Conservatism event, currently taking place in Rome.

Other participants include Marion Marechal, the niece of Front National president Marine Le Pen, and representatives of Poland's Law and Justice Party and Spain's Vox Party.

The MP for Shrewsbury and Atcham defended his participation, saying he would be making the case for nation states against European federalism.

&quot;Orban and Salvini are not to everyone's tastes, of course,&quot; he said in article for The Spectator.

&quot;And I don't agree with each and every one of their policies. But I am not Hungarian or Italian and both leaders have been elected on huge popular mandates in their countries. They represent serious ideas and concerns, some of which are shared by people in Britain.&quot;

Mr Kawczynski, whose attendance was first reported by the Guardian, added: &quot;Perhaps those criticising the event should take a more inquisitive approach rather than simply attacking its existence and maligning elected politicians from other countries who are due to speak.

&quot;If so, they might discover why the vast majority of Europeans feel more loyalty to their own countries than the abstract idea of a federal European super-state.&quot;

Labour's Andrew Gwynne said the prime minister must clarify whether the MP was given permission by Tory whips to go to the event.

&quot;It's disgraceful that just one week after Holocaust Memorial Day Daniel Kawczynski has shared a platform with anti-Semites, Islamophobes and homophobes,&quot; he said.

&quot;He should be immediately suspended from the Conservative Party.&quot;

Leading Jewish groups, such as the Board of British Deputies and the Jewish Labour Movement, has also called on him to be disciplined.

&quot;If the Conservative Party fails to discipline Mr Kawczynski, it runs the serious risk of the public assuming that they share his views on association with such people,&quot; the Board of Deputies said in a statement.

Crossbench peer, and former Labour MP, Lord Mann, who is the government's anti-Semitism tsar, said the MP's actions were &quot;unwise&quot; and Mr Kawczynski should be laying down an &quot;unequivocal challenge&quot; to the views represented at the conference.

And fellow Conservative MP Andrew Percy said his colleague's behaviour was &quot;wholly inappropriate&quot;, telling the BBC that he had advised him against attending the event. He said he would be raising the matter with party officials.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51379211</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>'Scandal' if Bercow got peerage - ex-Parliament official - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p082bmg8.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It &quot;would be a scandal that Parliament would struggle to live down&quot; if ex-Commons Speaker John Bercow got a peerage, an ex-Parliament official has said.

David Leakey who served in Parliament as Black Rod accused Mr Bercow of &quot;intolerable behaviour&quot;.

But Mr Bercow dismissed his claims as &quot;total and utter rubbish&quot;.

Meanwhile Diane Abbott has been criticised for saying it was &quot;unlikely&quot; ex-soldier Mr Leakey was bullied.

The shadow home secretary tweeted that Mr Leakey had &quot;served in Germany, Northern Ireland and Bosnia. But claims he was bullied (i.e. intimidated and coerced) by John Bercow. Unlikely.&quot;

She has since deleted her tweet.

Responding to her comment, David Penman - general secretary of the FDA Union which represents civil servant - said: &quot;What a ridiculous comment from an experienced MP, demonstrating blind political partisanship and a complete failure to understand how power is abused in the workplace.&quot;

And Labour MP Dan Jarvis - who served as an army officer - said &quot;having a distinguished service record does not preclude you from being a victim of workplace bullying&quot;.

&quot;All of us in the Labour/trade union movement have a responsibility to create a climate where people can voice their concerns and not have their experiences dismissed out of hand.&quot;

Mr Bercow has confirmed that he had been proposed for a peerage by outgoing Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn.

Getting a peerage would enable Mr Bercow to sit in the House of Lords - but he has suggested Downing Street is seeking to block his appointment to the upper chamber.

Speaking to the BBC's Today programme, Mr Leakey argued Mr Bercow should not be given a peerage on the grounds of his behaviour as Speaker.

&quot;He would fly into a rage, the red mist would descend, and he would be jumping up and down and balling out, and shouting insults,&quot; he said.

&quot;He called me an anti-Semite once after being rather rude and insulting about my background, education and military career.&quot;

In 2018 Mr Leakey accused the ex-Speaker of creating a climate of &quot;fear and intimidation&quot; and more recently has said he would submit a dossier to the Parliamentary Commissioner for Standards detailing his complaints.

Lord Lisvane, who served as Clerk of the House between 2011 and 2014, has confirmed to the BBC he has submitted a formal complaint, which was understood to be centred around bullying.

Hitting back at the accusations, Mr Bercow told Sky News the claims were &quot;total and utter rubbish&quot;.

He said Mr Leakey was &quot;not employed by me, he wasn't an employee of the House of Commons&quot;.

&quot;He is in absolutely no position whatsoever to comment on my relations with my parliamentary colleagues, of which he is completely and utterly ignorant.

&quot;What we have got here is somebody who left the House, who is thrashing about, desperate to remain relevant, popping up at every turn, trying to make himself seem very important, very centre-stage, very at the heart of things in the way that I went about my work.&quot;

In response, Mr Leakey said Mr Bercow &quot;either doesn't understand or can't remember how the role of Black Rod operates&quot; adding that &quot;30% of my work was within or for the House of Commons&quot;.

Mr Bercow stepped down as Speaker in October after 10 years in the role and was replaced by Sir Lindsay Hoyle.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51383884</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>David Cameron turns down offer to host COP26 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F2BA/production/_110783126_p082bt1t.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former prime minister David Cameron has said a government minister should host the climate conference.

He said that someone outside of government at the conference would have the effect of having two people do the same job.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51389204</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>Sir David Attenborough: 'Now is the moment' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science &amp; Environment</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13FE8/production/_110769818_p0827z1y.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The broadcaster and naturalist Sir David Attenborough has said &quot;now is the moment&quot; for action on climate change.

His comments came at a launch event for the COP26 climate summit which is to be held in Glasgow later this year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-51368482</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>O'Neill: PM 'doesn't really get' climate change - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/105E6/production/_110764076_p0827dnp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former minister Claire O'Neill has told the BBC the prime minister &quot;doesn't really get&quot; climate change.

&quot;The prime minister has made incredibly warm statements about this over the years,&quot; she said, adding that Boris Johnson admitted to her that &quot;he doesn't really understand it&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51371250</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-01 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>What is climate change? A really simple guide - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science &amp; Environment</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p080hmjm.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Scientists say global warming could have a catastrophic effect on the planet.

Human activities have increased carbon-dioxide emissions, driving up temperatures. Extreme weather and melting polar ice are among the possible effects.

The Earth's average temperature is about 15C but has been much higher and lower in the past.

There are natural fluctuations in the climate but scientists say temperatures are now rising faster than at many other times.

This is linked to the greenhouse effect, which describes how the Earth's atmosphere traps some of the Sun's energy.

Solar energy radiating back to space from the Earth's surface is absorbed by greenhouse gases and re-emitted in all directions.

This heats both the lower atmosphere and the surface of the planet. Without this effect, the Earth would be about 30C colder and hostile to life.

Scientists believe we are adding to the natural greenhouse effect, with gases released from industry and agriculture trapping more energy and increasing the temperature.

This is known as climate change or global warming.

The greenhouse gas with the greatest impact on warming is water vapour. But it remains in the atmosphere for only a few days.

Carbon dioxide (CO2), however, persists for much longer. It would take hundreds of years for a return to pre-industrial levels and only so much can be soaked up by natural reservoirs such as the oceans.

Most man-made emissions of CO2 come from burning fossil fuels. When carbon-absorbing forests are cut down and left to rot, or burned, that stored carbon is released, contributing to global warming.
• Climate change: Where we are in seven charts
• Five things the 1.5C report taught us

Since the industrial revolution began in about 1750, CO2 levels have risen more than 30%. The concentration of CO2 in the atmosphere is higher than at any time in at least 800,000 years.

Other greenhouse gases such as methane and nitrous oxide are also released through human activities but they are less abundant than carbon dioxide.

What is the evidence for warming?

The world is about one degree Celsius warmer than before widespread industrialisation, the World Meteorological Organization (WMO) says.

The 20 warmest years on record all occurred in the past 22 years, with 2015-18 making up the top four.

Across the globe, the average sea level increased by 3.6mm per year between 2005 and 2015.

Most of this change was because water increases in volume as it heats up.

However, melting ice is now thought to be the main reason for rising sea levels. Most glaciers in temperate regions of the world are retreating.

And satellite records show a dramatic decline in Arctic sea-ice since 1979. The Greenland Ice Sheet has experienced record melting in recent years.

Satellite data also shows the West Antarctic Ice Sheet is losing mass. A recent study indicated East Antarctica may also have started to lose mass.

The effects of a changing climate can also be seen in vegetation and land animals. These include earlier flowering and fruiting times for plants and changes in the territories of animals.

How much will temperatures rise in future?

The change in the global surface temperature between 1850 and the end of the 21st Century is likely to exceed 1.5C, most simulations suggest.

The WMO says that if the current warming trend continues, temperatures could rise 3-5C by the end of this century.

Temperature rises of 2C had long been regarded as the gateway to dangerous warming. More recently, scientists and policymakers have argued that limiting temperature rises to 1.5C is safer.

An Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) report in 2018 suggested that keeping to the 1.5C target would require &quot;rapid, far-reaching and unprecedented changes in all aspects of society&quot;.

The UN is leading a political effort to stabilise greenhouse-gas emissions. China emits more CO2 than any other country. It is followed by the US and the European Union member states, although emissions per person are much greater there.

But even if we now cut greenhouse-gas emissions dramatically, scientists say the effects will continue. Large bodies of water and ice can take hundreds of years to respond to changes in temperature. And it takes CO2 decades to be removed from the atmosphere.

How will climate change affect us?

There is uncertainty about how great the impact of a changing climate will be.

It could cause freshwater shortages, dramatically alter our ability to produce food, and increase the number of deaths from floods, storms and heatwaves. This is because climate change is expected to increase the frequency of extreme weather events - though linking any single event to global warming is complicated.

As the world warms, more water evaporates, leading to more moisture in the air. This means many areas will experience more intense rainfall - and in some places snowfall. But the risk of drought in inland areas during hot summers will increase. More flooding is expected from storms and rising sea levels. But there are likely to be very strong regional variations in these patterns.
• Vietnam's children and the fear of climate change
• Would you give up beef to help the planet?

Poorer countries, which are least equipped to deal with rapid change, could suffer the most.

Plant and animal extinctions are predicted as habitats change faster than species can adapt. And the World Health Organization (WHO) has warned that the health of millions could be threatened by increases in malaria, water-borne disease and malnutrition.

As more CO2 is released into the atmosphere, uptake of the gas by the oceans increases, causing the water to become more acidic. This could pose major problems for coral reefs.

Global warming will cause further changes that are likely to create further heating. This includes the release of large quantities of methane as permafrost - frozen soil found mainly at high latitudes - melts.

Responding to climate change will be one of the biggest challenges we face this century.
• How much warmer is your city?
• What is your diet's carbon footprint?
• Where we are in seven charts

What questions do you have about changes in our climate?

In some cases your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy.

Use this form to ask your question:</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-24021772</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
