<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Academics 'bullied' over ID cards</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The LSE report sparked a row after it claimed the cost of ID cards could reach three times the government's estimate of £6bn over 10 years.

Home Secretary Charles Clarke said the study was &quot;technically incompetent&quot;.

In a letter to the Times, LSE's Howard Davies said the government had adopted a &quot;bullying&quot; approach to his team.

Mr Clarke said the findings of the study, published earlier this week were &quot;fabricated&quot; and did discredit to the LSE's reputation.

In a Commons debate on the subject, he also accused one of the academics who helped to prepare the report of being &quot;partisan&quot; because he was already set against the cards.

The report was the result of six months' work, involved the contributions of more than 60 people and had been overseen by a dozen professors from LSE, Mr Davies said in his letter.

Mr Clarke had branded the study as &quot;mad&quot; before he had even seen it, Mr Davies added.

&quot;The report is not, of course, a corporate LSE document,&quot; he said.

&quot;It does, however, represent the honest and considered views of a team of experts.

&quot;It is unfortunate that, on an issue where the civil liberties concerns are so serious, the government should have chosen to adopt a bullying approach to critics whose prime motivation was to devise a scheme which might work at an acceptable cost.&quot;

The LSE report also claimed plans for ID cards were too risky and lacked the trust of the public.

And the government's proposed system was so complex it could itself become a target of terrorists, the academics warned.

Responding to the letter, a Home Office spokesman said Mr Clarke stood by his comments last week.

&quot;Details of the LSE report have been leaked to the media over a period of two weeks,&quot; he said.

&quot;The Home Office was repeatedly asked to comment on those details and it therefore seemed appropriate to ask for a copy.

&quot;Despite numerous requests, the LSE refused to provide one.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4643467.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Ministers reject Iraq terror link</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Chatham House and Economic and Social Research Council paper says the Iraq war has boosted al-Qaeda.

UK involvement in operations against Osama Bin Laden's network has also raised the attack risk, it adds.

But Foreign Secretary Jack Straw and Defence Secretary John Reid said there had also been attacks before the war.

The report, which comes less than two weeks after the London Tube and bus bombings, said the UK's anti-terrorist efforts had been focused on Northern Ireland.

It said the Iraq invasion, in which the UK had been &quot;pillion&quot; passenger, had damaged the counter-terrorism campaign.

Instead it had boosted support, training and fund-raising for al-Qaeda.

Prime Minister Tony Blair has consistently insisted linking the London attacks to British involvement in Iraq or Afghanistan was wrong.

But the report said: &quot;There is no doubt that the situation over Iraq has imposed particular difficulties for the UK, and for the wider coalition against terrorism.&quot;

It also stated Britain's &quot;international intelligence, police and judicial co-operation&quot; in operations against al-Qaeda had put it at risk.

Mr Blair's official spokesman said: &quot;Iraq was under the thumb of Saddam Hussein who killed hundreds of thousands of Iraqis. Afghanistan was under the thumb of the Taleban.

&quot;Is the report saying it was a mistake to allow Afghanistan and Iraq to exercise their democratic rights?

&quot;These are the hard questions the report does not address.&quot;

And Mr Straw told reporters ahead of a meeting of European Foreign Ministers in Brussels that &quot;the time for excuses for terrorism are over&quot;.

&quot;The terrorists have struck across the world, in countries allied with the United States, backing the war in Iraq, and in countries which had nothing whatever to do with the war in Iraq.

&quot;They struck in Kenya, in Tanzania, in Indonesia, in the Yemen, they struck this weekend in Turkey which was not supporting our action in Iraq.

&quot;It is the terrorists who will seek any excuse whatsoever for their action and it is the responsibility of people in the civilised world to stand up to that terrorism and not provide them with any excuse whatsoever.&quot;

Mr Reid argued that &quot;the terrorists will kill anyone who stands in the way of their own perverse ideology&quot;.

He told BBC Radio 4's Today programme: &quot;I do not accept, when the report says we have made ourselves more of a target because of involvement in Afghanistan and Iraq and our efforts to tackle al-Qaeda, that there is another alternative which is easier and better.

&quot;And the idea that somehow by running away from the school bully, then the bully will not come after you is a thesis that is known to be completely untrue by every kid in the playground and it is also refuted by every piece of historical evidence that we have.

&quot;Terrorism goes way back to the late 1980s and the early 1990s.&quot;

The report said UK security services only recognised Islamic terrorists as a major threat in the late 1990s.

Before then, groups had been able to operate in London with &quot;relative impunity&quot;.

&quot;In an open society, such as the UK, it is notoriously difficult to prevent no-warning co-ordinated suicide attacks, the characteristic modus operandi of al-Qaeda ,&quot; the report states.

&quot;The attacks on the transport system in London on 7 July represent precisely the nature of the threat from international terrorism that the UK authorities have been concerned about since 9/11.&quot;

It warned terrorists could try to get hold of nuclear, chemical or biological weapons.

&quot;Their track record shows that they would have no compunction about using this type of weapon to cause large numbers of civilian deaths,&quot; the report added.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4692861.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Hodge urges job help for Muslims</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Her call comes after a study suggested there was an 11% gap between Muslims and other graduates in finding work.

She will tell a seminar in London it is vital to discover why young Muslims with promising starts fail to get jobs.

According to independent research discrimination is one problem - but strong family ties and an unwillingness to relocate could also play a part.

Mrs Hodge will say that the situation is worrying and completely unacceptable and it is vital to discover why so many young Muslims have a promising start by getting into higher education, but then fail to find a job .

She will call on educators, trainers and employers to work together to improve matters. She will also say that it is important to find ways of encouraging young Muslims to feel integrated into British society, in the light of the terrorist attacks in London on 7 July.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4695153.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Public split over new hate laws</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Public opinion is divided over controversial plans to ban incitement to religious hatred, according to an ICM poll for the BBC News website. The poll, taken in the days following the London bombings, found 51% in favour of such a move but 44% against. The proposed new law is meant to protect people of all faiths from abuse but critics say it curbs free speech. The poll of 1,005 people found those who were religious almost as likely to be against it as those who were not. The survey, which was commissioned as part of a BBC News website series on faith in the UK, found strong support for laws that respect and are influenced by religious values. Take a look at the poll findings in more detail 

 There was a more divided picture when it came to the broadcast of material that might cause religious offence. It also explored attitudes to homosexuals and women holding religious office, following the recent controversy over gay clergy and the Church of England backing the ordination of women bishops.
• 61% of people believe Britain's laws should respect and be influenced by religious values
• 78% approve of women being given high religious office
• 48% approve of people living in a homosexual relationship holding high religious office, with 39% against
• 1% more Christians were in favour of gay clergy than against
• Women are 8% more likely than men to approve of gay people holding high religious office Approval for laws respecting religious values was, not surprisingly, high among those who belonged to religions, but even among those with no religion 3% more were in favour than against. The fact that the poll was carried out in the days following the London bombings makes the results all the more intriguing 

 Some 49% of all respondents said broadcasters &quot;should not avoid language or story lines which might cause any of the main religious groups to take offence&quot;, with 45% saying they should. Among religious people, 45% thought broadcasters should avoid causing offence, but a greater number, 49% thought they should not. Among non-religious people, 45% thought offence should be avoided, and 51% felt it should not. There was a gender divide on this issue too, with 42% of men saying broadcasters should avoid causing religious offence, compared to 48% of women. The Racial and Religious Hatred Bill currently going through parliament would create a new offence of incitement to religious hatred and would apply to comments made in public or in the media, as well as through written material. The aim is to protect people from incitement to hatred against them because of their faith. But ministers insist it will not ban people - including artists and performers - from offending, criticising or ridiculing faiths. In the BBC's poll, 51% supported legislation &quot;aimed at preventing abuse or inciting hatred of people because of their religious faith&quot;. But 44% thought &quot;stopping people from criticising those with other religious beliefs is an unjustified limit on free speech&quot;. Among people belonging to religions, a category which included Christians, Muslims, Hindus, Sikhs, Jews and other faith groups, 43% were opposed to a ban, compared to 44% among people with &quot;no religion&quot;. In January an ICM poll for The Guardian newspaper suggested stronger public support for incitement to religious hatred laws. The poll found 57% agreeing a ban was &quot;needed to stop those who want to stir up hatred against people of particular religious faiths&quot;. It found 36% said the new law was &quot;wrong because people should be allowed to express their opinions freely, however hateful&quot;.
• The BBC/ICM poll is based on interviews with 1,005 people between 8 and 11 July this year. Send us your comments on the postform below One cannot simply legislate away problems. This Bill can only be weak or open to 'common sense' interpretation. If the former, it's a waste of time; if the latter, I offer up the old adage that 'common sense isn't always common practice'.

Stephanie Boyd, Edinburgh, Scotland The state apparatus has no place in any religious discussion. Free speech all the way - even if I dislike what you have to say - there is a difference between expressing an opinion and acting upon it - and we already have laws that handle the latter well enough.

Andy, Glasgow, UK What next? An offence of criticising political beliefs? This is an affront to free speech and will prevent any rational examination of all religious beliefs no matter how deserving of, or in need of such examination they might prove to be. No religion, or any other philosophy, or belief system, should be afforded such protection. It is dangerous to do so. 

Phil Andrews, Essex, UK Outlawing religious hatred, yes. Stopping an lapsed-to-ex Catholic like the late Dave Allen from poking fun at his own faith - definitely not.

Ken, London, UK I think that the question that &quot;laws should respect and be influenced by UK religious values&quot; has been wrongly formulated. I, as well as most other people that are not religious, agree with many values that are shared by the main religions (like caring for other, especially weaker people). So, these values should be respected by our laws. But I am horrified by religions dictating non-humane laws that constrict freedom or equality between sexes.

Steven Kolenberg, Luxembourg Many &quot;holy books&quot; contain lots of passages that are easy to construe as inciting religious hatred, and should therefore be among the first things to be banned under the proposed legislation, if it's interpreted honestly and without prejudice. Religious people should be careful not to saw off the tolerant, secular humanist branch they're sitting on.

Bill, London, UK The incitement to religious hatred Bill is much too vague and open to abuse 

 It is dangerous to have any Bill going through parliament backed by promises that of course it wouldn't be misused: it is only the courts that can decide how to interpret the law. I am very worried that as it stands the incitement to religious hatred Bill is much too vague and open to abuse.

Jamie, Luton, Beds Surely any reasoned enlightened study of religion is likely to lead to its ridicule? This will most likely cause offence and the legislation will be enacted. The Government's position in therefore unsustainable. Thinkcrime is here, 21 years overdue.

Nick, Hertford If people of faith could provide some evidence that God exists, then I would be in favour of the law. Until then it's just a law protecting the superstitious.

Paul, UK It is good enough for us to let sleeping dogs lie. Frankly speaking, where does one draw the line? And most especially, it may be very subjective in application.

Namdi Onwuachu, Milton Keynes, UK Your poll on hate laws is deeply flawed. The two options offered are not really alternatives to each other and certainly not mutually exclusive, yet you did not offer a 'both' option. I'm sure many people (like me) back new laws to prevent the incitement of religious hatred, but also think that criticism of religion should be permitted and is possible within the scope of such a law.

Rob, Leeds, UK Hopefully these statistics will not influence the powers that be as you cannot count on the opinion of anyone who declares to be of no religious belief, since the proposed bill is not likely to affect them.

Tracie Yebovi, London It is the rest of us non-believers (the majority in the UK) that need protection from the religious. Salman Rushdie is still on the run, the play that offended some Sikhs is still closed, and blasphemy is still on the statute books to protect the Church of England.

Dan, London The law would need to make it very clear what constitutes an offence if this legislation goes through. The core of this country, and indeed the 'Free West', is Freedom of Speech, and let us not forget the millions who died defending it in the First and Second World Wars.

Rich, UK I think it would be unfortunate if people's freedom of expression was restricted by whatever a particular group deems as offensive. Overtly inciting hatred on any particular group (religious or otherwise) is obviously wrong and I think that it is right to have laws to control this. However I think the boundaries of acceptability should be clearly defined by the government and not by the standards of the most intolerant group.

Robert, Cambridge, UK I am not in favour of any law that restricts the right to express freedom of speech and most vehemently against religious organisations dictating government policies and peoples thinking.

John Marshall, Preston, England As a Muslim, I feel that these laws are unnecessary. Yes, I may appreciate the security it will offer my religion, but I strongly believe that as Muslims, we cannot stifle open discussion and debate - we have been around for more than 1400 years, and we are more than capable of defending our religion, as are other religions.

Ziyad Abubacker, Luton Faith, like anything else, should be subject to criticism. There should be a clear distinction in the law between 'faith' and the practitioners of the faith. There should also be a discussion on where faith ends and culture begins. Culture can corrupt faith and faith can corrupt culture. There are just too many nuances for the law to tackle at the moment.

Suzannna, Cork, Ireland As this law would not affect comedians, artists and other performers, it is highly probable that programmes such as 'Jerry Springer The Opera' would be free from sanction as it's 'comedy'. Whereas people like myself who preach the gospel would be hauled off to jail for 'incitment to religious hatred'. As a Christian I already feel marginalised in this country, this bill will only add to that feeling.

Chris, Cornwall I can agree with a Bill &quot;preventing abuse or inciting hatred of people because of their religious faith&quot;. However, I also agree that &quot;stopping people from criticising those with other religious beliefs is an unjustified limit on free speech&quot;. The poll tells us nothing. There is a world of difference between incitement to hatred and legitimate criticism. For instance, I could criticise a minister or priest for giving boring sermons. But I would not thereby seek to encourage anyone to hate either that minister/priest or the religion he represents. 

Rob Mackenzie, Edinburgh I think this the section of this bill that covers religious hatred is the most sinister law the present Government have yet tried to bring in. No matter what it actually says, it is the kind of bill that opens the way for self-censorship, and so in the long run I suspect will lead to a general presumption among news media against broadcasting or publishing anything that might question religious faiths. This at a time when the need for such questioning is more relevant than it has ever been. 

Peter Baber, West Yorkshire I think the incitement to religious hatred laws will close down free speech and thoughtful debate about the truth claims of religions/secularism. We need to engage with these ideas, not disengage, which is what these laws will inadvertantly achieve.

Mark Birri, New Barnet, England I think it is important that any proposed laws on banning incitement to hatred based on religion should be fashioned so as to still allow free speech and the exchange of ideas. It should be possible to criticize a religion or philosophy without criticising individuals who practise it. If I am born into a religion, it is unfair that people criticize me personally for my beliefs; however it is important to be able to challenge the basis/structure/legal aspects of the religion itself. 

John Gibbons, Galway Ireland The touchstone should be the fact of incitement to hatred. That needs to be curbed - by making speakers accountable for the results of their words. But it is virtually impossible to stop some people being offended. Freedom of speech is too precious to be sacrificed to the sensibilities others.

Nick Woods, Great Yarmouth UK I do not understand why religions should be singled out as ideologies that need 'special protection'. 

Ralf, Brighton UK It is very dangerous to bring in a law which has the capacity to prevent people from criticising religion. Whatever the intention of the law, that side effect is inevitable. The introduction of this law will see more fanatics hide behind the shield of their faith, and the integration that needs to take place simply won't happen.

David Mercier, Kent, UK I believe that Free Speech trumps a hate speech law. Then again an over the top hate statement should have some kind of remedy. They use to say that the marketplace will sort it out and, of course, if it isn't broadcast it becomes a tree falling in an empty forest. Still, I side with free speech.

John Joyce, Southampton , NY , USA The BBC may edit your comments and not all emails will be published. Your comments may be published on any BBC media worldwide. 

 

 



 

 Rights and religion

 Information and contacts to help you make a difference

 

 

 

 What the world thinks of God</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4675545.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Deportation laws to be reviewed</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Home Secretary Charles Clarke has ordered an immediate review of his powers to exclude and deport people.

The moves come as Downing Street said talks aimed at getting consensus on new terror laws in the wake of the London bombs would begin on Monday.

Opposition MPs say they want agreement but warn against &quot;knee-jerk reactions&quot;.

Mr Clarke on Thursday briefed the Cabinet about the review of his exclusion and deportation powers.

He wants to ensure that any non-British citizen suspected of inciting terrorism is deported immediately.

There would be agreements with North African countries to make sure asylum seekers were not tortured on return to their country of origin, says No 10.

The home secretary also wants to ensure he automatically reviews cases where people banned from other countries try to come to the UK.

It follows worries about some radical preachers coming to the UK.

In 2004, 14 people were banned from coming to the UK under existing powers, 12 of them on national security grounds.

Efforts to examine what new anti-terror measures are needed after the bombings, which killed 52 people, are being stepped up.

Downing Street says it wants to build consensus about the content of new laws and the pace at which they are introduced.

Mr Clarke will meet his opposition counterparts - Conservative David Davis and Lib Dem Mark Oaten - next Monday.

On Tuesday, Tony Blair will meet Muslim community leaders, as well as Conservative leader Michael Howard and Liberal Democrat leader Charles Kennedy.

The prime minister will then host a meeting of senior members of the intelligence agencies and police on Thursday. He will meet Mr Howard and Mr Kennedy again the following Monday.

Mr Blair's official spokesman said: &quot;We stand ready to give the police and the security services any powers they need as a result of this atrocity and the investigation into it.&quot;

Earlier, Mr Howard said he hoped there could be &quot;genuine consensus&quot; over new measures.

&quot;We are all in this together,&quot; he said. &quot;We all have to work together as a national community - Christian and Muslim, Hindu and Jew - to deal with this danger.&quot;

Mr Oaten said the Lib Dems, like the Tories, had already called for a new offence of making &quot;acts preparatory to terrorism&quot; and would look at the idea of outlawing incitement to terrorism.

The Lib Dem spokesman said the starting point was to try to agree consensus.

But he warned: &quot;If we feel that we're having knee-jerk rushed legislation then despite what took place last week we have a responsibility to make sure we have good robust laws which work in this country.&quot;

One of the bombers reportedly visited an Islamic study camp in Pakistan earlier this year.

Foreign Secretary Jack Straw told reporters Pakistan faced a big challenge to improve such religious seminaries - known as Madrassas.

&quot;We are concerned about what goes on in some, though not all, of the Madrassas in Pakistan but so too is President Musharraf and many, many people in the Pakistan political parties and Pakistan Government,&quot; he said.

Mr Straw said there was &quot;intensive and increasingly substantial co-operation&quot; with Pakistan on counter-terrorism but he refused to discuss contacts on the current investigation.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4681639.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | ID cards 'wouldn't stop attacks'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>But the home secretary said on balance he believed ID cards would help rather than hinder the ability to deal with particular terrorist threats.

He also suggested that in future civil liberties might have to be curtailed.

Consideration would need to be given to checks on people boarding tube trains, ID cards and data exchange, he says.

He also insisted the small reduction in the official threat level made before the bombings had made no difference to the attacks.

Asked by BBC Radio 4's Today programme if ID cards could have prevented Thursday's atrocity, Mr Clarke said: &quot;I doubt it would have made a difference.

&quot;I've never argued ... that ID cards would prevent any particular act.

&quot;The question on ID cards, but also on any other security measure actually, is on the balance of the ability to deal with particular threats and civil liberties, does a particular measure help or hinder it?

&quot;I actually think ID cards do help rather than hinder.

&quot;If you ask me whether ID cards or any other measure would have stopped yesterday, I can't identify any measure which would have just stopped it like that.&quot;

However, he later told the BBC that ID cards had helped officials identify the perpetrators of last year's bomb attacks on packed commuter trains in Madrid.

But Conservative shadow home secretary David Davis said the bombings had not changed his party's opposition to ID cards.

&quot;The home secretary admitted himself that ID cards would not have prevented this and may not even have helped in the investigation afterwards so it doesn't change the argument,&quot; Mr Davis told BBC News.

The prime minister had said this was an attack on people's lives and their way of life.

Mr Davis added: &quot;An important part of our way of life is maintenance of our civil freedoms.&quot;

In a separate interview on BBC Breakfast, Mr Clarke was asked about how people could be kept safe in the wake of the attacks.

&quot;I don't think any of us want to live a life where we have to go through security checks every moment of our lives and so we have to find the right way to move forward,&quot; he said.

&quot;The key thing is to study after these terrible events what needs to be done and discuss properly what alternative solutions there are.&quot;

Asked if that meant civil liberties being curtailed, Mr Clarke said: &quot;I always hope not.

&quot;But whether we look at identity cards or you look at exchange of data or you look at particular types of checking machinery when you get on a Tube train or whatever it might be, those are issues that have to be debated.

&quot;Today isn't the time for those debates. Today is the time to track down the perpetrators and see that we can try and make the arrests that are necessary.

&quot;People will have to look at the options and decide which is the right way to proceed.&quot;

Mr Clarke also said the decision recently to downgrade the official level of threat to the UK from severe general to substantial &quot;wouldn't have changed events&quot;.

And the fact that 1,500 Metropolitan Police officers had been sent to Gleneagles to police the G8 summit had made no difference to the response.

&quot;There were suggestions yesterday that the fact that we put resources into Scotland to deal with the G8 summit had lead to some lower position in London, but that is simply not true,&quot; he told Today.

&quot;The London police, the Metropolitan Commissioner and all his colleagues at all levels will tell you that we had a complete ability to deal with the situation yesterday. I spoke to them directly about it.&quot;

Meanwhile, QinetiQ, the privatised former Defence Evaluation and Research Agency, and London Underground have rejected claims made in the Times newspaper that body scanners are to be used on the Tube.

The two organisations say the report is &quot;inaccurate&quot; and there are no plans to use the scanners. QinetiQ is providing some equipment but cannot discuss it.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4663155.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Tory MPs to vote on leader rules</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The proposals, which would give MPs the final say on replacing Michael Howard, have been agreed by senior backbenchers and the party's ruling board.

They require that candidates enlist the support of 5% of Tory MPs before being allowed to stand.

The proposals come as former chancellor Kenneth Clarke drops his strongest hint yet that he will make a third bid for the leadership of the party.

Meanwhile, 10 Tory MPs, including four leadership hopefuls, have criticised the election proposals in a letter to the Daily Telegraph, saying they deserve to be defeated.

Under the proposals, ordinary party members would only get their say on a candidate once he or she had secured the backing of 5% of Tory MPs.

Their views would be passed back to MPs, who would then hold a series of ballots to choose a leader.

Tory MPs, who have all been sent details of the proposals, along with ballot papers, are being asked to say whether or not they support them.

Voting begins at 1200 BST and will end at 1400 BST on Wednesday, with the result expected to be announced at a meeting of the 1922 Committee that evening.

If the vote comes out in favour, the plans will be drawn up into a formal amendment to the Conservative Party constitution.

MPs would then vote on them formally over the summer.

MPs appear divided over the proposals, with some, including potential leadership candidates Theresa May, Michael Ancram, David Willetts and Andrew Lansley, saying rank and file members should have a greater say, as they currently do.

The four, who were among the authors of the letter to the newspaper, say the party should promote devolution of power rather than centralisation.

Conservative members have already rejected Michael Howard's plan to allow party chairmen to rank candidates before a binding ballot of MPs.

Under the current rules, introduced when William Hague was leader, MPs choose two candidates to be put to a vote of all party members.

The only time it was used, Iain Duncan Smith was elected over ex-chancellor Ken Clarke.

In a speech to the Tory Reform Group on Tuesday evening, Mr Clarke, 65, will say the top job would be a &quot;real privilege&quot;.

He has already suggested he has enough support from colleagues to mount a challenge.

&quot;The more I consider my options, the prospect of my becoming a candidate by the autumn becomes more attractive,&quot; he will say.

It would be the third time Mr Clarke has tried for the leadership. In 1997, fellow MPs picked William Hague over him.

Mr Clarke's pro-Europe views might be seen as less of a stumbling block following the collapse of the EU constitution and no apparent prospect of British membership of the euro.

In his speech, Mr Clarke warns that the party &quot;is in danger of becoming a natural party of opposition&quot; and Gordon Brown - widely predicted to be the prime minister in waiting - &quot;will not be easy to beat&quot;.

&quot;We must look and sound like a credible government in waiting by the time we are campaigning against Brown in the second half of this Parliament,&quot; he will say.

Other likely candidates for a leadership contest expected in October include David Cameron David Davis, Sir Malcolm Rifkind, Liam Fox, Andrew Lansley and Kenneth Clarke. Transport spokesman Alan Duncan has ruled himself out of the race.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4694961.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Tory MPs back new leader rules</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The proposals, already agreed by the party's ruling board and senior backbenchers, would give Tory MPs the final say in the coming contest.

Currently MPs select two candidates and ordinary party members vote on them.

The proposed scheme means they will be asked to rate candidates who have the backing of 5% of MPs. The decision then goes back to the Parliamentary party.

Voting in the consultative ballot of Conservative MPs about the leadership began at 1200 BST on Tuesday and ended at 1400 BST on Wednesday.

The result was announced at a meeting of the 1922 committee of Tory backbenchers.

The plans will now be drawn up into a formal amendment to the Conservative Party constitution.

MPs and local party chairmen will vote on them at a special convention over the summer.

Tory MPs appeared divided over the proposals, with some, including potential leadership candidates Theresa May, Michael Ancram, David Willetts and Andrew Lansley, saying rank and file members should have a greater say, as they currently do.

After Wednesday's vote, Theresa May said: &quot;I am disappointed that we have decided to send out the message that we can't trust our members to make the decision about who should lead our party.&quot;

The current rules were introduced by former Conservative leader William Hague.

The only time they were used, Iain Duncan Smith was elected over ex-chancellor Ken Clarke.

Meanwhile the C-Change think tank has suggested the Tories face a growing threat from the Liberal Democrats.

Its study says that Tory gains at May's general election mask evidence of a continuing fall in the core vote.

Of the 31 seats the party took from Labour at the general election, 18 of these were due to increased votes for the Lib Dems.

Party chairman Francis Maude told BBC Radio 4's Today programme that rebuilding the party and its support base would be a long job.

&quot;Anyone who thinks that this is suddenly going to fall into our lap would be deluding themselves,&quot; he said.

Shadow transport secretary Alan Duncan, who pulled out of the leadership race earlier this week, told BBC's Five Live that the Tories needed to widen their appeal.

Other likely candidates for a Tory leadership contest expected in October include Ken Clarke, David Cameron, David Davis, Sir Malcolm Rifkind, Liam Fox and Andrew Lansley.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4698605.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | UK urges terrorist asset seizure</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He predicted there will be continuing problems if some countries fail to cut off terrorists' supply of money.

Mr Brown said he wanted the issue discussed at the World Bank and IMF.

&quot;Just as there will be no safe haven for those who perpetrate terrorism, there will be no hiding place for those who finance terrorism,&quot; he said.

A plan to co-ordinate European anti-terror efforts was agreed after last year's Madrid train bombings, but Mr Brown now wants it to be implemented immediately.

He said many countries had invested a great deal in systems to help track down sources of terrorist finance.

The UK has frozen 45 different bank accounts - containing a total of £377,200 - since 11 September 2001.

Other European countries, as well as America, had taken similar action, said Mr Brown.

&quot;But it's important to realise that you're only as strong as your weakest link,&quot; he argued.

&quot;Where there are countries that are not taking action to cut off the sources of terrorist finance, we will clearly have continuing problems.&quot;

Help would be available for other countries, said Mr Brown, but he did not say whether or not there might be sanctions against those failing to take action.

The chancellor said the European action plan agreed last year needed to be implemented as soon as possible.

&quot;Across Europe we will act as one to send a message to terrorism that while lives have ended, the cause for justice never dies,&quot; he said.

&quot;And we will show at every stage that because we hold steadfast to enduring ideals of freedom and justice, terrorism will always be defeated by democracy.&quot;

Among the measures in the EU action plan he wants pushed through are:
• Ensuring all member states can take action nationally to freeze terrorist assets - EU-wide mechanisms cannot currently be used to freeze accounts of EU citizens
• Making it compulsory for wire transfers of money to be accompanied by information about the identity of the sender
• Completing the European Commission-sponsored review of EU structures on tackling terrorists' finance
• Introducing a code of conduct to prevent abuse of charities by terrorists.

London's transport network was attacked with four bombs on Thursday. The blasts, on three packed Tube trains and a double-decker bus, killed at least 52 people and injured more than 700.

On Wednesday, Home Secretary Charles Clarke will chair an emergency meeting with his European counterparts on co-operation on counter-terrorism operations.

Mr Clarke wants to force telephone and internet service firms across Europe to keep records of all private telephone calls, text messages and e-mails so they can be passed on to the police if necessary.

Foreign Secretary Jack Straw pressed for the moves when he met MEPs in Brussels on Tuesday.

Fears about the costs had been exaggerated, said Mr Straw, but it was a price worth paying to save lives.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4673975.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Cherie warns on anti-terror moves</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It would be &quot;all too easy&quot; to fight back in a way &quot;which cheapens our right to call ourselves a civilised nation&quot;, said the barrister in Malaysia.

She stressed her comments should not be seen as making light of the attacks.

But Tory homeland security spokesman Patrick Mercer said the remarks came at a &quot;desperately insensitive time&quot;.

Cherie, a QC who practises under her maiden name Booth, said: &quot;Nothing I say here could possibly be construed as making light of those horrible acts of violence, or of the responsibility imposed on the UK and other governments to keep the public safe, or of the difficult and dangerous task performed by the police and intelligence services.&quot;

But, she added &quot;at the same time it is all too easy for us to respond to such terror in a way which undermines commitment to our most deeply held values and convictions and which cheapens our right to call ourselves a civilised nation&quot;.

The QC, addressing an audience of 1,000 lawyers, civil servants and diplomats in Malaysia, said judges made rulings in a way that taught citizens and government about the &quot;ethical responsibilities&quot; of participating in a true democracy committed to &quot;universal human rights standards&quot;.

She said courts should be &quot;guardians of the weakest, poorest and most marginalised members of society against the hurly-burly of majoritarian politics&quot;.

A good example of this working was the decision by the UK's highest court, the House of Lords law lords, that the UK's policy of holding foreign terrorist suspects indefinitely without charge broke human rights laws.

&quot;What the case makes clear is that the government, even in times when there is a threat to national security, must act strictly in accordance with the law,&quot; she said.

But Mr Mercer said: &quot;Cherie Blair or Cherie Booth, whichever name she's going under just at the moment, is entitled to her private opinions of course and to express those.

&quot;But she is the prime minister's wife and I think this is a desperately insensitive time for her to be making those sorts of comments.&quot;

Mr Blair says extra powers being looked at include extending the time people can be held without charge.

On Tuesday Mr Blair vowed not to &quot;give an inch to terrorism&quot; and said Iraq was no excuse for the London bombings.

He said 11 September 2001 was a wake up call for the international community, but argued some people &quot;then turned over and went back to sleep again&quot;.

&quot;Let us expose the obscenity of these people saying it is concern for Iraq that drives them to terrorism. If it is concern for Iraq then why are they driving a car bomb into the middle of a group of children and killing them?

&quot;We are not going to deal with this problem, with the roots as deep as they are, until we confront these people at every single level - and not just their methods but their ideas,&quot; he added.

Also on Tuesday Mr Blair held talks with Conservative leader Michael Howard and the Liberal Democrats' Charles Kennedy about possible new powers to tackle terrorism.

These could include allowing the use of &quot;phone tap&quot; evidence in court.

Mr Howard said the Tories saw difficulties with calls from the police to extend the time a terrorist suspect can be held without charge from 14 days to three months.

Police chiefs say they only want to be able to ask a judge to extend detentions bit-by-bit up to the new time limit.

Mr Kennedy said &quot;reasonable progress&quot; had been made in the talks and he hoped this would continue in a measured way so &quot;we don't surrender basic civil liberties in the process&quot;.

There is already agreement on proposals to create new offences of engaging in acts preparatory to terrorism and of indirect incitement to terrorism.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4719977.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair vows to hunt down bombers</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>&quot;We will pursue those responsible wherever they are and we will not rest until they are identified, and as far as possible, brought to justice.&quot;

He told MPs that Londoners' &quot;stoicism&quot; since the tube and bus bombs, which claimed 52 lives, was an inspiration.

The prime minister said Britons were &quot;determined... not to be defeated&quot;.

Conservative leader Michael Howard praised the government's response to last week's atrocity.

&quot;We wish to give the government our full support as they face difficult decisions in the future,&quot; he said.

Liberal Democrat Charles Kennedy also struck a note of unity and chose to highlight the condemnation of the attacks by the &quot;vast majority&quot; of British Muslims.

Earlier Mr Howard had called for an inquiry, to see if any lessons could be learned.

In the Commons he said it should be of limited scope with its remit determined by the government. It should not interfere with the current efforts to identify the dead or catch the bombers, he said.

Mr Blair said everyone involved would want to see if there could be improvements in their response.

Those responsible for killing 52 and injuring more than 700, probably Islamic extremists, would be hunted down.

&quot;The 7 July will always be remembered as a day of sadness,&quot; Mr Blair said before pointing out that people were determined to return to normal just four days later.

&quot;At the moment of terror striking, when the eyes of the world were upon them, [Londoners] responded and continue to respond with a defiance and a strength that are universally admired,&quot; he said.

The government is prepared to introduce new emergency anti-terrorism powers if the police and the security services felt these were needed, he said.

The prime minister's official spokesman said ministers believed they had identified where new powers were required, but were willing to listen to any request from the security services for other measures.
• The first victim of the bombs was officially named as Susan Levy, 53, from Cuffley in Hertfordshire
• Scotland Yard says its inquiry has been helped by a strong response from the public.
• A book of condolence has been opened at City Hall in London, with mayor Ken Livingstone the first to sign it.
• Home Secretary Charles Clarke wants all EU countries to agree that communication firms retain details of all calls made, texts and e-mails sent for a year.
• London Underground reported that passenger numbers were down slightly on usual numbers.

Since the bombings the main political parties have made a point of saying they need to put on a united front.

And in the usually combative Commons there was a rare unity among MPs of all parties.

Mr Blair said that the sort of people who carried out the attack on tube and bus passengers were &quot;by their very nature&quot; hard to stop.

&quot;But our security services and police do a heroic job for our country day in day out and I can say that over the past years, as this particular type of new and awful terrorist threat has grown, they have done their utmost to keep this country and its people safe,&quot; he said.

Police and security agencies say they are now almost certain that they are not dealing with a suicide bomb attack.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4670945.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair defends Asbo tsar's gaffe</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A Number 10 spokeswoman said the prime minister had &quot;a high regard&quot; for Louise Casey, 38, who is director of the Home Office's anti-social behaviour unit.

The spokeswoman said her comments had to be &quot;put into perspective&quot; as they were made in an after dinner speech.

She said people often made remarks in a similar situation which they regretted.

Mr Blair has not spoken to Ms Casey, the spokeswoman said, and it is not known whether she has apologised.

Ms Casey made her comments at a conference attended by senior civil servants, chief constables and criminal justice practitioners last month.

A guest recorded the speech in which she poked fun at Home Secretary Charles Clarke.

Speaking in Stratford-upon-Avon, Ms Casey told her audience: &quot;I suppose you can't binge drink anymore because lots of people have said you can't do it. I don't know who bloody made that up, it's nonsense.&quot;

On the tape, obtained by BBC News, she said some ministers might perform better if they &quot;turn up in the morning pissed&quot;.

&quot;Doing things sober is no way to get things done,&quot; she added.

But her strongest criticism was reserved for Downing Street, which she suggested was &quot;obsessed&quot; with conducting extensive research before formulating policies.

She apparently joked that she would &quot;deck&quot; Downing Street policy advisers if they kept spouting jargon at her.

At the weekend reports claimed Tony Blair had criticised Mr Clarke over a lack of action on the &quot;respect agenda&quot;.

However, Downing Street insisted it was &quot;absurd&quot; to suggest Mr Blair was unhappy with Mr Clarke's handling of the issue.

Although the tone of Ms Casey's speech was light-hearted - she said the tea lady was more powerful than ministers - a number of people in the audience are reported to have walked out.

Downing Street said Mr Blair had &quot;full confidence&quot; in her and his &quot;high regard for her was well known because of her record of achievements in the past&quot;.

But a spokeswoman added: &quot;The remarks were made after a dinner and should be put into some sort of perspective.

&quot;Lots of people have said things after dinner and when they see them in the cold light of day would regret them and no doubt she would not have wished to see them in this morning's newspapers.&quot;

A Home Office spokesman said Ms Casey was achieving a great deal in leading the campaign to tackle anti-social behaviour.

&quot;But, like all Home Office employees, she is subject to the Civil Service Code. We are looking into her reported remarks,&quot; he added.

Harry Fletcher, assistant general secretary of the National Association of Probation Officers, said Ms Casey's remarks were &quot;extraordinary&quot;.

They were &quot;certainly inappropriate comments to be made by a civil servant, never mind one who is heading up the anti-social behaviour unit,&quot; he told BBC Radio 4's Today programme.

Shadow home secretary David Davis said it was &quot;ironic&quot; that the official appointed to report to Tony Blair on anti-social behaviour appeared to be &quot;an advocate of binge drinking&quot;.

&quot;Maybe this explains why alcohol-related violent attacks are up 25% and why Labour are so keen to unleash 24-hour drinking,&quot; he added.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4656305.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair: Iraq no excuse for terror</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He acknowledged Iraq was being used to recruit terrorists, but insisted the roots of extremism were much deeper.

He said 11 September 2001 was a wake up call for the international community, but argued some people &quot;then turned over and went back to sleep again&quot;.

The prime minister was speaking to reporters after talks about new terror laws with Tory and Lib Dem leaders.

He said: &quot;Let us expose the obscenity of these people saying it is concern for Iraq that drives them to terrorism. If it is concern for Iraq then why are they driving a car bomb into the middle of a group of children and killing them?

&quot;We are not going to deal with this problem, with the roots as deep as they are, until we confront these people at every single level - and not just their methods but their ideas,&quot; he added.

&quot;11 September for me was a wake up call. Do you know what I think the problem is? That a lot of the world woke up for a short time and then turned over and went back to sleep again.&quot;

In a 75 minute media conference Mr Blair said there was no justification for suicide bombing whether in Israel or in &quot;Palestine, Iraq, in London, in Egypt, in Turkey, anywhere. In the United States of America, there is no justification for it. Period&quot;.

Earlier, after the talks in Downing Street, Conservative leader Michael Howard said the prime minister was seriously considering allowing the use of &quot;phone tap&quot; evidence in courts.

They also discussed extending the time suspects can be held without charge.

But he said the Tories saw extreme difficulties with calls from the police to extend the time a terrorist suspect can be held without charge from 14 days to three months.

Police chiefs say they only want to be able to ask a judge to ask to extend detentions in instalments up to the new time limit.

Mr Kennedy said &quot;reasonable progress&quot; had been made in the talks and he hoped this would continue in a measured way so &quot;we don't surrender basic civil liberties in the process&quot;.

Downing Street has said Mr Blair still intends to listen to &quot;considered advice&quot; before supporting the use of telephone call recordings at trials.

There is already agreement on proposals to create new offences of engaging in acts preparatory to terrorism and of indirect incitement to terrorism.

Police meanwhile continue to hunt the men behind Thursday's failed bomb attacks on three London Underground trains and a bus.

They are holding five other men in connection with the attacks - but the five are not suspected of being bombers themselves.

On Tuesday officers found a large amount of &quot;possible&quot; explosives at a block of flats in New Southgate, north London, where bomb suspect Yasin Hassan Omar had been living since 1999.

The other bombing suspect named so far, Muktar Said Ibrahim, 27, has also been linked to the same flat.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4716505.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair says 'terror will not win'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mr Blair said: &quot;It is a very sad day for the British people but we will hold true to the British way of life.&quot;

The prime minister flew to London from the G8 summit, which continued in his absence. He rejoined the talks in Gleneagles on Thursday evening.

A statement from G8 leaders called the blasts &quot;an attack not on one nation but on all nations and civilised people&quot;.

The Queen said she was &quot;deeply shocked&quot; and sent sympathy to those affected.

US President George Bush said there was an &quot;incredibly vivid contrast&quot; between the work at the G8 to alleviate poverty and the &quot;evil&quot; of those wanting to kill.

Foreign Secretary Jack Straw chaired the G8 talks while the prime minister went to London to chair Cobra, the committee involving ministers, emergency services and security agencies.

Mr Straw said the blasts bore the &quot;hallmarks of an al-Qaeda related attack&quot;.

The prime minister said there would be the &quot;most intense&quot; police and security service action to ensure those responsible were brought to justice.

In a televised message from Downing Street, Mr Blair sent &quot;profound condolences&quot; to victims' families and to those injured in the blasts and he thanked the emergency services.

&quot;It is through terrorism that the people who have committed this terrible act express their values and it is right at this moment that we demonstrate ours,&quot; said Mr Blair.

&quot;They are trying to use the slaughter of innocent people to cow us, to frighten us out of doing the things that we want to do, of trying to stop us going about our business as normal as we are entitled to do.

&quot;They should not and they must not succeed.&quot;

Mr Blair said those behind such attacks claimed to act in the name of Islam but he stressed that the vast majority of Muslims abhorred terrorism as much as anyone else.

A joint statement from the G8 leaders said: &quot;We are united in our resolve to confront and defeat this terrorism...

&quot;We will not allow violence to change our society and values nor will we allow it to stop our work at this summit.&quot;

London Mayor Ken Livingstone said the attacks were a cowardly and indiscriminate attempt at mass murder which would fail in its bid to destroy free society.

The mayor added: &quot;They seek to turn Londoners against each other... London will not be divided by this.&quot;

Conservative leader Michael Howard and Liberal Democrat leader Charles Kennedy both sent their sympathies to those injured and the families of those killed.

They praised the &quot;heroic&quot; work of the emergency services.

Mr Howard said it was a &quot;dreadful day for London and for our country&quot; and pledged his party's full support for the government.

&quot;This country is completely united in our determination to defeat terrorism and to deal with those who are responsible for the appalling acts that we have seen today,&quot; he said.

Mr Kennedy said: &quot;What has happened is appalling and those who carried out these attacks must be brought to justice...

&quot;The moral contrast between those who seek to disrupt and destroy and those who are trying to build for the future [at the G8 summit] could not be more stark. The terrorists must not prevail.&quot;

The Archbishop of Canterbury, Rowan Williams, said &quot;solidarity and common purpose is vital for us all at this time of pain and sorrow and anger&quot;.

He said extra precautions would be taken in Scotland but there was no additional &quot;specific&quot; threat and the focus would be on the G8 summit.

Welsh First Minister Rhodri Morgan said the whole of Wales would &quot;feel nothing but revulsion at these savage acts&quot;.

Respect MP George Galloway said the attacks were &quot;despicable but not remotely unpredictable&quot;.

Mr Galloway said Londoners had &quot;paid the price&quot; of the government failing to heed security service warnings that attacks on Iraq and Afghanistan would increase the threat of a attack in the UK.

But Home Secretary Charles Clarke said those responsible for such attacks simply wanted to destroy democracy and stressed the 11 September attacks in America had preceded the Iraq war.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4659933.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | UK | Massive hunt for London bombers</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Home Secretary Charles Clarke said looking for potential bombers was like searching for &quot;needles in haystacks&quot;.

The Queen and Prince Charles are visiting casualties, while Tony Blair prepares for the G8 summit's last day.

Transport operators ran a near-normal service on the Tube on most lines, but there were fewer commuters than usual.

Of the 300 people admitted to hospital on Thursday, about 80 remain, either convalescing after emergency surgery or too badly burned to return home.

Mr Clarke said a claim on the website of a previously unknown group, the Secret Organisation Group of al-Qaeda of Jihad Organisation in Europe, saying it was behind the blast, was being taken seriously.

Scotland Yard have confirmed seven people died in the Liverpool Street explosion and another seven were killed at Edgware Road. At least 21 lost their lives at the King's Cross blast.

Police have been unable to establish whether a suicide bomber was responsible for the attack on a bus in Woburn Place that claimed at least two lives.

But newspapers quoted an eyewitness who got off the bus moments before the blast who saw an agitated man in his mid-20s fiddling with his bag.

Richard Jones, 61, an IT consultant, told the Daily Mail: &quot;This chap started dipping down into his bag and getting back up. He did it about a dozen times in two or three minutes and looked extremely agitated.&quot;

The nature of the other three bombings is still unclear.

Mr Clarke has said the death toll is expected to rise. Police are likely to release more details about casualties and the hunt for the bombers later.

They have indicated there will be a more visible police presence in the capital on Friday.

The home secretary said the failure to predict Thursday's bombs should not obscure past successes.

But he admitted: &quot;It certainly was a failure of intelligence in the sense that we didn't know this was coming.

&quot;But by definition when you're looking for needles in haystacks you can miss the needles and the tragedy of yesterday is that we did miss the needles.&quot;

Police have said they had no warning of any attacks, or intelligence about any other imminent threats.

And the home secretary defended the recent downgrading of the terrorism threat from severe general to substantial.

Foreign Secretary Jack Straw said Thursday's attacks bore all the hallmarks of the al-Qaeda network.

Anyone worried about relatives or friends they have not heard from is advised to contact a special police hotline on 0870 156 6344.

London was starting to return to normal on Friday, with much of the transport system running as normal.

But the Circle and Hammersmith and City lines will remain closed. Parts of the District line, Metropolitan line and Piccadilly line are suspended.

King's Cross station was due to re-open for suburban rail services only.

Buses are expected to operate normally, except around the immediate areas where the explosions took place.

Transport officials have urged passengers to remain vigilant and keep hold of their baggage at all times.

The prime minister, who left the G8 summit to meet police and security officials in London after the attacks, is due to get back to business with other world leaders later.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4662395.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | UK concern over Pakistan schools</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Shehzad Tanweer, according to his uncle, went to one of the schools in December wanting to learn to recite the Koran by heart.

Mr Straw said the Pakistan government was also concerned about some of the schools, called madrassas.

He said Pakistan was increasingly cooperating on counter-terrorism.

The International Crisis Group recently said the Pakistan government had &quot;allowed religious organisations, jihadi groups and the madrassas that provide them with an endless stream of recruits to flourish&quot;.

It suggests 10-15% of the madrassas are radical.

&quot;We are concerned about what goes on in some, though not all, of the madrassas in Pakistan but so too is President Musharraf and many, many people in the Pakistan political parties and Pakistan government,&quot; he said.

Mr Straw said there was a major reform programme in Pakistan to provide secular education alongside the religious schools.

And he said there was &quot;intensive and increasingly substantial co-operation&quot; between the UK and Pakistan on counter-terrorism.

He refused to reveal details of any contacts with Pakistan officials over the London bombings investigation.

Labour MP Mohammed Sarwar told BBC News the madrassas provided young people living in &quot;abject poverty&quot; in Pakistan with food and clothes, as well as religious education.

It was therefore convenient for parents to send children to the schools.

&quot;We have to deal with this problem and we should ensure that in madrassas they are in state control,&quot; he said.

&quot;Secondly, it is very important that science education and education for other things should be an essential part of those madrassas.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4682931.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair urges debate on EU's future</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Speaking as the UK took over the EU presidency, Mr Blair said Europe's &quot;social model&quot; would be discussed at an informal summit in Britain this autumn.

He said there were risks to the plan but the issue was at the centre of debate about the EU's future direction.

Mr Blair and other UK ministers met the whole European Commission in London.

At a news conference with commission president Jose Manuel Barroso, he said EU enlargement, reducing regulation and strengthening EU borders would be discussed during the UK's six-month presidency.

The UK is also chairing the G8 and Mr Blair said he was setting aside time at next week's summit to discuss a new initiative on achieving Middle East peace.

Talks on fixing the EU budget for 2007-13 collapsed two weeks ago with Mr Blair insisting he would only negotiate the UK's annual rebate if European farm subsidies were reformed.

France and other countries say a deal fixing the Common Agricultural Policy until 2013 cannot be changed.

The prime minister said budget talks would be a major part of the UK presidency but he did not know whether an agreement would be possible.

Mr Barroso said leaders should nurture a &quot;culture of compromise&quot; rather than treat EU talks like a boxing match.

&quot;We are a union of 25, very soon we hope 27, which is diverse and nobody is going to impose its own point of view to the others,&quot; he said.

&quot;To reach an agreement everyone will have to contribute.&quot;

BBC Europe correspondent Chris Morris said Mr Blair had thrown down the gauntlet by debating the European &quot;social model&quot;.

The talks will centre around a paper produced by the European Commission about the sustainability of the budget.

Mr Blair last month stressed he did not want to ditch social protection in favour of an Anglo-Saxon economic model which trampled on the poor.

On Friday, he said Europe should have a &quot;strong social dimension&quot;.

&quot;Europe is not just about free trade and it is not just about the economy,&quot; he said.

&quot;But it is no use us trying to compete in the tough, changing world unless we are prepared to make the changes necessary, including not abandoning our social model, but updating it and modernising it.&quot;

The UK is resisting European Commission calls for an end to its opt out from rules limiting the working week to 48 hours.

British Foreign Secretary Jack Straw said public faith in the EU was undermined by &quot;gratuitous interference&quot; from Brussels in issues which should be left to nation states.

The Conservatives are sceptical the government will deliver on its words.

Shadow Europe minister Graham Brady said: &quot;Their agenda is to increase Britain's contributions to the EU budget and the talk about radical reform to the Common Agricultural Policy really is just that.

&quot;The document they published yesterday (Thursday) setting out the government's priorities does not mention that radical reform at all. It's all back of an envelope stuff.&quot;

Liberal Democrat foreign affairs spokesman Nick Clegg said the UK presidency faced three tests: CAP reform; maintaining momentum on EU enlargement, amid disputes about whether Turkey should join; and delivering economic reform.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4639683.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | UK plans global extremists list</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He said the database would list &quot;unacceptable behaviour&quot; such as radical preaching, websites and writing articles intended to foment terrorism.

Individuals' presence on the list means they may face exclusion from the UK.

Hopes for an international conference on Islamic extremism were also outlined by Prime Minister Tony Blair.

Mr Clarke told MPs he wanted to apply more widely the home secretary's powers to exclude an individual from the UK if their presence is deemed &quot;not conducive to the public interest&quot;.

In a Commons statement he said: &quot;In the circumstances we now face, I have decided that it is right to broaden the use of these powers to deal with those who foment terrorism or seek to provoke others to terrorist acts.

&quot;I intend to draw up a list of unacceptable behaviours which would fall into this - for example preaching, running websites or writing articles which are intended to foment or provoke terrorism.&quot;

He said there would be consultation before the final list of &quot;unacceptable behaviours&quot; was decided upon.

Mr Clarke said he had asked the Home Office, Foreign Office and the intelligence agencies to &quot;establish a full database of individuals around the world who have demonstrated relevant behaviours&quot;.

Anyone wanting to enter the UK would then be checked against this list - and if they are on it they may be refused permission to enter the country.

In a statement on the aftermath of the London bombings in which 56 people died, Mr Clarke also said he planned a new offence of &quot;indirect incitement to terrorism&quot;, to add to the current offence of direct incitement.

He said it &quot;targets those who, while not directly inciting, glorify and condone terrorist acts knowing full well that the effect on their listeners will be to encourage them to turn to terrorism&quot;.

Earlier, at prime minister's questions, Mr Blair told MPs the UK was looking at holding an international conference for countries concerned about or affected by Islamic extremism.

He said the aim was &quot;to try and take concerted action across the world to try to root out this type of extremist teaching&quot;.

He said: &quot;Though the terrorists will use all sorts of issues to justify what they do, the roots of it do go deep, they are often not found in this country alone therefore international action is also necessary.&quot;

Mr Clarke, during his statement, said the UK had reached an agreement with Jordan which would enable Britain to deport Jordanian nationals suspected of inciting or supporting terrorism.

Under international convention the UK government cannot send people back to a country where they might face mistreatment or the death penalty.

The memorandum of understanding removes this bar to deportations.

However, Amnesty International's UK Director Kate Allen said promises from countries like Jordan, known to have used torture, &quot;are not worth the paper they are written on&quot;.

She questioned how Mr Clarke would monitor whether these promises were being kept.

Jordanian-born cleric Abu Qatada could face deportation as a result of the agreement.

Court challenges mean it is likely to be months before deportations happen.

The government is seeking similar &quot;memorandums of understanding&quot; with a number of North African countries.

The prime minister's official spokesman said there were a number of Jordanian nationals who may be subject to deportation proceedings after the memorandum is signed, but he refused to disclose any further details.

Abu Qatada, who fled to the UK claiming persecution and was held in Belmarsh Prison without charge as part of the government's post-11 September crackdown, is currently subject to a control order.

Police uncovered tapes of his sermons at a Hamburg flat used by some of the 11 September hijackers.

He has been convicted of terrorism in his absence in Jordan and several European countries are believed to be trying to extradite him.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4699745.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Religious hate law clears Commons</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>MPs gave the Racial and Religious Hatred Bill a third reading by 301 votes to 229, a majority of 72.

Shadow minister Dominic Grieve said the bill would not improve race relations.

But Minister Paul Goggins said: &quot;I believe we need to take on the hate mongers, whether they are terrorists or whether they are extremists.&quot;

The bill would create a new offence of incitement to religious hatred and would apply to comments made in public or in the media, as well as through written material.

The plans, which have failed to make it through Parliament twice before, cover words or behaviour intended or likely to stir up religious hatred. Jews and Sikhs are already covered by race-hate laws.

They will now undergo scrutiny in the House of Lords.

Home Office Minister Mr Goggins described the bill as small, tightly focused with &quot;not much room for manoeuvre&quot;, although he accepted it was &quot;not the whole answer&quot;.

&quot;But there is a gap and we seek to close that gap through this legislation,&quot; he said.

But shadow attorney general Mr Grieve warned that the legislation remained &quot;catastrophically flawed&quot;.

It would not improve race relations and would prevent the lawful expression of differences of view, he said.

&quot;If the government really wants to tackle this issue, it is going to have to get away from the promises made to various people of some equal playing field, accept that religion and race are different, start to look at the real nature of the problem and try to come up with some constructive solutions.&quot;

He also argued that a failure to define religion in the bill meant sects, including Satanists, Scientologists and believers in female genital mutilation would be protected.

He said the measures could struggle to get through the House of Lords.

But Mr Goggins said it would be the job of the courts to define a religion.

&quot;We've left it to the courts, that's right that we do that because over time a religion may change,&quot; he said.

Liberal Democrat spokesman Alistair Carmichael said he was &quot;embarrassed&quot; that elected representatives were sending a bill to the Lords &quot;that is so bad at this stage&quot; when so much time had been spent on it.

&quot;It is a bill that's ill-conceived in its thinking, it will be dangerous in its execution and I'm confident we have not seen the last of it,&quot; he said.

But Labour ex-Cabinet minister Frank Dobson said it was incumbent on MPs to protect their constituents from those who incited fear and hatred.

An attempt by the Lib Dems, backed by the Tories, that would have outlawed religious hatred as a pretext for stirring up hatred against a racial group was defeated by 291 votes to 233, a government majority of 58.

Labour MP Ann Cryer, who backed the amendment, said she was concerned that restrictions contained in the bill would stifle debate.

&quot;I am simply not convinced that legislation which encourages further segregation, however well-intentioned, will provide the protection it aims to deliver,&quot; she said.

Last month a coalition of Tory and Lib Dem MPs failed to block the bill's second reading by 303 votes to 246, giving a government majority of 57.

Critics, including comic actor Rowan Atkinson, have argued that the measures will limit freedom of expression and stop them from telling religious jokes.

But Home Secretary Charles Clarke said the bill was not about stopping people from telling jokes about religion and would not curb artistic freedom.

He said it was &quot;about behaviour that destroys individuals' lives and sets one community against each other&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4673301.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | EU agrees new security measures</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>UK Home Secretary Charles Clarke chaired an emergency summit on terror measures after the London bombs.

He said there was unanimous agreement that EU nations must do better and &quot;cannot delay in getting this right&quot;.

People across Europe will also be asked to observe Thursday's two-minute silence for the London victims.

The tribute will take place at 1200 BST.

After the talks in Brussels, Mr Clarke said: &quot;All of us across the EU are absolutely determined to accelerate work to make terrorism more difficult.

&quot;It focuses around a wide range of different exchanges of data and information.&quot;

Mr Clarke said progress had been made on agreeing the &quot;substance&quot; of plans to force European phone and internet firms to keep records of calls, text messages and e-mails.

BBC Europe correspondent Tim Franks said it was still unclear how law enforcement agencies would be able to access the data - and whether the scheme would be overseen by the European Parliament.

UK companies already store data for a year under a code of practice and Mr Clarke wants the scheme rolled out across Europe.

Critics of the idea say it is too costly and it will take too long to search the mass of stored data for the move to be useful.

Italian MEP Lilli Gruber said: &quot;Once you are monitored with your private telephone calls, telephone messages and private emails, this is a police state.&quot;

But Mr Clarke said telecommunications data was important in investigating whether the bombers were part of a broader network.

He also rejected claims that a UK minister told French politicians that some of the bombers had been arrested by police last year.

Among measures agreed at the summit were:
• Sharing more information on lost and stolen explosives
• Tackling terrorist finances, including new laws on wire transfers of money and measures against money laundering
• Ensuring common standards for those countries with identity card schemes
• A new effort to stop the recruitment of potential terrorists.

In a statement from the summit, the ministers said the bombings were &quot;an affront to universal values on which the European Union is based&quot;.

They added: &quot;The terrorists, who reject that commitment and seek to use violence to impose their ideas, will be defeated.&quot;

EU interior ministers gathered for a similar summit after March 2004's Madrid bombings which killed 191 people.

That meeting led to the faster implementation of the European Arrest Warrant and boosted the sharing of police information to thwart future attacks.

UK ministers now want that action plan to be implemented in full as quickly as possible.

EU Justice and Security Commissioner Franco Frattini suggested it was time to &quot;blame and shame&quot; nations which had failed to implement the previously agreed measures.

Mr Clarke also faced questions about the implications of the plans from the European Parliament's civil liberties committee.

One MEP said introducing measures which sounded tough did not mean they would be effective.

And the former deputy chief constable of Greater Manchester Police, John Stalker, said he did not believe the new measure would make any difference.

&quot;I don't think that there's anything that politicians at the moment can do that would make the work of anti-terrorist squads any easier,&quot; he told BBC Two's Newsnight.

Fears have also been raised about intrusion into privacy but Mr Clarke said civil liberties had to be treated proportionately.

&quot;I argue that it is a fundamental civil liberty of people in Europe to be able to go to work on their transport system in the morning without being blown up and subject to terrorist attack,&quot; he said.

He also said the fact the London bomb suspects were British gave &quot;extra impetus&quot; to understanding &quot;radicalisation&quot; and how people were recruited for attacks.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4677241.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Lib Dems win Cheadle by-election</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The election was triggered by the death of Lib Dem MP Patsy Calton from cancer shortly after May's general election.

Mark Hunter held the Greater Manchester seat for the Lib Dems with 19,953 votes, a 3,657 majority over Tory candidate Stephen Day, who came second.

Mr Hunter said people had voted for a &quot;more honest and positive approach&quot;. Labour's Martin Miller came third with 1,739 votes but lost his £500 deposit.

The swing was 0.63% from Conservatives to Liberal Democrats - Mr Miller lost his deposit because he won less than 5% of the vote.

The outcome will come as a relief to Lib Dem leader Charles Kennedy, who has been criticised by some elements in the party since the election.

He is due to visit Cheadle later on Friday to celebrate the victory.

Mr Kennedy said: &quot;This is a first class victory for the Liberal Democrats.

&quot;It is further proof that British politics is now three party politics - with the Lib Dems as a growing force for the future.&quot;

He told BBC Radio 4's Today programme the party had &quot;fought the seat very hard&quot; - but this was normal for a by-election and not the result of fears that losing the seat might cost him his leadership.

Mr Kennedy was recently re-elected unopposed as party leader. He denied reports he had warned his frontbenchers he would sack anybody trying to destabilise his leadership.

&quot;I said no such thing,&quot; he said, although he had told colleagues not to be distracted by press reports from Westminster which were &quot;utterly irrelevant to real politics outside&quot;.

Mr Kennedy said he had reorganised parts of the party since the election.

&quot;You can't as a leader make an omelette without cracking eggs and then you get some unfavourable remarks,&quot; he added.

Ms Calton won Cheadle from the Conservatives in 2001 with a majority of 33, the smallest in the country.

Although unable to campaign because of a recurrence of her cancer, Ms Calton increased her majority in this year's May election to 4,000.

Mr Hunter told BBC News he believed there was a &quot;backlash&quot; against the &quot;American-style&quot; canvassing tactics which parties like the Conservatives had used.

&quot;This has been a hard fought campaign. The Conservatives have failed again and have disgraced themselves with more negative and personal mud-slinging than ever before,&quot; Mr Hunter said.

He said he was &quot;extremely proud&quot; to be representing Cheadle as their next MP.

Mr Day, who was the area's MP until 2001, said he would not stand as a parliamentary candidate again, adding: &quot;I am pleased to see that the Conservative share of the vote has gone up.

&quot;This is the best by-election result we have had in a long time and it is the Labour Party which is in trouble.&quot;

But Labour's Mr Miller said the result &quot;showed that people were willing to vote for anyone to make sure the Conservative Party did not win&quot;.

The Conservatives have not gained a seat in a parliamentary by-election since 1982.

Shadow Commons leader Chris Grayling said he was disappointed but not surprised the Tories had failed to win the seat.

He said the result was similar to the general election and little had happened politically since then to &quot;change the overall lie of the land between the different parties&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4681533.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Fuel duty increase delayed again</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Fuel duty is due to rise at least in line with inflation every year but Gordon Brown used his Budget in March to defer the rise.

Now the Treasury says it will review whether to raise the tax in the autumn pre-Budget report.

The tax was frozen last year because of &quot;volatility in the oil market&quot;. Oil prices have since risen further.

Fuel duties have now been frozen since October 2003.

On Tuesday, John Healey, Financial Secretary to the Treasury, said: &quot;Following sustained pressure from G8 finance ministers, OPEC (which represents most of the largest oil producing countries) have committed to increasing quotas by up to 1 million barrels a day by September.

&quot;But in the short-term uncertainty, and the risk of price volatility, remains high, with oil trading last week at above $59 per barrel.&quot;

The government says fuel duty has not risen in real terms since 1999 and at 47.1p per litre, taxes on the main types of petrol and diesel are lower now in cash terms.

The freeze was welcomed by Steve Williams from the Road Haulage Association, which staged protests about fuel prices during the election campaign.

Mr Williams said: &quot;Obviously it's good news. We are having enough trouble as it is without a further increase in duty.&quot;

But he urged the government to go further and introduce a system which reduced duty if oil prices went beyond $60 a barrel, for example.

The government's general policy of imposing an inflation rise in fuel duty is designed to meet environmental commitments.

Friends of the Earth said it was extremely disappointed by Tuesday's decision, saying the cost of motoring had fallen by 6% in real terms since Labour came to power in 1997.

A spokesman said traffic levels had risen in the same period and road transport accounted for 22% of the UK's carbon dioxide emissions.

&quot;Coming just before the G8 summit, this sends the wrong signal about tackling climate change,&quot; he added.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4653175.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Violent offences top million mark</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Police figures show 1,035,046 violent incidents against the person, excluding sexual offences and robberies.

Total recorded crime fell 6% to 5.6m incidents, but gun crime was up 6%.

Minister Hazel Blears stressed overall crime fell, saying the apparent rise in violent crime merely reflected better reporting and recording of offences.

Ms Blears, a Home Office minister, also told the BBC that the separate British Crime Survey, which interviews people to ask if they have been crime victims, showed a decrease in violent crime.

But shadow home secretary David Davis said the police figures were &quot;further evidence that the government continues to fail on violent crime&quot;.

&quot;With violent crime continuing to spiral out of control, it beggars belief that the government's only response is to unleash 24-hour drinking on our town and city centres,&quot; he added in a reference to proposed drink law changes.

There was no great demand for extended drinking times, he told the BBC.

&quot;I see no reason to go ahead with 24 drinking until we've actually piloted, tested out some of the methods the government is proposing.&quot;

For the Lib Dems, Mark Oaten said violent crime was &quot;directly linked&quot; to drink.

&quot;Our concern is that extending opening times for up to 24 hours will make the problems of alcohol-related crime worse, not better,&quot; he said.

Ms Blears said the government had already promised to keep 24-hour licensing under review when it is introduced in November.

She rejected the call by Mr Davis to pilot the liberalisation in selected areas arguing people from outside would flood in to take advantage of longer drinking hours.

The police figures show there was a 20% fall in burglary and a 17% drop in car thefts. There were just under 11,000 gun crimes, up 6%, and 73 people were killed with guns over a 12 month period - five more than the previous year.

Sexual offences rose by 17% to 61,000 but this was said to be partly down to reforms of sex crime laws and efforts by police and politicians to encourage more victims to come forward.

The president of the Association of Chief Police Officers, Chris Fox, meanwhile has defended police detection rates of 26%.

He said policing was not just about catching criminals - it was about preventing crime in the first place.

&quot;There are millions of people who have not been a victim of crime that would have been if we hadn't focused on reducing crime,&quot; he said.

The government has also published the British Crime Survey, based on interviews with 45,000 people, which suggests violent crime is down 11%.

Home Secretary Charles Clarke said he was &quot;extremely encouraged&quot; by the &quot;very positive&quot; figures in the British Crime Survey - which the Home Office regards as more accurate.

&quot;Although the BCS records an 11% decrease in violent crime, I recognise that this remains an issue of concern for many people and the increase in police recorded violent crime contributes significantly to the fear of crime,&quot; he said.

Another estimate of crime in England and Wales published three weeks ago by the Home Office suggested there were 14.7 million crimes committed against children and adults in England and Wales in 2003-04.

Mr Clarke highlighted the government's Violent Crime Reduction Bill which he said would give new powers to police and local authorities to tackle violent criminals &quot;and ensure they are effectively punished&quot;.

&quot;We have made significant progress on violent crime, but I accept that more needs to be done and the government is determined to achieve further reductions,&quot; he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4700575.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-24</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair pays tribute to resilience</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He told the BBC Radio 4's Today programme Londoners' response had been &quot;extraordinary&quot; and that they would not be &quot;terrorised by terror&quot;.

He said the government would act with caution and not bring in strict new laws to boost security.

&quot;The British have a very great inner resilience,&quot; he said.

&quot;Several of the leaders at the (G8) summit commented to me how remarkable the British people are that they are simply not going to be terrorised by terror in this way,&quot; Mr Blair said.

&quot;I think that we will continue with our way of life, I genuinely believe that.

&quot;Even as we mourn the lives of those people killed so brutally and unnecessarily the sense, I think, and I hope, within the country, is to pull together and to make sure people can't divide us.&quot;

Security measures alone cannot protect the UK from attack and the underlying causes of terrorism must be &quot;pulled up by the roots&quot;, Mr Blair said.

&quot;All the surveillance in the world&quot; cannot stop people going on a bus to blow up innocent people.

He said the &quot;dreadful perversion of the true faith of Islam&quot; must be tackled.

And he argued the &quot;worst terrorist atrocity&quot; - the 11 September attacks - came before the Iraq war.

The prime minister returned to Downing Street from the G8 summit on Friday evening to chair a meeting of Cobra, the government's emergencies committee.

In the interview, broadcast at 0810 BST on Saturday, he said it was inevitable terrorists would try to attack the UK.

&quot;It's just tragic that they have succeeded,&quot; he says.

He praised the resilience of Londoners who pulled together as they mourned those killed in Thursday's blasts.

Mr Blair said the terrorists would have won if the UK became an illiberal society.

Instead, it was proud of being open, liberal, multi-racial and multi-religious, with strong restrictions on government powers.

The prime minister said debate will continue on measures such as identity cards to help counter illegal immigration and crime.

But he argues: &quot;Probably with this type of terrorism the solution cannot only be the security measures. I have never really doubted that myself.&quot;

Ultimately, the government had to protect people but &quot;the underlying issues have to be dealt with too in terms of trying to get rid of this dreadful perversion of the true faith of Islam.&quot;

That meant people within the Muslim community standing up and saying they abhorred violence which was &quot;wholly inconsistent&quot; with their faith, he said.

He welcomes the fact that such efforts are already taking place.

Mr Blair says there also has to be a drive to create a fairer and more just world and to foster peace in the Middle East.

Respect MP George Galloway has said Londoners have &quot;paid the price&quot; of the government failing to heed warnings that military action in Iraq and Afghanistan would increase risks of an attack on the UK.

But Mr Blair said the bombers in Madrid had been planning further attacks before they were caught even after the government had changed.

And the 11 September attacks in America had been the reason for the war in Afghanistan.

After the high of winning the Olympics and the tragedy of the blasts, Mr Blair says he has gone through an &quot;extraordinary gamut of emotions&quot;.

He says there is nothing more awful than seeing death and destruction - not just because he is a national leader but because of thoughts for grieving families.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4666311.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-25</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | New laws target terror training</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>New offences could cover people going to terrorist camps overseas or finding out how to build a bomb through the internet, said the Home Office.

Other proposals include making it illegal to incite terrorism indirectly by &quot;glorifying&quot; bombings.

The Home Office stresses the plans were in train before the London bombs. It will consult opposition MPs next week.

The new Anti-Terrorism Bill will also include introducing a new offence of &quot;acts preparatory to terrorism&quot;.

Home Office Minister Hazel Blears said: &quot;We want to make sure we can intervene early enough to disrupt people who are planning acts of terrorism and get convictions.&quot;

The bill is expected in the autumn and the legislation could be on the statute books by next summer.

The timetable is the same as originally planned for new anti-terror legislation before the 7 July attacks.

But ministers say they will take notice if the police and security services want the measures sooner, or if they want further powers.

Home Secretary Charles Clarke outlined details of the plans in a letter to his opposition counterparts, Conservative David Davis and Liberal Democrat Mark Oaten.

The new offence against terrorist training would cover teaching both in the UK and abroad.

It would target people &quot;providing or receiving training in the use of hazardous substances and in other methods or techniques for terrorist purposes&quot;.

Former Metropolitan Police chief Lord Stevens has suggested 3,000 British-born or British-based people have passed through al-Qaeda training camps.

But Ms Blears said the new offence would only cover those given training in the future rather than being used retrospectively.

The plan for new laws against &quot;acts preparatory to terrorism&quot; has been long debated.

In his letter to opposition parties, Mr Clarke said it could be used where precise details of terrorists' plans were not known or even decided by the plotters themselves.

&quot;There may be clear evidence of an intention to commit a serious terrorist act,&quot; he said.

&quot;For example, instructions on how to build a bomb, evidence of intention to acquire chemicals and evidence that terrorist related websites have been accessed.&quot;

But the government says that looking at terrorist-themed websites would not necessarily be a criminal act under the new training offence.

The new incitement offence could be used against extremist preachers or others making public speeches.

Inciting terrorism directly is already against the law and the new law would try to cover indirect incitement.

Ms Blears said: &quot;It would apply where people would seek to glorify terrorist activity, perhaps, for example, saying 'isn't this a marvellous thing that this has happened' and 'these people are martyrs'.&quot;

She acknowledged there would be &quot;intense&quot; discussions about striking the right balance between freedom of speech and protecting the public.

Opposition parties have echoed the government's hopes of consensus on the new laws.

Conservative shadow home secretary David Davis said the plans were a &quot;sensible start&quot;.

He supported the principle behind the plans but said the details would need to be debated to ensure effective laws.

Liberal Democrat spokesman Mark Oaten said raised concerns about the new offence of &quot;indirect incitement to commit terrorist acts&quot;.

He said he wanted to ensure the offence could be properly defined, and was also worried about potential implications for civil liberties.

But the Lib Dems were &quot;fully comfortable&quot; with the other two proposed new offences, he said.

Other changes which could appear in the new bill include:
• Closing a loophole which means it is not an offence to plan an explosion overseas
• Extending terrorism stop and search powers to cover bays and estuaries
• Preventing banned organisations avoiding the rules by changing their names</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4687189.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-26</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair's make-up bill tops £1,800</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Between 1999 and 2005 Downing Street paid £1,050.22 for cosmetics for Mr Blair's media appearances.

Another £791.20 was spent over the past two years on make-up artists.

But this seems modest compared with Irish premier Bertie Ahern, who is reported to have spent more than £115,000 on his appearance since 1997.

The Independent reported in June that Mr Ahern had spent 28,000 euros (£19,000) on make-up in the past year, and said his office had confirmed that since 1997 Mr Ahern's appearance had cost taxpayers 167,000 euros (£115,895).

The figures relating to Mr Blair's expenditure on cosmetics were revealed on Thursday by government whip Lord Bassam of Brighton, in answer to a Parliamentary question by Tory Lord Hanningfield.

The written Parliamentary answer was given out on the final day before MPs and peers broke for the summer.

The day was also marked by an attempted bomb attack on London transport, similar to the attacks carried out on 7 July.

The Sunday Times suggested Mr Blair's use of make-up spiralled during stressful periods, such as the Iraq war.

It said his spending on cosmetics peaked between 2003 and 2004, when the prime minister was being asked to justify intelligence reports on weapons of mass destruction.

There was also speculation during the last election campaign about whether Mr Blair had been using fake tan.

But the brands and products used by Mr Blair were not revealed in the Parliamentary answer.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4711689.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-27</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Hoon suggests compulsory voting</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Commons leader says a move towards compulsory voting is necessary to reinvigorate UK democracy.

The proposals, which would give voters a &quot;none of the above&quot; choice, follow the 61% general election turnout.

But the Conservatives' constitutional affairs spokesman, Oliver Heald, said: &quot;There is little public support to make it a criminal offence not to vote.&quot;

And Mr Hoon's fellow Labour minister James Plaskitt said the plans &quot;amount to a cop out&quot;.

Mr Hoon argued that people appreciated their MP's role in doing constituency work, but they had difficulty translating this to their role at a national level.

During the election campaign he had met electors who claimed they would not be voting because they could not see the connection between their concerns about schools and hospitals and casting their ballot, he said.

&quot;We need to get people more engaged in political processes, to explain, to take through the argument from the local level,&quot; he told BBC2's the Daily Politics.

&quot;The idea of having a debate about compulsory voting is to get that engagement ... these are my ideas, my thoughts.&quot;

Compulsory voting is already in place in countries including Australia, Austria, Belgium and Greece.

Mr Hoon said British people could expect a &quot;modest fine&quot; for failing to vote, although he steered away from saying he wanted the scheme to be completely compulsory.

&quot;Rather like the introduction of seat belt legislation - if the idea goes out that it's something that is required of people, actually they adjust to it very quickly,&quot; he said.

Asked if the ballot would include a box for &quot;none of the above&quot; politicians, Mr Hoon said: &quot;I think that's absolutely vital.

&quot;People do in effect abstain by spoiling their ballot papers.&quot;

While it is compulsory to be registered as a voter, it is estimated that more than 2.5m people had failed to do so, meaning turnout was even lower, said Mr Hoon.

Mr Heald said: &quot;There is little public support to make it a criminal offence not to vote.

&quot;At a time when anti-social behaviour and violent crime is out of control, the police have better things to do. The challenge for politicians is to excite electors with their ideas.&quot;

Roger Knapman, leader of the UK Independence Party, said the move was &quot;typical New Labour control freakery&quot;.

&quot;Democracy can only be built by consent, not by compulsion,&quot; he said.

&quot;If the government was truly interested in democratic participation, then it would do everything it could to show that it was relevant, responsive and most of all actually cared about and understood the lives of ordinary voters.&quot;

Mr Plaskitt, a work and pensions minister, said: &quot;I think it amounts to a cop-out for the political parties collectively.

&quot;If the voters are drifting away from participating then they are actually telling us something about the offer that all the political parties are making to the electorate and they are telling us they are not satisfied with that.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4648095.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-28</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Former PM Sir Edward Heath dies</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>His successor Lady Thatcher said he was a &quot;political giant&quot; and &quot;in every sense the first modern Conservative leader&quot;.

Sir Edward, who was knighted in 1992, won his first seat for the Tories in Bexley in 1950 and led the 1970-74 Conservative government.

He took Britain into what was then the European Economic Community, but lost his leadership of the Tory party to Margaret Thatcher in 1975.

Lady Thatcher said he was the first modern leader for the party, &quot;by his humble background, by his grammar school education and by the fact of his democratic election&quot;.

Prime Minister Tony Blair said: &quot;He was a man of great integrity and beliefs he held firmly from which he never wavered.

&quot;He will be remembered by all who knew him as a political leader of great stature and significance.&quot;

Earlier on Sunday Sir Edward's spokesman had revealed he was gravely ill and receiving medical attention at home.

The former premier had celebrated his 89th birthday with a party at his home in Salisbury a week ago.

Sir Edward's term in office was blighted by industrial action and problems with the economy.

With the country on a three-day week and rubbish piling up in the streets, the miners threatened to bring his government down.

Industrial unrest, combined with economic difficulties, led to the Tories being pushed from power in February 1974.

Sir Edward never forgave Mrs Thatcher for ousting him as leader and refused to serve in her cabinet.

When asked in a TV interview if it was true that when Mrs Thatcher was herself deposed he said &quot;rejoice, rejoice,&quot; he joked: &quot;I think I said it three times.&quot;

After more than 50 years as an MP he retired from politics in 2001.

His former colleague Lord Walker said history would &quot;give him a high rating&quot;, adding that he was a &quot;very great man and an enormous patriot&quot;.

Former Labour chancellor Denis Healey said Sir Edward had been a friend for many years after the pair met at Oxford University.

&quot;I liked him very much and I think he represented the sensible wing of the Tory Party but of course like others, Ken Clarke and Geoffrey Howe in particular, they could just not win over the extreme right-wing Conservatives.&quot;

In 2003, Sir Edward's health deteriorated while he was on holiday in Austria.

He was being treated for a minor stomach upset at Salzburg's main hospital when tests revealed he was suffering from a pulmonary embolism - a blood clot on the lung.

Sir Edward, a bachelor, was famed for his love of music and sailing, in which he competed at international level.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4691051.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-29</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Mayor blames Middle East policy</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The London mayor told BBC News he had no sympathy with the bombers and he opposed all violence.

But he argued that the attacks would not have happened had Western powers left Arab nations free to decide their own affairs after World War I.

Instead, they had often supported unsavoury governments in the region.

Mr Livingstone was asked on BBC Radio 4's Today programme what he thought had motivated the bombers.

He replied: &quot;I think you've just had 80 years of western intervention into predominantly Arab lands because of the western need for oil.

&quot;We've propped up unsavoury governments, we've overthrown ones we didn't consider sympathetic.

&quot;And I think the particular problem we have at the moment is that in the 1980s... the Americans recruited and trained Osama Bin Laden, taught him how to kill, to make bombs, and set him off to kill the Russians and drive them out of Afghanistan.

&quot;They didn't give any thought to the fact that once he'd done that he might turn on his creators.&quot;

Mr Livingstone said Western governments had been so terrified of losing their fuel supplies that they had kept intervening in the Middle East.

He argued: &quot;If at the end of the First World War we had done what we promised the Arabs, which was to let them be free and have their own governments, and kept out of Arab affairs, and just bought their oil, rather than feeling we had to control the flow of oil, I suspect this wouldn't have arisen.&quot;

He attacked double standards by Western nations, such as the initial welcome given when Saddam Hussein came to power in Iraq.

There was also the &quot;running sore&quot; of the Palestinian/Israeli conflict.

&quot;A lot of young people see the double standards, they see what happens in Guantanamo Bay, and they just think that there isn't a just foreign policy,&quot; said Mr Livingstone.

Mr Livingstone said he did not just denounce suicide bombers.

He also denounced &quot;those governments which use indiscriminate slaughter to advance their foreign policy, as we have occasionally seen with the Israeli government bombing areas from which a terrorist group will have come, irrespective of the casualties it inflicts, women, children and men&quot;.

He continued: &quot;Under foreign occupation and denied the right to vote, denied the right to run your own affairs, often denied the right to work for three generations, I suspect that if it had happened here in England, we would have produced a lot of suicide bombers ourselves.&quot;

Mr Livingstone also criticised parts of the media for giving too much publicity to certain figures who were &quot;totally unrepresentative&quot; of British Muslims.

Mr Livingstone later took questions about the bombings from members of the London Assembly.

He said the unity shown by Londoners in the wake of the attacks was a commemoration to those who died and showed a determination not to give in to terrorism.

The mayor said most of the Tube would be working normally by the end of the week and the Underground should be working as before by the end of the month.

But he warned Tube users they would have to put up with the kind of disruption caused by packages left on trains which was seen during past IRA bombing campaigns.

There had been &quot;very, very little&quot; cancellations of existing hotel bookings and flights to London, said Mr Livingstone.

But there had been an immediate drop in new bookings for long-haul flights and hotels and a &quot;dramatic reduction&quot; in British people bringing children into the capital.

Before this month's attacks, the levels of American tourists visiting London were only running at 75% of the numbers seen before the 11 September 2001 attacks in the US.

One way to counter the &quot;turn down&quot; in tourist trade was to attract more people from the UK and other parts of Europe, said Mr Livingstone.

Mr Livingstone said he did not have information about hotels raising prices for people trying to stay in London after the attacks.

But if there was evidence of &quot;profiteering&quot;, the Greater London Authority would &quot;name and shame&quot; those hotels involved and refuse to do business with them in the future, he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4698963.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-30</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Byers admits untruth on Railtrack</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He told the High Court his evidence to a Commons sub-committee was not accurate. He apologised but said he had not been trying to conceal any plot.

Mr Byer's words came on the last day in the case of Railtrack shareholders who are claiming compensation.

About 50,000 shareholders claim the government deliberately allowed the rail infrastructure firm to fail in October 2001, and are demanding £157m in compensation.

When Mr Byers was questioned by a Commons sub-committee, he said he was not aware of a change in Railtrack's status being discussed before 25 July 2001.

But in the court on Thursday he was challenged over this version of events by the shareholders' barrister - who produced documentary evidence showing the work had started.

They included e-mails and notes from Department of Transport officials showing that taking Railtrack into administration had been one of the options being discussed as early as June.

Quizzed by Keith Rowley, QC for Railtrack shareholders, Mr Byers admitted his answer to MPs had been untrue.

&quot;It is true to say there was work going on, so, yes, that was untrue,&quot; he said.

Questioning Mr Byers again about the &quot;welter of documentation&quot; on the options for Railtrack, Mr Rowley, QC said: &quot;You could not possibly have believed that the answer you gave ... was true, could you?&quot;

&quot;I accept this is not an accurate statement,&quot; said Mr Byers.

He was asked if it was &quot;deliberately not an accurate statement&quot;.

Mr Byers replied: &quot;It was such a long time ago, I cannot remember, but it is not a truthful statement and I apologise for that.

&quot;I cannot remember the motives behind it.&quot;

The MP later told the court he had been under pressure during the hearing and had not set out to conceal any conspiracy or plot.

Responding to Mr Byers' admission, shadow transport secretary Alan Duncan said whatever the verdict in court, the government &quot;will still have to face the verdict of parliament&quot;.

&quot;I make no judgement about the court case but it seems from all the evidence that is emerging that this is a growing scandal of government from which Stephen Byers and Gordon Brown have no escape.

&quot;If, as it seems today, Stephen Byers lied to a parliamentary committee, not only is that a disgrace in itself but it shows that their plans for Railtrack were deeply devious and could be a scandal of enormous proportions.

&quot;Whatever happens in court this issue is not going to go away.&quot;

Mr Byers resigned as transport secretary in May 2002.

At the time, he said he had tried to &quot;behave honourably&quot;, adding &quot;the people that know me best know I am not a liar&quot;.

Mr Byers has told the High Court the Treasury had concerns about ending Railtrack and removing the role of shareholders.

He said Chancellor Gordon Brown had a list of 10 conditions to be met before he would agree to Railtrack being changed to a non-shareholder company.

The list was internally nicknamed &quot;The 10 Commandments&quot;, he said.

At a meeting on 19 September 2001 - three weeks before Railtrack went into administration - Tony Blair told Mr Byers he had to talk to the chancellor if he wanted more money to fund the company.

But the court heard it was left to Mr Byers to decide whether to take the company into administration if he decided to refuse Railtrack's request for more money - subject to the Treasury conditions.

Mr Byers said he had worked with his officials to see if the conditions could be met.

On Thursday, the shareholders QC, Keith Rowley, about when he made up his mind.

&quot;I suggest there was a clear strategy, developed by you and your officials, accepting that Railtrack would not immediately collapse but might fall over in a year or two, to force Railtrack into administration by ensuring you held all the cards and all other options were closed off,&quot; said Mr Rowley.

But Mr Byers replied that his discussions with officials were &quot;sensible contingency planning&quot; in case it was decided to refuse to give the company more funds.

There is one more witness to be heard in the court case and lawyers for both sides will spend most of next week delivering their closing speeches.

The judgement in the case is not expected to be delivered until after the court's summer break.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4683927.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-31</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | PM meets police and intelligence</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The prime minister has indicated the issue of using phone intercept evidence in court will be discussed.

The meeting comes exactly two weeks after 52 people plus four bombers died in attacks on three trains and a bus.

Meanwhile, Pakistan is denying British newspaper reports over the supposed arrest of Haroon Rashid Aswad.

A number of newspapers reported the British Muslim had been held during raids on religious schools in Lahore.

Doubt has also been cast over the allegations that he entered Britain and left again shortly before the London bombings.

Discussions of tactics to prevent future attacks will dominate Mr Blair's agenda on Thursday.

A key issue is phone tap evidence, with the UK one of the few Western nations not to allow its admission in court.

Answering a question from Conservative leader Michael Howard at Wednesday's Prime Minister's Questions, the prime minister said he was happy to consider the idea.

&quot;My own view has always been that if we possibly can use intercept evidence, we should because of the obvious value it can provide in certain cases,&quot; he told MPs.

&quot;The difficulty is that up to now we have been advised by the security services that the disadvantages outweigh the benefits.

&quot;However, I think in the light of what has happened, it is obviously sensible to go back and consult them again.&quot;

He added that as a &quot;matter of principle&quot; he would prefer to have the use of intercept evidence in court proceedings available.

Intelligence officers and senior policemen have tended to be opposed to the use of phone tap evidence in court, fearing that secret methods could be exposed.

Former M15 officer Michael Flint told BBC News the security services are not equipped to cope with the new kind of threat.

&quot;You need people with ethnic backgrounds to conduct the surveillance operations. The people that they had before, white young males and females, would simply stand out.&quot;

He said in the four or five years of the current raised threat there had not been time to build up close links with intelligence services in the Middle East and South Asia.

Professor Anthony Glees, director of Brunel University's Centre for Intelligence and Security Services, said intelligence officers needed to return to &quot;elementary tasks&quot; like monitoring subversion, and other &quot;Cold War tactics&quot;.

Mr Blair has also said he wants an international conference about issues arising from Islamic extremism.

He told MPs: &quot;Though the terrorists will use all sorts of issues to justify what they do, the roots of it do go deep, they are often not found in this country alone therefore international action is also necessary.&quot;

On Wednesday Home Secretary Charles Clarke revealed he has asked the Home Office, Foreign Office and the intelligence agencies to establish a full database of extremists.

Anyone wanting to enter the UK would be checked against the list - and if they are on it they may be refused permission to enter the country.

In a statement on the aftermath of the London bombing, Mr Clarke also said he planned a new offence of &quot;indirect incitement to terrorism&quot;, to add to the current offence of direct incitement.

He said it &quot;targets those who, while not directly inciting, glorify and condone terrorist acts knowing full well that the effect on their listeners will be to encourage them to turn to terrorism&quot;.

Mr Clarke told MPs he wanted to apply more widely the home secretary's powers to exclude an individual from the UK if their presence is deemed &quot;not conducive to the public interest&quot;.

&quot;I intend to draw up a list of unacceptable behaviours which would fall into this - for example preaching, running websites or writing articles which are intended to foment or provoke terrorism.&quot;

The government has also announced that task force to tackle Islamic extremism &quot;head on&quot; is being set up in the wake of the bombings.

On Thursday, victims of the London attacks will be remembered at the British Medical Association in Tavistock Square - where a bus was blown up, killing 14 people.

A service will take place in the courtyard of the BMA's headquarters where many of the injured people were treated.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4701823.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-32</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | 'No internal inquiry' into blasts</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>He said &quot;now is not the time&quot; for an inquiry, but for a decision on what legal steps were needed against terror.

And he denied proposed new anti-terror measures were &quot;slamming the stable door after the horse had bolted&quot;.

A newspaper says MI5 had assessed one of the bombers, Mohammad Sidique Khan, but decided he was not a threat.

The Sunday Times said the 30-year-old teaching assistant had been subject to a routine threat assessment when his name cropped up during an investigation last year.

However, officers apparently decided that as he was only &quot;indirectly linked&quot; to that investigation, he posed no threat and no action was taken.

Khan, from Dewsbury, West Yorkshire, killed himself and six other passengers in the Edgware Road bombing on the London underground.

Hasib Hussain, 18, from Holbeck, Leeds was responsible for the Number 30 bus bombing, in which 13 people died; Shehzad Tanweer, 22, from Beeston in Leeds for the Aldgate Tube blast, which killed six, and Germaine Lindsay, 19, from Aylesbury, Buckinghamshire, for the King's Cross Tube explosion in which 26 people were killed.

The London bombings did not mean that the intelligence and security services had failed or that existing laws were wrong, Lord Falconer said.

&quot;We have got to learn the lessons and that is why we are bringing forward these new laws. Now is not the time for any form of inquiry,&quot; he said.

&quot;I think all the political parties are agreed that the right course at the moment is to focus on what further steps need to be taken in relation to the law but also getting to the root of that evil ideology that is driving this terrorism.&quot;

The new anti-terror laws proposed by the government are due to be discussed by Home Secretary Charles Clarke and his opposition counterparts on Monday.

The new Anti-Terrorism Bill - in train before the London attacks - is expected in the autumn and the legislation could be on the statute books by next summer.

Mr Clarke has already outlined details of the plans in a letter to Tory David Davis and Liberal Democrat Mark Oaten, in an attempt to gain consensus.

The planned new offences would outlaw &quot;indirect incitement&quot; and &quot;acts preparatory&quot; to, and &quot;providing or receiving training&quot; in terrorism.

Lord Falconer told BBC News that under the new laws, people &quot;attacking the values of the West&quot; and &quot;glorifying the acts of suicide bombers&quot; would be imprisoned for &quot;long periods&quot; and &quot;deported wherever possible&quot;.

But no law could stop terrorism altogether, he added.

&quot;The evil ideology driving this is getting to the hearts and minds of a very small number of people,&quot; Lord Falconer said.

&quot;We need to be effective in dealing with them... to make it absolutely clear there will be no compromise.&quot;

Shadow home secretary David Davis said he hoped for &quot;a pretty constructive outcome&quot;.

The government had &quot;done a good job in terms of crystallising what we are trying to do to stop people inciting young men, or anybody for that matter, to terrorism&quot;, he added.

Mr Davis also called for additional proposals to allow phone taps and other intercept evidence in court.

Labour former cabinet minister Clare Short said it was vital that the laws did not prevent people discussing the political situation.

She warned that the prime minister's wife Cherie Blair could face prosecution if anti-incitement laws were not carefully drafted.

Mrs Blair apologised three years ago after saying some young Palestinians felt they had &quot;no hope&quot; but to blow themselves up.

&quot;The problem is going to be in finding the right words and implementing it in a way which is really dealing with people who are inciting and not preventing honest discussion of the underlying causes of this horrendous political situation the world is in now,&quot; said Ms Short.

&quot;The proposal is that indirect incitement should consist of statements made with the intention of encouraging other people to commit terrorist acts.

&quot;That most certainly is not the sort of thing that Clare Short is referring to.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4690459.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-33</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Bombers' ideology 'evil' says PM</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Such violence was not in response to any particular policy or founded in any injustice, but in a &quot;fanaticism&quot; that had to be confronted, he said.

Some Labour MPs, including ex-minister Clare Short, said they had &quot;no doubt&quot; the attacks were linked to Iraq.

Meanwhile, police have raided another house in Beeston, Leeds, near the home of London bomber Shehzad Tanweer.

The bomb attacks killed 51 people and injured hundreds more. The four bombers are also thought to have died.

&quot;If it is the plight of the Palestinians that drives them, why, every time it looks as if Israel and Palestine are making progress, does the same ideology perpetrate an outrage that turns hope back into despair?

&quot;If it is Afghanistan that motivates them, why blow up innocent Afghans on their way to their first-ever election?

&quot;If it is Iraq that motivates them, why is the same ideology killing Iraqis by terror in defiance of an elected Iraqi government?

&quot;What was 11 September 2001 the reprisal for?&quot;

But some Labour left-wingers said there was a link between the Iraq war and the attacks.

John McDonnell, Labour MP for Hayes and Harlington, said it was &quot;intellectually unsustainable&quot; to say the war in Iraq had not motivated the bombers.

&quot;For as long as Britain remains in occupation of Iraq the terrorist recruiters will have the argument they seek to attract more susceptible young recruits to the bomb team. Britain must withdraw now.&quot;

And in an interview for GMTV's Sunday programme, Labour ex-minister Clare Short, who resigned over the Iraq war, said she &quot;had no doubt&quot; the atrocities were linked to Iraq.

&quot;We are implicit in the slaughter of large numbers of civilians in Iraq and supporting a Middle East policy that for the Palestinians creates this sense of double standards - that feeds anger,&quot; she said.

Earlier on Saturday, the family of one of the bombers said he may have been &quot;brainwashed&quot; into carrying it out.

In a statement, they described 30-year-old teacher Mohammad Sidique Khan as &quot;a kind and caring member of our family&quot; and appealed to the public for information.

The family of another of the bombers, 18-year-old Hasib Hussain, have also expressed their &quot;devastation&quot; at events.

British police have turned their attention to finding those who may have helped the bombers carry out last Thursday's attacks.

Officers are searching a house in Leeds linked to Egyptian biochemist Magdi Mahmoud al-Nashar, who has been arrested in Cairo.

Egypt's interior minister said press reports linking Mr al-Nashar to al-Qaeda were &quot;groundless&quot; and based on a hasty conclusion.

Three of the bombers were from West Yorkshire - Hussain, from Holbeck in Leeds; Khan, from Dewsbury, and Tanweer, 22, of Beeston, Leeds, and police are searching their homes.

The wreckage of the number 30 bus, which had its roof ripped off in the blast that killed 13 in Tavistock Square, was taken away for further forensic examination on Saturday.

On Friday Britain's top Muslims issued a joint statement of condemnation branding the London bombings &quot;utterly criminal, totally reprehensible, and absolutely un-Islamic&quot;.

But Britain's highest ranking Asian police officer, Tarique Ghaffur, said Muslims and their leaders must do more than just condemn the bombings.

Mr Ghaffur, the Metropolitan Police Assistant Commissioner, urged members of the community to inform on potential terrorists and their supporters.

The police would have to engage better with minorities - but the minorities would have to take the first step, he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4688909.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-34</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Internet given election verdict</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Hansard Society study points to research suggesting online activity has doubled since the 2001 polls and has made voters feel better informed.

But still only 15% of the population went online to get information about the election, it says.

The report says the internet was used too much as a &quot;one-way&quot; conversation.

The election followed the increased use of online campaigning in last year's US presidential elections.

The success of Democrat Howard Dean in using the internet to attract donations fuelled speculation of a surge in online campaigns in the UK.

But Steve Ward, from the Oxford Internet Institute, says people should not expect the US experience to be repeated in the UK.

He argues the British political system offers fewer incentives for using the internet, whereas US presidential candidates have to build campaigns from scratch for the primaries.

&quot;In the UK, well-entrenched party machines and the relatively localised nature of election campaigning mean that currently traditional communication tools work just as well if not better,&quot; he says.

Dr Ward, who wrote an essay for the new report, says an NOP opinion polls suggests the internet made a bigger impact at this election than in 2001:
• Out of all internet users, about 13% sent or received emails about the election in 2005, compared to 5% in 2001
• 17% used the internet for election information on at least a few occasions, up from 7%
• Figures for online activities such as discussion, opinion polls, volunteering and donations are still small but are more than double 2001 levels
• 18% of those questioned this year said the internet had helped them make a better informed choice and 19% said that it helped them make up their mind - compared to 6% in 2001.

Dr Ward adds: &quot;Internet users may be as likely to vote today as they were four years ago, but the overall importance of the internet for the election has greatly increased.&quot;

At the launch , Stephen Coleman, professor in e-democracy at Oxford University, said there had been no surge in internet election use.

Instead, there had been an incremental and pragmatic use in the campaign of a medium used in other ways for the rest of the year.

Prof Coleman said there were three main uses of the internet during the election: activities unconnected with the poll; people going online to avoid the election and find other news; and those using the internet to find out more about the vote.

But he said only 3% of people expected to have contact with their MP once the election was over.

&quot;There can be little doubt about the potential of the internet as a medium of democratic interactivity,&quot; says Prof Coleman.

He says: &quot;But unless and until parties, politicians and pundits abandon the one-way conversation that has come to characterise contemporary politics, no amount of broadband gee-whizzery will save them from the collective yawns of the demos.&quot;

Prof Coleman said the 2001 election had seen the emergence of blogs and other discussion outside traditional scripted politics.

If the political machines tried to grasp those tools too much there was a risk the public might &quot;migrate elsewhere&quot;, he warned.

New Liberal Democrat MP Lynne Featherstone, a long-time blogger, said online campaigning was just one of the tools she used.

But she suggested it had played a substantial part in overturning a 26,000 Labour majority in Hornsey and Wood Green over the course of two elections.

The BBC News website's election output received 28 million page views on the day after the election, with more than 3 million people looking at at least one election page.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4654243.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-35</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Clarke 'shocked bombers British'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mr Clarke said the attacks were a &quot;clarion call&quot; for everybody in the UK to defend their society rather than assume &quot;we are all OK&quot;.

The Muslim community especially must &quot;stand out&quot; against the ideology which promotes bombings, he told BBC News.

He said he would consider all means necessary - including deportation - against those fomenting terrorism.

Speaking ahead of an emergency EU summit about security measures in Brussels, Mr Clarke said it was &quot;a central hypothesis&quot; that the bombers were part of a wider network.

Mr Clarke said there were organisations who wanted to destroy the fundamental structure of UK democracy.

&quot;I think that is the clarion call to us, to us as politicians, as broadcasters, to faith leaders, to lawyers, to everybody, to say we have to fight for this society we have, rather than just coasting along and assuming it's all OK.&quot;

Mr Clarke said the right balance was needed between civil liberties and security.

The belief that &quot;home-grown terrorism&quot; was to blame for the bombings means intelligence must be improved, despite the &quot;first class&quot; job done by the police and security services, he said.

During the EU talks in Brussels, Mr Clarke will push for European agencies to share more intelligence information.

But he argued the anti-terror strategy had to address the fact that ideology, not poverty, was the driving force behind such attacks.

&quot;It's ensuring that the whole of the Muslim community, supported by the whole of the society, stands out against this sort of belief.&quot;

Mr Clarke said he was encouraged by the Muslim community's response.

He said he was looking directly at people who &quot;preach hatred&quot;, with deportation one option.

The home secretary said the UK had to assume other people were prepared to carry out attacks.

Intelligence had to be at the centre of addressing that problem, he argued.

Former Metropolitan Police chief Lord Stevens has suggested that three thousand people, who are now in Britain have trained in al-Qaeda camps.

Mr Clarke said he did not accept that figure but a &quot;large number&quot; of people had attended such camps.

&quot;But only a very few come to this cataclysmic decision that those four individuals did on Thursday,&quot; he added.

Tony Blair on Wednesday met a delegation of Muslim MPs to discuss the discovery of the suspected bombers.

The Muslim Council of Britain says it reacted with &quot;anguish, shock and horror&quot; to news that British-born Islamic youths were involved in the attacks.

The council's secretary-general, Sir Iqbal Sacranie, said: &quot;Nothing in Islam can ever justify the evil actions of the bombers.&quot;

Shahid Malik, whose Dewsbury constituency was the scene of police raids in the bombing investigation, said the Muslim community faced a &quot;massive wake-up call&quot;.

He told BBC News after his meeting with Mr Blair: &quot;The challenge is straightforward - that those voices that we have tolerated will no longer be tolerated, whether they be on the streets, in the schools, in the youth clubs, in a mosque, in a corner, in a house.

&quot;We need to go beyond condemning - we need to confront.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4677995.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-36</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | US is key to climate deal - Blair</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Alongside Africa, the UK prime minister has made the issue a key plank of his ambitions for Britain's G8 presidency.

But the US, which refused to sign up to the Kyoto agreement on carbon emissions, wants the focus instead to be put on cleaner technology.

A new leak of the text to be discussed at next week's G8 summit suggests key areas are disputed by the US.

The Guardian newspaper says a leaked version of the communiqué shows the US objects to the part of the text saying there is strong evidence that global warming is happening and human activity is contributing to it.

All G8 countries agree that global energy demands are likely to rise by 60% over the next 25 years, producing more greenhouse gases, says the report.

But the US disagrees with a sentence saying: &quot;But we know that we need to slow, stop and then reverse growth in greenhouse gases to reduce our exposure to potentially serious economic, environmental and security risks.&quot;

UK ministers say the only document which matters is the one which emerges from the summit at Gleneagles.

And Environment Secretary Margaret Beckett said: &quot;The UK is in no doubt about the strength of scientific evidence on climate change.

&quot;But the theology is less important than action. It would be really worthwhile if we could get an action plan that moves us all towards a shared goal of a low carbon economy.&quot;

The US is the world's largest producer of greenhouse gases.

Mr Bush has conceded that greenhouse gases are creating a &quot;long-term problem that we have got to deal with&quot;.

He says scientists have to find a way to &quot;drive better, to have better engines for our cars and different fuel sources for cars&quot;.

Appearing on MTV Mr Blair said: &quot;The only solution to this is one that includes America. If America is outside there isn't a solution.

&quot;What I am trying to do at the G8 is say: 'America is not going to sign the Kyoto Treaty, let's leave that to one side'.&quot;

Mr Blair stressed that the US was spending more on developing new clean energy technologies than any other nation and that was the direction that they now had to go in.

&quot;Can I get agreement on that? I don't know but I'm going to try,&quot; he said.

Asked if Mr Bush was just wrong on climate change, Mr Blair replied: &quot;It is possible for any of us to be wrong in positions of power.&quot;

Seated alongside Bob Geldof, Mr Blair was also asked about his other key priority for Britain's G8 presidency - debt reduction and increased aid to Africa.

The prime minister added: &quot;Africa has been a passion of mine. Concern about development was, in part, what brought me into politics.

&quot;Thirty years ago, I guess I was the age of most people here. Thirty years later, I am in a position to do something about it.&quot;

All Eyes On Tony is due to be screened on MTV on Friday.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4639261.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-37</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Asylum removals 'falling short'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>In September 2004 Tony Blair said monthly removals should exceed rejected applications by the end of 2005.

But according to the National Audit Office (NAO), the immigration authorities are struggling to meet the prime minister's demands.

Immigration Minister Tony McNulty said the government had upped removals and cut asylum applications significantly.

&quot;We remain committed to our aim of removing more people on a monthly basis by the end of 2005 than there are new unfounded claims,&quot; he added.

&quot;In 1996 the number of removals was equivalent to only 20% of predicted unfounded claims, now that proportion is around 50%.&quot;

Problems found by the NAO included delays in obtaining travel documents, poor co-ordination between different branches of the system and insufficient use of an existing assisted voluntary return programme.

The NAO's report 'Returning Failed Asylum Applicants' notes that between 1994 and May 2004 363,000 asylum applications were rejected but just 79,500 people removed - leaving 283,500.

It notes that some of those still in the country would have been granted leave to remain or would now be able to stay thanks to EU expansion - and some might have left the UK voluntarily.

In May 2004 the database of the Immigration and Nationality Directorate (IND) identified 155,000 failed applicants as potentially removable, although that figure excludes cases which predate the database's introduction in 2000.

Neither figure incorporates people who overstayed their leave to remain in the UK, a number that has not been quantified.

The NAO report says that in the five year period from 2000/1 to 2004/5 the IND increased the number of failed applicants being returned to their country or origin or a safe third country by 35% up from 8,960 to 12,110.

But the removal or voluntary return of 1,000 a month in 2004/5 was significantly less than the number of unsuccessful applications, which averaged around 2,150 each month.

The NAO noted that the IND spent £300m in 2003 to 2004 on removals and voluntary returns; £308m on supporting failed applicants and legal costs associated with applicants appealing against being turned down were on top of that bill.

Edward Leigh, the Conservative MP who chairs the Commons public accounts committee for which the NAO reports, said: &quot;It is shocking that IND cannot give a solid estimate of how many failed applicants are still in the UK.

&quot;But the NAO tells us it could have been as many as 283,000 in May 2004 - which means an even higher number today.&quot;

NAO chief Sir John Bourn said: &quot;The Immigration and Nationality Directorate has made progress but needs to do a better job to track and manage cases and do more to encourage failed asylum applicants to return home voluntarily.&quot;

Sir Andrew Green, chairman of Migrationwatch UK, said: &quot;The security implications of this are clearly serious. The chaotic state of our asylum and immigration system becomes daily more apparent.&quot;

Separately, ministers have announced that four areas of the UK will trial a new scheme to help those asylum seekers who have been accepted for settlement as refugees.

The Sunrise project aims to help refugees integrate into British society far more quickly by giving them expert guidance on rebuilding their lives in Britain. The trials will take place in Glasgow, Leeds, West London and Manchester.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4693551.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-38</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Letwin backs Cameron for leader</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mr Letwin used an article in the Sunday Telegraph to hail Mr Cameron, 38, as a man with the &quot;instincts&quot;, talents and beliefs to return the party to power.

The declaration by Mr Letwin, seen as an intellectual heavyweight, is a coup for &quot;young pretender&quot; Mr Cameron.

The shadow education secretary is fast emerging as the main leadership challenger to favourite David Davis.

It will increase his chances of establishing himself as the sole candidate of the party's centre-left to take on Mr Davis when leader Michael Howard steps down in the autumn.

In the article, Mr Letwin praised the &quot;modernising&quot; vision of a &quot;civilised Britain&quot; combining free markets with a stronger society put across by Mr Cameron in a recent speech.

The speech &quot;established him in the front rank of British politics&quot;, Mr Letwin said.

He praised Mr Cameron personally, saying: &quot;I hope that he will stand. If he does, despite my admiration for other friends and colleagues, I will back him.&quot;

He singled out shadow trade and industry secretary David Willetts for his &quot;thoughtful&quot; argument that the Conservatives should be &quot;at once a liberal party of free markets and a communitarian party that aims at the strengthening of society&quot;.

He acknowledged that Mr Howard's decision to delay his departure after announcing his resignation on 6 May had been &quot;controversial&quot;.

But it had given the party an opportunity for &quot;intelligent and much-needed constructive discussion&quot; about its future, he insisted.

&quot;All of this fills me with optimism about the future of our party,&quot; he said.

&quot;We are thinking again - the first prerequisite for any political movement.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4645769.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-39</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Kennedy praises 'tremendous win'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The election was triggered by the death of Lib Dem MP Patsy Calton from cancer shortly after May's general election.

Mark Hunter held the Greater Manchester seat for the Lib Dems with 19,953 votes, a 3,657 majority over Tory candidate Stephen Day, who came second.

Mr Kennedy said: &quot;This is a first class victory for the Liberal Democrats.&quot;

Labour's Martin Miller came third with 1,739 votes but lost his £500 deposit.

The swing was 0.63% from Conservatives to Liberal Democrats.

Mr Kennedy was met by Lib Dem supporters bearing banners and balloons as he visited Cheadle on Friday morning.

He said: &quot;What was really tremendous about this result was not just that the government lost its deposit, sweet though that was...

&quot;It was the fact that weeks after the general [election]...we actually got a swing to the Liberal Democrats.&quot;

The outcome will come as a relief to Mr Kennedy, although he denies fearing that losing the seat might cost him his leadership.

He denied reports he had warned his frontbenchers he would sack anybody trying to destabilise his leadership.

&quot;I said no such thing,&quot; he said.

But he had told colleagues not to be distracted by press reports from Westminster which were &quot;utterly irrelevant to real politics outside&quot;.

Mr Kennedy said he had reorganised parts of the party since the election.

&quot;You can't as a leader make an omelette without cracking eggs and then you get some unfavourable remarks,&quot; he added.

Mr Hunter said he was proud to be Cheadle's MP and claimed people had voted for a &quot;more honest and positive approach&quot;.

He told BBC News he believed there was a &quot;backlash&quot; against the &quot;American-style&quot; canvassing tactics used by parties like the Conservatives.

&quot;The Conservatives have failed again and have disgraced themselves with more negative and personal mud-slinging than ever before,&quot; said Mr Hunter.

The new MP has stood down as leader of Stockport Borough Council.

Ms Calton won Cheadle from the Conservatives in 2001 with a majority of 33, the smallest in the country.

Although unable to campaign because of a recurrence of her cancer, Ms Calton increased her majority in this year's May election to 4,000.

Conservative Mr Day was the area's MP until 2001 but says he will not stand again as a parliamentary candidate.

He said: &quot;I am pleased to see that the Conservative share of the vote has gone up.

&quot;This is the best by-election result we have had in a long time and it is the Labour Party which is in trouble.&quot;

Labour's Mr Miller said the result &quot;showed that people were willing to vote for anyone to make sure the Conservative Party did not win&quot;.

The Conservatives have not gained a seat in a by-election since 1982.

Shadow Commons leader Chris Grayling said he was disappointed but not surprised the Tories had failed to win the seat.

He said the result was similar to the general election and little had happened politically since then to &quot;change the overall lie of the land between the different parties&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4685583.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-40</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair seeks to tackle extremism</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mr Blair said there would be &quot;profound shock and anxiety&quot; after the news the suspected suicide bombers were British.

Talks are to begin on bringing in new laws covering preparations for attacks and to make it easier to deport people trying to &quot;incite hatred&quot;, he told MPs.

Mr Blair, who is to host a summit of UK Muslim leaders, said the &quot;moderate and true voice of Islam&quot; must be mobilised.

Police seeking the masterminds behind the attacks are believed to be looking for a fifth person in connection with the attacks which killed at least 52 people in London last Thursday.

The uncle of one of the suspected London suicide bombers said his family had been &quot;left shattered&quot; by the news.

Bashir Ahmed, 65, said the family of Shehzad Tanweer, who recently studied religion in Pakistan, could not accept he was capable of the bombings.

In Parliament, Mr Blair said there was &quot;a need and a willingness to act&quot;.

Consultations would begin in the next couple of weeks over possible new anti-terror legislation, due to be published this autumn, he said.

The laws would focus on measures the police and security services believed necessary to &quot;combat the incitement and the instigation of terrorism as well as the acts of terrorism themselves&quot;.

&quot;We will look urgently at how we strengthen the procedures to exclude people from entering the UK who may incite hatred or act contrary to the public good and at how we deport such people if they come here more easily,&quot; he continued.

Mr Blair said security measures alone would not deal with what was more than an isolated criminal act.

&quot;It is an extreme and evil ideology whose roots lie in a perverted and poisonous misinterpretation of the religion of Islam,&quot; he said.

Mr Blair met Muslim MPs on Wednesday morning to discuss how to tackle &quot;this evil within the Muslim community&quot;.

&quot;In the end, this can only be taken on and defeated by the community itself,&quot; he said.

The prime minister condemned any attacks on British Muslims, saying the vast majority were decent and law abiding.

There had to be international efforts to mobilise the true Muslim faith, he said.

Conservative leader Michael Howard said anyone who nurtured resentment against Muslims would be behaving in the way terrorists wanted.

He said: &quot;It will take us a long time to come to terms with the fact that these attacks appear to have been committed by those who were born and brought up in our midst.&quot;

Liberal Democrat leader Charles Kennedy said everyone shared &quot;a sense of national dismay&quot; on hearing the bombers were British.

Everybody should keep stressing that the vast majority of Muslims totally condemned the bombings, he said.

Labour's Shahid Malik, whose Dewsbury constituency was the scene of police raids in the bombing investigation, said the Muslim community faced a &quot;massive wake-up call&quot;.

Mr Malik added: &quot;The challenge is straightforward - that those voices that we have tolerated will no longer be tolerated.&quot;

Liberal Democrat MEP Baroness Nicholson has suggested the bombings amounted to a &quot;civil war&quot;, prompting criticism from Tory MEPs.

But she said her words should not be taken out of context and were &quot;merely to point out the fact that last Thursday British citizens attacked other British citizens and nothing more&quot;.

The UK Home Office also denied the suggestion by French interior minister Nicolas Sarkozy that some of the suspected London bombers had been arrested in 2004.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4678821.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-41</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Protest in Brazil after shooting</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Jean Charles de Menezes, 27, was shot eight times at Stockwell station after he was mistaken for a suicide bomber.

Tony Blair has said he is &quot;desperately sorry&quot; but urged people to support the police in &quot;difficult circumstances&quot; in the wake of the London bombings.

The hundreds of protesters in Gonzaga said the apology did not go far enough.

The Landless Rural Workers' Movement said it would demonstrate on Tuesday in front of the British Embassy in Brasilia and the consulate in Rio de Janeiro.

Foreign Secretary Jack Straw also apologised at a meeting with Brazilian counterpart Celso Amorim on Monday.

Security sources have said electrician Mr Menezes was in the UK on an out-of-date student visa.

Mr Straw said he did not know Mr Menezes' precise immigration status but said it was his &quot;understanding that he was here lawfully&quot;.

Mr Amorim said the dead man's family wanted his body quickly returned to Brazil.

And he said compensation from the Metropolitan Police was important for what was a &quot;humble&quot; family.

&quot;It would not lessen the shock and concern at the death of this innocent person but it would be something concrete in addition to the apologies that have been made verbally,&quot; he said.

Earlier, Mr Blair was asked about the death after he discussed anti-terror measures in a meeting with French prime minister Dominique de Villepin.

He told reporters: &quot;We are all desperately sorry for the death of an innocent person. I understand entirely the feelings of the young man's family.

&quot;But we also have to understand the police are doing their job in very, very difficult circumstances and it is important that we give them every support.&quot;

The prime minister said the police would have been criticised for failing to act had the man turned out to be a terrorist.

The death of Mr de Menezes has sparked new debate over the police shoot to kill policy against suspected suicide bombers.

Labour peer Lord Ahmed warned that illegal immigrants would try to run away if challenged by police.

&quot;And whilst we need to catch those illegal immigrants or asylum seekers, nevertheless we can't shoot them because they're not terrorists,&quot; he said.

'No need for fear'

Liberal Democrat peer Baroness Falkner was among those meeting police at Scotland Yard on Monday to discuss the shooting.

&quot;One terrible tragedy does not mean the entire ethnic minority communities of Britain need to fear for their lives,&quot; she said.

At their talks in Downing Street, Mr Blair and Mr de Villepin agreed that the UK and France would share lists of the people who incite terrorism.

Mr de Villepin said &quot;jihadists&quot; who had trained and fought in other countries posed a particular threat.

&quot;They have been operational and if they have done it once, they can do it again,&quot; he told reporters.

France already shared information about such people with Germany, he said.

With Parliament now on its summer break, Mr Blair insisted political decisions would continue to be taken irrespective of whether individual ministers were on holiday.

He said ministers remained in touch constantly and Parliament could be recalled if necessary.

Mr Blair again said terrorists should not be allowed to use the Iraq war as a justification for their &quot;ideology&quot;.

This weekend's bombings in Sharm al-Sheik in Egypt underlined the &quot;global state&quot; of terrorism, he said.

The French prime minister, who opposed the Iraq conflict, said nations had to work together against terrorists who often based their actions around crises, such as the wars in Bosnia, Afghanistan and Iraq.

Political resolutions were needed for conflicts which could be &quot;open wounds&quot;, he argued.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4714691.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-42</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Ex-PMs join in tributes to Heath</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>MPs, peers and other dignitaries were among 1,600 paying their last respects at the service in Salisbury Cathedral.

Sir Edward, prime minister from 1970 to 1974, is best remembered for taking the UK into the European Community (EEC).

In his address, the Bishop of Salisbury said Sir Edward's &quot;commitment to unity&quot; ran through his whole life.

The Rt Rev David Stancliffe paid tribute to Sir Edward's convictions over Europe, as well as his love for music, sailing and debate.

He said: &quot;Ted built bridges between countries and nations, between artists and ordinary people, between east and west, between young and old.

&quot;He was a shy person who did not have much time for smooth words and social pleasantries.

&quot;From his maiden speech, calling for Britain to participate in early attempts to build a united Europe onwards, his commitment to unity ran like a golden thread through his life.

&quot;No one can doubt his lifelong commitment to Europe, nor for that matter to the unity of the world. In this he exerted his fullest force.&quot;

The service saw Sir Edward's coffin draped with a union jack and covered in white lilies.

It was taken on a wheeled wooden carriage from his home, Arundells, which is in the grounds of Salisbury Cathedral and entered the church to the trumpeted notes of the Last Post.

In the procession ahead of the coffin into the Cathedral, his Knight of the Garter medal was carried on a cushion.

In line with Sir Edward's wishes, all 1,600 seats in the cathedral were taken by dignitaries alongside ordinary members of the public.

Among the congregation were Lady Thatcher, Sir John and Norma Major, Conservative leader Michael Howard and Liberal Democrat leader Charles Kennedy.

And previous Tory Cabinet ministers at the service included Lord Geoffrey Howe, Lord Douglas Hurd and Sir George Young.

Earlier, Sir John Major said he had been &quot;very fond of Ted&quot; and had been a &quot;very strong supporter of his&quot; when he was prime minister.

&quot;He was a man of very strong convictions even though they were sometimes unpopular, he said.

Sir John added: &quot;He was a source of extremely strong convictions, whether you agreed with them or you disagreed with them, here was a man who knew what he was, knew what he stood for and was not a man for shifting.&quot;

Lord Armstrong, Sir Edward's former private secretary, said Sir Edward had been a man of &quot;great integrity ...vision and determination&quot;.

&quot;He came into office with a very clear idea of what he wanted to achieve as prime minister and that achievement was entering the European Community,&quot; he said.

&quot;He was loyal to his friends and loyal to his institutions, which were the College of Oxford, the Conservative Party and the Church of England.&quot;

Sir Edward died of pneumonia on 17 July, aged 89, at his home in Cathedral Close, Salisbury.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4713911.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-43</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair 'warns Clarke over respect'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It says the prime minister told Charles Clarke at a meeting that more must be done to address low-level disorder.

Downing Street insisted it was &quot;absurd&quot; to suggest Mr Blair was unhappy with Mr Clarke's handling of the issue.

Conservative David Davis blamed &quot;seven years of failed policy&quot;, while the Lib Dems said it was &quot;passing the buck&quot;.

The leaked document, obtained by the Sunday Telegraph and Sunday Times and dated 21 June, contains minutes of the previous day's meeting on the subject in Downing Street.

BBC correspondent Guto Harri said the language used suggested that not enough progress was being made on tackling low level disorder, truancy and school discipline.

&quot;On respect the prime minister said this was a real issue for the public,&quot; the minutes are reported as saying.

&quot;We needed to address it now otherwise a sense of fatalism would set in.&quot;

Newspaper reports say Mr Blair also expressed frustration that the recent debate about ID cards had been dominated by considerations of cost and that sentencing policy was shaped by the number of prison places available.

Number 10 and the Home Office both deny the meeting involved in any way a &quot;dressing down&quot; for Mr Clarke.

&quot;The prime minister has complete confidence in the home secretary and to suggest otherwise is absurd,&quot; the Downing Street spokesman said.

&quot;The prime minister very often works very closely with a secretary of state, as he did with me on health,&quot; he said.

But shadow home secretary David Davis said: &quot;It is not good enough for the prime minister to rebuke his latest home secretary for the public perception of his actions.

&quot;These are the results of eight years of failed policy, not seven months of inadequate spin.&quot;

Liberal Democrat home affairs spokesman Mark Oaten said it showed the government's approach to anti-social behaviour is not working.

&quot;As ID cards become more and more unpopular, Tony Blair's comments are the start of a ministerial pass the buck,&quot; he continued.

&quot;No-one in government will want to end up taking the blame for this expensive fiasco.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4645681.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-44</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair praises 'magnificent' Heath</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mr Blair, who was leading House of Commons tributes to Sir Edward, said: &quot;He was magnificent ... a prime minister our country can be proud of.&quot;

Business in the Commons and Lords has been cancelled to allow the tributes.

Tory leader Michael Howard said: &quot;Today we remember a prime minister who was a most distinguished parliamentarian.&quot;

Lady Thatcher, who replaced him as Tory leader, earlier said &quot;we are all in his debt&quot;.

&quot;Ted Heath was a political giant. He was also, in every sense, the first modern Conservative leader - by his humble background, his grammar school education and by the fact of his democratic election.

&quot;As prime minister, he was confronted by the enormous problems of post-war Britain. If those problems eventually defeated him, he had shown in the 1970 manifesto how they, in turn, would eventually be defeated.

&quot;For that, and much else besides, we are all in his debt.&quot;

Sir Edward, who was knighted in 1992, won his first seat for the Tories in Bexley in 1950.

He led the Tory government as prime minister between 1970 and 1974, and was responsible for bringing Britain into what was then the European Economic Community, before losing the leadership of the Conservative Party to Margaret Thatcher in 1975.

In the Commons Mr Blair told MPs how Sir Edward could be &quot;very blunt&quot;, but &quot;once you got to know him, very kind&quot;.

He drew laughter when he told how he first met Sir Edward in the 1980s.

&quot;He said: 'Are you an MP?' 'Yes,' I said. 'Which party?' 'Labour,' I said. 'Well you don't look like it or sound like it,' he said.

Mr Blair said Sir Edward &quot;would fill the House. I can picture him now, often speaking without a note, with humour, incisive argument and magisterial disdain for the opposing view, swatting away anyone ill-judged enough to make a hostile intervention&quot;.

Quoting former Labour Chancellor Roy Jenkins, a friend of Sir Edward, Mr Blair added: &quot;He was a great lighthouse which stands there flashing out beams of light, indifferent to the waves which beat against him.

&quot;That was indeed how he was - an extraordinary man, a great statesman, a prime minister our country can be proud of. We shall miss him.&quot;

Mr Howard described Sir Edward as one of the &quot;political giants&quot; of the 20th Century, who had made an &quot;historic contribution&quot; to Britain.

He said Sir Edward was &quot;fearless in his views, and rock-like in his integrity, and who always sought to serve his country to the very best of his ability&quot;.

Liberal Democrat leader Charles Kennedy said: &quot;Where Sir Edward was concerned on both a very human level and equally a statesmanlike level, he was a gifted man, a very good man and indeed a very great man ...we miss him very much.&quot;

Sir Edward's former colleague Lord Walker said history would &quot;give him a high rating&quot;, adding he was a &quot;very great man and an enormous patriot&quot;.

Former Labour Chancellor, Denis Healey, said he had been friends with Sir Edward for many years after meeting him at Oxford University.

&quot;He represented the sensible wing of the Tory Party,&quot; he told BBC Radio Five Live.

Sir Edward's former political secretary Lord Hurd said: &quot;He got us into the European Union. That was a huge step, a very difficult one, which I doubt would have happened without his particular kind of thoroughness and determination.&quot;

He told BBC Radio 4's Today programme that Sir Edward had been the first prime minister to confront trade union power - a move that Margaret Thatcher took note of and learned from.

However, Lord Hurd said Sir Edward had been someone who was &quot;terrific to work for&quot;, but who lost interest in politics towards the end. &quot;He was much more interested in places he'd been to, people, sailing, music - those were the things that still caught his attention,&quot; he said.

Lord Carrington, who was energy secretary in Sir Edward's Cabinet, said: &quot;He was a great friend. He was a man of utmost integrity. You couldn't imagine Ted Heath doing anything dishonourable.&quot;

But Lord Carrington said his wife and he had found Sir Edward a &quot;very lonely&quot; man after they had lunch with him 10 days ago.

Former Tory Chancellor Lord Howe said Ted Heath was a &quot;man of great commitment and energy&quot;.

Ex-Labour MP Tony Benn, who became good friends with Sir Edward said: &quot;He was a far greater figure than Mrs Thatcher. She did enormous damage and his analysis of what she did was correct.&quot;

Sir Edward never forgave Mrs Thatcher for ousting him as leader and refused to serve in her Cabinet.

When asked in a TV interview if it was true that when Mrs Thatcher was herself deposed he said &quot;rejoice, rejoice,&quot; he joked: &quot;I think I said it three times.&quot;

Ex-Liberal leader Jeremy Thorpe said Sir Edward would be &quot;sadly missed&quot;.

&quot;In view of the widespread opposition to the common market among Conservatives at the time it took courage, integrity and sheer guts from Edward Heath to bring the Tory Party round,&quot; he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4691797.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-45</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Blair backs Cherie terror views</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Speaking in Malaysia, Cherie Blair said it would be &quot;all too easy&quot; to fight back in a way &quot;which cheapens our right to call ourselves a civilised nation&quot;.

She stressed her comments should not be seen as making light of the attacks.

Mr Blair said he had said similar things about the need to balance civil liberties with security.

Conservative homeland security spokesman Patrick Mercer said the remarks made by Mrs Blair came at a &quot;desperately insensitive time&quot;.

Cherie, a QC who practises under her maiden name Booth, said: &quot;Nothing I say here could possibly be construed as making light of those horrible acts of violence, or of the responsibility imposed on the UK and other governments to keep the public safe, or of the difficult and dangerous task performed by the police and intelligence services.&quot;

But, she added &quot;at the same time it is all too easy for us to respond to such terror in a way which undermines commitment to our most deeply held values and convictions and which cheapens our right to call ourselves a civilised nation&quot;.

The QC, addressing an audience of 1,000 lawyers, civil servants and diplomats in Malaysia, said judges made rulings in a way that taught citizens and government about the &quot;ethical responsibilities&quot; of participating in a true democracy committed to &quot;universal human rights standards&quot;.

She said courts should be &quot;guardians of the weakest, poorest and most marginalised members of society against the hurly-burly of majoritarian politics&quot;.

A good example of this working was the decision by the UK's highest court, the House of Lords law lords, that the UK's policy of holding foreign terrorist suspects indefinitely without charge broke human rights laws.

&quot;What the case makes clear is that the government, even in times when there is a threat to national security, must act strictly in accordance with the law,&quot; she said.

Asked if he thought it had been insensitive for his wife to make her remarks at this moment in time, Mr Blair said: &quot;I think I have said myself that it's important that we balance these things.

&quot;Civil liberties of people are very important to protect our way of life, and it's important to protect people's security.

&quot;I think, probably, to be fair, if you read the whole of the speech she was saying the same thing.&quot;

But Mr Mercer said: &quot;Cherie Blair or Cherie Booth, whichever name she's going under just at the moment, is entitled to her private opinions of course and to express those.

&quot;But she is the prime minister's wife and I think this is a desperately insensitive time for her to be making those sorts of comments.&quot;

Mr Blair says extra powers being looked at include extending the time people can be held without charge.

On Tuesday Mr Blair vowed not to &quot;give an inch to terrorism&quot; and said Iraq was no excuse for the London bombings.

He said 11 September 2001 was a wake up call for the international community, but argued some people &quot;then turned over and went back to sleep again&quot;.

&quot;Let us expose the obscenity of these people saying it is concern for Iraq that drives them to terrorism. If it is concern for Iraq then why are they driving a car bomb into the middle of a group of children and killing them?

&quot;We are not going to deal with this problem, with the roots as deep as they are, until we confront these people at every single level - and not just their methods but their ideas,&quot; he added.

Also on Tuesday Mr Blair held talks with Conservative leader Michael Howard and the Liberal Democrats' Charles Kennedy about possible new powers to tackle terrorism.

These could include allowing the use of &quot;phone tap&quot; evidence in court.

Mr Howard said the Tories saw difficulties with calls from the police to extend the time a terrorist suspect can be held without charge from 14 days to three months.

Mr Kennedy said basic civil liberties were not surrendered by the proposals.

There is already agreement on plans to create new offences of engaging in acts preparatory to terrorism and of indirect incitement to terrorism.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4721599.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-46</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | UK | Wanted Briton detained in Zambia</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The man was held in the border town of Livingstone after entering the country from Zimbabwe, Zambian officials said.

The Foreign Office said it was seeking access to a British national reportedly in custody, but did not name him.

US reports say the man is Haroon Rashid Aswat, who is alleged to have made contact with two suicide bombers before they carried out their mission.

Scotland Yard said: &quot;It's all speculation and not something that we will discuss at the moment.&quot;

A Foreign Office spokesman said: &quot;We are currently seeking consular access to a British national reported to be in custody in Zambia.&quot;

It has been suggested that Mr Aswat was in the UK shortly before the London attacks and called two of the bombers on his mobile phone.

According to news reports from the US, he was arrested last week for his alleged role in planning a terrorist training camp in Oregon in 1999.

Scotland Yard declined to shed any light on claims Mr Aswat was the possible mastermind of the July 7 attacks.

The four suicide bombers struck on three underground trains and a bus, killing 52 people and injuring 700.

Meanwhile, Metropolitan Police Commissioner Sir Ian Blair said he remained confident those responsible for last week's attempted bombings in London would be caught.

Speaking in a debate on BBC One, Sir Ian said the &quot;net was closing&quot;.

Police are questioning 21 July suspect Yasin Hassan Omar following his arrest in Birmingham on Thursday, but the search for the other three men continues.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4726541.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-47</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Terror laws talks reach consensus</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Legislation covering offences of preparing, training for and inciting terror acts, will come before the Commons and Lords from October.

Meanwhile officials in Pakistan have confirmed three of the four London bombers visited the country last year.

The toll from the attacks has risen to 56, including the four bombers.

All 55 bodies taken from the bomb sites to the a temporary mortuary - set up in the grounds of the Honourable Artillery Company in Clerkenwell - have been identified.

On Monday the identity of the 56th person was confirmed by the Identification Commission, said incident coroner Paul Knapman.

Six more of the victims have been named.

The BBC has obtained new video footage of suicide bomber Mohammad Sidique Khan, filmed as he gave a lesson in dealing with bullying to children at a community centre in Leeds.

His activities as a youth worker and teacher led him to meet two of the other suicide bombers, Hasib Hussain, 18, and 22-year-old Shehzad Tanweer, said BBC correspondent Catherine Marston.

Khan and Tanweer travelled in and out of Pakistan together, spending three months there last year, said the authorities.

Officials said Hussain flew in last July. It is not clear how long he stayed.

With forensics experts still examining the four blast sites, police said the investigation was the largest anti-terrorism operation ever mounted in the UK.

Some 2,000 police officers had been involved, with up to 500 likely to stay permanently on the case. They estimated about 25,000 CCTV tapes would be viewed during the investigation.

The legislation agreement came after talks between the home secretary, Conservative David Davis and Liberal Democrat Mark Oaten.

Last week the Home Office stressed the plans were in train before the London bombs.

Following Monday's meeting Mr Clarke said: &quot;The central message from today is a determination by all of us to legislate on counter-terrorism.&quot;

Controversial proposals, such as &quot;control orders&quot;, will be left out of the legislation with the government returning to them in January.

The Anti-terrorism Bill should become law by December, up to six months earlier than expected.

Tory shadow home secretary Mr Davis said he was pleased with the outcome of the talks and that Mr Clarke had accepted a number of his proposals.

Lib Dem home affairs spokesman Mark Oaten said the meeting had been &quot;extremely constructive&quot; with agreement in principle to the government's plans.

The talks came as a report by the Royal Institute of International Affairs and the Economic and Social Research Council said the UK's involvement in the Iraq invasion heightened the risk of terrorist attacks.

The report also said the invasion boosted al-Qaeda's recruitment and fundraising.

In another development it emerged the police were investigating large purchases of perfume, worth almost £1,000, by bomber Germaine Lindsay in Aylesbury a few days before the attacks.

Perfume can be used as an explosives accelerant, said BBC home affairs correspondent Daniel Sandford.

Lindsay was reportedly keen to buy a brand in a distinctive metal bottle.

The talks also coincided with the presentation of a fatwa, or religious decree, by Muslim leaders condemning the London bombings.

The document, signed by 500 Muslim scholars around the UK, was presented by members of the British Muslim Forum in Westminster.

On Sunday it emerged one of the London bombers was investigated by MI5 last year but was deemed not to be a threat.

Mohammad Sidique Khan, 30, was subject to a routine assessment by the security service because of an indirect connection to an alleged terror plot.

He was one of hundreds investigated but was not considered a risk by the security services.

Fifty-two people were killed and 700 were injured in the blasts. The four bombers also died.

Khan, from Dewsbury, West Yorkshire, killed himself and six other passengers in the Edgware Road bombing on the London underground.

Hasib Hussain, 18, from Holbeck, Leeds was responsible for the Number 30 bus bombing, in which 13 others died; Shehzad Tanweer, 22, from Beeston in Leeds for the Aldgate Tube blast, which killed eight, and Germaine Lindsay, 19, from Aylesbury, Buckinghamshire, for the King's Cross Tube explosion in which 27 people were killed.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4691909.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-48</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Asbo adviser mocks drink campaign</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Louise Casey, 38, head of the Home Office anti-social behaviour unit, made the remarks in an after-dinner speech, which was secretly recorded by a guest.

She also poked fun at Home Secretary Charles Clarke in the speech to chief constables and senior civil servants.

A Downing Street spokesman said Tony Blair retained full confidence in her.

Speaking in Stratford-upon-Avon, Ms Casey told her audience: &quot;I suppose you can't binge drink anymore because lots of people have said you can't do it. I don't know who bloody made that up, it's nonsense.&quot;

On the tape, obtained by BBC News, she said some ministers might perform better if they &quot;turn up in the morning pissed&quot;.

&quot;Doing things sober is no way to get things done,&quot; she added.

But her strongest criticism was reserved for Downing Street, which she suggested was &quot;obsessed&quot; with conducting extensive research before formulating policies.

She apparently joked that she would &quot;deck&quot; Downing Street policy advisers if they kept spouting jargon at her.

At the weekend reports claimed Tony Blair had criticised Home Secretary Charles Clarke over a lack of action on the &quot;respect agenda&quot;.

However, Downing Street insisted it was &quot;absurd&quot; to suggest Mr Blair was unhappy with Mr Clarke's handling of the issue.

Ms Casey made her comments at a conference attended by senior civil servants, chief constables and criminal justice practitioners last month.

Although her tone was light-hearted - she said the tea lady was more powerful than ministers - a number of people in the audience are reported to have walked out during her speech.

BBC home affairs correspondent Danny Shaw says the remarks are likely to cause both Ms Casey and the government &quot;deep embarrassment&quot;.

The prime minister's official spokesman said Mr Blair had &quot;full confidence&quot; in her and his &quot;high regard for her was well known because of her record of achievements in the past&quot;.

But the spokesman said: &quot;The remarks were made after a dinner and should be put into some sort of perspective.

&quot;Lots of people have said things after dinner and when they see them in the cold light of day would regret them and no doubt she would not have wished to see them in this morning's newspapers.&quot;

A Home Office spokesman said Ms Casey was achieving a great deal in leading the campaign to tackle anti-social behaviour.

&quot;But, like all Home Office employees, she is subject to the Civil Service Code. We are looking into her reported remarks,&quot; he added.

Harry Fletcher, assistant general secretary of the National Association of Probation Officers, said Ms Casey's remarks were &quot;extraordinary&quot;.

They were &quot;certainly inappropriate comments to be made by a civil servant, never mind one who is heading up the anti-social behaviour unit,&quot; he told BBC Radio 4's Today programme.

&quot;It was an attempt at humour and you could hear on the tape some of the audience were laughing.

&quot;It's worrying that these comments are made by a person who's heading up an extremely important initiative which is being headed up both by the Home Office and Number 10.

&quot;It won't do anything to ease the tension - if there are any tensions - between the leading figures.&quot;

Shadow home secretary David Davis said it was &quot;ironic&quot; that the official appointed to report to Tony Blair on anti-social behaviour appeared to be &quot;an advocate of binge drinking&quot;.

&quot;Maybe this explains why alcohol-related violent attacks are up 25% and why Labour are so keen to unleash 24-hour drinking,&quot; he added.

Ms Casey was appointed as director of the unit by Tony Blair and was last month told to report directly to the prime minister on the issue of restoring &quot;respect&quot; to Britain's streets.

She is responsible for encouraging the use of anti-social behaviour orders by police and local authorities clamping down on loutish behaviour.

One of the top priorities of Mr Blair's &quot;respect&quot; agenda is to reverse the tide of drunken violence blamed on binge drinkers in Britain's city centres.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4654723.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-49</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Halt Zimbabwe removals says judge</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The call comes after a Refugee Legal Council representative said there was evidence to suggest asylum seekers faced being abused in Zimbabwe.

They were in danger because they had claimed asylum in the UK, he said.

Mr Justice Collins said this made it &quot;arguable&quot; that it was unsafe to send back failed asylum seekers.

He stressed he was not saying it was dangerous, but that the Refugee Legal Council (RLC) should have the chance to put its evidence to Home Secretary Charles Clarke.

The judge directed that the issue should go to a court hearing on 4 August.

In the meantime, failed asylum seekers should not be removed &quot;until this is sorted out&quot;, he suggested.

Home Office lawyers said Mr Clarke had no evidence of any systematic abuse of failed asylum seekers who had been returned to Zimbabwe.

Mr Justice Collins, a specialist in immigration law, said: &quot;There is no question but the situation in Zimbabwe gives rise to real concern about the safety of those being returned to it.&quot;

The judge also condemned the deportation of a Zimbabwean woman which went ahead despite the removal order being cancelled after the woman applied for a High Court review.

The fax the Home Office sent to Securicor to cancel the order was handled by a temporary member of staff who did not realise its importance.

Mr Justice Collins said: &quot;How anyone could fail to appreciate the significance of a fax from the Home Office telling them removal directions had been cancelled frankly escapes me.

&quot;Even a half-wit would understand. All I can say is that I sincerely hope nothing like this ever happens again.&quot;

His comments come after the archbishop of Canterbury said it would be &quot;deeply immoral&quot; to deport failed asylum seekers to Zimbabwe.

In a statement to Parliament on Wednesday, Mr Clarke said 33 failed Zimbabwean asylum seekers were on hunger strike, although campaigners say it is many more.

In total, 106 failed Zimbabwean asylum seekers are being detained pending removal from the country.

Mr Clarke said the government's assessment of the situation in Zimbabwe was being constantly monitored and the UK was pressing Zimbabwe to end human rights abuses.

On asylum seekers, he said: &quot;Each case is considered thoroughly before removal proceeds and any new information or representations are examined accordingly.&quot;

The Home Office says it will now carefully consider the judge's comments but there has so far been no policy change.

But a Home Office official told an immigration tribunal in London in a separate hearing that returns to Zimbabwe had been halted already.

After the hearing, the official, Peter Armstrong, told a reporter: &quot;That is information I have picked up in the office. It is in light of recent developments in Zimbabwe. There has been no official announcement.&quot;

Liberal Democrat spokesman Mark Oaten said the government must listen to the court.

&quot;It is indefensible to continue with deportations in the face of the evidence that individuals are being mistreated following removal from the UK,&quot; he said.

Conservative deputy leader Michael Ancram earlier asked why the government was trying &quot;to send Zimbabwean asylum seekers in fear of their lives, back to the bloodstained hands of Mugabe and his thugs&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4657667.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-10 00:00:00-50</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Politics | Image of bombers' deadly journey</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>They have also confirmed the names of all four men for the first time.

Mohammad Sidique Khan, 30, Germaine Lindsay, 19, Hasib Hussain, 18, and Shehzad Tanweer, 22, were pictured in Luton at 0720 BST on Thursday 7 July.

Three bombs exploded on the London underground at 0850 BST, and one on a bus at 0947. Fifty-five people died, including the four bombers.

The picture was released in an attempt to find out more about their final movements.

Peter Clarke, head of the Anti-Terrorist Branch, said: &quot;The investigation continues on many fronts, but we have been very grateful for the contribution made by the public in response to our previous appeals.

&quot;However we still need to find out more about these four men and their movements, both on the morning of the bombings, and in the days and weeks beforehand.&quot;

It is thought Hussain was responsible for the bus bombing, in which 13 people died, Khan the Edgware Road blast that killed six people; Tanweer for the Aldgate blast, which killed six, and Lindsay for the Russell Square explosion where 26 people were killed.
• Ten addresses in West Yorkshire and one in Aylesbury, Buckinghamshire, have been searched. Seven of the 10 West Yorkshire searches are still ongoing.
• Police have extra time to question a man, arrested on 12 July on suspicion of the commission, instigation or preparation of acts of terrorism, and held at a central London police station
• Police have taken more than 800 witness statements and received 3,500 calls to the anti-terrorist hotline
• The wreckage of the bombed number 30 bus has been moved from Tavistock Square in central London for further forensic examination

Earlier, Tony Blair said it was time to stand up to the &quot;evil ideology&quot; behind the London bombings and other attacks.

He said such violence was not a response to any particular policy or injustice, but was a &quot;fanaticism&quot; that had to be confronted.

The prime minister told Labour party members it would be a &quot;misunderstanding of a catastrophic order&quot; to think extremists would act differently if the developed world changed its behaviour.

&quot;If it is the plight of the Palestinians that drives them, why, every time it looks as if Israel and Palestine are making progress, does the same ideology perpetrate an outrage that turns hope back into despair?

&quot;If it is Afghanistan that motivates them, why blow up innocent Afghans on their way to their first-ever election?

&quot;If it is Iraq that motivates them, why is the same ideology killing Iraqis by terror in defiance of an elected Iraqi government?

&quot;What was 11 September 2001 the reprisal for?&quot;

But some Labour left-wingers saw a link between the Iraq war and the attacks.

John McDonnell, Labour MP for Hayes and Harlington, said it was &quot;intellectually unsustainable&quot; to say the war in Iraq had not motivated the bombers.

&quot;For as long as Britain remains in occupation of Iraq the terrorist recruiters will have the argument they seek to attract more susceptible young recruits. Britain must withdraw now.&quot;

Labour ex-minister Clare Short, who resigned over the Iraq war, told GMTV's Sunday programme she &quot;had no doubt&quot; the atrocities were linked to Iraq.

&quot;We are implicit in the slaughter of large numbers of civilians in Iraq and supporting a Middle East policy that for the Palestinians creates this sense of double standards - that feeds anger,&quot; she said.

The families of Khan, Hussain and Lindsay have all issued statements expressing their shock and sadness at events.

&quot;Our thoughts are with all the bereaved families and we have to live ourselves with the loss of our son in these difficult circumstances,&quot; Hussain's family said.

Khan's family said: &quot;We are devastated our son may have been brainwashed into carrying out such an atrocity.&quot;

Tanweer's uncle said the family had been &quot;left shattered&quot; by news of his involvement.

British police are now searching for those who may have helped the bombers carry out the attacks.

One house being searched in Leeds is linked to Egyptian biochemist Magdi Mahmoud al-Nashar, 33, who was arrested in Cairo as part of the inquiry into the bombings. He has denied any involvement.

Egypt's interior minister said press reports linking Mr al-Nashar to al-Qaeda were &quot;groundless&quot; and based on a hasty conclusion.

Other properties being searched are the Holbeck home of Hussain, the Dewsbury home of Khan, and the Beeston home of Tanweer. The property searched in Aylesbury was where Lindsay lived.

On Saturday police sealed off and searched a house in Tempest Road, Beeston, Leeds, not far from where Tanweer lived.

On Friday Britain's top Muslims issued a joint statement of condemnation branding the London bombings &quot;utterly criminal, totally reprehensible, and absolutely un-Islamic&quot;.

But Britain's highest ranking Asian police officer, Tarique Ghaffur, said Muslims and their leaders must do more than condemn the bombings.

Mr Ghaffur, the Metropolitan Police Assistant Commissioner, urged members of the community to inform on potential terrorists and their supporters.

The police would have to engage better with minorities - but minorities must take the first step, he said.

Police are urging anyone with information that could help their investigation to call the confidential Anti-Terrorist Hotline on 0800 789 321.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/uk_politics/4689739.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
