<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Macron pension reform: Why are French workers on strike? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Europe</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1728D/production/_110016849_hi058437837.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>France's biggest strike in decades has shut down public transport services and reduced the number of hospital staff, teachers and police officers at work in the latest protest against President Emmanuel Macron's reforms.

In this case, unions representing millions of staff in both the public and private sectors are unhappy about a plan to overhaul the country's pension system, which they say will force people to work longer or face reduced payouts when they retire.

One opinion poll put public support for the latest strike action at 69%, with backing strongest among 18-34 year-olds.

So why is Mr Macron looking to implement such unpopular new measures - and just how controversial are they?

Well, France currently has a complex system of 42 different pension schemes for its private and public sectors, with variations in retirement age and benefits. Mr Macron wants to create a unified system.

Pension benefits are largely calculated using an employee's 25 highest-paid years of work in the private sector, while in the public sector it is based on payments made in the last six months before retirement.

The French president's new plan aims to reward employees for each day worked, earning points that would later be transferred into future pension benefits.

In November, a report commissioned by France's Prime Minister Edouard Philippe concluded that, under the existing system, the country's pension deficit could be as high as €17.2bn ($19bn; £14.5bn) by 2025.

The cost of France's current system, in terms of public spending as a percentage of GDP (the country's entire economic output), is among the highest in the world - at 14%.

Mr Macron, aware of France's ageing population, has said his universal pension plan would be fairer than the current system.

The age at which citizens can start drawing a pension varies across the European Union (EU).

The official retirement age in France has been raised in the last decade from 60 to 62, but remains one of the lowest among the OECD group of rich nations - in the UK, for example, the retirement age is 66.

So how controversial is his plan?

The move to a universal points-based pension system would remove the most advantageous pensions for a number of jobs ranging from sailors to lawyers and even opera workers.

While Mr Macron has not suggested immediately increasing the age of retirement from 62, those retiring before 64 would receive a lower pension based on the points earned.

For example, someone retiring at 63 could receive 5% less, so unions fear it will mean having to work longer for a lower pension.

Public sector workers who do arduous or dangerous jobs can also retire years earlier under the current system.

But metro workers, for example, say reforms would force them to work longer by effectively taking away their right to retire early, negotiated decades ago to compensate for having to work long hours underground.

One of France's largest unions, CFDT, said its mostly private sector members would not be participating in Thursday's strike.

CFDT, considered to be one of the more moderate unions, has previously said that reform was needed because the current pension system was not sustainable. The union has also said that a credit-based system might actually improve retirement payments for women.

Mr Macron's new system would not penalise workers who take time off due to illness or maternity leave, offering compensation points.

A recent poll concluded that 75% of people thought that pension reforms were necessary, but that only a third believed the government could deliver them.

Despite the public understanding of the need for change, the latest strike action has overwhelming support. It is expected to last beyond Thursday and some trade union leaders have warned they will keep it up until Mr Macron abandons his campaign promise to overhaul the retirement system.

The Macron administration will be hoping to avoid a repeat of the country's general strike over pension reforms in 1995, which crippled the transport system for three weeks and drew massive popular support, forcing a government reversal.

We hear a lot about demonstrations in France relating to grievances over pay and conditions at work, from Uber drivers striking in Paris to widespread &quot;gilets jaunes&quot; (yellow-vest) protests - but large nationwide strikes involving both private and public sector workers are less common.

A lack of official data and differences in the methods used by countries to record levels of industrial action make it hard to determine whether France leads the way.

According to figures collated by the OECD between 2008 to 2015, France is second only to Denmark on a list of European nations with the most working days affected by strike action. Belgium is third.

French statistics agency Dares reported in 2017 that employers in France lost more than 300 days per 1,000 employees. In 2014 it was 69 days, according to Dares.

Separately, the European Trade Union Institute recently published a &quot;strike map&quot; showing the number of &quot;days not worked&quot; in France between 2010 and 2017 was on average 125 per 1,000 employees. For Spain the number was 50 and for the UK just 20 days.

In Spain, though, strike action is often not recorded or counted, and in countries such as Italy and Greece the data is said to be unreliable.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-50670613</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit preparations: 'We've stockpiled 10,000 wine bottles' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/8B5F/production/_110697653_p081qjtv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Worries for the future over settlement scheme

Guillermo, who is Spanish but was born and raised in the UK, has applied to stay via the EU settlement scheme and has concerns about the future.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51302765</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Petrol and diesel car sales ban brought forward to 2035 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science &amp; Environment</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p0827z1y.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A ban on selling new petrol, diesel or hybrid cars in the UK will be brought forward from 2040 to 2035 at the latest, under government plans.

The change comes after experts said 2040 would be too late if the UK wants to achieve its target of emitting virtually zero carbon by 2050.

Boris Johnson unveiled the policy as part of a launch event for a United Nations climate summit in November.

He said 2020 would be a &quot;defining year of climate action&quot; for the planet.

The summit, known as COP26, is being hosted in Glasgow. It is an annual UN-led gathering set up to assess progress on tackling climate change.

Sir David Attenborough said at the launch event at London's Science Museum that he was looking forward to COP26 and found it &quot;encouraging&quot; that the UK government was launching a &quot;year of climate action&quot;.

&quot;The longer we leave it... the worse it is going to get,&quot; he said.

&quot;So now is the moment. It is up to us to organise the nations of the world to do something about it.&quot;
• How will the petrol and diesel car ban work?

In a statement made ahead of the launch, Mr Johnson said the ban on selling new petrol and diesel cars would come even earlier than 2035, if possible.

Hybrid vehicles are also now being included in the proposals, which were originally announced in July 2017.

People will only be able to buy electric or hydrogen cars and vans, once the ban comes into effect.

The change in plans, which will be subject to a consultation, comes after experts warned the previous target date of 2040 would still leave old conventional cars on the roads following the clean-up date of 2050.

The Scottish government does not have the power to ban new petrol and diesel cars but has already pledged to &quot;phase out the need&quot; for them by 2032 with measures such as an expansion of the charging network for electric cars.

Mr Johnson said the 2050 pledge was necessary because the UK's &quot;historic emissions&quot; meant &quot;we have a responsibility to our planet to lead in this way&quot;.

The announcement comes as COP26's former president Claire O’Neill, who was sacked on Friday, wrote a bitter letter accusing Mr Johnson of failing to support her work.

The prime minister's official spokesperson said Downing Street had &quot;no comment&quot; to make on the letter, but thanked Mrs O'Neill for her work towards the conference.

He said her replacement would be a &quot;ministerial post&quot; with details set out &quot;in due course.&quot;

Mr Johnson did not answer the BBC's David Shukman's questions about the row.

Mr Johnson said: “Hosting COP26 is an important opportunity for the UK and nations across the globe to step up in the fight against climate change.

“As we set out our plans to hit our ambitious 2050 net zero target across this year, so we shall urge others to join us in pledging net zero emissions.

“There can be no greater responsibility than protecting our planet, and no mission that a global Britain is prouder to serve.&quot;

At the Science Museum the prime minister added that a &quot;catastrophic period of global addiction&quot; to hydrocarbons had led to the planet being &quot;swaddled in a tea cosy&quot; of carbon dioxide.

But Green Party MP Caroline Lucas said on Twitter: &quot;Carbon emissions are not 'swaddling the planet like a tea cosy'. They are behind wildfires in Australia, soaring temperature records and the broken lives of those least responsible. The PM needs to understand that - and act.&quot;
• Clean car target 'needs to be sooner'

Friends of the Earth's Mike Childs said the government was &quot;right&quot; to bring forward the ban, but that 2030 would be better than 2035.

“A new 2035 target will still leave the UK in the slow-lane of the electric car revolution and meantime allow more greenhouse gases to spew into the atmosphere,&quot; he said.

He said the government could show &quot;real leadership&quot; ahead of COP26 by reversing plans to develop &quot;climate-wrecking roads and runways&quot;.

AA president Edmund King said: &quot;Drivers support measures to clean up air quality and reduce CO2 emissions but these stretched targets are incredibly challenging.&quot;

The chief executive of the society of motor manufacturers and traders (SMMT) accused the government of &quot;moving the goalposts&quot;.

&quot;With current demand for this still expensive technology still just a fraction of sales, it's clear that accelerating an already very challenging ambition will take more than industry investment,&quot; Mike Hawes said.

He said the government's plans must safeguard industry and jobs, as well as ensuring current sales of low emission vehicles were not undermined.

Meanwhile Mrs O’Neill accused Mr Johnson of promising money and people to support her work, but failing to deliver either.

She also said he admitted to her that he &quot;doesn't really get&quot; climate change and claimed he had refused to give Scottish First Minister Nicola Sturgeon an official role at COP26.

Cabinet minister Michael Gove said Mrs O'Neill was a &quot;close friend&quot; but that he disagreed with her comments.

He told BBC Radio 5 Live Mr Johnson described his own political outlook as &quot;that of a green Tory&quot;.

Mrs O'Neill said her &quot;absolute desire for action has not been comfortable for some&quot;, adding that this was &quot;not about me&quot; or Mr Johnson - but about working towards &quot;rapid decarbonisation&quot;.

She said at COP26 the UK must &quot;absolutely double down on taking our great leadership and ambitions in this space, and really energising the world as to why this is a huge opportunity&quot;.
• How much warmer is your city?
• What is your diet's carbon footprint?
• Where we are in seven charts

What questions do you have about a ban on the sale of petrol, diesel or hybrid cars and the COP26 conference in Glasgow?

In some cases your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy.

Use this form to ask your question:</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-51366123</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Workers blame 'painful jobs' for pulling sickies - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/013A/production/_110741300_gettyimages-135385322.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Some 8.6 million people threw sick days last year because they found their jobs &quot;too painful&quot;, a survey suggests.

Released on what some dub &quot;National Sickie Day&quot;, the research claimed concerns about work culture, colleagues and workloads were to blame.

However, it also said 12 million workers went to work genuinely sick.

The IT company Insight, which did the research, warned of &quot;serious issues within organisations' culture&quot; and called for more flexible working.

It based the findings on a Kantar survey of 1,246 working adults, done over a week in January this year.

The responses were weighted to draw a picture of the wider working population, which numbers almost 33 million people, according to official figures.
• Is it OK to call in sick with a common cold?
• 'I pulled sickies every few months due to stress'

&quot;Employers have a duty of care to their employees to look after their safety and wellbeing, and this includes their physical and mental health,&quot; said Tom Neil, Acas Senior Adviser.

&quot;For people to be able to be honest about how they feel at work, good work practices including having an inclusive culture and effective people management are key.&quot;

In the survey, a quarter of respondents said they had taken a sick day in the last year because doing so felt &quot;too painful&quot;.

Some said they felt overworked or that poor systems and processes made it hard to get work done. Others blamed conflicts with workmates.

However, 37% of respondents said they had come into work in the past year despite feeling sick.

Many said this was because they could not afford unpaid sick leave or did not want to use up a paid sick day. Others said they did not want to feel judged by their employer or co-workers.

Meanwhile about a fifth - or an estimated 6.5 million - said they would be happy to work from home when sick but their firms would not let them.

According to some surveys, more employees call in sick on the first Monday of February than any other day of the year, with an estimated 215,000 doing so last year.

But in 2019, the employment law firm Elas said it had found other days with higher absence rates.

It said the top 10 days for absence last year all fell on a Monday, with 16 September topping the list. The most comment reasons given were:

According to the Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development, the typical employee's number of sick days dropped to 5.9 in 2019 - the lowest in the 19-year history of its annual survey of HR professionals.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51347503</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>What will happen to oil if there is another war? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1B9C/production/_110386070_001941748-1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mitch Kahn remembers how, when fighting began in the second war in Iraq, prices for US crude oil spiked $10 per barrel overnight.

That would have meant a profit of $50,000 if a trader had made the smallest purchasing trade possible. Or, just as big a loss if the trader had decided to sell.

Mr Kahn was working as an independent trader on the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) on Vesey Street in downtown Manhattan, where crude oil, gas and heating oil were traded downstairs and precious metals were traded upstairs.

In 2004, when the second war in Iraq broke out, prices were decided by open outcry: the shouts and yells of (mostly) men who stood in a ring. Some bought, some sold, the price settled between what sellers and buyers were offering.

The ring got so loud that several traders wore earplugs, Mr Kahn says. But for him, the adrenaline was enough to keep his hearing clear.

While trading today is 24 hours, in 2004, when the bell buzzed at 14:30 EST, the market shut.

That day in 2004, when the market opened, the trader on his right began to shout.

He remembers the trader next to him trying to sell some oil, &quot;and the market collapsed.&quot;

Within minutes, a barrel of oil was $20 cheaper. But that is less likely to happen today.

&quot;Markets move differently now,&quot; he says.

In fact, Mr Kahn points out, despite Friday's price spike, everything about the oil markets are different today than the last time war started in Iraq.

Places it is produced, the way it is refined and how it is traded bear no resemblance to oil he was working with when his adrenaline carried him through screaming price moves of the past.

The price of Brent crude vaulted more than 4% to hit $69.50 a barrel on Friday.

Oil prices swung on news that Iranian General Qasem Soleimani was killed in a US drone strike at Baghdad airport, which the Pentagon described as &quot;defensive action&quot;.

Stock prices of BP and Royal Dutch Shell both rose around the 1.5%.

The single biggest factor that changes the game in oil from 2004 to now, says Michael Widmer, a commodities strategist at Bank of America, is that the US makes enough oil to be independent.

The US is no longer reliant on crude from the Middle East.

&quot;The rules have changed materially,&quot; says Mr Widmer.

The drone attacks on the Saudi Arabian oil plants in September serve as a good example.

&quot;This is one of the biggest ever hits to the global oil market, in terms of supply and it had no sustained impact,&quot; he says.

That day the market surged almost $10 a barrel, but not much happened in the aftermath.

While tensions rose on the political scene with terse rhetoric flying between Iran and the US and a plan to deploy new sanctions, oil slid back down to below $60 a barrel a fortnight later.

But the sour political discourse outlasted any fears of price disruption.

That is because more countries, notably Russia and the US, are pumping out oil now.

Opec, the cartel of mainly middle eastern countries which used to control much of the supply of oil, no longer holds the same sway.

&quot;Now when Opec cuts its production numbers, it just makes more breathing space for other countries to increase theirs,&quot; says Mr Widmer.

Alan Gelder, vice president of chemicals and oil markets at Wood Mackenzie, says one way to look at it is that Opec used to produce half the world's oil, but now makes less than a third of it.

In the Gulf War, which began in 1990, oil came from two places. Either it was made by Opec, or it was produced in places considered expensive and risky, like the North Sea.

Finding oil and getting it out of the ground from the ocean, especially 40 years ago, was an unpredictable and dangerous affair.
• How US shale oil is forcing prices down - BBC News

Now, because of the fracking done in North America, there is a glut of oil.

&quot;Back then, commodity markets were just getting established. There are lots more participants in the market now,&quot; says Mr Gelder.

And far more information is available today than it was five years ago, he adds.

When Saudi Arabian producers were attacked last September, satellite imagery of ships leaving port and the plants themselves, showed that production restarted quickly and exports had resumed.

&quot;Years ago, people would be frantically calling one another, trying to figure out what was going on,&quot; he says.

At the moment Opec and other oil producing companies like Russia have agreed to hold back on pumping out as much oil as they can.

That makes it particularly difficult to know what will happen to the price of oil as tensions rise in the Middle East.

In the short term, analysts at Citibank expect prices to stay high on retaliation fears.

Attacks on US oil company pipelines, or where Western and American oil companies have invested in new exploration, would drive crude higher.

Any resolution of the conflict between Iran and the US will de-escalate the situation and prices will deflate, they say.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50981538</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>CEO Secrets: Can you be the boss if you're in chronic pain? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1136C/production/_110780507_p0829kgg.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When Shazia Ginai took over as the boss of Neuro-Insight, she thought CEOs had to be &quot;bulletproof&quot;. She has a medical condition which causes her chronic pain, and wondered if she could do the job.

But being open didn't lower her standing with her staff. Instead it's drawn them closer to her.

Find more business tips at CEO Secrets. You can also follow the series on the BBC News app by adding the topic 'CEO Secrets' in My News.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312928</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Bubble tea: A sweet treat that went global - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12216/production/_110726247_p081ykvv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Bubble tea - also called pearl tea or boba tea - is a sweet drink that combines milk, flavoured tea and tapioca pearls that are sucked up through an extra-large straw and chewed.

Invented in Taiwan in the 1980s, it has now become popular worldwide. The BBC's Sarah Toms went to a recent exhibition in Singapore to find out more.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312934</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: China to pump billions into economy amid growth fears - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1356E/production/_110741297_gettyimages-1196094984.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>China is to pump a net 150 billion yuan ($22bn; £16.3bn) into its economy on Monday to help protect it from the impact of the coronavirus outbreak.

China's central bank said the move would ensure there was enough liquidity in the banking system and help provide a stable currency market.

The virus has so far infected more than 14,000 people and claimed 305 lives - all but one inside China.

The money will be deployed when China's markets reopen on Monday.

It comes after a holiday to mark the Lunar New Year was extended in the hope of reducing the spread of the virus.

Financial regulators in the country have said they believe the impact on China's already slowing economy will be &quot;short term&quot;.
• First death from coronavirus outside China
• Can people recover from coronavirus? And other questions

But analysts say the impact of the virus - which has left major cities in full or partial lockdown - could harm growth if it lasts for a prolonged period.

China's travel and tourism sectors have already taken a hit over an unusually quiet Spring Festival break, while cinemas were forced to close to try to contain the virus.

Meanwhile, numerous factories have suspended production while companies have instructed employees to work from home

Foxconn, Toyota, Starbucks, McDonald's and Volkswagen are just a few of the corporate giants to have paused operations or shuttered outlets across China.

The country saw economic growth of 6.1% last year - the slowest in around three decades, in part because of its prolonged trade war with the US. A partial trade deal easing tensions was struck earlier this month, but most tariffs remain in place.

Economist George Magnus, associate at Oxford University's China Centre, told the BBC the size of central bank's injection reflected &quot;policymakers' concerns about the state of the economy&quot;.

&quot;The coronavirus repercussions on the economy mark the latest in a series of setbacks in the economy over the past year, including a handful of bank failures sparking contagion fears, forcing the central bank to become ever more generous with the provision of liquidity to markets.&quot;

In total, the central bank will inject 1.2 trillion yuan into the financial system on Monday - the largest single day addition on record.

The net figure will be considerably lower, however, although the bank said it could make more cash available throughout the week.

China's central bank has announced other economic measures in the face of a deepening coronavirus epidemic, including providing banks with 300 billion yuan to lend to affected companies.

Authorities have also relaxed tariffs on goods imported for use in the virus fight - including those from the US.

Investors are bracing for volatility when Chinese markets reopen on Monday. The country's stock, currency and bond markets have all been closed since 23 January and were due to reopen last Friday.

Global markets have been rattled by the epidemic, with the US S&amp;P 500 notching up its worst week since October on Friday.

More on the coronavirus outbreak:
• Coronavirus: What it does to the body
• How quarantine has fought disease through the ages</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51347497</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>What is a 'Canada-style' trade deal? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/C68B/production/_103572805_gettyimages-481599449.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Prime Minister Boris Johnson has said when it comes to trade with the EU after Brexit: &quot;We want a comprehensive free trade agreement, similar to Canada's&quot;.

The EU's agreement with Canada is called the Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement, or Ceta for short.

The EU began negotiating with Canada in 2009, and Ceta provisionally came into force in 2017, although it has not yet been signed off by all the EU member states.

What does Ceta do?

We've heard a lot about wanting a &quot;zero-tariff, zero-quota&quot; deal between the UK and the EU. Ceta does not do that.

Ceta gets rid of most, but not all, tariffs (that's taxes on imports) on goods traded between the EU and Canada. Tariffs remain on poultry, meat and eggs.

It also increases quotas (that's the amount of a product that can be exported without extra charges) but does not get rid of them altogether. For example, quotas on EU cheese exports to Canada increase from 18,500 tonnes to 31,972 tonnes a year.

It does little for the trade in services and in particular almost nothing for the trade in financial services, which is very important for the UK economy.

It also does not remove border checks, so there is still a possibility that goods have to be examined at ports to make sure they meet regulatory requirements, and their paperwork is in order.

What does it say about standards?

Ceta protects EU &quot;geographical indications&quot;, meaning for example that you can only make Parma ham in Italy and camembert cheese in France, and Canada can't import something that calls itself camembert from any other country.

They have also agreed to open up government contracts to each other, so Canadian companies could bid to build French railways, for example.

There is also co-operation between the two countries on standards, so a piece of equipment made in an EU country can go through all its safety and quality checks there, without needing to have them repeated in Canada - and vice versa.

Ceta also allows professional qualifications to be recognised both in Canada and the EU, making it easier, for example, for architects or accountants to work in both places.

And it aligns Canadian rules in some areas of copyright and patents with those of the EU.

Is the UK's trade with the EU like Canada's?

Countries that are closer to each other tend to trade more, especially in goods, and this is the case with the UK and the EU.

The UK exported £291bn of goods and services to other EU countries in 2018, which was 45% of all UK exports.

It imported £357bn of goods and services from the EU, which was 53% of all UK imports.

On the other hand, Canada exported 46.2bn Canadian dollars (£26.7bn) of goods and services to the EU in 2017, which was 7.9% of its exports.

It imported 63.6bn Canadian dollars of goods and services to the EU, which was 10.5% of its imports.

What is an Australian-style deal?

The prime minister also mentioned having an arrangement with the EU similar to Australia's.

The EU does not have a free trade deal with Australia. They are in negotiations for one, but they currently operate mainly on World Trade Organisation (WTO) rules.
• Reality Check: What does a 'WTO Brexit' mean?

There was an EU-Australia Partnership Framework agreed in 2008, which reduces barriers to trade, but was not a free trade agreement.

So, trading on a similar basis to Australia would be largely the same as trading under WTO rules. In other words, it's another way of saying the UK would leave with no trade deal in place.

What claims do you want BBC Reality Check to investigate? Get in touch</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-45633592</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: Could it damage the global economy? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/171D1/production/_110637649_gettyimages-1195300772.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>China is struggling with a new virus that has already killed more than 20 people.

It is a serious health issue. The World Health Organization has called it an emergency for China, though not for the world, not so far at least.

Inevitably, it will have economic consequences. But how severe and how far will they spread?

Economists are very wary about putting any figures on it at this early stage.

But it is possible to identify what form the impact will take and to look at the economic damage done by previous similar episodes, notably the outbreak of severe acute respiratory syndrome - better known as Sars - in 2002-3, which also began in China.

It is within China that there already is some economic damage. Travel restrictions have been imposed in parts of the country at a time [the Chinese New Year] when many people travel. So the tourism business is already being hit.

Consumer spending on entertainment and gifts will also be affected. For entertainment, many will be reluctant to take part in activities outside the home that could lead to exposure to the virus. Many people are sure to have cancelled plans of their own volition to avoid risks of exposure to the disease.

The impact is magnified by the fact that Wuhan, the city where it began, is an important transport hub.

Travel restrictions are also a problem for any business that needs to move goods or people around. Industrial supply chains will be affected. Some deliveries may be disrupted and some will become more expensive.

There will be lost economic activity as a result of people not being able or willing to travel to work.

There will also be a direct financial cost from treating patients borne by health insurers (public and private) and by patients.

Outside China, much will depend on the spread of the disease. If there are outbreaks elsewhere some of the same effects may be apparent, although almost certainly on a much smaller scale.

The extent of these effects will depend to a large degree on how easily transmissible the virus proves to be and the death rate among those infected. Encouragingly many people so far have made full recoveries, though there have been tragic exceptions.

It is often the case that economic problems are quickly reflected by financial markets, where traders' views about what assets are worth are affected by their expectations about future developments.

On this occasion that have been some negative consequences for stock markets, particular in China. But they have not been large. Even the Shanghai Composite Index is higher than it was six months ago.

There are some businesses who could gain, such as drugs makers. What is immediately available is symptom relief. In the longer term there might be profitable opportunity in developing a vaccine against the virus.

Paul Stoffels, chief scientific officer at Johnson &amp; Johnson told the BBC that his teams had already done the &quot;basic work&quot; on a vaccine. He thought it could be available in about a year.

There has also been a surge in demand for surgical masks and gloves to protect against becoming infected. Shares in Chinese companies that make these items - drugs and protective equipment - have seen some sharp price rises.

The best historical example to give guidance is probably the Sars outbreak.

One estimate suggested a cost to the global economy of $40bn (£30.5bn).

Jennifer McKeown of Capital Economics, a London based consultancy, suggests that global growth was a full percentage point weaker in the second quarter of 2003 than it would have been without Sars. That is quite a substantial hit, but she also says it made up the ground quite quickly afterwards.

She says the picture is complicated by other factors that affected global growth at the time but she concludes &quot;it is very hard to pick out any lasting damage to global GDP (economic activity) from Sars, which was an unusually severe and widespread virus&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51239745</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What does it mean for my business? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Suffolk</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EF39/production/_110714216_p081vkyl.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Preparations, port delays and planning for a potential no-deal - these are some of your big Brexit questions.

BBC East business correspondent Richard Bond has been answering some of the queries from businesses in Suffolk.

The UK formally leaves the European Union (EU) at 23:00 GMT on Friday, 31 January.

It will immediately enter an 11-month transition period.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-suffolk-51318721</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: 'You have to be optimistic as a fisherman' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F9BB/production/_110713936_p081vhnd.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Fishing is set to play a big role in post-Brexit trade negotiations between the UK and EU.

Fisherman Andy McLeod from Brixham voted Leave in the referendum, in the hope that British boats would get a bigger share of fishing rights after Brexit.

But he fears that he and his colleagues will just end up being &quot;pawns to be sacrificed, for the greater good of the country&quot;.

Video produced and edited by Oliver Smith. Filmed by Tony Smith.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312932</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Eurozone economy barely growing at all - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/2D03/production/_88232511_88232510.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The eurozone economy of 19 European Union countries barely grew at all in the final quarter of last year.

A first official estimate puts economic growth in the region at 0.1% during the three months to the end of December 2019.

Two of the eurozone's largest economies shrank in the period: France by 0.1% and Italy by 0.3%.

However, the jobs market was in better shape, with the number of people unemployed falling by 34,000.

No separate figures for Germany have been published yet. But Claus Vistesen of Pantheon Macro says that on the basis of the data released so far, growth in Europe's largest economy was about 0.2%.

Among those that have published their own national data, Spain is the strongest, continuing the pattern of a relatively robust rebound after its financial crisis.

But the overall picture is downbeat.

In France, the decline reflected companies selling from their stocks of goods, rather than producing new ones, and also a fall in exports.

Trade tensions and the impact they have had on exports have been a recurrent problem, dampening economic performance in a number of countries, notably Germany, since US President Donald Trump took office. Strikes and protests over pension reform were also a factor in France.

Italy's decline in economic activity also partly reflected stocks being run down.

The eurozone has been supported ever since the regional financial crisis by the policies of the European Central Bank (ECB).

It has very low interest rates, one of which is currently below zero, and for much of the time, has pursued a policy of quantitative easing, buying financial assets with newly created money.

The weak growth figures suggest the end of those unusual policies is still some way off.

The ECB has a target of inflation below, but close to, 2%, and one of the reasons it has maintained such low interest rates has been because it considers inflation has been too low.

Other figures just published show the headline inflation rate rose slightly in January to 1.4%. But the underlying rate, which excludes volatile energy and food prices, slipped to 1.1%.

The more encouraging news was a decline in unemployment. At 7.4%, it is the lowest since May 2008.

There are some very wide variations between countries. But even those with the highest unemployment rates - notably Greece and Spain - have seen huge falls since the eurozone crisis was at its height.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51327611</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Bank of England: City watchdog looks into pound's jump - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/BDBB/production/_110717584__110702774_boe_bbc.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The City watchdog is to investigate a jump in the pound which took place shortly before the Bank of England's interest rate announcement on Thursday.

The rise has raised questions over whether the decision to hold the Bank's base rate at 0.75% had been leaked.

The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) said: &quot;We are aware of the incident and are looking into it.&quot;

In December, the Bank referred to the FCA a leak of an audio feed of sensitive information to traders.
• UK rates held as economy shows signs of picking up

The value of sterling increased about 15 seconds before midday on Thursday, when the Bank's Monetary Policy Committee (MPC) made its announcement.

It rose from $1.3023 to $1.3089 against the dollar, and saw a similar increase against the euro.

The pound continued to rise following the announcement, although this was a smaller increase.

The Bank of England confirmed that it referred this incident to the FCA.

The FCA is the markets regulator. It does not usually look into &quot;spot&quot; currency trading, where one currency is traded for another for delivery on a specific date, but it can step in in certain circumstances. For example, if it affects other regulated markets.

Andrew Sentance, former member of the Bank's MPC, told the BBC's Today programme that its nine members make a decision on the interest rate one day before it is announced.

He said: &quot;There is confidential information circulating in the Bank for quite a long time.

&quot;But it could just be something coincidental, so we shouldn't jump to conclusions,&quot; Mr Sentance added.

In December, the Bank admitted that one of its suppliers had &quot;misused&quot; an audio feed of sensitive information.

The Bank's news conferences are usually broadcast via video, but there was also an audio back-up feed in case of problems.

This audio was available between five and eight seconds before the video feed, and was leaked to hedge fund traders.

This incident was also referred to the FCA, which is still looking into the matter. It has not launched a formal investigation into it.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51323091</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: Britain 'will not be aligning with EU rules' - Raab - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p0822qx1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Britain will &quot;not be aligning with EU rules&quot; in any post-Brexit trade deal, the foreign secretary has said.

Dominic Raab argued agreeing to stick strongly with EU regulations would &quot;defeat the point of Brexit&quot;.

But Irish PM Leo Varadkar said the UK needed to commit to a level playing field to get a free trade deal.

Talks to negotiate a free trade deal between the UK and the EU are due to start next month, following the UK's formal withdrawal from the bloc.

On Monday Boris Johnson is expected to set out his position ahead of those talks, where he will tell the EU he is prepared to accept customs checks at Britain's borders if he cannot secure the sort of trade deal he wants.

EU chief negotiator Michel Barnier will also outline his approach to negotiations.
• Brexit: What happens next?
• Seven things Brexit will change and seven it won't

One option the PM could support would be a Canada-style free trade deal which allows tariff-free trade for the majority of goods, but would not cover the UK's service industry - which accounts for more than 80% of UK jobs.

Reports in recent days have suggested EU chiefs want the UK to continue to follow EU rules on standards and state subsidies - while accepting the jurisdiction of the European Court of Justice in any trade disputes.

The PM is expected to say that he will accept no alignment and no jurisdiction of the European courts when talks start in March.

He is also preparing to say he would rule out relaxing rules on workers' rights, food hygiene standards and environmental protections.

Speaking to the BBC's Andrew Marr Show, Mr Varadkar said it was possible for the UK to have a &quot;Canada-style agreement&quot;.

However, he added: &quot;Canada isn't the UK; you're geographically part of the European continent, we share seas and airspace and our economies are very integrated.

&quot;And one thing we feel very strongly in the EU is that if we are going to have tariff-free, quota-free trade with the UK, which is essentially what we have with Canada on almost everything, then that needs to come with a level playing field.

&quot;We, for example would have very strong views on fair competition and state aid.&quot;

A level playing field is a trade policy phrase for a set of common rules and standards that prevent businesses in one country undercutting their rivals over those operating in other countries in areas such as workers' rights and environmental protections.

He also cautioned against &quot;setting rigid red lines&quot; for the post-Brexit trade negotiations arguing &quot;it makes coming to an agreement more difficult because the other side doesn't feel like it has got a fair deal unless those red lines are turned pink.&quot;

Mr Raab said the UK would enter trade talks &quot;with a spirit of goodwill&quot; but added &quot;the legislative alignment - it just ain't happening&quot;.
• Mavericks to mainstream: The long campaign for Brexit

Labour's John McDonnell said Mr Johnson's desire to diverge from EU rules &quot;contradict&quot; what the PM had previously said on protecting environmental, consumer and employment rights.

&quot;On the one hand he said there will be [protections] on the other hand he is sabre-rattling saying that won't happen in the negotiations,&quot; he said.

But Brexit Party leader Nigel Farage welcomed the prime minister's approach arguing it was in the UK's &quot;national interest&quot; to be &quot;a competitor on their [the EU's] doorstep.&quot;

The government also wants to make progress in striking free trade agreements with countries such as the United States, Japan, Australia and New Zealand.

The EU's own approach to the negotiations needs to be agreed by all 27 member states - which would be unlikely to happen before the end of February.

While the UK officially left the EU at 23:00 GMT on Friday, it will remain wedded to EU rules during a transition period which ends in December this year.

The UK can request an extension to this transition period, but Mr Johnson has previously said he will not do so.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51345776</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Will house prices rise or fall this year? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12A9C/production/_110344467_carnival1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Buying or selling a home can feel like an endless merry-go-round for anyone caught up in a tortuous house move.

In one £1.5m property in East Sussex, the fairground nature of many property transactions has been taken literally. The converted Victorian bathhouse is filled with funfair nostalgia.

The home, which features a retro bowling alley, a basketball arcade game and a coconut shy above the sink, went on the market in 2019.

It is not just the features which were unusual. The very fact it was listed for sale was uncommon too. Listings in the UK housing market last year were down 8% on the previous year, according to property portal Rightmove.

The dominant feature of the market in the last 12 months has been caution. Many potential sellers decided to stay put amid political and economic uncertainty, amid the Brexit debate and general election.

A carnival-themed home may feel like the appropriate metaphor for the goings-on in Westminster last year. While this put off sellers, demand among potential buyers remained relatively stable.

Low interest rates meant mortgages were relatively cheap for anyone finding a home within their budget. First-time buyer numbers were also surprisingly healthy. Debt, divorce, schools and new jobs still prompted people to move.

That led to prices rising on average across the country, if only by a little, rather than wholesale property price drops. The Nationwide Building Society says, on average, UK house prices went up by 1.4% over the year. The falls were mostly seen in and around London - the market most affected by Brexit uncertainty.

Other areas of the country saw prices rise faster than wages and the cost of living. Mortgage lender the Halifax suggests that Billingham in County Durham saw the biggest average price rise, up 12.3% in October 2019 compared with the same month a year earlier. Ilkeston saw a 9.1% rise over the same period. The next eight on the list - Sale, Wilmslow, Blackburn, Bolton, Burnley, Chorley, Bootle and Southport - are all in the North West of England and saw price rises of 6% or more.
• The UK cities where rent is rising the fastest

These figures are based on the Halifax's mortgage data, so do not give a full picture but do reflect the North-South divide in price movements seen last year, as prices in London dropped.

It was a similar picture among tenants, Manchester and Liverpool were the most searched areas among renters after Bristol, according to Rightmove.

What will happen in 2020?

The result of the general election has brought a level of political certainty and a clear route, in the short-term at least, for the Brexit process.

Many experts suggest this could play out in the housing market with a release of some pent-up demand among buyers and sellers. People who put off making one of the biggest financial decisions of their lives may now feel more confident in making that step.

While that may inject some activity in the housing market in the first few months of the year, most commentators do not expect it to last. Before long, they say, the uncertainty and debate over the UK's future relationship with the EU could mean more caution in the sector.

As a result, they are mostly predicting that house prices will rise by 2% from the start to the end of 2020.

These predictions are for a UK average, but the housing market must always be considered on a local level. House prices can be affected by anything from schools to new developments and transport links, sometimes recording different rates of change from street to street.

Richard Donnell, director of research and insight at Zoopla, suggests that the more &quot;affordable&quot; cities for property, such as Glasgow, Belfast and Liverpool, could witness the biggest rises in prices in 2020, up by about 4%. The least affordable - London - could see prices rise by about 2%, he says.

Affordability, as in any year, is crucial to demand, particularly from first-time buyers. The eyes of the experts consulted for this article are firmly on the new government and its housing policies.

Miles Shipside, of Rightmove, says these policies need to focus on those first-time buyers, many of whom are struggling to save a deposit and may not want to buy a new-build home through the government's Help to Buy assistance scheme.

&quot;It will be interesting to see whether we really do get a programme to actually build truly affordable homes,&quot; says Andrew Montlake, from mortgage broker Coreco.

Andrew Burrell, from analysts Capital Economics, suggests housing is not at the top of the government's priorities.

&quot;With no new policy initiatives expected, it is difficult to see any lift-off for the market,&quot; he says.

The Conservatives' significant majority may have brought some short-term clarity to the timetable of the UK's departure from the EU, but every commentator expects more complexity to come.

&quot;It is quite possible that Brexit will cast a shadow over the economy as we move closer to the end of the year and trade arrangements need to be concluded,&quot; says Simon Rubinsohn, from the Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors (RICS).

The return of uncertainty may prompt some people to simply lock themselves away from the European debate.

So, they may have been tempted by another, rather unusual, property that was put on the market in 2019.

The London penthouse with views over the River Thames and Canary Wharf was put up for sale for £2m.

The views outside are one key feature, but a cave-themed cinema room also catches the eye.

Caves and carnivals may have marked 2019 both in unusual properties and as a metaphor for UK politics but, ultimately, house prices were little changed.

There may be more darkness than light in EU negotiations and some pinball politics to contend with again in 2020. For the experts, that means buyers and sellers could play it safe and house prices could well hold steady again.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50852981</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Aviation not the enemy in climate battle, says Heathrow boss - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EFDE/production/_110760416_gettyimages-973359948.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Flying is not &quot;the enemy&quot; in the fight against climate change, the chief executive of Heathrow Airport has said.

John Holland-Kaye told the BBC's Today programme: &quot;The answer is not to stop people flying. It has to be about decarbonising aviation.&quot;

The UK's aviation industry is promising to reduce its net carbon emissions to zero by 2050.

Cleaner engines, new fuels and planting trees will all help, according to the industry group Sustainable Aviation.

Mr Holland-Kaye said: &quot;The enemy is carbon, not aviation. We need to protect the ability to fly in a world without carbon.

&quot;When the government blocked Heathrow expansion 10 years ago, people started flying through Amsterdam and Paris instead, taking two flights instead of one and not a single tonne of carbon was saved.&quot;

He said synthetic fuels were the way forward. &quot;It has been around for about 100 years and is becoming more affordable. It needs a real push on investment.&quot;

'Crisis is here and now'

Sustainable Aviation says the industry's plan will mean airlines can cut pollution even as passenger numbers grow by an expected 70%.

But campaigners say the only way to cut airline pollution is by reducing air travel and cancelling new airports and runways.

&quot;We need to restrict flying,&quot; said Muna Suleiman, from Friends of the Earth. &quot;We can't have airport expansion at the same time.&quot;

Rail travel and buses are greener alternatives and taxes should be applied to frequent fliers, she said.

Biofuels, which Sustainable Aviation say will be part of the industry's plan, still pollute, Ms Suleiman added. &quot;The crisis is here and now.&quot;

The aviation sector is under increasing pressure to come up with a plan to cut emissions, especially as it has no commercial comparator yet to the electric car, which is seen as the auto industry's hope for cutting emissions.

While other forms of transport produce more carbon, individual journeys on planes produce large amounts of CO2.

Sustainable Aviation says the UK industry can reduce its emissions of CO2 from 30 million tonnes a year to zero, without restricting growth.

An economy-class return flight from London to New York emits an estimated 0.67 tonnes of CO2 per passenger, according to the calculator from the UN's civil aviation body, the International Civil Aviation Organization.

That is equivalent to 11% of the average annual emissions for someone in the UK or about the same as all of those caused by someone living in Ghana for more than a year.

US firm Wright Electric said last week it had started electric engine development for a 186-seater plane, and hoped to begin test flights in 2023.

British Airways is investing in a project to make fuel from rubbish.

&quot;We are going to have to do this through many projects,&quot; Alex Cruz, chief executive of British Airways, told the BBC.

&quot;Biofuels will give us a greener alternative and we are attracted by that,&quot; he said, while conceding that they will still produce carbon dioxide and that they are expensive at the moment.

&quot;We do believe we will reach a point where the price will be compatible with the rest of fuel prices.&quot;

BA will also retire old planes, with the double-decker Boeing 747 being phased out in 2024.

Other plans include planting trees - so-called carbon offsetting - and investing in renewable power sources, said Matt Gorman, a council member of Sustainable Aviation.

&quot;Aviation is one of the more difficult sectors to decarbonise but we are absolutely confident it can be done,&quot; said Mr Gorman. &quot;We have to do it&quot;

The aviation sector has a problem. On one level, it is extremely successful. Passenger numbers in the UK are higher than they've ever been, and massive growth is expected worldwide over the next couple of decades.

More passengers means more planes, and all else being equal that means an awful lot more emissions. The sector only accounts for about 2.5% of global CO2 output at the moment, but the obvious risk is that share could rise significantly.

You don't have to be Greta Thunberg to realise where that could lead. There's a risk that faced with growing public pressure to act on climate change, regulators could start to clamp down on the sector in a meaningful way - and that could hit growth.

So here in the UK, businesses are taking pre-emptive action. Action they claim will reduce emissions to zero without curbing growth.

So how effective will the plans be? Boeing and Airbus are already selling a new generation of aircraft that are much more efficient than their predecessors, and it's fair to say that there are plenty of benefits to be gained from investing in new technology.

But the value of &quot;market-based measures&quot; such as carbon offsets is harder to calculate and hotly debated. People within the industry claim the projects they support are carefully chosen and reap real benefits.

Climate campaigners say that's greenwash - and they'd rather we simply decided to fly a lot less.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51364103</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-04 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>HS2: Johnson drops 'keep digging' hint over future of project - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/5F8E/production/_110726442_mediaitem110726441.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Boris Johnson has suggested the only answer to the &quot;hole&quot; enveloping HS2 is &quot;to keep digging&quot;.

In an interview for Sky Kids' FYI show, the PM criticised the &quot;profligate&quot; rail project and its &quot;hopeless&quot; management.

But he appeared to rule out pulling the plug on the controversial scheme, which might cost in excess of £100bn, saying &quot;in a hole the size of HS2, the only thing to do is keep digging&quot;.

A final decision on the UK's largest construction project is due next month.

HS2 is designed to link London, Birmingham, Manchester and Leeds, cutting overcrowding on the railways and helping to rebalance the UK's economy.

But the project has faced criticism from both Conservative and Labour MPs for being over budget and behind schedule.

An official review of the project, seen by the BBC, warns the project could now cost up to double the official 2015 estimate of £56bn while there is a &quot;considerable risk&quot; its first phase between London and Birmingham might need more money.

But the government commissioned report, led by Doug Oakervee, &quot;strongly advises&quot; against cancelling the project and says that only building one section of the line &quot;doesn't make sense&quot;.

Quizzed about the fate of the project, Mr Johnson hit out at HS2 Ltd, the company set up in 2009 to oversee it.

&quot;The truth is, the people who did it spent far too much money, they were profligate with the way they did it,&quot; he told the children's current affairs programme, in a recording to be broadcast on Saturday,

&quot;They just wasted money. And the whole way it was managed was hopeless.&quot;

Asked what he would do next, he replied: &quot;So we're in a hole, we're in a mess. But we've got to get out of it. And we need a way forward, so we're thinking about how to sort it out now.

&quot;In a hole the size of HS2, the only thing to do is keep digging. That's what you've got to do. It's a big hole.&quot;

Phase 1 of HS2 between London and Birmingham is due to open at the end of 2026, with the second phase to Leeds and Manchester scheduled for completion by 2032-33. It is designed to carry trains capable of travelling at 250mph (402km/h).

The project has already cost £9bn. On Wednesday, the chancellor Sajid Javid threw his support behind the link, despite the spiralling costs.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51331162</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
