<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Carlos Ghosn: Japan presses for ex-Nissan boss's extradition from Lebanon - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1777/production/_110370060_058232941-1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Japan has renewed its call for Lebanon to return fugitive ex-Nissan boss Carlos Ghosn.

Lebanon does not typically surrender its citizens but Japan says it can request his extradition.

According to reports, Mr Ghosn walked out of his house on 29 December before boarding a bullet train to Osaka.

He was then reportedly smuggled out of the country in a flight case, usually used to transport musical equipment.

Mr Ghosn, who ran Nissan until he was arrested on charges of financial misconduct in November 2018, was banned from seeing his wife while on bail.

But, in the final days of 2019, he skipped bail to board a private jet that took him to Turkey before he travelled on to Lebanon, where he is a citizen and where his wife was waiting.

Security cameras caught the 65-year old walking out of his house in Tokyo alone at around 14:30 local time on 29 December, according to Japanese media.

He reportedly then met two men at a Tokyo hotel who escorted him to the city's Shinagawa station where they caught a train to Osaka, Japan's second city.

There, the three men checked into a hotel near Kansai Airport, the reports said.

Mr Ghosn was not seen leaving the hotel but the two other men were caught by security cameras exiting with two big boxes, according to the reports.

The Wall Street Journal said Mr Ghosn was loaded on to the private jet bound for Turkey in a flight case, with holes drilled into the bottom so that the fugitive executive was able to breathe.

The paper said the case was not checked by airport security before it was loaded on to the plane.

Japan's justice ministry said it did not have records of Mr Ghosn departing Japan.

&quot;It is believed that he used some wrongful methods to illegally leave the country,&quot; the country's Justice Minister, Masako Mori, said at a press conference on Monday.

&quot;I have instructed the immigration agency to further tighten the departure process,&quot; she added.

Since fleeing, Mr Ghosn has avoided media interviews but he is expected to break his silence at a press conference on Wednesday.

Last week, he issued a short statement that said he alone arranged for his unauthorised departure from Japan and played down speculation that his wife, Carole, and other members of his family helped arrange for him to escape.

Mr Ghosn denies the charges of financial wrongdoing in Japan, instead claiming the country's justice system is &quot;rigged&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51010128</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Frankfurt Motor Show: Love, hate and electric cars - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/2EFA/production/_108762021_mediaitem108762020.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>I have a love-hate relationship with international motor shows such as this week's extravaganza in Frankfurt.

On the one hand, if you like cars, if you have a single drop of petrol in your veins, it's impossible not to be impressed by the array of awesome engineering on display. And that of course is the general idea.

Manufacturers spend huge sums developing their latest four-wheeled fantasies, laden with up-to-the-minute electronic gizmos, which apparently will do everything for you except brush your teeth. They want you to be impressed.

But there's a very big downside as well. The sheer scale of these events is staggering. Hundreds of exhibitors and hundreds of thousands of visitors are crammed into a series of giant pavilions, each the size of many football pitches.

On press day, every manufacturer has its own presentation, complete with flashing lights, wall to wall video and a booming soundtrack. Many of them happening at the same time.

It's hot, stuffy and very, very noisy. Getting around is a major chore, especially in Frankfurt, where it can take 20 minutes to get from one side of the show to the other. I walked more than eight miles (13 kilometres) yesterday, just moving between interviews. As a colleague put it, &quot;why does BMW have to be in another bloody postcode?&quot;.

So why bother going? Well, for a start, it is a great way to take the pulse of the industry, to see what people are thinking, and what they're worried about. I've attended far too many of these shows in my career, but each one has been different.

For many years now, the dominant themes have been electrification and automation.

At the major European shows in Frankfurt, Geneva and Paris there's been endless speculative talk about the need to develop battery powered cars, and about how we'll live with self-driving machines.

Porsche set to lead the charge at Frankfurt show

Electric car models to triple in Europe by 2021

But here in Frankfurt, what used to be speculation is becoming reality. The launch of Volkswagen's ID.3 is being seen as a landmark moment. Not because it looks particularly flashy or exotic - it doesn't - but because this is the first purpose-built electric car the German giant has produced, the first fruit of a €30bn (£27bn) investment programme, designed to turn the company into a market leader in electric cars.

There's an irony here, of course. Four years ago, Volkswagen was a very different company. It was during the 2015 show in Frankfurt that the US environmental authorities dropped their bombshell, accusing the German company of deliberately manipulating emissions tests. Executive heads rolled, billions of dollars in fines were paid, and the company embarked on a very different corporate strategy.

Now the VW Group is well positioned to hit the front in a race to produce electric cars which other manufacturers have had no choice but to join - although established players in the market for affordable EVs, such as Renault, Nissan and Kia, can be expected to fight for every sale.

New EU rules which will be phased in from next year will force manufacturers to reduce the average emissions from their car fleets dramatically, or face hefty fines. Because the rules will apply to new car registrations, they won't be able to design a few token low-emission models and leave them in a dark garage somewhere. They will actually have to sell them.

It's fair to say this is making some car firms a little nervous. One problem with electric cars at the moment, leaving aside arguments over issues such as charging points, is that they cost more to build than conventional cars. That means prices are higher, yet they are less profitable to sell. That may change as the market develops, with economies of scale coming into play, but at the moment it is an issue.

Manufacturers, then, have been spending a great deal of money to develop new cars that will probably produce lower profits than existing models, at a time when the industry as a whole is facing up to a slowing global economy, falling sales in major markets and the effects of mounting trade tensions. The chief executive of Jaguar Land Rover, Ralf Speth, told me it all added up to a &quot;perfect storm&quot; for the industry.

Perhaps it's no surprise then, that this show has seen fewer eye-catching concept cars than other recent events. I've become accustomed to seeing wacky fantasy models which claim to show off how self-driving cars will be integrated into our lives - such as Renault's car-in-your-living-room .

Not so this time. Manufacturers are more concerned right now with getting electric cars into production and on sale than indulging in futuristic dreams. Of course, automated technology is still being developed at breakneck pace - and advanced systems, such as lane-keeping assistance, are finding their way onto cars in the showrooms. But most of the really sci-fi creations have been put away.

Not all of them though. Audi has still brought along its AI:Trail, a concept for a future self-driving off-road vehicle. It looks rather fearsome - a cross between a lunar buggy and something out of a Mad Max movie. With drones for headlights.

If the future really is dystopian, Audi at least will be ready.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49673933</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Ex-Nissan boss Ghosn leaves a Tokyo jail on bail - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/A8B6/production/_105909134_p072q58l.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Carlos Ghosn, the former boss of Nissan, has been released from a detention centre in Japan on bail following his arrest in November. He has been charged with financial misconduct and aggravated breach of trust, but denies wrongdoing.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-47467763</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Tesla overtakes Volkswagen as value hits $100bn - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11B7B/production/_110617527_tesla_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Tesla has displaced Volkswagen as the world's second most valuable carmaker, after a dramatic rise in share price pushed its market value to more than $100bn (£76.1bn).

The milestone sets the stage for chief Elon Musk to collect billions in pay tied to hitting that target.

Tesla's share price has more than doubled since October, when the firm reported a rare quarterly profit.

Shares rose 4% on Wednesday, making its valuation second only to Toyota.

Although Mr Musk's company has some way to go to catch up with the Japanese car making giant. Toyota has a stock market valuation of more than $230bn.

Some analysts say the rise in price reflects Tesla's performance in recent months, during which it has opened a factory in Shanghai and met its production goals.

This month, Tesla said it had delivered more than 367,500 cars last year - up 50% from 2018. Investors expect the new factory to act as a springboard that will allow it to capture more of the Chinese market.

Despite the increase, Tesla's sales remain small compared to those of its competitors.

Volkswagen delivered almost 11 million vehicles last year, while Toyota sold more than 9 million in the first 11 months of 2019.

Tesla has also never made an annual profit and it is facing investigations after complaints about battery fires and unexpected acceleration.

The company is due to report its latest quarterly results to investors this month.

If Tesla sustains the $100bn valuation, it could unlock the first piece of a $2.6bn compensation package for Mr Musk.

The plans calls for Mr Musk to receive payouts in shares over 10 years, with the first award contingent on the firm reaching $100bn in market capitalisation and sustaining that value over both a month, and six-month average.

Tesla also had to reach $20bn in revenue and earn $1.5bn, after adjusting for items like taxes - thresholds the carmaker reached in 2018.

Tesla was valued at about $55bn when the pay deal was approved.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51214824</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Tesla delivers its first 'Made in China' cars - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F9F9/production/_110339936_em_3fl2vuaan9hj.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Tesla has delivered its first cars made in China, marking a major milestone for the electric vehicle maker.

Fifteen Model 3 sedans were handed over at the company's so-called &quot;Gigafactory&quot; near Shanghai.

It comes as Elon Musk's company aims to secure a significant slice of the world's biggest car market.

Tesla's move into the country comes as the trade war has forced other American companies to shift production out of China.

During a ceremony at the company's multi-billion dollar plant in Shanghai, 15 of its employees received cars they had purchased.

The event means deliveries of cars have started a little over a year after construction of the factory got underway.

California-based Tesla said that it wanted to start handing over vehicles before the Lunar New Year beginning on 25 January, and now plans to scale up deliveries from the start of 2020.

The Chinese-made Model 3, priced at $50,000 (£38,000) before subsidies, will compete with local electric car makers, including NIO and Xpeng Motors, as well as global brands such as BMW and Mercedes-Benz.
• Tesla gets the go-ahead to build cars in China

US technology giants Apple, Google, HP, and Dell have all reportedly started the process of moving production from China to other Asian countries.

That's as US tariffs on Chinese-made goods make them more expensive when they are imported into America, or companies have to absorb the cost themselves.

It also comes after intense pressure from US President Donald Trump for American companies to bring back manufacturing to the US. In August Mr Trump issued a demand for all US firms to move production out of China.

However, Tesla doesn't plan to export the cars it makes in China to the US, where they would be hit with tariffs. Instead it wants to sell the cars in China itself.

Previously Tesla was exporting all of the cars it sold in China from the US, which meant they were hit with tariffs in China.

The company isn't just expanding its manufacturing into China. In November, it revealed plans to build a huge European production facility on the outskirts of Berlin in Germany.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50921729</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>'Grave concern' as sales of low emission cars fall - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13491/production/_107739987_electric.car.lady.standing.g.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sales of low emission cars in the UK have fallen for the first time in more than two years, the industry has said.

The decline comes as overall sales of new cars continued to fall, dropping 4.9% in June from the year before.

The Society of Motor Manufacturers and Traders said the fall in alternatively fuelled cars, such as hybrid electric vehicles, was &quot;a grave concern&quot;.

It said efforts to sell such cars were being undermined by confusing policies and &quot;premature&quot; removal of subsidies.

The SMMT said sales of plug-in hybrid cars in June had halved since the same month a year earlier, while hybrid electric vehicle sales were down 4.7%.

This meant that the alternatively fuelled car sector saw overall sales fall for the first time since April 2017.

In last year's Budget, subsidies for plug-in hybrids were scrapped, and reduced for battery electric vehicles.
• How to get the best price when buying a car

&quot;Another month of decline is worrying but the fact that sales of alternatively fuelled cars are going into reverse is a grave concern,&quot; said Mike Hawes, SMMT chief executive.

&quot;Manufacturers have invested billions to bring these vehicles to market but their efforts are now being undermined by confusing policies and the premature removal of purchase incentives.

&quot;If we are to see widespread uptake of these vehicles, which are an essential part of a smooth transition to zero emission transport, we need world-class, long-term incentives and substantial investment in infrastructure.&quot;

A Department for Transport spokesperson said: &quot;The plug-in car grant has supported the purchase of 180,000 new cars with over £700m, including 100,000 plug-in hybrids, and the government is now focusing on the cleanest, zero emission models.

&quot;That focus has paid off - with registrations of battery electric vehicles up over 60% this year compared to the same period in 2018.&quot;

When will the tipping-point for electric sales arrive in Britain?

Driving-up sales of fully electric vehicles is the top priority for the Department for Transport, hence its decision to scrap grants for hybrids last year which will have contributed to the decline of hybrid sales.

Privately officials admit that the charging infrastructure for electrics is not where it should be.

The government says it is working with local authorities across the UK to address that.

Charging points on streets with no off-street parking is a particular challenge.

Another reason given for why sales of all low emission cars has not yet sky-rocketed in Britain is the up-until-now relatively low number of models on the market.

That is set to change over the next year or so with plenty in the pipeline.

And manufacturers have another reason to act. They could face fines if their new cars aren't green enough once European Union regulations kick-in in 2021.

Much has been said of the government's target of no new diesels and petrols by 2040.

But a more interesting question is: when will the tipping-point for electric sales arrive in Britain?

Experts inside and outside of government talk about 2025.

Norway has already reached its electric tipping point. High taxes for polluting vehicles and financial incentives for electrics mean for many there it's cheaper to buy and run an electric car.

Getting, at least close, to price parity in Britain will also be key.

Karen Johnson from Barclays Corporate Banking said that while the dip in overall car sales was &quot;no surprise&quot;, the fall in alternatively fuelled vehicles &quot;will be more of a shock, and should make policymakers sit up and take note&quot;.

&quot;There are two main factors hitting new car sales. One is the broader economic environment that is affecting consumer and business confidence across the retail sector, with big-ticket items particularly affected. The other is the continuing confusion around fuel types and the impact of new regulation on the future value of vehicles,&quot; she said.

&quot;People are having to guess what the next policy move will be and this is affecting the used car market, with some book values down in part due to fears about future prices if further regulatory changes are introduced. This has a knock-on effect on appetite for new vehicles.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48865702</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>'The most powerful Italian sports car ever made' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1156C/production/_105902017_p072nhvf.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Automobili Pininfarina's Battista &quot;hypercar&quot; is the fastest road legal car ever - and it's electric.

Chief executive Michael Perschke talks to the BBC's Theo Leggett about why the company built the £2m battery-powered machine.

Read Russell Hotten's feature about the Battista here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-47461409</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Porsche set to lead the charge at Frankfurt show - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/BB68/production/_108667974_1-high_taycan_turbo_s_2019_.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Frankfurt Motor Show, which gets under way later this week, will showcase some of the most exciting new models the car industry has produced in years. Yet even the organisers admit the event is not quite what it used to be.

Inside the vast exhibition halls, an array of high-tech new electric designs will certainly be attracting plenty of attention.

But outside dark political clouds are looming, and behind the scenes the legions of be-suited executives are likely to be worried - about trade tensions, falling sales in key markets and, of course, Brexit.

The Internationale Automobil-Ausstellung, or IAA, remains one of the biggest motor shows in the world. There will be more than 800 exhibitors from 30 countries, spread across an area the size of 24 football pitches.

Yet although the major German carmakers - VW Group, Daimler and BMW - will be determined to put on an elaborate display at their home event, other big names will be missing, among them Toyota, Nissan, and Fiat Chrysler.

This has been a trend for a number of years now, and not just at Frankfurt.

Exhibiting at car shows is expensive, while manufacturers are investing huge sums in developing new technologies, such as electric cars and autonomous systems, and their budgets are under pressure.

While major events like the IAA do attract a lot of publicity, there's also a great deal of competition for headlines. Small wonder then, that carmakers are increasingly becoming choosy about where and when they show off their wares.

The American manufacturer Ford, for example, often prefers to hold major product launches at in-house events.

&quot;We believe such events provide a more focused environment where we can take the time with our audiences rather than in the busy arena of an auto show&quot;, says spokesman John Gardiner.

Meanwhile the German automotive industry association, the VDA, which organizes the Frankfurt show, is well aware the world is changing. It wants to focus more attention than ever on new technologies, such as electrification, automated driving and connectivity.

As the VDA president Bernhard Mattes put it at a press conference ahead of the event, &quot;we have recast the IAA - as the international platform for the individual mobility of the future&quot;.

Against that backdrop, it is no surprise that many of the biggest attractions at the show will be electric.

They include the new Porsche Taycan. Officially unveiled last week, it is the first all-electric model ever to be produced by the Stuttgart manufacturer, and goes into production at a brand new factory today.

It has a top speed of 161mph, and is capable of accelerating from 0-60mph in 3.2 seconds, while it has a range of 279 miles between charges.

This makes it a bona-fide sportscar, although critics have been quick to point out that in performance terms it still has some way to go to match its closest rival - the well-established and cheaper Tesla Model S.

But arguably more significant in industry terms is the new ID.3, a battery powered hatchback which will be unveiled in Frankfurt.

In the wake of the 2015 diesel emissions scandal, Volkswagen announced it would invest tens of billions of euros to develop an entirely new generation of electric cars, using a toolkit of common components in order to keep costs down.

The ID.3 is the first of those new models to go into production, and its launch is a highly symbolic moment for the VW Group. The point is being reinforced by a rebranding exercise, which will also see the company unveil a new logo at the show.

That will probably ensure the VW Group hogs the headlines. But its rival Daimler will be hoping to claim at least a share of the limelight.

The company has been badly affected recently by falling sales of diesel cars, the effects of global trade tensions, and the need to recall and fix tens of thousands of cars which were allegedly fitted with emissions cheating software.

Under its new chief executive Ola Källenius, Daimler has launched a major cost cutting drive in an effort to boost its profits. It is also working with other manufacturers to pool the costs of developing new technologies.

It is planning to show off a new electric people carrier, the EQV, as well as a concept for an electric saloon, the EQS.

BMW will use the show to put its all-electric mini on display. The new model will be built at its plant in Oxford, with production beginning next year.

Jaguar Land Rover, meanwhile, is also hoping to make an impact with a new take on an old favourite. The company will reveal its new Defender - a replacement for the rugged off roader that first rolled out of the factory in 1948, and remained in production for an astonishing 67 years.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49615364</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>CES 2020: Sony announces electric car concept - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/107DF/production/_110415576_sony2.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Electronics giant Sony has surprised attendees of the CES tech show by unveiling an electric car dubbed the Vision S.

The vehicle is a prototype designed to show off the firm's sensors and in-car entertainment technologies.

The dashboard is flanked by an ultra-wide panoramic screen &quot;for driving information and entertainment&quot;.

However, Sony did not indicate that it had any plans to sell the car to the public.

&quot;We will accelerate our efforts to contribute to the future of mobility,&quot; said Sony's chief executive Kenichiro Yoshida as he revealed the surprise.

Bob O'Donnell, from Technalysis Research, was at the press event.

&quot;It was quite a shock to be honest with you,&quot; he told the BBC. &quot;It highlights how the company is reinventing itself.&quot;

Among the internal features of the car is sensing technology that can detect occupants of the vehicle and recognise them, in order to allow for gesture control of the entertainment systems.

In total, Sony has included 33 sensors in the Vision S prototype. The Japanese firm is known to have developed powerful image sensors that can be used to analyse the road in front of a vehicle.

Mr O'Donnell said that such technology could perhaps aid assisted-driving systems in future vehicles, helping judge when to apply the brakes or adjust the steering but still leaving most decisions up to the motorist.

&quot;Assisted driving could be as useful, in fact, in some ways even more useful than autonomous driving,&quot; he added.

Also unveiled at CES was a concept car from Mercedes-Benz, which has teamed up with the creators of science-fiction film Avatar to develop the Vision AVTR (Advanced Vehicle Transformation).

The car has no steering wheel or engine but features movable reptilian &quot;scales&quot;, a wooden floor, transparent doors and an &quot;infotainment&quot; system operated by gesture.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-51015921</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Tumble in UK car output 'a grave concern', says trade body - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/66A4/production/_105467262_gettyimages-459115032.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>UK car production sank to its lowest in almost a decade in 2019, with output forecast to continue falling this year.

Factories produced 1.3 million units last year, down 14.2% on 2018 and the third consecutive year of decline, according to figures from the Society of Motor Manufacturing and Traders.

Structural changes in the industry, Brexit uncertainty, and weak exports were all factors, the trade body said.

Production of cars to be sold in the UK fell 12.3% last year, while vehicles for export fell 14.7%. With 81% of cars built for export - the vast majority sent to the European Union - Mr Hawes again stressed the importance of a barrier-free EU trade deal after Brexit.

Shipments to EU countries fell by 11.1% last year, but the bloc remains the industry's most important market

&quot;Given the uncertainty the sector has experienced, it is essential to protect our global competitiveness, and that starts with an ambitious free trade agreement with Europe - one that guarantees all automotive products can be bought and sold without tariffs or additional burdens,&quot; he said.

Britain leaves the EU at 23:00 GMT on Friday, although trade rules will remain unchanged until the end of the transition period in December.

Mr Hawes does not anticipate any disruption to exports or imports, as the threat of a cliff-edge Brexit that spooked the industry last year has receded.

But given the integrated nature of the European motor industry, with parts, components and cars going back and forth across borders several times during the production process, a trade deal needed to be struck as soon as possible, he said.

&quot;This will boost manufacturing, avoid costly price rises and maintain choice for UK consumers. Negotiations will be challenging but all sides stand to gain,&quot; Mr Hawes said. He estimates that the imposition of tariffs on cars and components will add £1,500 to the price of an average car, currently about £22,700.

A satisfactory trade deal will unlock a pipeline of investment into the UK, by both manufactures and the supply chain, he said. Carlos Tavares, chief executive of France's PSA Group, which owns Vauxhall, has stressed the importance of a trade deal to secure investment at the UK company's Ellesmere Port factory, in Cheshire.

It's dreadful news for car workers, but the fall in new cars sales may be good for the environment.

It may also provoke a deeper debate about the role of the car in society.

Perhaps people are putting off buying a car until they see how Brexit works out, or because they're uncertain how electric car charging will progress.

But other changes are underway - such as the move away from car ownership among young people.

In the 1990s, 80% of people were driving by 30; now this marker is only reached by 45. And men under 30 are travelling only half the miles their fathers did.

Some young people can't afford cars. Others worry about the environment, and take public transport or perhaps hire a car when they need one.

Yet still the government predicts a growth in traffic, and is planning £28.8bn spending on roads.

The independent Commission on Travel Demand says this should lead to a government re-think about travel priorities.

Manufacturing output this year is forecast to fall less sharply, to about 1.27 million units, with companies having already started adjusting to structural changes, such as the slump in diesel cars, new emissions regulations, and investment in electric and hybrid cars.

Mr Hawes said a bright spot in last year's figures was a 34.7% rise in production of electric and hybrid vehicles. But with 192,304 units produced, it was a small part of the overall total. &quot;The challenge to the industry is how quickly it can move,&quot; Mr Hawes said. &quot;Environmental pressures are not going away. They are going to increase.&quot;

Alongside the production data, the SMMT released new figures highlighting the motor industry's contribution to the UK economy. About 168,000 people - one in 14 - employed in manufacturing works in automotive, with an additional 279,000 jobs supported by the sector.

In the north east and west Midlands, automotive accounts for more than one in six manufacturing jobs.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51300835</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Electric cars dominate at the Geneva Motor Show - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/59F7/production/_105913032_p072rn48.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>As the global car industry shows off its latest models and concept cars in Switzerland, many more vehicles than normal are electric powered.

One key factor behind the rise in electric cars is tough new EU emissions rules, as the BBC's Theo Leggett reports.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-47469456</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Toyota Europe boss in stark no-deal Brexit warning - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13145/production/_105894187_p072mpjv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Toyota Motor Europe's President and chief executive, Johan van Zyl, says a no-deal Brexit would make building new models at its Derbyshire plant at Burnaston &quot;extremely complicated&quot;. He warns if the situation were very bad the plant could also eventually run out of work. He adds that preparing for a potential no deal has been very costly.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-47454574</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Volkswagen in 'dieselgate' talks with motorists - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/05F6/production/_101162510_gettyimages-109422673.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Volkswagen has said it is in talks with a group of German drivers who are suing the car giant over excessive emissions from its diesel cars.

The motorists say they were affected when VW &quot;cheated&quot; emissions rules by installing unlawful &quot;defeat devices&quot; in its diesel cars.

The carmaker and the Federal Association of Consumers (VZBV) said the talks were at an early stage.

There was &quot;no guarantee&quot; of a settlement, they said.

&quot;The common goal of VZBV and Volkswagen is a pragmatic solution for the benefit of the customer,&quot; they declared, adding that they had agreed to keep the talks confidential.

The class action case is among the first of its kind in Germany.

Because of a new draft law in 2018, consumer rights groups became able to represent customers taking companies to court - and to bear their costs.

VZBV, an umbrella group of consumer associations, is state-financed and represents a wide range of members, from building owners to workers to the German cycling federation.

Proceedings began in September 2019 in a local court near the VW factory, the Higher Regional Court of Brunswick. Deliberations had to be moved to a town hall, as so many attended, according to a Reuters report.

VW disclosed in 2015 that it had used illegal software to manipulate the results of diesel emissions tests.

At the time, the company said that about 11 million cars were fitted with the &quot;defeat device&quot;, which alerted diesel engines when they were being tested. The engine would then change its performance in order to improve the result of the test.

Since the scandal broke, the carmaker has spent more than €30bn (£25bn) in legal costs and fines.

Volkswagen has faced a flurry of legal action worldwide, including the UK, where the High Court in London has begun hearing a case brought on behalf of tens of thousands of motorists. The carmaker's current and former senior employees are facing criminal charges in Germany.

In May 2019, the company, which also owns Audi, Bentley, Bugatti, Lamborghini, Porsche, Seat and Skoda, said in its annual report that it had set aside a further €1bn (£847m) in legal provisions which included this case.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50971156</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>New car registrations at lowest level since 2013 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/17598/production/_110404659_gettyimages-500260065.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>New car registrations in the UK last year fell to their lowest level since 2013, according to the Society of Motor Manufacturers and Traders (SMMT).

It was the third consecutive year of decline, and the SMMT expects that trend to continue in 2020.

Those expectations are largely due to weak consumer confidence and confusion over clean-air legislation.

The organisation also says the industry is facing serious challenges adapting to new emissions legislation.

It says new rules will require a huge expansion in the use of electric and hybrid cars.

But according to the SMMT's chief executive, Mike Hawes, the fallout from Brexit remains the biggest &quot;clear and present danger&quot; to the sector in the UK.

The SMMT's figures show a total of 2.31 million new cars were registered in 2019, down 2.4% from the year before.

Since reaching a record high of 2.69 million vehicles in 2016, the market has been steadily contracting, in response to what Mr Hawes describes as a &quot;perfect storm&quot; for the industry.

A key factor has been the collapse in demand for diesel-powered cars, which fell by 22% compared with 2018.

Where once they accounted for half of all new cars sold, now they make up just a quarter of the market.

The SMMT says uncertainty over future air quality rules, and in particular over potential restrictions on diesel vehicles entering city centres, has left consumers confused.

That, combined with political uncertainty and a general fall in consumer confidence, has meant many potential buyers have decided to hang on to their old cars rather than investing in new ones.
• Five reasons the car industry is struggling

&quot;You can never put it down to one single factor. It has been a perfect storm over the past few years&quot;, says Mr Hawes.

&quot;It's really no surprise the market has been declining. That's why we need a return of confidence and strong economic conditions&quot;.

The situation is not expected to improve this year, however, with the SMMT forecasting a further 1.6 % fall in registrations in 2020.

One area in which sales have increased dramatically over the past year is the market for &quot;alternatively fuelled vehicles&quot;, in other words electric cars and hybrids. They rose by more than a fifth. Registrations of pure-electric cars were up 144%, albeit from a very low level.

The problem for the industry is that this increase is not happening nearly fast enough. New EU rules which are being phased in this year, and which enter fully into force in 2021, oblige manufacturers to cut the average CO2 emissions of their new car fleets dramatically - or face swingeing fines.

These targets are expected to remain in force, even after the UK has left the EU. But they imply a cut of more than a third in overall CO2 output, and the industry believes that meeting them will be extremely challenging.

In fact, the SMMT calculates that without other changes, the market share of electric vehicles would have to rise from the current 1.6% to 27% - or the combined share of electric vehicles and hybrids would have to increase from 7.4% to 56%.

In reality, manufacturers will not rely solely on selling more low- or zero-emission vehicles in order to meet the targets. They will also be able to withdraw their most-polluting models and sell more efficient petrol and diesel vehicles, for example.

But sales of electric and hybrid vehicles will still need to rise very substantially, and Mr Hawes insists government must play a role.

&quot;These are still expensive technologies. They carry a price premium,&quot; he says.

&quot;That's why incentives are so significant in determining the uptake.&quot;

But of all the clouds hanging over the industry, one remains darker than the rest in the eyes of the SMMT: the aftermath of Brexit.

Although the UK is due to leave the EU on 31 January, what happens after the transition period remains uncertain.

The government insists it will be able to conclude a trade deal with the EU by the end of the year.

But if that doesn't happen, there remains the possibility that the movement of cars and car parts across the channel could be subject to steep tariffs or disruptive border checks and delays.

&quot;That is probably the clear and present danger,&quot; says Mr Hawes

&quot;Yes, we will always sell cars in the UK and buy cars in the UK. Where they come from will be affected by Brexit. How much you pay will be affected by Brexit.&quot;

&quot;That is right before us now.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50985412</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Davos 2020: Can Formula 1 really go 'carbon neutral' by 2030? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12220/production/_110627247_8fbd9c4a-877e-4550-b085-fa8dbf542679.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It is no secret that Formula 1 racing is a polluting sport, or that its previous owner Bernie Ecclestone wasn't particularly interested in sustainability.

But things have changed since the elite motor-racing series was taken over by US media giant Liberty Media in 2017. Last year F1 announced its first ever sustainability plan, with an ambitious goal to make itself &quot;carbon neutral&quot; by 2030.

When I meet Yath Gangakumaran - the man responsible for leading the plan - at the World Economic Forum in Davos, he is keen to distance himself from sport's old guard, although he won't comment on Mr Ecclestone's tenure.

&quot;Up until 10-15 years ago sport wasn't run in a mature way - typically by ex-players not business professionals. It's become much more professional and is catching up with other industries, and that includes on sustainability.&quot;
• Lewis Hamilton on his mission to be 'carbon neutral'

Formula 1's carbon footprint is &quot;material&quot;, he says, but it has little to do with the cars, which are among the most fuel efficient on the planet thanks to their lightweight design and innovative hybrid engines.

The main problem are the races themselves - 22 in total this year - which require large amounts of equipment, cars and people to be shipped around the world, often by aircraft. In 2019, the sport's 10 teams each notched up an average of 110,000 air miles.

Then there is the huge amount of C02 emissions generated by F1's 500 million fans globally who will travel far and wide to see the sport.

It makes the 2030 target seem wildly ambitious, but as F1's director of strategy Mr Gangakumaran is bullish: &quot;There is no point just throwing out a target and having it as a marketing gimmick. Ultimately you will be held accountable, and so you should.&quot;

The former Sky Sports executive, who is only 31, seems sincere, but there are parts of Formula 1's plan that raise questions.

First to note is that the plan will only target emissions generated by the activities of the F1 business - which manages the series - and the individual teams who compete.

That amounts to some 256,000 CO2 equivalent tonnes per year, according to Liberty Media, which calculated F1's carbon footprint for the first time ever last year.

But the plan won't cover emissions generated by fans - the much bigger part of the problem. When they are accounted for, F1's footprint rises to some 1.9 million CO2 equivalent tonnes.

&quot;We think it is just too difficult to control what our fans do because they are ultimately their own custodians. So we think it is most appropriate and achievable to focus on what we do have control over,&quot; says Mr Gangakumaran.

That said, Liberty will encourage fans to use public transport to get to Formula 1 events, or to offset their air travel if they fly. It has also pledged to make races sustainable by 2025, including banning single-use plastics.

The sport will also continue to fly its operation around the world, and while Mr Gangakumaran says its absolute carbon footprint will decrease, it will have to rely on some carbon offsetting.

This may anger the fiercest environmental campaigners, who view offsetting - for instance, by planting trees to compensate for your emissions - as a cop out.

But Mr Gangakumaran says the business will keep it to a minimum and has to be realistic. &quot;We are a global sport and we have fans around the world who want to see F1. That requires travel.&quot;

The business also plans to spend more on transferring its own sustainable technologies to the wider world - something it has a strong record of.

In its 70-year history, Formula 1 has pioneered ground-breaking aerodynamics and efficient brake systems that have found their way into everyday road cars.

Other industries have benefited too. Take the way an F1-inspired aerofoil attached to chiller cabinets has cut refrigeration costs by about 15% in some supermarkets.

The strip, the result of a collaboration between Williams Advanced Engineering and Aerofoil Energy, was rolled out by Sainsbury's across its 1,400 supermarkets and convenience stores in 2017.

Professor Mark Jenkins, an F1 expert at Cranfield University, says Liberty Media's 2030 goal is highly ambitious and should be lauded. &quot;But whether it is achievable is another question.&quot;

He notes that Formula 1 has increased its number of races from 21 to 22 this year, while Mr Gangakumaran concedes there are plans for several more.

Prof Jenkins says: &quot;One of the obvious ways to reduce the carbon footprint would be reduce the number of races. But F1 also needs to increase its sales so there is a tension there.&quot;

In addition, the sport will introduce a cost cap in 2022 as it looks to even out competition between teams. The three that dominate - Mercedes, Red Bull and Ferrari - will be hit the hardest.

&quot;It will limit what they can spend at a time when they are also being asked to become more sustainable. Is that really wise?&quot; says Prof Jenkins.

Liberty Media's contracts with its F1 teams are up for renewal at the end of this year.

But Mr Gangakumaran says the firm is in advanced discussions and he is quietly confident the teams will re-sign.

He adds that Liberty has factored in the growing number of races into its carbon reduction plan, and that there will only one or two more. Becoming more sustainable could actually save F1 money, he adds.

All eyes will be on F1 as it works towards its goal. It also faces stiff competition in the sustainability stakes from events such as the World Cup, which could become carbon neutral by 2022.

&quot;You can't say anything is 100% but we wouldn't be putting these targets out there if they weren't ambitious enough or we didn't think we could achieve them,&quot; Mr Gangakumaran says. &quot;Most importantly our fans are totally behind us on this.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51226066</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Canada prosecutors propose £110m Volkswagen fine - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1118F/production/_110613007_vwlogo.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Canadian prosecutors want to fine Volkswagen millions of Canadian dollars over its emissions scandal.

Volkswagen was charged in December with importing nearly 128,000 vehicles into Canada that violated emissions standards.

The company then pleaded guilty to dozens of counts of diesel emissions violations.

Globally the scandal has already cost the company more than €30bn in fines, penalties and buyback costs.

The company said last month it had reached &quot;a proposed plea resolution&quot; in Canada without giving more details.

Volkswagen pleaded guilty after being charged with 60 counts of breaching the Canadian Environmental Protection Act and providing misleading information.

Volkswagen has been hit with a flurry of legal actions since 2015, when it admitted to US investigators that it had installed software on its cars to cheat pollution tests.

The company has since said that 11 million cars worldwide had the software, which could improve the performance of vehicles when they were being tested for emissions.

In May 2019, it set aside an additional €5.5bn in contingent liabilities amid ongoing lawsuits around the world.

Last week, Poland's consumer watchdog UOKiK said it was fining Volkswagen more than 120 million zlotys (£24m) for misleading customers about vehicle emissions.

In December the firm was hit with a A$125m (£66m) fine by Australia's consumer watchdog, the highest ordered by a court for breaches of Australian consumer law.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51215786</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Aston Martin warns on profits but Rolls-Royce sales surge - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12694/production/_110421457_ai87rasy.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Aston Martin, the luxury British carmaker famed for kitting out James Bond, has issued a profit warning after a &quot;very disappointing&quot; 2019.

Shares in the 106-year-old firm plunged by as much as 16% after it said annual earnings were expected to fall by nearly half from a year earlier.

But the fortunes of BMW-owned rival Rolls-Royce were very different.

Rolls-Royce, the car of choice for those who like to be chauffeured, sold a record 5,100 vehicles last year.

In a trading update, Aston Martin said the &quot;challenging trading conditions highlighted in November continued through the peak delivery period of December resulting in lower sales, higher selling costs and lower margins&quot;.

It said core retail sales - which covers sales from Aston Martin dealers to consumers - were up 12% from a year earlier. However, wholesale volumes - which covers how many cars the dealers are ordering from Aston Martin itself - were down 7% to 5,809.

&quot;From a trading perspective, 2019 has been a very disappointing year,&quot; said Aston Martin chief executive Andy Palmer.

The company said it was expecting earnings of between £130m and £140m, well below the £247.3m it reported last year.

When Aston Martin listed its shares on the London Stock Exchange in October 2018, its shares were priced at £19 each. However, the latest bad news has now dragged the share price down to about £4.50.

&quot;It is remarkable that a company with such a strong brand can consistently issue bad news,&quot; said Russ Mould, investment director at AJ Bell.

&quot;Aston Martin has been one of the biggest flops on the stock market in living memory and today's trading update does nothing to improve its tarnished reputation.

&quot;The big question is why wealthy people aren't buying its luxury cars. Working for this company should be a marketeer's dream, but the team responsible for attracting customers clearly haven't got the formula right.&quot;

Rolls-Royce boss Torsten Müller-Ötvös told the BBC that a big driver of its higher sales was the launch of the Cullinan SUV, which he said now had &quot;very stable, robust&quot; orders.

But he said sales were not expected to grow at the same rate in 2020.

Part of the difference between the successes of the two brands could come down to how they define themselves.

&quot;We are not really in the car business, we are in the luxury goods business,&quot; Mr Müller-Ötvös said.

&quot;We are famous for bespoke, so you can basically customise a Rolls-Royce to build your own masterpiece, and I think that has attracted quite a lot of clients worldwide.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51017849</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Aston Martin: F1 billionaire owner leads rescue deal - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12694/production/_110421457_ai87rasy.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A consortium led by billionaire Lawrence Stroll will put in £182m, with the rest of the money coming from existing investors.

Mr Stroll partly owns the Racing Point Formula 1 team, which will be branded Aston Martin from 2021 under the deal.

The move comes hours after a board meeting held to discuss how to prop up the ailing firm.

Aston Martin's best known customer is fictional spy James Bond and the company recently revealed that four of its cars will feature in the next Bond movie, No Time To Die.

The carmaker said its latest financial moves were aimed at strengthening its balance sheet after its &quot;disappointing performance&quot; in 2019.

Mr Stroll's consortium will take a 20% stake in the company and he will become its executive chairman.

As a result, Penny Hughes will be stepping down as Aston Martin's chairman once the deal is completed.

It's all very well to build James Bond's company cars, but Aston Martin can't rely on a flashy brand alone.

Many of its troubles can be traced to the decision to build a new factory at St Athan in South Wales, where it will produce its long-anticipated sports utility vehicle, the DBX.

An ambitious move, it could have big long-term benefits for the carmaker.

But in the short term, it has been struggling to generate enough cash to pay its bills, including the costs of setting up the factory.

Dealers have been reducing stock rather than ordering new cars, while average selling prices have been falling, weighing on profits.

Last year, the company was forced to borrow £120m at a steep interest rate in order to prop up its operations. It had been facing the prospect of borrowing even more.

The new funding from Lawrence Stroll will give Aston Martin some much-needed stability. It now has breathing space in which to get the DBX into production, and implement a cost-cutting programme.

Meanwhile the Canadian billionaire will be able to put an Aston Martin badge on his F1 cars - opening up new opportunities both to burnish the brand and to exploit its petrol-scented cachet.

She said: &quot;The difficult trading performance in 2019 resulted in severe pressure on liquidity which has left the company with no alternative but to seek substantial additional equity financing.

&quot;Without this, the balance sheet is not robust enough to support the operations of the group.

&quot;Notwithstanding recent weak trading, the strength of the Aston Martin brand and our expanding portfolio of cars has allowed us to attract a strong new partner in Mr Stroll to support the turnaround of the business.&quot;

Earlier this month, the 106-year-old firm issued a profit warning, saying annual earnings were expected to fall by nearly half from a year earlier.

It said core retail sales - which covers sales from Aston Martin dealers to consumers - were up 12% from a year earlier. However, wholesale volumes - which covers how many cars the dealers are ordering from Aston Martin itself - were down 7% to 5,809.

The company said it was expecting earnings of between £130m and £140m, well below the £247.3m it reported last year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51323241</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>VW hit with record fine in Australia over emissions scandal - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/8358/production/_110242633_gettyimages-493571650.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Volkswagen (VW) has been slapped with a record fine by Australia's consumer watchdog to settle lawsuits over the carmaker's global emissions scandal.

The A$125m ($86m; £66m) penalty is the highest ordered by a court for breaches of Australian consumer law.

VW has been hit with a flurry of legal action since 2015, when it emerged the firm had been cheating emissions tests.

Australian regulators have also launched proceedings over VW's consumer loans.

The Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC) has alleged in a federal court that VW failed to make proper checks into borrowers' living expenses, or to determine if the loans were unsuitable for them.

The allegations relate to 49,380 consumer loans made between 2013 and 2016.

The fine relating to the emissions scandal came from the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission (ACCC), which said that VW admitted it had failed to disclose the existence software aimed at cheating emissions tests on 57,000 vehicles imported into Australia between 2011 and 2015.

In 2015, the US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) found that many VW cars had software in diesel engines that could detect when they were being tested, and then change the performance to improve results.

VW admitted 11 million cars worldwide had software that reduced readings of emissions in tests.

Globally, VW has been forced to pay out more than $33bn in fines, recall costs and civil settlements globally.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50862356</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-05 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>Jaguar's 50-year old XJ model to be electric-powered - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/160FE/production/_107766309_p07g4pz6.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>What do drivers think of electric cars?

Electric cars are expensive, the batteries run out and then they have to be charged up, but why are they so popular in Milton Keynes?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48886743</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
