<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>COP26: Johnson 'refused to give Sturgeon climate summit role' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/162E8/production/_110765809_055581390.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Boris Johnson refused to give Nicola Sturgeon an official role in the Glasgow COP26 climate summit, according to the event's former co-ordinator.

Claire O'Neill said she had made the suggestion in a bid to end the &quot;stand-off&quot; between the UK and Scottish governments over the global conference.

She said Mr Johnson had &quot;heartily and saltily&quot; rejected the proposal.

Ms O'Neill also accused the Scottish government of behaving &quot;disgracefully&quot; ahead of the conference.
• Is Scotland leading the way on climate change?

The key UN-led summit is due to be held in November at the Scottish Events Campus, which includes the Armadillo and the SSE Hydro.

Ms O'Neill claimed the Scottish government had been contracting buildings from the site which should instead be used by the climate change conference.

The Scottish government later confirmed it had booked the Glasgow Science Centre, which sits opposite the events campus, for the duration of the summit - but said that this had been done after the COP26 organisers had booked what they needed.

A spokesman said it was not surprising or unreasonable for the government to have a base of its own when the event is happening in Scotland, and pointed out that Ms Sturgeon, the Scottish first minister, had been invited to and attended the previous three COP summits.

Ms O'Neill is a former Conservative minister for energy and clean growth who stood down as an MP ahead of the last general election.

She had been co-ordinating plans for the COP26 summit, but was stripped of her role as president last week - and will be replaced by a serving government minister.

Speaking to the BBC's Today programme, she claimed that the prime minister had admitted to her that he &quot;doesn't really get&quot; climate change.

And she said there was &quot;huge lack of leadership and engagement&quot; on the issue from the UK government, adding: &quot;The prime minister has made incredibly warm statements about this over the years.

&quot;He's also admitted to me that he doesn't really understand it. He 'doesn't really get it', I think is what he said.&quot;

Ms O'Neill said it was the prime minister himself who chose Glasgow as the location for the summit, but she had been told by people involved that the original analysis for the cost of the event was &quot;hundreds of millions of pounds off track&quot;.
• Climate summit policing will cost more than £200m

She also said she had been told that &quot;the Scottish government has absolutely behaved disgracefully and has been contracting buildings from the COP site, for example, that should absolutely be made available to the conference&quot;.

She went on to allege that there was a &quot;complete stand-off between the two governments, and that her suggestion had been that we &quot;need everybody in&quot; and that the &quot;playground politics, the yah-boo of this, has got to stop&quot;.

And she said Scotland had a &quot;great track record&quot; on the environment, adding: &quot;I did suggest that we give Nicola Sturgeon a job and she was involved in this, which the PM heartily and saltily rebutted.&quot;

Mr Johnson was reported to have told a fringe event at the Scottish Conservative conference in September that he did not want to see Ms Sturgeon &quot;anywhere near&quot; the climate summit as it was the UK government that had brought it to Glasgow rather than the SNP.

Ms O'Neill was speaking ahead of the prime minister pledging that 2020 will be a &quot;defining year of climate action&quot; as he announced that a ban on selling new petrol, diesel or hybrid cars in the UK will be brought forward from 2040 to 2035 at the latest.

Mr Johnson unveiled the policy as part of a launch event for the climate summit alongside Sir David Attenborough, but did not answer questions from the BBC's David Shukman about the row.

In a letter to the prime minister, which has been published by the FT newspaper, Ms O'Neill said she had been told he was considering moving the summit from Glasgow to an English venue - an allegation which Downing Street has dismissed.

The Scottish government said there had been a &quot;significant increase in engagement&quot; in recent weeks from the UK government, which has insisted that Mr Johnson is fully committed to tackling climate change.

And Ms Sturgeon tweeted: &quot;It's not about Boris Johnson or me - it is about tackling the climate crisis. My commitment is that political differences will not stop me and my government working to make it a success.&quot;

Ms Sturgeon has also requested that the Scottish government's environment secretary, Roseanna Cunningham, be allowed to attend UK Cabinet and sub-committee meetings on climate Change and COP26, which the prime minister has said he will chair.

The UN summit, known as the 26th Conference of the Parties, will be held in Glasgow in November and see participating countries assess progress on tackling climate change.

It will be attended by countries that have ratified the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC), a treaty which came into force in 1994.

About 200 world leaders will seek to agree a new, long term deal on rising temperatures.

The COP meeting in Madrid last year saw a compromise deal struck on curbing carbon pledges but left a raft of complex issues unresolved.
• How much warmer is your city?
• What is your diet's carbon footprint?
• Where we are in seven charts

What questions do you have about a ban on the sale of petrol, diesel or hybrid cars and the COP26 conference in Glasgow?

In some cases your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy.

Use this form to ask your question:</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51369932</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Falling numbers take part in P1 assessments - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11D84/production/_103529037_gettyimages-109723570.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The number of primary one pupils who sat controversial standardised assessments has fallen, according to official figures.

Last year 91% of primary one children took part in the literacy and numeracy tests, which are designed to seem like a computer game and not a test.

This compares to about 95% in the 2017-18 school year, when the tests were introduced.

It is not clear from the government statistics why the drop happened.

In both numeracy and literacy assessments, the total number of pupils taking part fell by about 5,000 on the previous year.

Why might the drop have happened?

Campaigners urged parents to ask schools to withdraw their children from the scheme. But supporters will note that the overwhelming majority of children took part, suggesting the campaign to urge parents to boycott the scheme had little impact.

Some schools may have accepted requests from parents to withdraw their children from the scheme.

However, there may also have been more incidences where teachers felt, purely from their own professional judgement, that individual children should not have taken part.

There were claims that some children had been left distressed by the assessments - however, the Scottish government made clear this should never happen.

Why are the assessments controversial?

They were brought in in a bid to gather more data about children's progress, with literacy and numeracy tests at P1, P4, P7 and S3 level.

The pupils use a computer to complete the tests, which appear like a game that asks them a series of multiple choice questions.

If they get the answers right, the questions get progressively harder.
• What are P1 assessments really like?

The Scottish government insists these are not high-stakes tests, and provide teachers with useful information to make early interventions where pupils might be struggling.

However, they faced opposition from groups including the EIS teaching union, political parties, and parents groups like Upstart Scotland.

Some oppose any form of testing in P1 in principle, some argue against how the scheme has been put into practice, and others argue that the assessments are a waste of time for teachers and do not give them any information they did not already have.

And in Holyrood, all the opposition parties voted in 2018 to see the current P1 assessments &quot;halted&quot;.

MSPs were all critical of the assessments, albeit for different reasons, with the Greens and Lib Dems hitting out at the principle of standardised testing in general.

A Labour MSP said the data was not useful and some children found the tests upsetting.

Despite this political opposition, the assessments continued but with &quot;important modifications&quot; after they were independently reviewed.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-51372911</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Scotland's care system 'failing' too many children - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10A3C/production/_110765186_p04c44t9.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Scotland's care system is failing to give too many children the foundation they need for later life, a three-year review has found.

The Independent Care Review said many young people experienced a &quot;fractured, bureaucratic and unfeeling&quot; system.

There are about 15,000 children in Scotland's care system.

Fiona Duncan, the chairwoman of the review, said the human cost of their distressing and disturbing experiences often had a lifelong effect.

She said the review had calculated that an &quot;eye-watering&quot; £875m a year was spent picking up the pieces of earlier failures in the care system.

This is money spent on mental health, homelessness and addiction services, which a far higher proportion of care leavers require as adults.

The independent root-and-branch review, which was instigated by First Minister Nicola Sturgeon at the SNP conference in 2016, spoke to 5,500 people - more than half of whom had been in care themselves.

Ms Duncan questioned whether the care system was actually a &quot;system&quot; at all and said it could often prolong the pain it was trying to protect.

She added that people who were trying to do their best for young people were being &quot;thwarted&quot; by a system that operated when families and children were in crisis.
• Brothers and sisters have been regularly separated and have no say about their future contact
• Girls who have been sexually abused have been held in secure care
• Some Children's Hearing panels struggle to understand and empathise with the young people before them
• Care has become &quot;monetised&quot; with competition rather than collaboration
• Children who have gone through secure care feel that restraint was used as punishment
• Some children &quot;actively sought restraint as it was the only time they felt human touch&quot;
• Some children feel staff were cold and stigmatising
• There is an overworked and stressed workforce

Ms Duncan said the scale of the &quot;listening&quot; that had been done for the review demonstrated the &quot;human cost is lifelong&quot;.

&quot;Overcoming trauma requires a foundation of stable, nurturing, loving relationships&quot;, she said.

&quot;However, the current 'care system' is failing to provide that foundation for far too many children.&quot;

'I was at risk of being harmed again'

Julian remembers being taken away from his parents in the middle of the night when he was five. He says it was dark, he was scared and he was not allowed to say goodbye. No-one explained where he was going or why, he says.

Even after he was taken into foster care full-time, he was not kept safe from harm, Julian says.

&quot;I was put back into a situation where I was at risk of being harmed again,&quot; he says. &quot;I was put into care because of neglect and the State should have been there to protect me. In many ways it failed to do that.&quot;

At the age of seven, he was adopted but he feels that neither he nor his adoptive parents were given the support they needed. He struggled at school and started self-harming.

&quot;I was so angry and frustrated and confused and I did not know how to cope,&quot; Julian says.

At 16, he left home, moved into a homeless hostel and became addicted to alcohol. He describes the care system as a &quot;cattle market&quot; for homelessness.

Julian, who is now 27, says he woke up one day and realised he needed to change.

He asked for help after years of refusing it and his early twenties went teetotal.

After studying for Highers, and an HNC, this September he is due to start a university degree studying law.

His motivation? He says his life has been dominated by legal processes over which he had no control. He believes that working within those legal processes he could help bring about change.

Among her findings, Ms Duncan questioned whether the Children's Hearings System - where decisions are made that affect people for the rest of their lives - was fit for purpose and if it should rely on volunteers.

Children's Panels across Scotland are staffed by about 2,500 trained volunteers.

The review also called for an end to the inappropriate use of secure care and a complete overhaul of the care inspectorate.

To avoid its recommendations being left on the shelf, the group has already set up an implementation group.
• Everyone involved in The Children's Hearing System must be properly trained in the impact of trauma, childhood development, neuro-diversity and children's rights.
• There should be changes to how panels work and who sits on them
• No longer sending 16 and 17-year-olds to prison or detention
• An end to acute and crisis services
• Support for families rather than stigmatisation

Ms Duncan said families were not getting the support they needed in order to keep their children at home with them.

She said if children did need to be removed from families then it was &quot;essential&quot; siblings were kept together for as long as it was safe to do so.

She said the whole workforce, paid and unpaid, must be supported to &quot;love, nurture and cherish children&quot;.

For the first time the review also put a price on the annual cost of the looking after children in the care system, which is £932m.

&quot;What we have sought to do is understand where all of the pockets of money are all across Scotland that are spent on children and young people in this thing that we call the care system,&quot; Ms Duncan said.

&quot;It is an estimate because it was almost impossible to get access to all the information we needed. It is pretty accurate but it is a low estimate.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-51314908</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Scottish independence: How Brexit has changed the debate over EU membership - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/77FB/production/_110751703_parliament_afp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Brexit has transformed the debate over independent Scottish membership of the EU.

In the 2014 referendum campaign, the EU's top official actively discouraged the Yes movement.

The then president of the European Commission, Jose Manuel Barroso, said securing membership would be &quot;extremely difficult, if not impossible&quot; for Scotland.

Several EU foreign ministers also made clear an independent Scotland would need to apply to get back in, contradicting the Scottish government's plan to seek continued membership.

That was when the UK was a full member of the EU. It enjoyed the solidarity of the other 27 countries.

With Brexit, that can no longer be relied upon.

That's not to say serving EU leaders want to promote Scottish independence.

Some countries, like Spain, will avoid doing anything that might encourage the independence movements within their own borders.

Most will want to avoid being drawn into what they consider as the domestic politics of the UK.

Latvia's long-serving foreign minister, Edgars Rinkevics, told BBC Scotland his country deals with membership applications on a &quot;case-by-case&quot; basis.

However, he made clear an application from within the UK, under Article 49 of the Treaty of the European Union, would be welcome.

&quot;Whenever somebody in the UK decides to apply Article 49, we would be the staunchest supporters of (the) Article 49 process,&quot; he said.

Asked if he meant an application from part of the UK as well as an application from the UK as a whole, he said &quot;I will leave it for you to decide.&quot;

His diplomatic caution is not untypical.

Asked last week if there was a way back for Scotland, the EU's chief Brexit negotiator, Michel Barnier, said simply: &quot;We will see.&quot;

It is easier for those who have left high office to be more candid.

The former EU council president, Donald Tusk, said at the weekend there would be &quot;empathy&quot; for a Scottish membership application.

His predecessor, Herman Van Rompuy, has also acknowledged that Brexit has changed EU attitudes to Scottish independence.

One EU official told BBC Scotland last year that change amounted to a &quot;paradigm shift&quot;.

That is not to say the path to EU membership would be without complication.

The EU requires new members to sign up to joining the euro, although Sweden offers a masterclass in how to avoid actually adopting the currency.

The EU also requires its members to reduce any budget deficits to 3% of GDP or lower.

If an independent Scotland's deficit was anything like the 7% figure the Gers report ascribes to the devolved nation, it would need to agree measures to bring that down.

An assessment by the European Policy Centre concluded that while an independent Scotland could not expect &quot;special treatment&quot; from the EU, the bloc should &quot;engage positively&quot; with it.

One key issue would be the manner in which Scotland secured independence. The EU would frown upon a referendum like the one held in Catalonia despite Spanish opposition.

That is one reason the first minister, Nicola Sturgeon, wants any indyref2 agreed with the UK government and underpinned by powers transferred from Westminster.

One senior MEP told me privately that SNP politicians could help their cause further by distancing themselves from Catalan nationalists.

In those circumstances, the MEP suggested, Spain would find it easier to support an independent Scotland's membership of the EU.

All 27 member states must approve any application.

There is another important change Brexit brings to this debate: the border question.

If an independent Scotland joined the EU it would be inside the European single market and customs union, while the rest of the UK was outside.

This would logically require a system of checks on goods crossing the border between Scotland and England, which both the UK and Scottish governments say they do not want.

Perhaps these checks could be minimised as Boris Johnson has promised they will be across the Irish Sea, which has effectively become a trade border as a result of Brexit.

But the evidence from the Irish example is that the EU is likely to insist on some checks on goods coming into the European single market from the UK.

While the EU offers Scotland barrier-free access to a much larger potential market, the vast majority of Scotland's current trade is with the rest of the UK.

In the 2014 referendum there was an argument about whether or not an independent Scotland could become an EU member state.

In any future campaign, the argument is more likely to focus on the terms of membership and whether or not swapping the UK union for the European version is a good idea.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51357050</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Number of deaths rises among homeless people in Scotland - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/ED79/production/_109039706_gettyimages-949215976.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The number of homeless people who died in Scotland rose by 19% in 2018, according to a new report.

The figures published by National Records of Scotland (NRS) estimated that there had been 195 deaths during the year - up from 164 in 2017.

It said the death rate in Scotland was more than double that of England or Wales.

Housing Minister Kevin Stewart said the Scottish government was working to &quot;transform&quot; services for the homeless.

The 2018 figures cover a period of exceptionally harsh winter weather, which came to be known as the Beast from the East.

The NRS said its report provided experimental statistics which were still in their testing phase.

The figures include people who were in temporary accommodation at the time of their death, as well as those who were sleeping rough.
• Scotland had the highest rate of homeless deaths of all GB countries in 2018, with a rate of 35.9 per million population compared to 16.8 in England and 14.5 in Wales
• More than half (53%) of homeless deaths in 2018 were drug-related
• About three quarters of homeless deaths were male - 74% of the total in 2017 and 79% in 2018
• The mean age at death was 43 for females and 44 for males.

The report indicates that the cities of Glasgow, Edinburgh, Aberdeen and Dundee had above-average death rates in 2018.

Glasgow and Aberdeen recorded the highest rates - 100.5 and 67.8 deaths per million population.

Shetland recorded 111.8 deaths per million population, but the NRS warned that this figure should be treated &quot;with caution&quot; because of the very small number of deaths.

No homeless deaths were identified in four council areas - Angus, East Renfrewshire, Moray and the Scottish Borders.

The housing charity Shelter Scotland described the figures as &quot;individual personal tragedies&quot;.

Director Graeme Brown said they were &quot;people living in desperate situations ultimately failed by the system&quot;.

&quot;It is vital that the effort to end this loss of life does not end with the publication of the figures,&quot; he added.

&quot;The housing, health, social care and justice sectors need to work more closely together to ensure people get the tailored support they need for health issues such as mental illness and addictions.

&quot;We also need to see housing that supports people to recover and stay well.&quot;

Mr Stewart said the reasons for individuals becoming homeless were &quot;complex&quot;, but could include addiction, poor mental health, and family breakdown.

He said: &quot;This report shows that of the number of people who died while experiencing homelessness, 53% were drug-related deaths.

&quot;This reflects the wider public health emergency Scotland is facing over drug deaths.&quot;

He added: &quot;One person being made homeless is one too many and that is why the Scottish government are working in partnership to transform services to ensure our system supports those at risk.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-51384196</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>MSPs reject bid to change business rates system - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/AE03/production/_110774544_gettyimages-862506084.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>MSPs have overwhelmingly rejected a bid to give councils the power to set business rates.

Business leaders feared that ending the current uniform business rates system would lead to higher charges and the abolition of relief schemes for smaller firms.

Green MSP Andy Wightman had pushed for the responsibility to be devolved to Scotland's 32 local authorities.

But MSPs voted by 103 to 10 against the move.

The Tories, who had backed the proposal to change the Non Domestic Rates (Scotland) Bill at committee stage, reversed their stance, with Labour and the SNP also opposed.
• Why did business rates become a battleground?

Tracy Black, CBI Scotland director, said: &quot;Scottish firms will be relieved to see common sense prevail with the uniform business rate being protected, avoiding further complications to the business rates system.

&quot;As the economy continues to stutter, businesses have long called on politicians to support a simplified rates system that encourages greater investment.&quot;

Andrew McRae, Scottish policy chairman for the Federation of Small Businesses, said: &quot;MSPs had a big call to make today. If they didn't amend this legislation, we'd have seen bills going up and national reliefs axed.

&quot;This was not the time to hit small businesses with new annual rates bills in excess of £7,000.

&quot;Our MSPs are to be congratulated for recognising this threat and acting decisively to address it.&quot;

David Lonsdale, director of the Scottish Retail Consortium, said: &quot;Retailers, and the business community as a whole, will breathe a huge sigh of relief that MSPs have listened and voted to retain the consistency, simplicity and predictability that the uniform business rate brings, and that the reckless plan to abolish it has been defeated.&quot;

Mr Wightman argued that &quot;Scottish businesses had managed fine for over a century and more during which councils set the rates&quot;.

When councils had been responsible for setting business rates, he said there had been &quot;plenty of opportunities&quot; for firms to lobby local authorities on the issue.

But he claimed business rates were now determined in &quot;private meetings between business elites and the cabinet secretary&quot;.

The Green MSP said: &quot;Non domestic rates is a local tax, it belongs to local government and it belongs to councils.

&quot;Just as the Scottish Parliament sets Scottish tax rates, so too should local authorities set their local tax rates.&quot;

Public Finance Minister Kate Forbes stressed that Mr Wightman's amendments were &quot;opposed by the majority of Scottish businesses&quot; and the local government body Cosla.

Tory finance spokesman Murdo Fraser said ending the uniform business rate &quot;at this stage was not appropriate and would add risks and complications to doing business in Scotland&quot;.

He added while the Conservatives were &quot;still sympathetic to exploring the principle of localisation we do not believe this is the right time or this bill is the right vehicle for that policy&quot;.

Fellow Tory MSP Graham Simpson said when his party had backed the move previously it was &quot;about allowing a debate to continue&quot;.

Mr Simpson said: &quot;What Andy Wightman has achieved is to have that full and proper debate.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51379019</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Former Daily Record editor becomes SNP spin doctor - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1281/production/_110773740_murrayfoote.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The SNP has appointed a former editor of the Daily Record as its new head of communications at Holyrood.

Murray Foote was editor of the newspaper when it published its famous The Vow front page ahead of the Scottish independence referendum.

He revealed he was a supporter of independence after leaving the newspaper in 2018.

Mr Foote, who replaces Fergus Mutch, will begin his new job with the SNP next week.

Mr Mutch left the role after failing to be elected for the party in the West Aberdeenshire constituency during December's general election.

The Vow saw the leaders of the three main parties at Westminster - David Cameron, Ed Miliband and Nick Clegg - sign a pledge to devolve more powers to Scotland if the country rejected independence.

It was published on the front page of the Daily Record just two days before the referendum in response to an opinion poll which suggested that Yes was on course to win.

Former first minister Alex Salmond has argued that The Vow played a crucial role in the outcome of the referendum - although some polling experts have questioned how big a part it played.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51375788</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>MSPs oppose handing rates power to councils - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://m.files.bbci.co.uk/modules/bbc-morph-news-waf-page-meta/4.1.2/bbc_news_logo.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>That's all from BBC Holyrood Live on Tuesday 4 February 2020.

MSPs have voted against devolving power over non-domestic rates to local authorities.

The Greens were seeking to change the law so the tax could be set by councils.

But Labour and the Conservatives backed the Scottish government to maintain the uniform business rate, after the council body Cosla, business organisations and the shopworkers union expressed concern.

MSPs also voted to remove business rates relief from private schools, though Tory MSPs argued against the move.

The final vote on the bill takes place tomorrow evening.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51356870</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>NHS Tayside mental health staff endure 'fear and blame' culture - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Tayside and Central Scotland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16751/production/_110758919_carseview.01.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Tayside mental health staff have been left &quot;demoralised&quot; by a &quot;culture of fear and blame&quot;, a report has found.

The independent inquiry into mental health services in the region took evidence from more than 1,500 people.

It said there was a danger that NHS Tayside could be perceived to be &quot;more interested in protecting its reputation than looking after the interests of its patients&quot;.

NHS Tayside said it welcomed the report which it &quot;knew would be challenging&quot;.

The report, which made more than 50 recommendations, said: &quot;A breakdown in trust and a loss of respect has undoubtedly led to poor service, treatment, patient care and outcomes.

&quot;The breakdown in trust and respect is caused by the lack of effective, engaged strategic leadership and planning.&quot;

It added that a &quot;radical&quot; approach to restoring trust was urgently needed.

The investigation was initially ordered into Dundee's Carseview Centre but was expanded following a campaign by families of people who took their own lives.

An interim report last year highlighted concerns over illegal drugs in wards and patient restraints, saying some patients were frightened of staff members.

The final 136-page report said it was clear there had been a breakdown of trust in &quot;many aspects&quot; of the provision of mental health services in Tayside.

The report said: &quot;Frontline staff feel that the organisation is more interested in identifying who is to blame and attributing fault than genuinely learning in a supportive environment.&quot;

It said the &quot;most striking failure of governance&quot; was the lack of a mental health strategy for Tayside.

Services were said to be currently operating to a &quot;short-term vision&quot;, with an emphasis on &quot;reacting to increases in service demand&quot;.

The report, entitled &quot;Trust and Respect&quot;, makes 51 recommendations, including conducting an &quot;urgent whole-system review&quot; of mental health and wellbeing provision across Tayside.

The report's author David Strang said rebuilding trust in Tayside's mental health services was a &quot;big challenge but absolutely achievable&quot;.

He said: &quot;Many patients have felt that they've not been listened to and cared for properly.

&quot;They've felt judged and they've felt isolated, and many of them are already feeling broken and vulnerable.

&quot;The culture in Tayside needs to change so that lessons are learned from things that have gone wrong in the past and long-term plans are put in place to improve services.&quot;

Mr Strang said many staff had also told the inquiry team that they felt &quot;undervalued and that their voice isn't heard&quot;.

He added: &quot;It's really important that people are put at the centre of healthcare and that they're listened to and valued.&quot;

Last week the Scottish government announced extra support for NHS Tayside to help the struggling health board make &quot;significant improvements&quot; in mental health care.

NHS Tayside chief executive Grant Archibald said the report's findings posed &quot;major challenges for the organisation&quot; but that the board was &quot;fit to rise to meet those&quot;.

He apologised to anyone who had been &quot;let down by experience of our service.&quot;

Mr Archibald said: &quot;Our commitment is always to put the patient at the heart of our service, to give them the care they should expect, to make them feel cared for and professionally managed.&quot;

Mental Health Minister Clare Haughey said: &quot;It is absolutely vital that people using mental health services, as well as those delivering these services, feel safe and know they will receive the right help, in the right place when they need it.&quot;

She said she had received assurances immediate action would take place as a result of the report and there would be a progress update in February 2021 to ensure required improvements had been made.

She added that the Scottish government had provided further support to NHS Tayside, addressing service provision, clinical practice, organisational development and community-led services, and would monitor its progress.

Cosla's health and social care spokesman, councillor Stuart Currie, said: &quot;Cosla will work alongside Scottish government, NHS boards, local authorities and integration joint boards to allow for learning from the Strang report to be implemented across Scotland.&quot;

He said there would be a continued focus on working together, and collaborating with those who used the services and their families.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-tayside-central-51356037</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>SNP MPs accused of 'stunt' over English-only NHS vote - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/18157/production/_110774689_capture.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>SNP MPs have been been accused of a parliamentary &quot;stunt&quot; after they were blocked from voting on an &quot;English-only&quot; bill about the NHS.

Convention in the Commons has meant MPs from Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland have not had a say on bills deemed to apply only in England.

However, the SNP's Westminster leader Ian Blackford said the bill would have spending implications for Scotland.

Conservative Michael Gove said the move was a stunt to &quot;manufacture grievance&quot;.

The draft bill falls under the English votes for English laws (Evel) convention.

It was created in response to devolution where bodies such as the Scottish Parliament control areas including health and education for those living in Scotland.

During Tuesday's vote in the House of Commons, SNP MPs voted against UK government plans for the NHS in England by walking through the voting lobbies with the opposition.

But Commons deputy speaker Dame Eleanor Lang ruled members did not have a right to vote if their constituencies were not in England.

She added: &quot;Members who do not represent constituencies geographically situated in England do not have a right to vote in these particular divisions.&quot;

SNP MP Pete Wishart tweeted a picture of the group holding See no Evel, Hear no Evel and Speak no Evel signs.

Mr Wishart - who chairs the Scottish affairs select committee - said: &quot;Today we are witnesses a huge ramping up of English Votes for English Laws (Evel).

&quot;Their NHS funding bill will have impacts on Barnett Consequentials in Scotland, affecting health spending here, yet we can not move any amendment or vote on any tabled. An absolute disgrace.&quot;

Following the vote, Conservative Cabinet minister Michael Gove said: &quot;Until the Scottish government makes sure that the health of the people of Scotland is looked after, the people of Scotland will regard this as a transparent stunt by people who instead of representing their constituents seek to manufacture grievance.&quot;

What is the Barnett formula?

For 42 years, public spending across England, Northern Ireland, Scotland and Wales has been based around something called the Barnett formula.

In principle, the way this works is extremely simple.

When the UK government decides to spend more or less on things such as health and education in England, the Barnett formula is used to decide how much money the other nations receive.

For example, if health spending increases by £100 per person in England, the devolved governments should receive the equivalent amount.

This exact amount is based on the size of their population.

However, the devolved governments are free to spend any extra money on whatever they want. Funding doesn't have to go on health just because the money went on health in England.

As well as population, the size of the grant will also be affected by the level of responsibility the devolved governments have for different policy areas. For example, the Welsh Government does not have responsibility for police funding, so its grant is not affected by changes in this area.

The formula is named after its inventor, the former Labour Chief Secretary to the Treasury Joel Barnett. He devised it in 1978 when he was a member of the government of James Callaghan.

It has no legal status and is merely a convention used by the Treasury.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51378669</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-05 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Why are we building gas-powered ships? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-05</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1704E/production/_110568249_glennsannox.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former Ferguson shipyard owner Jim McColl has given evidence at Holyrood's ferry inquiry. He has suggested it would be cheaper to scrap two problem-hit &quot;green&quot; ferries and build three simpler ships instead. So why has the government insisted on sticking with the over-budget gas-powered ferries?

The two ferries being built in Port Glasgow have been making headlines for all the wrong reasons.

Glen Sannox and &quot;hull 802&quot; are the first UK-built ships capable of running off liquefied natural gas, or LNG, as well as conventional diesel.
• Look back on Jim McColl's evidence to Holyrood's ferry inquiry
• Call to 'scrap CalMac ferries and start again'

But they are three years late, £100m over budget and have dragged Scotland's last commercial Clyde shipyard into administration, prompting nationalisation. And some have questioned just how &quot;eco-friendly&quot; they really are.

Was LNG the wrong choice - or a wise decision, poorly executed?

If you have a gas boiler or cooker in your home, you'll already be familiar with natural gas - which mainly consists of methane.

If you cool this gas to minus 162C it turns into a liquid occupying only 1/600th of its original volume.

This Liquefied Natural Gas (LNG) is much easier to transport and can be used as a portable fuel for ships or even trucks and cars.

But it is still a fossil fuel that produces carbon dioxide when burned.

Ending our reliance on natural gas in our homes is seen as a key climate change goal - so why are we building gas-powered ships?

A 'bridge' fuel on the journey to zero emissions?

Advocates of LNG argue it's less harmful to the environment than traditional marine fuels such as oil or diesel.

LNG engine manufacturers say they produce up to 30% less carbon dioxide than diesel equivalents.

But that doesn't take into account greenhouse emissions during extraction and transport of the gas.

The UK currently has no facilities to liquefy natural gas so LNG would have to be imported - probably from the Gulf state of Qatar.

The LNG for CalMac's new ships first has to make an 8,000-mile journey by sea, arriving at the Isle of Grain terminal on the Kent coast.

It will then travel a further 460 miles by road tanker to Ardrossan in North Ayrshire or more than 600 miles to Uig on the Isle Skye.

Together, the two ships would require between four and six road tanker loads of LNG a week.

There are other problems - methane, the main component of natural gas, is itself a greenhouse gas, 28 times more potent than carbon dioxide.

A small amount of this methane can pass through an engine unburned - something known as methane slip - and enter the atmosphere.

CMAL, the government-owned agency which owns the ships used by CalMac, says the latest engines minimise methane slip.

It also hopes Scotland will eventually have its own bulk LNG storage capacity, which would improve the overall carbon footprint.

While the greenhouse emission benefits of LNG can be debated, when it comes to air quality there are clear benefits.

The smoke you see from a ship's funnel contains nitrogen and sulphur oxides - NOx and SOx as they're known - and other harmful particulates.

These can contribute to global warming indirectly, but the main concern is their link to respiratory diseases and cancers.

Using LNG dramatically cuts NOx emissions and almost eliminates SOx pollution.

New legally-binding regulations, known as IMO 2020 kicked in on 1 January, requiring marine diesel to contain less than 0.5% sulphur.

Shipping firms have three main choices: switch to expensive low sulphur fuel, fit &quot;scrubbers&quot; to remove the pollutants from exhaust gases - or use alternative fuels such as LNG.

Scottish ferries have been using low sulphur fuel for years so they're already IMO 2020 compliant, but LNG offers further air quality improvements.

Is it a technically-difficult fuel to use?

The bulk tankers that transport LNG across the seas have been using it as a fuel for decades.

Even with powerful refrigeration, a small amount of LNG turns back to gas while it is being transported.

Shipping firms learned they could save money by burning this boil-off gas (or Bog as it's known) to drive their ships' steam turbines.

Since 2003 the Finnish firm Wartsila has been selling dual-fuel marine engines that can run off LNG directly, switching seamlessly back to diesel when required with no impact on performance.

This is the system used on CalMac's new ferries.

But while the technology isn't particularly new, it does pose extra design challenges compared to an all-diesel vessel.

A large cryogenic storage tank - like a giant chilled thermos flask - is required on the ship along with special refrigerated refuelling pipes.

While the technology has been around for some time, CalMac's new ferries are the first to be built in the UK. Design decisions have to be approved by insurers and regulators.

Major investment is also needed in infrastructure to supply the LNG to these ships (or &quot;bunkering&quot; - a term that dates from the days of coal when a ship's fuel was literally stored in a bunker).

The Scottish government is currently seeking tenders for a £5m contract to build and maintain LNG bunkering facilities at Ardrossan and Uig.

What about 'future fuels' like hydrogen?

There are currently 300-400 LNG-powered ships in use or under construction worldwide, and that figure is rising rapidly.

But in the face of a &quot;climate change emergency&quot; some argue we should be looking at more radical zero-emission solutions such as hydrogen.

When hydrogen is used as a fuel - either burned in an engine or used in fuel cell to generate electricity - the only by-product is water.

Before the ferry fiasco dragged it into administration, Ferguson Marine had teamed up with the University of St Andrews and others to develop a prototype hydrogen-powered ship.

The plan was to build a small ferry for the five-mile route in Orkney between Kirkwall and Shapinsay.

The turmoil at Ferguson hasn't helped that project - it is still in development but unlikely to be completed for another two or three years.

Elsewhere, the Norwegian firm Norled is already building the world's first hydrogen ferry, due to be operating in the fjords in late 2021.

Hydrogen could work well for island communities like Orkney which have plenty of renewable energy sources.

The cleanest way of obtaining the gas is by splitting water molecules using electrolysis, a process which requires electricity.

Orkney is already using wind and tidal schemes to produce hydrogen locally - storing it in tanks and using it as a fuel for cars, or to generate electricity from fuel cells when it's needed.
• How hydrogen is transforming these tiny Scottish islands

For short routes, hydrogen could be carried on a ferry in compressed form rather than as a liquid.

But for longer journeys where more fuel is needed, there are technological challenges - storing hydrogen as a liquid requires temperatures of minus 260C.

A better solution may be to turn the hydrogen into ammonia, which is far easier to store in liquid form - a German firm is developing engines that could run on ammonia.

The world's first all-electric ferry, MV Ampere, began operating on a short route in Norway five years ago.

Last summer, the 197ft (60m) long all-electric &quot;Eferry&quot; Ellen went into service in southern Denmark, and can travel 25 miles (40km) between charges.

CalMac already operates the world's first seagoing diesel/electric hybrid ferries (three small ships, all built on-time and on-budget at Ferguson shipyard).

They run for 40% of the time on battery power, before having to switch to diesel generators. The batteries are recharged from the mains overnight.
• Plug in and sail: Meet the electric ferry pioneers

The main constraint is the weight of the batteries (more batteries, less cargo) and concerns over how long the batteries will last before they need replacing.

At the moment it is only an option for short routes, but as technology advances, battery-power looks set to become more common, either on all-electric ships or in hybrid systems.

Other &quot;future fuels&quot; such as hydrogen and ammonia are developing rapidly but it is early days for these technologies.

One ferry user group has suggested as an interim solution we should look at conventional diesels coupled with fuel-efficient hull designs like catamarans.

Pentland Ferries has recently taken delivery of such a vessel - MV Alfred, built in Vietnam at a cost of just £14m - but CMAL says that would conflict with its remit of having ships interchangeable between routes.

The world's shipping industry seems to view LNG as a sensible, well-tested option. A recent study predicted that by 2025 60% of shipbuilding orders would involve LNG.

So it looks like shipyards will be building a lot more gas-powered ships - whether that will satisfy climate change concerns is another matter.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-51114275</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
