<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>David Cameron turns down offer to host COP26 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F2BA/production/_110783126_p082bt1t.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former prime minister David Cameron has said a government minister should host the climate conference.

He said that someone outside of government at the conference would have the effect of having two people do the same job.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51389204</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>O'Neill: PM 'doesn't really get' climate change - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/105E6/production/_110764076_p0827dnp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former minister Claire O'Neill has told the BBC the prime minister &quot;doesn't really get&quot; climate change.

&quot;The prime minister has made incredibly warm statements about this over the years,&quot; she said, adding that Boris Johnson admitted to her that &quot;he doesn't really understand it&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51371250</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Election results 2019: Analysis in maps and charts - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12F72/production/_110128677_promo_results_mapv7__976.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>They have made gains in Labour heartlands across northern England and Wales. The SNP have made gains across Scotland.

Labour have had their worst return of seats in any general election since 1935.

Both Labour and the Liberal Democrats now have more female than male MPs.

The interactive map below shows all the seats that have changed from one party to another. Select the &quot;results&quot; tab to see what has happened in the rest of the UK.

If you can't see the map click here.

The Conservatives increased their vote share in many areas that voted Leave in the 2016 EU referendum.

By contrast they lost votes in strong Remain constituencies such as those in Scotland and London. But Labour lost votes in both strong Remain and strong Leave areas.

Strong Leave and strong Remain constituencies are those where an estimated 60% or more of the electorate voted for that option at the EU referendum.

These estimates of constituency Brexit votes were modelled by Professor Chris Hanretty, as the 2016 referendum result was only recorded by local authority and not by Westminster constituency.

The Conservatives were clear winners in constituencies estimated to have voted majority Leave in 2016. They won almost three quarters of all these seats.

By contrast, there was no clear winner among Remain backing constituencies, with a crowded field of parties all winning substantial numbers of seats.

Labour did best of all those parties but only took 40% of the constituencies that backed Remain.

Labour also straddled the Brexit divide taking a roughly equal number of Leave (106) and Remain (96) seats.

Most other parties had a clearer Brexit divide.

Overall, the Conservatives broke new ground, moving into many traditional Labour heartlands.

In 2017, Labour held 72 of the 100 constituencies with the most working class households (defined as C2DE using data from the 2011 census).

In 2019, this figure fell to 53 and the Conservatives increased their share from 13 to 31.

In every nation and region of Britain, the scale of Labour's losses outweighed any gains made by the Conservatives.

The Conservatives did lose votes in the south of England and Scotland, but these were balanced by gains in the rest of England and Wales.

The Lib Dems increased their share of the vote across the UK, but failed to translate these gains into more seats.

In Scotland, the SNP made 14 gains, and lost just one seat, while the Conservatives lost seven and Labour lost six seats.

In Wales, the Conservatives gained six seats and Labour lost six, mostly in the north east. Overall, Labour's share of the vote was down to 41% from 49% in 2017.

The Conservatives polled consistently well across England and most of Wales, reflecting their overall 44% share of the UK vote.

You can use the interactive map below to show the vote share for other parties as well as the turnout.

Labour's strength was concentrated in London and areas around cities in south Wales, the North East and North West. At 32%, Labour's share of the vote is down around eight points on the 2017 general election.

Overall, they lost 60 seats and gained only one, Putney in London.

A total of 220 female MPs have been elected. This is 12 more than the previous high of 208 in 2017.

For the first time, both the Liberal Democrats and Labour have more women MPs than men. Of Labour's 202 MPs (excluding Speaker Lindsay Hoyle), 104 are women and of the Liberal Democrats' 11 MPs, seven are women.

Turnout, on what was a cold and damp polling day, was 67.3%. slightly lower than the last election in June 2017.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50770798</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: Tories claim big scalps in Wales - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16DB8/production/_110142639_3comp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Wales' first three female Conservative MPs have been elected as the party claimed six key seats from Labour.

Sarah Atherton's 2,131 majority win in Wrexham was followed by Virginia Crosbie taking Ynys Mon and Fay Jones winning Brecon and Radnorshire.

The Tories also turned Bridgend, Vale of Clwyd, Clwyd South and Delyn from red to blue in other targeted seats.

Labour remained the biggest party while Plaid Cymru held their four seats, but the Liberal Democrats were wiped out.

Prime Minister Boris Johnson and First Minister Mark Drakeford spoke on Friday evening, a Downing Street spokeswoman said.

&quot;They talked about their shared commitment to the union and to growth and prosperity for Wales within a strengthened United Kingdom,&quot; she said.

&quot;The prime minister made clear how the UK is strongest when all four nations unite and all work together to unleash the potential of the entire country.&quot;

He also said &quot;we can get Brexit done&quot; - &quot;enabling us to move forward together&quot;, the spokeswoman added.

Labour now has 22 seats in Wales, with the six they lost taking the Tories' tally to 14 - the party's best result since 1983.

Turnout in Wales was 66.6%, down from the 2017 election by 2%.

Speaking after securing a majority, Prime Minister Boris Johnson said his party would now be able to &quot;get Brexit done&quot;.

&quot;With this election I think we put an end to all those miserable threats of a second referendum,&quot; he said.

&quot;You may only have lent us your vote and you may not think of yourself as a natural Tory... your hand may have quivered over the ballot paper and you may intend to return to Labour next time around and if that is the case, I am humbled that you have put your trust in me and you have put your trust in us, and I and we will never take your support for granted.&quot;

He added the party would deliver on each and every one of its campaign promises, and now spoke &quot;for everyone from Kensington to Clwyd South&quot;.
• Results of the 2019 general election in Wales
• What happens next with Brexit?
• What does a Conservative majority mean for Wales?

Where did the Tories make gains?

Speaking after her win, Sarah Atherton, who is filling the seat vacated by Labour's Ian Lucas, said she was &quot;delighted and privileged&quot; to be the first Welsh female Conservative MP.

&quot;The people of Wrexham wanted Brexit done and delivered. I think that's why we have got a majority of 2,000 tonight,&quot; she said.

The Tories also took Bridgend from Madeleine Moon, with Jamie Wallis winning by 1,157 votes.
• As it happened: Wales gains help Tory victory
• General Election 2019: The winners and the losers
• In pictures: Joy and heartbreak at Welsh counts

Ms Moon said: &quot;Bridgend now has an MP with no political experience, other than three years on a parish council. We're in a huge mess in Bridgend.&quot;

Political analyst Laura McAllister said &quot;getting Brexit done&quot; had been a successful campaign message from the Tories which had &quot;tapped into the mood of the Welsh public very well&quot;.

Former Welsh Secretary Alun Cairns, who resigned from the cabinet at the start of the campaign following a row about what he knew about a former aide's involvement in the collapse of a rape trial, held on to his seat in the Vale of Glamorgan.

If you cannot see the graphic click here.

Another former Welsh Secretary, David Jones, who was originally going to stand down in Clwyd West before changing his mind, also held on to his seat, while Monmouth, Preseli Pembrokeshire, Carmarthen West and Aberconwy remained blue, as did Montgomeryshire with new incumbent Craig Williams.

Tory David TC Davies, who held on to his Monmouth seat with 52% of the votes, said his party needed to move towards the centre in order to win the next general election.

&quot;There is going to be a huge expectation on us, I'm very well aware a lot of people voted Conservative for the first time in this election so I don't see this as a mandate for some sort of extreme government, I see this as a mandate for a government on the centre political ground.&quot;

He reiterated a promise to invest in public services and raise the minimum wage, adding: &quot;It is not true that we wanted to privatise or sell off the NHS, we will never undermine our national health service.&quot;

Former Tory MP Glyn Davies said he was &quot;absolutely astonished&quot; by the party's performance.

Paul Davies, the Conservative leader in the Welsh assembly, said: &quot;After winning seats like Delyn and Clwyd South we now have the joint largest number of Welsh Conservative MPs in Parliament, to help ensure that a positive voice for Wales is heard loud and clear in Parliament.

&quot;We now need to refocus ahead of the Welsh Parliamentary elections in 2021 and ensure that this failing Welsh Labour government, who have been running our health service for the last 20 years, are held to account and the people of Wales get the services they deserve.&quot;
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics

What went wrong for Labour?

Despite its losses, Labour held on to the marginal constituencies of Gower, Alyn &amp; Deeside and Cardiff North - all of which were at risk to the Tories - the latter seeing Anna McMorrin increase her majority to 6,982.

Ms McMorrin blamed Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn for the party's defeat nationally and said it needed to rebuild without him in charge.

&quot;He's shown tonight that he's lost good, decent, hardworking members of Parliament up and down the country, who are needed for this country to rebuild and to ensure that we're protected and represented and that we create a fairer society,&quot; she said.

&quot;That can't happen now, and I think the only person who can take responsibility is is our leader.&quot;

Mark Tami, whose majority was cut from more than 5,000 to just 213, is the last Labour MP left in north Wales - representing Alyn &amp; Deeside.

&quot;We've obviously suffered a very bad defeat and I've lost many colleagues, I've just about hung on,&quot; he said.

&quot;There are a number of issues - Brexit was an issue, the leadership of the party was an issue and we really have to look at ourselves and decide which way we go forwards.

&quot;I think our policy on Brexit was, well... if you stand in the middle of the road, you get run over.

&quot;There were some very positive things we were offering but it wasn't cutting through... this is really 'rethinking who we are' territory.&quot;

Labour also held on narrowly to Newport West while Llanelli, Neath, Rhondda, Ogmore, Pontypridd, Blaenau Gwent, Caerphilly, Cardiff Central, Cardiff West, Cynon Valley, Islwyn, Merthyr and Rhymney, Torfaen, Cardiff South and Penarth, and its two Newport and two Swansea seats remained red.

Plaid Cymru was forecast to take three seats, down one, but held on to all four - Carmarthen East, Ceredigion, Dwyfor Meirionnydd, and Arfon, where Hywel Williams increased his slender majority of 92 to 2,781.

The Liberal Democrats were left without a seat after Jane Dodds was ousted by the Conservative Ms Jones, who won the Brecon and Radnorshire seat back for her party just four months after it was lost in a by-election.

Ms Jones, who won by 7,131 votes, said she was &quot;honoured&quot;.

Ms Dodds wrote on Twitter: &quot;I'm not going to lie, last night was a really rough night - not just for me, but for the Liberal Democrats across the UK.&quot;

What are Plaid Cymru saying?

Plaid Cymru leader Adam Price defended his party's decision to form a remain pact with others who wanted to stay in the EU.

He also attacked Labour for the &quot;horrendous and indefensible error of trying to sit on the fence&quot; on Brexit.

&quot;They lost trust and integrity and that was reflected in the result that they had,&quot; he added.

How have other Labour MPs reacted?

Labour's Stephen Kinnock, who held on to his Aberavon seat, said it was a &quot;disastrous night&quot; for his party and he was &quot;shell-shocked and heartbroken&quot;.

He blamed Mr Corbyn's &quot;weak leadership&quot; and &quot;deeply damaging decision to back a second referendum&quot;.

He added: &quot;We've had nine long years of the Tories gutting our public services, causing a huge rise in homelessness, and triggering an explosion in child poverty and yet we have suffered a crushing defeat.&quot;

Following Labour's poor performance across the UK, Mr Corbyn said he intended to step down as leader.

Labour's Tonia Antoniazzi was cheered and heckled during her Gower acceptance speech when she said Brexit voters were &quot;taken advantage of&quot;.

She said the people of Gower had been &quot;disastrously served by a political shambles that has served to bring the UK into disrepute&quot;.

Chris Bryant, who held on to his Labour Rhondda seat, called it the &quot;worst night for Labour since 1935&quot;.

He said his party was now looking at &quot;being out in the wilderness for even longer&quot; unless there was &quot;some serious soul-searching&quot;.

Stephen Doughty, who has held the Cardiff South and Penarth seat for seven years, tweeted: &quot;I fear the future for our younger generation. I fear for the public institutions and integrity of our country. Dark times. Some of us must offer new hope amidst despair.&quot;

Mr Drakeford said that despite Labour's losses in Wales, the results did not change some fundamental issues.

&quot;People in north east Wales need jobs and will need a Welsh Labour Government to defend those jobs and help them with it,&quot; he said.

&quot;But we will be investing in things which provide housing for people, services for people - those things are important and we have to work harder to communicate those things to people.&quot;

But he said although it had been a disappointing night for the party, he did not believe it had alienated voters and Welsh Labour had held a &quot;whole swathe&quot; of valleys seats.

On the future, he said: &quot;Brexit is going to happen, I don't think there's any denying that - we will have to work hard to make sure that they [Westminster Government] understand the implications of that for Wales.

&quot;And where there are bad implications - which there will be - they take those into account and take the necessary actions to mitigate the adverse impacts that Brexit will bring to Wales.&quot;

The political map of Wales has changed enormously. Aside from the single seat of Alyn &amp; Deeside, Labour has been vanquished from north Wales.

The Conservatives are celebrating a return to their high watermark of 1983 when they held 14 seats in Wales, Boris Johnson's Brexit message resonated among Welsh Labour leave voters.

But many Welsh Labour sources say Jeremy Corbyn was a major factor in turning off the party's traditional supporters.

They will also question the approach of their Welsh leader Mark Drakeford.

Should he have done more to &quot;Welshify&quot; this election and distinguish Welsh Labour from the UK party? Was that even achievable given the dominance of the two characters of Mr Corbyn and Mr Johnson?

The Liberal Democrats will rue the day they pushed for this election - their hubris has been mercilessly punished.

And Plaid will breathe a big sigh of relief that they hung on to two ultra marginals, and were let off the hook by a split leave vote in Carmarthen East. Coming third in their target seat of Ynys Mon is a blow that leaves them at the status quo of four seats.

If you cannot see the graphic click here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50766203</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Beckbury residents vent pothole anger - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Shropshire</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/118C6/production/_110387817_p07zgr20.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Residents in a Shropshire village say potholes are so common they amount to &quot;tax&quot; on rural drivers.

Businessman Ian Field, who lives in Beckbury, says he has spent £6,000 on vehicle repairs in the last two years.

He has written to the government with a dossier of photographs showing a dozen large potholes.

He says they are strewn across all major routes into the village and many of them are deep, posing a danger to vehicles.

&quot;I’d go as far to say that this is akin to an additional tax for residents or a small business operating in a rural area – you simply wouldn’t have this in a major town,&quot; he said.

A Shropshire Council spokesman said the local authority was &quot;working hard to identify and tackle potholes and other defects&quot;.

He said the number of potholes typically increase by about a fifth at this time of year and the recent weather had &quot;amplified the problem&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-shropshire-50988823</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Blyth Valley: A constituency that changed its mind - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/CBE1/production/_110139125_f3k06p_.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Once, you would have got long odds on the first Conservative election win coming from Blyth Valley in Northumberland.

As a former mining community, it hardly seemed natural Tory territory. But mental health care assistant Ian Levy overcame a Labour majority of almost 8,000 to secure it.

In his victory speech, he pledged to bring investment and change to the community as soon as he arrived in Westminster.

So what do Mr Levy and Prime Minister Boris Johnson need to deliver to ensure that promise to the people of Blyth Valley means something?

Unemployment in Blyth Valley is above the national average. That is typical of many communities in the North East that are still wrestling with the impact of industrial decline.

It's a community proud of its mining heritage, but the days when coal was king are slipping into memory. The town council says that in 1961 Blyth was one of the busiest ports in England, shipping more than six million tonnes of coal. But &quot;the late 1960s had seen a rapid decline in the traditionally male-dominated heavy industries&quot;.

Instead its seafront now faces a cluster of offshore wind turbines, and it has ambitions to service a new generation of turbines in the North Sea. Its port also remains an important employer, and manufacturing a significant part of the economy.

And some new industries are moving in. Sir Paul McCartney's former wife Heather Mills is planning to build a vegan food factory there.

But like many communities of its size, Blyth has a struggling town centre – though it is in the running for money from the government's Future High Street Fund.

Perhaps the new MP and Mr Johnson will need to deliver more jobs - and better paid ones - to ensure local people have money to spend there. At the moment many of the constituents commute into Tyneside for work and leisure.

Economic studies suggest the exporting North East economy has most to lose from leaving the European Union in terms of lower economic growth.

The constituency did vote for Brexit though, with more than 6 in 10 backing leaving the EU in the 2016 referendum.

How the Blyth Valley vote divided up

Blyth lost its railway station in 1964 in the Beeching cuts. Trains still pass through the town, but they are only carrying freight at the moment.

Voters, then, might have been attracted by the Conservative election pledge to look at reversing some of those 1960s cuts.

The Tories have promised a £500m Beeching reversal fund, and have mentioned the return of passenger services to Blyth as one of the projects which could win support from that fund.

But the estimated cost of £99m to return services to the Ashington, Blyth and Tyne line has yet to be committed.

That leaves many locals relying on buses, so they will also want to see the prime minister deliver on promised investment into the network.

The local health trust that covers the constituency outperforms much of England, though in the most recent figures it still missed A&amp;E and cancer targets.

It performed well though when it came to meeting mental health targets.

The Northumbria Healthcare NHS Foundation Trust has been rated as &quot;outstanding&quot; by the Care Quality Commission.

And this is one community where Boris Johnson might not have to deliver a new hospital.

A new purpose-built emergency care hospital opened in Cramlington in the constituency in 2015. It was the first of its kind, and has been seen as a model of how hospitals should operate.

Although the constituency as a whole is about average for life expectancy, it has an above average number of over-65s - an ageing population that will want to see the government come up with a solution to social care funding.
• Check your local NHS performance with our tracker

The North East of England has some of the best performing primary schools, but some of the worst performing secondary schools.

But actually Blyth Valley has a better educational record than much of the region. Although achievement was slightly below average at primary level, secondary standards are above average.

It is one of the few parts of the country where at least some students are in a three-tier schooling system, with First, Middle and High Schools.

You can bet the schools though will want to see more funding delivered by the prime minister and their new MP.

The local further education college will also hope Mr Johnson makes good on promises to put money into a sector which suffered a funding squeeze under David Cameron and Theresa May.

Northumbria Police has suffered some of the worst funding cuts - in fact its chief constable described them as the worst in the country in 2018.

The force has lost more than 1,000 officers since 2010 and had to dip into its financial reserves to avoid deeper cuts. Part of the problem was a narrow base for council tax - meaning cuts from central government were not replaced by local funds.

Mr Johnson has already committed to increasing the number of police. The Home Office expect 185 extra officers to be recruited in the Northumbria force area by 2021, but that does not replace all those that have been lost.

The prime minister and new MP will be under pressure to show they will go further in a community which is in the top 10% of the country when it comes to crime.

Immigration into the area is negligible. Figures aren't available purely for Blyth Valley, but from mid 2016-2017, it is estimated that the short-term international migration flow to the entire Northumberland region was made up of just 47 people.

Given the county's population is over 300,000, this is not a community struggling to cope with the weight of inward migration.

Blyth Valley is also an overwhelmingly white constituency.

That does not mean voters are not concerned about immigration into the UK more widely.

But in a region with skill shortages, some employers will be keen to retain access to workers from overseas – and the PM will have to balance those two competing demands.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50782411</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: 10 things you need to know about the campaign - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/CD76/production/_110089525_e0f149b3-0954-4a49-8672-041ff33e310e.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>We've had key messages hammered home, the odd gaffe and rows over TV debates.

But what else have we learnt since Boris Johnson called a snap election?

1) It's been a presidential-style campaign

We don't have a presidential voting system in the UK, but you wouldn't know it from the campaigns of the two main parties.

The choice is between Boris Johnson and Jeremy Corbyn, the Conservatives and Labour have said throughout - with both leaders travelling up and down the country to appeal to voters.

We have barely seen some of the front bench - Home Secretary Priti Patel or Business Secretary Andrea Leadsom at main campaign events, for example - and on Labour's side we haven't seen shadow Brexit secretary Keir Starmer or shadow foreign secretary Emily Thornberry.

But, during a sit-down interview with BBC Breakfast, Mr Corbyn said it was &quot;not a presidential election&quot;.

He was responding to a question on whether he has been a hindrance on the doorstep, amid reports that some candidates are finding voters do not want to support him personally.

Our political editor Laura Kuenssberg says the voters she has met on the campaign trail are fixed on the two central characters of Boris Johnson and Jeremy Corbyn - they are so well-known.

She says both have bands of &quot;true believers&quot; but the men who are vying to be prime minister are also facing very serious doubts from some of the public.

2) Parties have upped their digital game - but there has been misinformation and 'fake news'

The battleground is no longer just on the doorstep and campaign trail - as we know, it's online too.

On Facebook, the parties splurged the cash. At one point earlier this month, the Facebook Ad Library showed that about 2,500 adverts paid for by the Conservative Party were live, compared with 3,000 for the Liberal Democrats, but only 250 for Labour.

And this time, there were also non-party groups sending Facebook users ads.

But there has been some criticism of the way platforms have been used.

The Conservatives were criticised for posting an edited video of Labour's Keir Starmer on their social media and for rebranding their @CCHQPress account - the Tory press office - as &quot;factcheckUK&quot; during the ITV debate between Mr Johnson and Mr Corbyn.

And Labour was questioned over a claim posted on Facebook that a Conservative trade deal with the US after Brexit could cost the NHS up to £500m a week, by driving up the price of medicines.

Now, a campaign group is calling for fact-checking of political advertising to be a legal requirement after what it describes as a &quot;fake news and disinformation general election&quot;.

But controversy over social media election campaign posts has potentially helped to spread political messages, according to one media analyst.

In recent days we've seen misinformation over the case of the four-year-old boy, Jack, who was pictured on the floor of Leeds General Infirmary after being admitted with suspected pneumonia.

The hospital apologised and despite a statement from the hospital's chief medical officer, numerous posts spread on social media claiming the photo was staged.

Our Reality Check team have been busy fact-checking claims throughout this campaign, see more from them here.
• Are these the 6 most controversial numbers so far?

3) Rows over TV interviews and... blocks of ice

Boris Johnson faced accusations that he was &quot;running scared&quot; from scrutiny after failing to take part in a sit-down BBC interview with Andrew Neil - something that led the presenter to issue a direct challenge to the PM.

Mr Johnson did not face Neil - like the other main party leaders - but the Tory party leader says he has taken part in two head-to-head debates and &quot;118 sit-down interviews with journalists&quot; during the campaign.

And Channel 4 &quot;empty chaired&quot; the Tories and the Brexit Party with ice sculptures during its climate change debate. The Tories complained to Ofcom over impartiality, but the regulator decided not to investigate. It concluded that the Conservative viewpoint had been given due weight.

We know that the Conservatives and the Brexit Party are targeting Labour Leave voters - while the Labour Party has been campaigning hard to keep them on side.

During the campaign, both of the main party leaders have travelled to these areas - in north-east Wales, the Midlands and the north of England, which are said to form Labour's &quot;red wall&quot; - to make their pitches.

Polling expert Sir John Curtice says if Mr Johnson is to win an overall majority, he is likely to have to win a significant number of marginal seats from Labour.

Of Labour's 50 most marginal seats, 39 voted in favour of Leave in the 2016 referendum and in 16, more than 60% voted for Brexit.
• Sir John Curtice: Five things to watch for in the election
• Where are the seats that could turn the election?

Remember &quot;strong and stable&quot; from the 2017 campaign?

Well, that's long gone and, for the Conservatives, has been replaced with &quot;get Brexit done&quot;, with Mr Johnson promising to take the UK out of the EU by 31 January.

The party's campaign has been all about what the election was called over in the first place - Brexit.

For Labour they have hammered their message on the NHS - that if the Conservatives get into power that puts the NHS at risk of being &quot;on the table&quot; in any post-Brexit trade negotiations with the US - something the Tories have denied will happen.

The Liberal Democrats, on the other hand, want to &quot;Stop Brexit. Build a brighter future&quot;, and the SNP says it is &quot;stronger for Scotland&quot;. The party has &quot;stop Brexit&quot; on the side of its battle bus.

The SNP has been pushing for a second Scottish referendum, saying it is confident Labour would support a further vote if the party was in a minority government situation.

6) Politicians are always at risk of derailing their campaign last-minute

In what has seen to be a generally stable campaign, the last few days have proved rocky for both the Conservatives and Labour.

Boris Johnson was criticised after initially refusing to look at a picture of a sick four-year-old boy who had to sleep on the floor of a Leeds hospital.

An ITV reporter tried to show Mr Johnson the picture on his phone, but he refused to look, before taking the device and putting it in his pocket.

Mr Johnson eventually looked at the picture and apologised to the family.

Then Labour's Jonathan Ashworth apologised to his party after he criticised Jeremy Corbyn in a secret recording by his Tory activist friend.

In a recording leaked to Tory-supporting website Guido Fawkes, Mr Ashworth is heard saying he did not believe Labour would win the election.

Mr Ashworth has insisted he was &quot;joshing around&quot; in the conversation, while Mr Corbyn claimed the story was &quot;irrelevant&quot;.

7) Was this the 'climate change election'?

During this election, we've heard a number of &quot;green&quot; pledges and polling at the beginning of the campaign revealed a potentially significant shift, elevating the environment to being among voters' top priorities.

Greens co-leader Sian Berry called it the &quot;climate election&quot; at the campaign launch for the Green Party of England and Wales, saying &quot;some things are even bigger than Brexit&quot;.

A Friends of the Earth survey suggested that Labour had the strongest policies to protect nature and combat climate change.

Its election pledges narrowly beat the Green Party and the Liberal Democrats - with the Conservatives far behind, according to the environmental campaign group.

And climate change protesters in bee costumes from Extinction Rebellion glued themselves to the Liberal Democrats' electric bus, as well as the Conservatives' bus.

Lib Dem leader Jo Swinson defended her party's climate change policy to protesters in bee costumes, who said the plans were &quot;not ambitious enough&quot;.
• Which parties want to tax frequent flyers?

The election campaign has been marked by calls for tactical voting from both sides in the Brexit debate.

Prof Stephen Fisher, an election analyst at the University of Oxford, says: &quot;Among Leave supporters, tactical voting is likely to come into play in constituencies where the Brexit Party and the Conservatives are competing to take a seat from a party that is sympathetic to another referendum.

&quot;Tactical voting among Remain supporters is much more complicated because it involves more parties, with varying Brexit policies.&quot;

He says that relatively small changes in the number of votes a candidate receives have the potential to make a big difference.

In terms of the trends, our political editor Laura Kuenssberg says that actually, not much has changed during this campaign.

The Tories have been broadly ahead for most of the time, with Labour struggling to close the gap, and the Lib Dems haven't made the kind of breakthrough people thought they might do a few months ago.

And the SNP look likely to stay dominant in Scotland.

Polling expert Sir John Curtice says there have been two trends in the polls during this campaign - but they have effectively negated each other.

The Conservative vote is up - but so is the Labour vote, with the Brexit Party and Lib Dems being squeezed by both parties.

&quot;The net effect on the Conservative lead has been effectively zero,&quot; Sir John says.

9) A record number of women are running for office - and a high number of independents

At the beginning of the campaign, BBC analysis of Press Association figures found 1,124 of 3,322 registered candidates were women.

That's an increase from 2015's record of 1,033 - but in 2017, just 973 female candidates took part in that year's snap election, according to research by the House of Commons library.

There have been concerns that levels of abuse on social media might deter women from standing, with a number of high-profile former female ministers citing this as their main reason for quitting frontline politics.

There are also 205 independent candidates standing - and several are recognisable faces, including former Tories David Gauke, Dominic Grieve and Anne Milton, who were all expelled from the Conservative Party after rebelling over Brexit.
• Record number of women set to stand in election

10) And finally.... it's Christmas, actually

We've seen both sides channel the 2003 romantic comedy Love, Actually, using a famous scene in which a man uses a series of placards to tell a woman he loves her - but adding an election twist.

Labour's Tooting candidate, Rosena Allin-Khan, posted her video first on social media, which showed her targeting a Tory supporter on the doorstep. This was followed by a version from the Conservatives, with Boris Johnson urging voters to back him.

You can see a full list of Tooting candidates here.

We were also treated to Christmas-themed questions from interviewers, including at the first head-to-head live TV debate on ITV - when Boris Johnson and Jeremy Corbyn were asked what presents they would leave under each other's trees this year.

Mr Corbyn went for a copy of Charles Dickens' A Christmas Carol so Mr Johnson &quot;could then understand how nasty Scrooge was&quot;.

The PM offered up his Brexit deal as a good read, but when reminded the answer was meant to be non-political, he changed his answer to some damson jam.

Asked on BBC West Midlands Radio what he would get his partner Carrie Symonds for Christmas, Mr Johnson - staying on message - insisted he would &quot;get Brexit done&quot;.

Now it's down to voters to decide what election result they want for Christmas.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50741212</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Scotland election results 2019: SNP wins election landslide in Scotland - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/B77C/production/_110127964_058617188.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The SNP has made big gains across Scotland, with Nicola Sturgeon saying the country had sent a &quot;clear message&quot; on a second independence referendum.

The party won 48 seats after securing 45% of the vote - 8.1% more than in the last general election in 2017, when it won 35 seats.

The SNP also defeated Liberal Democrat leader Jo Swinson in East Dunbartonshire.

Ms Sturgeon said the result had exceeded her expectations.

The Conservatives have won six seats, the Liberal Democrats four and Labour one.

Neale Hanvey's victory in Kirkcaldy and Cowdenbeath is counted as an SNP gain from Labour because he was on the ballot paper as an SNP candidate.

Mr Hanvey had been suspended by the party over allegations he made anti-Semitic posts on social media, and will sit as an independent MP.

The Conservatives and Prime Minister Boris Johnson have won an overall majority across the UK after taking a string of former Labour strongholds in England and Wales.

Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn said it was a &quot;very disappointing night for the Labour Party&quot; and confirmed he would not lead the party into the next election.

The other main developments from Scotland's election night include:
• Liberal Democrat leader Jo Swinson narrowly lost her Dunbartonshire East seat to the SNP by just 149 votes
• Scottish Labour's Ian Murray held on to his seat in Edinburgh South as his party lost all of its other MPs.
• The SNP's Stephen Gethins lost to the Liberal Democrats in the UK's narrowest marginal seat, Fife North East.

Ms Sturgeon, the Scottish first minister, had already pledged to send a letter to the prime minister before Christmas requesting that Holyrood be given the power to hold indyref2.

Speaking at the Glasgow count, she said she would not pretend that everyone who voted for her party will necessarily support independence.

But she said it was a &quot;clear endorsement Scotland should get to decide our future and not have it decided for us&quot;.
• Corbyn: I will not lead Labour at next election

Ms Sturgeon added: &quot;Scotland has sent a very clear message - we don't want a Boris Johnson government, we don't want to leave the EU.

&quot;The results across the rest of the UK are grim but underlines the importance of Scotland having a choice.

&quot;Boris Johnson has a mandate to take England out of the EU but he must accept that I have a mandate to give Scotland a choice for an alternative future.&quot;

Nicola Sturgeon says she won't pretend that every single person who voted SNP necessarily supports independence. But she will insist this result is a thumping endorsement of her demand for a second referendum.

She will make an official request in the next few days to be granted the legal power to hold an independence vote.

And we know that Boris Johnson will refuse, sparking a huge debate about whether the Conservatives are ignoring the democratic choice of Scottish voters.

It's a debate that can only escalate as we leave the EU - and one which may fuel support for independence itself.

Scottish Secretary Alister Jack, who held Dumfries and Galloway for the Conservatives, said more people cast votes for unionist parties in Scotland than for the SNP.

And he was adamant the prime minister should continue to block Ms Sturgeon's calls for power to hold an independence ballot.

The Conservative vote had fallen by 3.5% to 25.1% across Scotland, while the Labour vote was down by 8.5% to 18.6%. The Liberal Democrat vote actually increased by 2.8% to 9.5% despite the loss of the party's leader.

Rutherglen and Hamilton West was the first Scottish constituency to declare its result at 01:25, with Margaret Ferrier - who previously held the seat between 2015 and 2017 - polling 23,775 votes, giving her a majority of 5,230 over her Labour rival Ged Killen.

That early success was quickly followed by the SNP's David Doogan defeating Conservative Kirstene Hair in Angus.

John Nicolson won the Ochil and South Perthshire seat after defeating Luke Graham of the Conservatives, while the SNP also won back Midlothian from Labour's Danielle Rowley,

The SNP's Mhairi Black comfortably held her Paisley and Renfrewshire South seat with a greatly increased majority, while Kenny MacAskill, the former Scottish justice secretary, won the East Lothian seat from Labour.

SNP MEP Alyn Smith won Stirling from Stephen Kerr of the Conservatives, but Scottish Secretary Alister Jack held Dumfries and Galloway for the Tories.

Douglas Ross also held his Moray seat for the Conservatives, while his colleague David Mundell held Dumfriesshire, Clydesdale and Tweeddale.

The SNP's Stephen Gethins lost by 1,316 votes to Wendy Chamberlain of the Liberal Democrats in Fife North East. Mr Gethins had won the seat by just two votes in 2017.

And Labour's Ian Murray held on in Edinburgh South, meaning he is the party's only MP in Scotland.

Mr Murray, a longstanding critic of Mr Corbyn, warned that his party's ideology must change or else it will &quot;die&quot; and said voters he spoke to on the doorsteps during this campaign did not see Mr Corbyn as prime minister and could not see Labour as a credible alternative government.

For a nationwide breakdown of results, see our results page.

If you can't see the look-up click here.

Or you can browse the A-Z list.

The SNP are once again the undoubted winners of the night, taking a slew of seats from their opponents including a big scalp in the form of Lib Dem leader Jo Swinson.

The party haven't had it all their own way - running up against Tory resistance in a few seats and losing North East Fife to the Lib Dems - but Nicola Sturgeon's team have piled on thousands of votes in every seat and have already secured a landslide.

Labour, meanwhile, have collapsed across Scotland, with their share of the vote down sharply. They even lost the shadow Scottish secretary, Lesley Laird, to a candidate disowned by the SNP and who will sit as an independent.

The Conservatives have clinched victory UK-wide, but have lost a clutch of Scottish seats to the SNP - and will be wondering what this means for their campaign to &quot;stop indyref2&quot;.

The Lib Dem vote share is up in most places, but any progress will be massively overshadowed by the loss of Ms Swinson. The party's leader has just gone from touting herself as a future prime minister to losing her seat for the second time in four years.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50766014</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What happens now? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/120A2/production/_110709837_brexit_flowchart_conservative_maj_29_01_640-nc.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The UK left the EU on 31 January 2020 and has now entered an 11-month transition period.

During this period the UK effectively remains in the EU's customs union and single market and continues to obey EU rules.

However, it is no longer part of the political institutions. So, for example, there are no longer any British MEPs in the European Parliament.
• What is Boris Johnson's deal with the EU?

The first priority will be to negotiate a trade deal with the EU. The UK wants as much access as possible for its goods and services to the EU.

But the government has made clear that the UK must leave the customs union and single market and end the overall jurisdiction of the European Court of Justice.

Time is short. The EU could take weeks to agree a formal negotiating mandate - all the remaining 27 member states and the European Parliament have to be in agreement. That means formal talks might only begin in March.

The government has ruled out any form of extension to the transition period.

If no trade deal has been agreed and ratified by the end of the year, then the UK faces the prospect of tariffs on exports to the EU.

The prime minister has argued that as the UK is completely aligned to EU rules, the negotiation should be straightforward. But critics have pointed out that the UK wishes to have the freedom to diverge from EU rules so it can do deals with other countries - and that will make negotiations more difficult.

It's not just a trade deal that needs to be sorted out. The UK must agree how it is going to co-operate with the EU on security and law enforcement. The UK is set to leave the European Arrest Warrant scheme and will have to agree a replacement. It must also agree deals in a number of other areas where co-operation is needed.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-46393399</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: What's it like to lose your seat as an MP? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EF82/production/_110141316_elsbxoiwoaq6pwh.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The general election brought surprise victories and shock defeats for MPs across the UK. Former politicians who failed to win the vote have shared how it feels to lose their seat in the House of Commons.

Hours after losing his seat in Bury North by 105 votes, former MP James Frith said it was &quot;too soon&quot; to say what the &quot;full impact&quot; of the defeat would be on him and his family.

However, he said he did feel &quot;a degree of release&quot; from the weeks of intense campaigning.

Mr Frith was one of the 60 Labour candidates to lose out in the general election, and one of 54 to see their seat turned over to the Conservatives. Although, in Bury North, this was more like a return to the Conservatives, after Mr Frith ousted David Nuttall in 2017.

&quot;I'm still processing it, the grieving is at the 'stunned' stage,&quot; the former rock band front-man said. &quot;We had a re-count where the results changed twice, but I conceded on the third re-count, congratulated my opponent and went home.

&quot;I stayed up the rest of the night, and in the morning I spent time with the children explaining it to them, one of my sons got very upset, but the younger two didn't really understand.&quot;

When Parliament dissolved, Mr Frith said he understood running in a marginal seat meant losing was &quot;a possibility&quot;, but added he felt the impact of being &quot;inches from winning&quot;.

Asked about the future, he said he'd like to be involved in &quot;rebuilding the party&quot;, but said for now he was going to take some &quot;well deserved time off for Christmas&quot;.

Ben Howlett became the Conservative MP for Bath in 2015 and lost his seat in the 2017 general election. &quot;I was back home after the count taking the washing out of the machine when Mrs May phoned to say sorry which was a bit surreal,&quot; he said.

The 33-year-old described his defeat as &quot;a bit like losing a close relative&quot;.

&quot;You don't do it as a nine to five Monday to Friday job - it's basically your life,&quot; he said. &quot;The people you work with become your family, you've got your team and the hundreds of people you've been helping.

&quot;Suddenly you have that ability to help people taken away. I got emotionally attached to some of the people I was trying to help with immigration cases and I had to hand them over to my successor.&quot;

Mr Howlett said he felt emotionally drained by the end of the count and had been living off adrenalin and coffee. &quot;I went out with my family for a Sunday dinner and it dawned on me that I had to close down my constituency office on Monday,&quot; he said.

&quot;Everyone else goes back to work and you're on your own for the first time in months or years. You're physically on your own and you're emotionally on your own. I remember sobbing on my own in my kitchen. You need a lot of support and people to turn to.&quot;

Mr Howlett now owns a policy advisory and development organisation in the health, care and local government sectors. &quot;I know MPs who carry on acting as MPs because that's all they've known and their families never get them back,&quot; he said.

Tania Mathias is an NHS doctor and was Conservative MP for Twickenham between 2015 and 2017.

&quot;Losing your seat is disappointing but it's not as bad as the worst night in hospital or in a conflict zone - nobody died,&quot; she said. &quot;At first I wasn't telling colleagues that because I felt it was downplaying how people were feeling. But my politician friends who are doctors understood.&quot;

Dr Mathias now works as an ophthalmology doctor and has continued to campaign for the Conservative Party.

She is a volunteer medical doctor with the charity Freedom from Torture and has led workshops in Kosovo, Bosnia Herzegovina and Sierra Leone for people standing in elections for the first time.

&quot;I tried my best and I wanted every single vote but when you lose you think 'hey I'm part of democracy' and you're really, really proud of that. The voters had their say and there was no violence so I'm happy.

&quot;[The murder of MP] Jo Cox puts everything into perspective. Every good conversation, every honest conversation is worth it. We have to keep this basic thing of being able to knock on a stranger's door and have that discussion about what you believe in.

&quot;If you've managed to put your message across and used every single minute of the day and night to communicate with your voters then be happy.&quot;

Simon Wright was the Liberal Democrat MP for Norwich South between 2010 and 2015. &quot;I once heard losing your seat described as the most public sacking imaginable and there's no escaping from that,&quot; he said.

&quot;By the time the results came in we had a fair sense of how things were going. So when the declaration came, it was more a sense of accepting what had increasingly become inevitable.

&quot;You always fight an election campaign as you want to win it so it will always come as a crushing blow and a bitter shock. But in the weeks that followed I took heart in the positive words and kind support from my former constituents and even my rivals.&quot;

Mr Wright said he felt &quot;very fortunate&quot; to find a new position as chief executive officer of children's bereavement charity Nelson's Journey within a matter of weeks.

He married wife Anna Thorpe in April 2019 and 100 friends joined them at Parkrun at Catton Park in Norwich on the morning of their wedding.

&quot;Circumstances lined up and I was able to find a new job that I really wanted to do and that I was really enthusiastic and passionate about,&quot; he said.

&quot;The time and emotional energy that goes into being an MP is very significant and you're pulled in lots of different directions. I've had more time for family, friends and hobbies and the running community has become a really big part of my life.

&quot;There is life after parliament so that doesn't have to be what defines your future.&quot;
• Who were the major political casualties at the 2019 general election?
• Let the healing begin, urges PM after poll win
• Jeremy Corbyn: 'I did everything I could to lead Labour'

Matthew Green was the Liberal Democrat MP for Ludlow between 2001 and 2005.

&quot;I was aware that I was going to lose from the weekend before because I did the number crunching,&quot; he said. &quot;But I didn't tell anyone in my team because I wanted to keep campaigning up to the end.

&quot;I had a few days of this surreal situation where I knew I was heading for defeat but I couldn't tell anyone. But when it came to it, it's a gut-wrenching thing. It's comparable to what I envisage would be a fairly sudden sacking or a company going bust.

&quot;It's a very uncertain time, you've still got a mortgage to pay. You've lost your job and you've got to close down your operation and make your team redundant, it's not pleasant.&quot;

Mr Green said he applied for jobs before creating a planning and architecture consultancy &quot;almost by accident&quot;.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics
• BREXIT: What happens now?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50712756</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Durham North West: The 'no-hope' seat the Tories won - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/ED3E/production/_110143706_comp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Among the Conservative Party's haul of astonishing election scalps was Durham North West - a seat the party was not targeting and one it once discounted as impossible to win. What happened?

There are safe seats where favoured candidates can be assured of an easy victory.

And then there are places where rookies have to do their best, hoping to prove their worth for a better seat next time. For the Conservatives, Durham North West was always the latter.

Labour since 1950, it was where Theresa May was sent to cut her parliamentary teeth. As expected, she lost to Labour incumbent Hilary Armstrong by a margin of nearly 14,000 votes.

Richard Holden's victory on Thursday was less dramatic. He beat Labour's Laura Pidcock - once tipped as potential party leader or, at least, successor as deputy - by a more modest 1,144.

The table below shows the full result.

If you can't see the graphic click here.

Jeremy Corbyn did, thinks Anne-Marie Kennedy, back home visiting her mother in Lanchester.

&quot;[He] now needs to go,&quot; she says. &quot;He needs to get someone in the Labour Party that can run the party properly.&quot;

Her mother, Pauline Harrison, is equally unimpressed with the Labour leader, who she believes does not want to unify people or get Brexit done.

&quot;The result is brilliant,&quot; she says.

But, if Boris Johnson might find these comments reassuring, Mrs Kennedy has a message for him too.

&quot;I think, Boris, you need to be true to your word for the people,&quot; she says.

Matthew Young, from Consett which saw its steelworks close a year into Margaret Thatcher's Conservative government, says Brexit was &quot;the crux&quot; of the election.

&quot;There's a man in power now who has promised to do that and I hope he does it,&quot; he says.

But Baroness Hilary Armstrong, who held Durham North West from 1987 until she stood down at the 2010 election, does not believe this was the deciding factor.

She thinks voters were more concerned about Labour's &quot;competence&quot;.

&quot;They quite liked some of the promises but they never believed we could deliver them,&quot; she says.

&quot;Ordinary working people feel let down. They just feel that the Labour Party has lost touch with them - and I agree with them.&quot;

Even the constituency's first Conservative MP, Richard Holden, sees his win in terms of a Labour loss.

&quot;This wasn't a result which was really even about me,&quot; he says.

&quot;This was, particularly from a lot of Labour voters spoken to on the doorstep, a real rejection of the way Jeremy Corbyn has been leading the Labour Party.&quot;

Among the voters who are shocked at the result, there are plenty looking forward to an emboldened Boris Johnson government.

Brenda Spelman, from Medomsley, is &quot;delighted&quot; with the Conservative win.

&quot;Onwards and upwards,&quot; she says. &quot;It can only get better. I think under Labour it would have got worse.&quot;

Until Thursday night North West Durham was the sort of &quot;no-hoper&quot; seat that young ambitious Conservatives looking to cut their political teeth were pointed towards.

A constituency made up of former mining and steel towns such as Consett, it was working class through and through.

At the height of Labour's success in 1997, the local MP Hilary Armstrong took nearly 69% of the vote - more than double all the other parties added together.

One Conservative keen to make her mark at the start of her career was Theresa May, a councillor in London when she travelled north to be selected as Conservative candidate at the 1992 general election.

She came second, with the future Liberal Democrat leader Tim Farron trailing in third. For Mrs May it was a step up the political ladder and by 1997 she'd been rewarded with the far more winnable constituency of Maidenhead.

But things have moved on - and the Conservative Party has proved it's capable of winning even in the former Labour heartlands of the North East.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics

Follow BBC North East &amp; Cumbria on Twitter, Facebook and Instagram. Send your story ideas to northeastandcumbria@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50779285</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: Ten lesser-known MPs to keep an eye on - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1098F/production/_110138976_c4256a26-fbc8-420d-aeb1-c862d5e87b89.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Parliament tends to be dominated by its grandest figures, the party leaders, and their cabinet or shadow cabinet teams.

But others can cut a dash in the Commons by weight of expertise, through passion for an issue, by sheer street-smarts, or simply by being in the right place at the right time.

So here are a few MPs who - while not aspiring to the top table - could exert serious leverage in the newly elected House of Commons.

After a strong performance in the race to succeed John Bercow as Speaker - and in a House of Commons with many more Conservatives - she must surely be the front runner to become Chairman of Ways and Means, the senior deputy speaker.

She would then have the key responsibilities of chairing budget debates and selecting amendments for consideration by committees of the whole house - a key task when the government begins to push through its Withdrawal Agreement Bill.

He pulled off a considerable coup in 2017, when, as a junior backbencher, he wrested the chairmanship of the Foreign Affairs Committee from ex-minister Crispin Blunt.

An ex-army officer - he served in Iraq and Afghanistan - Tugendhat writes notes to himself on an office whiteboard in Arabic to preserve privacy. He's a reasonable bet for a ministerial job, perhaps in the Foreign Office.

Hawkish on Russia - he said the Salisbury poisoning was &quot;if not an act of war… certainly a warlike act by the Russian Federation&quot; - expect him to be an influential voice on foreign policy if he remains on the backbenches.

Chairwoman of the Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy Committee - where she performed impressively - she is being tipped as the person around whom the remains of the Blairite-Brownite group of Labour MPs might coalesce.

That may not translate into an attempt on the leadership, but she may now become an important factional leader.

Few MPs come into Parliament with a clearly defined policy mission, but the ex-army officer who won Plymouth Moor View against the expectations of his own party, announced himself with a blistering maiden speech on the need for better care for military veterans.

He was an early backer of Boris Johnson's leadership campaign and was frequently seen shepherding the would-be leader around Westminster. His support was rewarded with the job he always wanted - defence minister responsible for veterans. Mercer will expect the political support and funding to reform the system.

Briefly Leader of the House in the dog days of Theresa May's premiership, the former Treasury minister found himself surplus to requirements when Boris Johnson took over. But with gazelle-like agility, he leapt into the vacancy created when Nicky Morgan left as chairwoman of the Treasury Committee.

He didn't have much time to make an impact in this key committee corridor job before the election was called, but if he is re-elected as Parliament's scrutiniser-in-chief of economic policy (and others may cast covetous eyes on the post) he will get to pronounce on levels of spending and public debt at a ticklish moment for the UK economy.

Double-hatted as Metro Mayor of South Yorkshire and MP for Barnsley Central. In a Parliament where one of the big themes looks certain to be devolution - and demands for greater powers for Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland - the mayor of a fair chunk of left-behind territory could find himself &quot;speaking for England&quot;.

Once talked up as a possible Labour leadership contender, he defied pressure to give up his Commons seat and maintains a perch in Westminster. He is a Parachute Regiment veteran with service in Kosovo, Iraq and Afghanistan.

Seen as a bit of a star of the 2017 intake, Afolami is on the Commons end of the Constitution Reform Group, a cross-party pressure group which wants to rebalance a constitution destabilised by an uneven devolution settlement.

This is the group behind the Act of Union Bill, a private member's bill proposed by the former clerk of the Commons, Lord Lisvane. It may all sound high-powered and rather nerdy, but the tug of war between the nations and regions of the UK is set to be a big theme of the new Parliament, and Afolami looks set to be a player.

Smart, personable, and articulate in two languages he seized and held a seat which has see-sawed between Plaid and the Lib Dems since the 1990s. In his maiden speech, he complained of the steady, silent haemorrhage of young people leaving their communities to seek opportunities elsewhere. A future leader?

Newly elected, he is nonetheless an experienced figure, having served in the European Parliament since 2004. He looks ready-made to become the SNP's new Brexit spokesman in Westminster.

She contested the most marginal seat in the country (the SNP won with a majority of just two votes in 2017) in North East Fife.

An ex-police officer who is already attracting rave reviews. Part of an infusion of new blood into a rather bruised and diminished Lib Dem parliamentary contingent.

Those leaving Parliament include Dr Sarah Wollaston, a GP who was originally elected as a Conservative in 2010 but ended up in the Lib Dems, by way of the short-lived Independent Group of MPs. Labour's Frank Field, a maverick Labour MP, almost permanently at odds with his constituency party, and the SNP's Stephen Gethins, who might have been a candidate to lead their Westminster group had he enjoyed a more comfortable majority, also both lost their seats.

Labour's Mary Creagh led a series of high-profile inquiries into the environmental issues around the fashion industry and toxic chemicals in everyday life. And Dennis Skinner - the Labour stalwart would have been the father of the House, the longest serving MP, had he survived the election - also departs. He was first elected in 1970, and fell just short of half a century in the Commons.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50786212</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Jeremy Corbyn: 'I will not lead Labour at next election' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07xsv43.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Jeremy Corbyn has said he will not lead Labour into the next election, following a &quot;very disappointing night&quot;.

With one seat left to declare, the party has won 203 seats.

Mr Corbyn said he would stay on as leader during a &quot;process of reflection&quot;, and said Brexit had &quot;polarised&quot; politics which had &quot;overridden normal political debate&quot;.

But others within Labour, including former MPs who lost their seats, blamed Mr Corbyn's leadership.

BBC political editor Laura Kuenssberg said Mr Corbyn was not intending to resign and it could take until April for a leadership contest to take place.

On the night, the Conservatives won a big majority, sweeping aside Labour strongholds across northern England, the Midlands and Wales in areas which backed Brexit in the 2016 referendum.

Some traditional Labour constituencies, such as Darlington, Sedgefield and Workington, in the north of England, will have a Conservative MP for the first time in decades - or in the case of Bishop Auckland and Blyth Valley - for the first time since the seat was created.

At 33%, Labour's share of the vote is down around eight points on the 2017 general election and is lower than that achieved by Neil Kinnock in 1992.
• LIVE: Updates and reaction as results come in
• Tories take Labour seats as they head for majority

Speaking at his election count in Islington North, where he was re-elected with a reduced majority, Mr Corbyn said Labour had put forward a &quot;manifesto of hope&quot; and criticised the &quot;way the media behaved&quot; towards his party during the campaign.

But he added: &quot;Brexit has so polarised and divided debate in this country, it has overridden so much of a normal political debate.&quot;

&quot;I recognise that has contributed to the results that the Labour Party has received this evening all across this country.&quot;

Labour primarily campaigned on a promise to end austerity by increasing spending on public services.

The party also promised to renegotiate Prime Minister Boris Johnson's Brexit deal, and then put it to a referendum vote alongside the option of remaining in the EU.

That strategy was criticised by party chairman Ian Lavery, who said it had led voters in traditional Labour seats to believe it was &quot;a Remain party&quot;.

&quot;They believe they should have been listened to - and they think that the Labour party have totally reneged on the result,&quot; he said.

But he added the strategy was not &quot;Jeremy Corbyn's decision&quot;, as it had been approved by delegates at the party's September conference.

Former Labour MP John Mann said the leader's unpopularity on the doorstep was palpable and Mr Corbyn should have &quot;gone already&quot;.

Others have blamed the party's support for another Brexit referendum and the long-running anti-Semitism row.

Margaret Hodge, MP for Barking, said Labour had become the &quot;nasty party&quot;.

Given the result, you might assume Jeremy Corbyn would swiftly fall on his sword - but he has instead called for a period of quiet reflection.

Party rules make it difficult to oust him, but already senior figures are asking how long this period will last.

Senior figures at Westminster and in local government feel delaying an inevitable leadership contest will lead to a similar result in May's council elections.

Mr Corbyn seems intent on staying in place until someone from his wing of the party is ready to take over - but the defeat of shadow minister Laura Pidcock has eliminated one of the potential left-wing leadership challengers.

Those who would prefer shadow Brexit secretary Sir Keir Starmer are keen that a new leader is in place soon to challenge Prime Minister Boris Johnson's Brexit policy.

The battle to establish the reasons for the defeat has already begun.

The narrative from the leadership that Brexit was to blame will be challenged robustly by those who want the party to change direction.

Shadow chancellor John McDonnell, a key ally of Mr Corbyn, said he was &quot;heartbroken&quot; at the result and insisted he would not take on the party leadership temporarily.

&quot;At some stage we'll go into a leadership election,&quot; he said.

&quot;Jeremy wants to ensure there is a period of reflection.&quot;

Earlier, he said he did not think the Labour leader had been &quot;the big issue&quot; of the campaign.

But former Labour justice secretary Lord Falconer called for the party to move quickly to replace Mr Corbyn as leader by March or April.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics

Gareth Snell, who lost his Leave-backing Stoke-on-Trent Central seat, called for both Mr Corbyn and Mr McDonnell to quit.

He accused senior figures in the shadow cabinet, who are defending Remain-voting seats in London, of &quot;sacrificing&quot; candidates in marginal constituencies in the Midlands and the north of England.

Elsewhere in the city, Ruth Smeeth, who lost her Stoke-on-Trent North seat to the Conservatives, described the election result as &quot;devastating&quot;.

&quot;For me, this is about whether the Labour Party has any right to exist [and] whether we have anything left to say,&quot; she said.

Another Labour MP to lose her seat, Caroline Flint in Don Valley, said: &quot;So many of my voters could not and did not want to support Jeremy Corbyn to be prime minister.&quot;

She added: &quot;There are moderate MPs who have driven us into a dead-end regarding Brexit and they have put the pursuit of Remain at the expense of our working-class heartlands and I feel annoyed, to say the least, about that.&quot;

Shadow Brexit secretary Sir Keir Starmer, speaking after holding his Holborn and St Pancras seat, said: &quot;As a whole movement, we need to reflect on this result and understand it together, but we also have a duty to rebuild, starting now.&quot;

Yvette Cooper, who unsuccessfully challenged Mr Corbyn for her party's leadership in 2015, said the results showed Labour has &quot;to change as a party&quot;.

She said Brexit had played a &quot;significant part&quot; in her party's performance, but the election &quot;was not just about Brexit&quot;.

&quot;It was about their perceptions of the party, their perceptions of the leadership,&quot; she added.

Speaking after an earlier exit poll predicted heavy losses for Labour, former Labour home secretary Alan Johnson told ITV News that Mr Corbyn had been &quot;incapable of leading&quot; and &quot;worse than useless at all the qualities you need to lead a political party.&quot;

Polling expert Professor Sir John Curtice said: &quot;It was clear that lots of Remain voters had doubts about Jeremy Corbyn's ability to handle Brexit and indeed, more broadly to handle anything.&quot;

In a statement, the Jewish Labour Movement - affiliated to the party for a century and representing about 2,500 members - said Labour's failure &quot;lies squarely with the party's leadership&quot;.

&quot;Because of the public's rejection of Corbyn as prime minister, the confused position on Brexit, or its total failure to tackle anti-Jewish racism, the party must truly listen,&quot; the statement said.

If you cannot see the graphic above, click here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50766114</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: Key words and phrases explained - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/0228/production/_110025500_promo_translator_guide_976v12_d.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>
• It is usually the leader of the opposition, currently Jeremy Corby, who calls for a vote of no confidence, in an attempt to topple the government. If more MPs vote for the motion than against it, then the government has 14 days to try to win back the confidence of MPs through another vote – while the opposition parties try to form an alternative government. If nothing is resolved, then a general election is triggered.
• A working majority in Parliament is what a government needs to carry out its legislative programme without risk of defeat. It means the government can rely on at least one more vote than the opposition parties. However, in the current Parliament, the government no longer has a majority and MPs from a range of opposition parties have joined forces to form a parliamentary majority big enough to defeat the government over plans for a no-deal Brexit.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-50236141</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Election results: Green Party's Caroline Lucas increases majority - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07xsthl.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Green Party's Caroline Lucas has been re-elected to her Brighton Pavilion seat with a greater majority.

The former party leader, who is its sole MP, defeated her closest Labour rival by almost 20,000 votes, increasing her majority by nearly 5%.

She gained 33,151 votes compared with 13,211 to Labour's candidate Adam Imanpour.

Ms Lucas said she was &quot;incredibly proud&quot; of the result but also &quot;deeply angry&quot; at a &quot;broken&quot; political system.

She said: &quot;I feel incredibly proud that my majority has increased because it demonstrates that Brighton Pavilion continues to believe in compassion, justice and a bigger future.

&quot;That matters so much when the status quo in this country is intolerable - and when we are now on course for it to become even more so.

&quot;As well as proud I feel deeply angry, too, that our political system is so badly broken and is still letting individuals and our country down so badly. It has been doing so for decades.

&quot;It has locked out millions and ignored their voices for years. And it's our children and the climate that will pay the highest price of all.

&quot;This may well have been a Brexit election but it was also the climate election and I am determined to make this the climate parliament.&quot;
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics

The Green Party joined the Liberal Democrats and Plaid Cymru in an electoral pact last month, which saw candidates stepping down in certain areas in order to bolster the chances of a Remain-backing candidate being elected.

The Green Party has been highly critical of the First Past the Post (FPTP) majority electoral system, whereby it is not the number of votes that matters, but the number of MPs chosen to sit in Parliament.

Ms Lucas said in a video posted on Twitter on Friday that the electoral system is &quot;rotten to the core&quot;.

&quot;These are dark times but the night is always darkest just before the dawn,&quot; Ms Lucas said.

&quot;This election has been called historic for many reasons already but we're making history all the time.

&quot;The distress, anger and sadness millions of us feel this morning about the future could be the catalyst for transforming our politics for good, forever and that's how we make this election the start of something truly historic.&quot;

She stressed the importance of taking action on climate change over the next 18 months, but raised concerns that the UK government will continue to &quot;wrangle&quot; over Brexit instead.

Jonathan Bartley, Green Party co-leader, said: &quot;We are so proud of everything that Caroline has achieved in Parliament over the last nine years. She will now continue to lead the fight against climate chaos.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50774493</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Election results 2019: Brexit Party 'killed Lib Dems and hurt Labour' - Farage - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07xswxj.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Brexit Party has &quot;killed the Liberal Democrats and hurt the Labour Party&quot;, Nigel Farage has claimed.

The Conservatives won 365 seats in the 2019 general election - up 47 from before the vote.

Labour won 203 seats (down 59), the SNP 48 (up 13) and the Lib Dems 11 (down by one). The Brexit Party did not win any.

But Mr Farage said the party took thousands of votes from Tory opponents and he was happy with its &quot;influence&quot;.

Speaking to the BBC after the announcement of the exit poll results, he said the Conservatives would win or come close in dozens of seats where they otherwise would not have done without the Brexit Party's help.

He added: &quot;I killed the Liberal Democrats and I hurt the Labour Party.&quot;

He said the party had killed off hopes of another referendum.

Meanwhile, Brexit Party chairman Richard Tice failed in his bid to win the constituency of Hartlepool.

MEP Mr Tice received 10,603 votes - around a thousand fewer than the Conservative candidate and nearly 5,000 fewer than Labour's Mike Hill, who won the seat.

If you cannot see the lookup tool, click here.

The election delivered a Commons majority of 80 for Prime Minister Boris Johnson.

Mr Farage claimed that Tory majority would not exist if his party had not withdrawn from fielding candidates in 317 Conservative-held seats.

&quot;I can tell you that if we had stood in every seat in the country it would have been a hung Parliament,&quot; he said. &quot;That would have been a disaster.&quot;
• Live: All the latest as results come in around the country
• Let the healing begin, urges PM after poll win
• Corbyn: ‘I did everything I could'
• Sturgeon: PM has 'no right' to block Indyref2

He added: &quot;I was determined, in this election, we would use our influence to stop a second referendum. That overwhelmingly was behind our decision to stand down in 317 seats.

&quot;Jo Swinson herself said that effectively poleaxed her campaign. And then taking the fight to Labour was important.

He added: &quot;Would I like to have won a few seats? Yes of course.&quot;

Born out of frustration with delays to the UK's departure from the EU, the Brexit Party was launched in April 2019, with ex-UKIP leader Mr Farage leading it.

When asked if the Brexit Party was now &quot;finished&quot;, Mr Farage said: &quot;We've used our influence, that's the important thing. If we get Brexit... we've done a good job.&quot;
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics

Arron Banks, who campaigned to leave the European Union alongside Mr Farage, said the exit poll suggested a &quot;brilliant victory&quot; for Boris Johnson, who now had a &quot;strong majority&quot; to negotiate a free trade deal with the EU.

He added that while the Brexit Party was now &quot;over&quot;, the &quot;pressure&quot; applied to the Tories had helped return them to their &quot;roots&quot;.

&quot;We set out to make the Conservative Party conservative again - and it's job done,&quot; he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50766123</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Former Black Rod says ex-speaker unfit for Lords - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/A331/production/_110777714_p082bgyj.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>David Leakey says John Bercow's &quot;explosive behaviour&quot; makes him unfit for the House of Lords.

He says he spoke out against Mr Bercow on behalf of colleagues, and is doing so again now because Mr Bercow has been nominated for a peerage by Jeremy Corbyn.

John Bercow says David Leakey's allegations are &quot;total and utter rubbish&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51386674</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Election results: Who are the major political casualties? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/132F6/production/_110128587_reuters-pa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Predictions for major scalps this year ranged from the foreign secretary to the prime minister. But in the event, who are the high profile politicians to lose out in the 2019 general election?

Jo Swinson, who began the campaign saying she was standing to be PM, was emotional as she thanked her family for their support after losing her Dunbartonshire East seat by just 149 votes.

Following the defeat by the Scottish National Party's Amy Callaghan, Ms Swinson said: &quot;Some will be celebrating the wave of nationalism that is sweeping on both sides of the borders.

&quot;But let me say now, for millions of people in our country these results will bring dread and dismay.

&quot;I still believe that we as a country can be warm and generous inclusive and open and that by working together with our nearest neighbours we can achieve so much more.&quot;

The 39-year-old was first elected as an MP in 2005. She held on to her seat until 2015, when she lost out to the SNP's John Nicolson.

The seat exchanged hands once again in 2017 when she beat Mr Nicolson. She became leader of the Liberal Democrats in July 2019.

Former Conservative Dominic Grieve, who fought many battles against Brexit in the House of Commons, was among those to lose his seat.

He was once the party's attorney general but was kicked out by Boris Johnson earlier this year after he backed a bill to try to stop a no-deal Brexit.

Mr Grieve ran as an independent for his seat of Beaconsfield and won the support of more than 16,000 voters.

But he was beaten by the new Tory candidate Joy Morrissey, who won with 32,477 votes.

If you cannot see the lookup tool, click here.

The Democratic Unionist Party's deputy leader since 2008, Nigel Dodds had been North Belfast MP since 2001, taking the seat from Ulster Unionist Cecil Walker.

But in the early hours of Friday it was announced Mr Dodds had been defeated by Sinn Fein's John Finucane, who received 23,078 votes to Mr Dodds's 21,135.

Mr Finucane said the result showed North Belfast - which had always been a unionist seat - &quot;rejects Brexit&quot;.

Mr Dodds, who studied law at Cambridge University, was key in negotiations between his party and both Mr Johnson's and Theresa May's governments in the run up to agreeing a deal with the EU.

Conservative Zac Goldsmith lost his Richmond Park seat to the Liberal Democrats, in the pro-Remain party's first gain of the night.

Mr Goldsmith had expected to to struggle against the Lib Dems' Sarah Olney - who held the seat between a 2016 by-election and the 2017 general election.

And those fears were confirmed when it was announced Ms Olney, who beat Mr Goldsmith in 2016, had received 34,559 votes.

Mr Goldsmith, a now ex-minister at the Department for Environmental, Food and Rural Affairs, got 26,793 votes.

A former London mayoral candidate, he won the seat in the 2017 election by just 45 votes - a 0.1% majority.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• BREXIT: What happens now?

A number of commentators had called 32-year-old Laura Pidcock a future leader of the Labour Party.

But she lost her seat of Durham North West to the Conservatives.

In 2017, her majority was more than 8,000. But this time around, the Tory candidate, Richard Holden, won the vote by 1,144.

Ms Pidcock, who previously worked for campaign group Show Racism The Red Card, was recently tipped as a successor to deputy Labour leader Tom Watson and is a long-term ally to Jeremy Corbyn.

Her maiden speech criticising Commons traditions and hitting out at inequality was widely shared, while she has also spoken out about the environment - particularly since she became a mother in 2018.

David Gauke - justice secretary and work and pensions secretary in Mrs May's government - is another big name to lose his seat overnight.

He played a major role in both David Cameron and Mrs May's Conservative governments.

Like Mr Grieve, Mr Gauke was kicked out by Mr Johnson for trying to stop a no-deal Brexit in the Commons earlier this year.

He ran as an independent in his seat of Hertfordshire South West and gained a lot of praise for his amusing Twitter videos throughout the campaign.

However, it wasn't enough, and while he secured almost 16,000 votes, his Tory successor, Gagan Mohindra, took more than 30,000.

Veteran Labour MP Dennis Skinner lost the seat of Bolsover to the Conservatives - with a swing of 11.5% away from Labour.

Mr Skinner had held the Derbyshire constituency since 1970.

Following Ken Clarke's decision to step down as an MP at this election, Mr Skinner was in line to become the Father of the House - but that mantle now falls to Tory MP Peter Bottomley.

Former Conservative MP Anna Soubry, now leader of the Independent Group for Change, lost her Broxtowe seat in Nottinghamshire. She mustered only 4,668 votes and did not come close to challenging her Conservative successor, Darren Henry.

Ex-Labour shadow cabinet minister Chuka Umunna, who was standing for the Lib Dems in the Cities of London and Westminster seat (where Boris Johnson cast his vote) also lost. He had been an MP since 2010.

Luciana Berger took a similar pre-election path to Mr Umunna - quitting Labour, joining the Independent Group for Change, before joining the Lib Dems. However, the Conservative's Mike Freer defeated her in Finchley and Golders Green.

Elsewhere, former Labour minister Caroline Flint was defeated by the Conservative's Nick Fletcher in Don Valley, South Yorkshire, a seat Ms Flint held since 1997.

And Anne Milton - one of the 11 Tory MPs who had the Tory whip withdrawn by Boris Johnson and never returned - also lost. The defeat came just days after her daughter Nikki Henderson helped environmental campaigner Greta Thunberg sail across the Atlantic for the COP25 summit in Madrid.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50768964</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: Hart gets Welsh post in government reshuffle - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/7D27/production/_110193023_mediaitem110193022.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Boris Johnson is carrying out a limited reshuffle of his government after urging newly elected Tory MPs to &quot;change our country for the better&quot;.

Simon Hart has been named as Welsh secretary, replacing Alun Cairns, who quit at the start of the election.

And Nicky Morgan stays as culture secretary, despite standing down as an MP. She is taking a peerage and will sit as a cabinet minister in the Lords.

Opposition parties said she had been &quot;rewarded for political sycophancy&quot;.

But Ms Morgan, who will be in charge of broadband and media policy, suggested she might only be in the role for a few weeks - pending what are expected to be far-reaching changes to the PM's top team after the UK has left the EU on 31 January.

Most cabinet ministers - including Chancellor Sajid Javid, Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab and Home Secretary Priti Patel - are staying put following the Conservatives' election victory. They have only been in post since July, when Mr Johnson became PM.
• What the election fall-out means for the BBC
• All you need to know about the UK leaving the EU
• Could the UK and EU sort a trade deal in months?
• What does 'Get Brexit done' mean?

There has been unconfirmed speculation that the PM is contemplating a much bigger shake-up in February, including changes to a number of departments, including the Department for Exiting the European Union, the Home Office and Department for International Development.

Ms Morgan took many by surprise when she announced that she would not be standing as MP for Loughborough at the election.

However, the former education secretary - who cited the abuse that female MPs had received as one of the reasons for her standing down - was one of Mr Johnson's most visible backers during the campaign, prompting speculation she intended to remain in public life.

And the news that she has accepted a life peerage and will remain in cabinet has attracted criticism.

Liberal Democrat culture spokeswoman Layla Moran said only an elected Upper Chamber would stop &quot;this kind of sycophancy being rewarded&quot; while Labour's Jo Stevens said the appointment was &quot;absolutely disgraceful&quot;.

While it is rare for cabinet ministers in charge of government departments not to be in the elected Commons, both the transport and business briefs were held by peers in the last Labour government.

The choice of Simon Hart as Welsh secretary marks a big promotion for the 56-year old MP, who was previously a junior Cabinet Office minister.

Reacting to his appointment, Mr Hart said: &quot;It's great to have this opportunity. I've got my orders and I'm going to try and do it as best I can.&quot;

The Welsh post has been vacant since early last month, when Alun Cairns quit over claims he knew about a former aide's role in the &quot;sabotage&quot; of a rape trial.

Mr Hart and Ms Morgan both backed Remain in the 2016 referendum but have been strong supporters of the PM's Brexit deal.

Mr Johnson has been getting down to business following last week's election victory, speaking to foreign leaders, including US President Donald Trump, and addressing all Conservative MPs at a private meeting in Parliament.

Earlier, he hailed the &quot;incredible achievement&quot; of the 109 Tory MPs elected for the first time last week, including many representing areas that had previously been die-hard Labour territory.

&quot;You've come from places that the Conservative Party have not been represented for a hundred years, if ever,&quot; he said at a photo call in the Palace of Westminster. &quot;That's a fantastic tribute to you.

&quot;But it also shows what we've got to do now because you have not only changed the political map of this country but you've changed our party for the better. What I want to do now is work with you to change our whole country for the better and that is what we're going to do.&quot;
• SCROLL AND SEE: The results that sealed it
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics
• BREXIT: What happens now?
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result

Downing Street has said the government plans to ask the new Parliament to have its first debate and vote on the PM's withdrawal agreement - the legislation needed to ratify Brexit - on Friday.

A spokesman said it planned to start the process of getting the Withdrawal Agreement Bill through Parliament in the &quot;proper constitutional way&quot;.

With a Commons majority of 80, the PM is expected to get the bill into law with few changes in time for the UK to leave the EU on 31 January.

Before that, the PM will set out his legislative plans for the year ahead in a Queen's Speech on Thursday.

What will happen this week?

Proceedings begin when MPs gather for their first duty: to elect the Speaker, Sir Lindsay Hoyle, who replaced John Bercow in November. Technically, MPs can hold a vote on this motion but this has never happened in practice.

Later in the day, the Speaker will begin the process of swearing in MPs, who are required to take an oath of allegiance to the Crown, or, if they object to this, a solemn affirmation. Those who speak or vote without having done so are deprived of their seat &quot;as if they were dead&quot; under the Parliamentary Oaths Act of 1866.

Two to three days are usually set aside for this process.

The state opening of Parliament. The Queen's Speech is the centrepiece of this, when she will read a speech written by ministers setting out the government's programme of legislation for the parliamentary session. A couple of hours after the speech is delivered, MPs will begin debating its contents - a process which usually takes days.

Depending on how rapidly Boris Johnson wants to move, the debate on the Queen's Speech could continue into Friday.

The government will introduce the Withdrawal Agreement Bill - the legislation that will implement Brexit - to Parliament.

MPs in the previous Parliament backed Mr Johnson's bill at its first stage but rejected his plan to fast-track the legislation through Parliament in three days in order to leave the EU by the then Brexit deadline of 31 October.

After the debate on the Queen's Speech is concluded, MPs will vote on whether to approve it. Not since 1924 has a government's Queen Speech been defeated.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50816908</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>General Election 2019: What's behind the Conservative victory? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11168/production/_110129996_ballot_box_crop.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Boris Johnson has won a decisive majority, on the back of a big swing from Labour to the Conservatives in Leave-voting Britain.

Yet north of the border the SNP dramatically almost swept the board.

With all results now declared, the prime minister has won a majority of 80 seats - the biggest Tory majority since 1987.

Meanwhile, at 44%, the party's share of the vote is set to be at its highest since 1979, when Margaret Thatcher became prime minister.

Labour, in contrast, finds itself with little more than 200 seats, even fewer than the party won in its previous worst post-war result in 1983.

The difference between Leave and Remain seats

However, the swing in the Tories' favour varied dramatically across the country.

In those seats where more than 60% of voters backed Leave in the 2016 EU referendum, the increase in Conservative support on average was 6%.

However, in those seats where more than 60% voted Remain, the party's vote actually fell by three points.

In contrast, Labour's vote fell on average by more than 10 points in the most pro-Leave areas.

Its vote fell by more than six points in the most pro-Remain ones.

This pattern had a clear impact on the geography of the election.

Support for the Conservatives rose by four points in the Midlands, the North East and Yorkshire - the regions of England that voted most heavily in favour of Leave.

In contrast, the party's vote fell back by a point in London and the South East.

And in Scotland, the party's vote fell by as much as four points.

Conversely, Labour saw its vote fall by 12 to 13 points in the North East and Yorkshire, while it fell by only six or seven points in London and the South of England.

The result also saw Labour lose ground heavily in its traditional working-class heartlands.

Support for the party fell by 11 points in those constituencies with most voters in working-class jobs.

Its share of the vote fell by only seven points in those with most middle-class voters.

The bond between Labour and its traditional working-class base is now badly strained.

In the EU referendum working-class voters voted heavily to leave the EU. These voters had already swung quite strongly to the Conservatives in 2017.

Labour tried to retain their support - remaining ambiguous about whether it was a pro-Remain or a pro-Leave party.

But this election simply saw the pro-Conservative trend continue yet further.

As a result, Labour dramatically lost many a seat in the North of England and the Midlands - places such as Ashfield, Bishop Auckland, and Workington - that had never previously elected a Conservative MP in a general election.

The success of the Conservatives in England and Wales was matched by that of the SNP in Scotland.

The party has won 48 of the 59 seats north of the border, and 45% of the vote across Scotland as a whole.

It is a result almost as good as the party's historic performance in the 2015 election.

And, in a country that voted in favour of Remain, it is likely to embolden the SNP in its pursuit of a second independence referendum.

That is a ballot to which the Conservatives are strongly opposed. So, a constitutional clash between the Scottish and UK governments seems likely.

One of the SNP's biggest scalps was the Dunbartonshire East seat of Liberal Democrat leader Jo Swinson - a defeat that capped a miserable night for the Liberal Democrats.

Despite advancing more strongly in pro-Remain areas, the party seems likely to end up with only 11 or 12 seats.

This will be no more than the number they won in 2017, even though their share of the vote is up by four points.

None of the many MPs who defected to the party during the last Parliament have been able to retain their seats.
• Five things to watch for in the election
• Is Brexit the most important issue for voters?
• Do people still vote according to class?
• The issues voters care about most

The announcement of the election was greeted with concern about the level of turnout, for a ballot held just a fortnight before Christmas.

In the event, about 67% of voters made it to the polls - just two points down on 2017.

Turnout fell most markedly in seats where Labour are relatively strong, suggesting that some of those who usually support the party opted to stay at home.

The Conservatives' success means that Britain will now leave the EU at the end of January.

However, it seems unlikely to end the debate about Britain's relationship with the EU.

The country's divisions over Brexit were exposed in the very different swings across the country.

Meanwhile, at 47%, fewer than half of voters backed the Conservatives or the Brexit Party - the parties in favour of leaving the EU without another referendum.

This is a point to which opponents of Brexit are likely to point in the weeks and months to come.

But for now at least, the day clearly belongs to Mr Johnson.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics
• BREXIT: What happens now?

This analysis piece was commissioned by the BBC from an expert working for an outside organisation.

Sir John Curtice is professor of politics, Strathclyde University, and senior research fellow at NatCen Social Research and The UK in a Changing Europe.

He worked on this piece with: Professor Stephen Fisher, Oxford University; Professor Rob Ford, University of Manchester; Professor Jouni Kuha, London School of Economics; Jon Mellon, University of Manchester; and Patrick English, University of Exeter.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50774061</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>Northern Ireland election results: DUP suffers losses - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07xqs7l.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Democratic Unionist Party (DUP) suffered a bruising night of general election results, losing two MPs including its Westminster leader.

Nigel Dodds lost his North Belfast seat to Sinn Féin's John Finucane while Emma Little-Pengelly was defeated by Claire Hanna of the SDLP in South Belfast.

SDLP party leader Colum Eastwood won Foyle with a thumping majority, while the Alliance Party took North Down.

A total of 803,367 votes were cast in Northern Ireland - a turnout of 62.09%.

The DUP and Sinn Féin both saw their share of the vote drop significantly compared with the 2017 general election - by 5.4% and 6.7% respectively.

The cross-community Alliance Party is set to come third in terms of vote share, with about 17%.

Its deputy leader Stephen Farry won North Down, the first result declared in Northern Ireland.

In Fermanagh and South Tyrone, Michelle Gildernew of Sinn Féin retained her seat after a recount, holding off Tom Elliott of the Ulster Unionist Party (UUP) by just 57 votes.

The graph below shows the vote share change in North Belfast. If you can't see it click here.

Mr Dodds' defeat in North Belfast, a seat he had held since 2001, was symbolic of a torrid election for the DUP.

The party's deputy leader - a high-profile supporter of Brexit - will not be returning to Westminster.

The DUP also had high hopes of winning North Down for the first time but the constituency elected its first ever non-unionist MP with Mr Farry's victory for Alliance.

He defeated Alex Easton of the DUP by just under 3,000 votes.

Later, Ms Little-Pengelly's loss to the SDLP in South Belfast capped a disappointing night for the party.

She had won the seat from the SDLP two years ago by 1,996 votes but Ms Hanna took it off her this time with a big swing and a majority of 15,401.

The DUP propped up a minority Conservative government after the 2017 general election but has not been rewarded by voters.

DUP leader Arlene Foster said Mr Dodds' defeat was down to a &quot;pan-nationalist front&quot; after the SDLP opted to stand aside in the constituency.

It was noticeable that the DUP MPs who retained their seats used their victory speeches to urge the return of power-sharing in Northern Ireland.

After the last general election the DUP and Sinn Féin were riding respective waves of success at Westminster and felt no need to go back to Stormont.

Two and a half years on, with devolution still not back in place, perhaps some voters used their ballot to punish the big two parties this time.

Another round of talks aimed at kick-starting Stormont is due to begin shortly - the government has insisted a new Northern Ireland Assembly election will be called if that fails.

Given the latest results the DUP and Sinn Féin might not be keen on facing the wrath of some voters at the ballot box again so soon.

Read more from Jayne: 'Some bruising defeats for DUP and Sinn Féin'

There was better news for the DUP in East Antrim, East Belfast, East Londonderry, Lagan Valley, South Antrim and Strangford where its candidates were all re-elected.

In Upper Bann Carla Lockhart won, retaining the seat for the DUP after its previous MP David Simpson stepped down.

Ian Paisley won in North Antrim but saw his majority cut from 20,643 to 12,000.

Mr Finucane's victory was a high point for the party - he secured a majority of 1,943 votes and it is the first time a nationalist has ever held the constituency - but it was a mixed picture elsewhere.

The SDLP won Foyle, which it lost to Sinn Féin in 2017, with a huge majority while Sinn Féin's majorities in South Down and West Belfast were cut.

Órfhlaith Begley and Francie Molloy were re-elected for Sinn Féin in West Tyrone and Mid Ulster respectively and their party colleague Mickey Brady held Newry and Armagh.

Sinn Féin president Mary Lou McDonald said she was confident her party would compete to win Foyle in the future.

Mr Finucane is Lord Mayor of Belfast and his father Pat was a solicitor who was murdered by loyalist paramilitaries in 1989.

He said: &quot;We have taken the opportunity to say North Belfast rejects Brexit, North Belfast is a remain constituency and wants a future as part of the European Union.&quot;

The Alliance Party had a strong performance this year in the council elections in Northern Ireland and then at the European Parliamentary elections when it won a seat for the first time.

The party last won a Westminster seat in 2010 before losing it five years later but it will once again have representation in the House of Commons after Mr Farry's victory.

He won 18,358 votes to Mr Easton's 15,390 to take the seat formerly held by independent MP Lady Hermon.

North Down was represented by Lady Hermon from 2001 until she stepped down this year.

In his victory speech, Mr Farry said &quot;voters had sent out a clear message that North Down wanted to remain [in the EU]&quot;.

He said there was no such thing as a good or sensible Brexit and that &quot;all forms of Brexit are damaging for Britain&quot;.

The party came second in the DUP safe seat of Lagan Valley.

Sorcha Eastwood won 13,087 votes, slashing Sir Jeffrey Donaldson's majority from 19,229 to just over 6,000.

You can use the feature below to search for your constituency and see results. If you can't see it click here.

The SDLP went into the night hopeful of taking South Belfast and Foyle but the scale of their victories in those seats was unexpected.

In Foyle, the seat once held by Nobel Peace Prize winner John Hume, Mr Eastwood won by 17,000 votes.

The graph below shows the vote share change in Foyle. If you can't see it click here.

Sinn Féin won the seat two years ago but the party's vote halved from 18,256 to 9,771 this time.

Mr Eastwood said Foyle voters had returned &quot;someone to go to Westminster to fight your case and to stand up to Boris Johnson&quot;.

In South Belfast Ms Hanna overturned a DUP majority of 1,996 to win by more than 15,000 votes.

With one constituency left to declare, the Conservative Party has secured a majority of 78 at Westminster.

As a result the party will not require the DUP to help it achieve a working majority as it did in 2017.

But the DUP's Brexit spokesman Sammy Wilson said as Prime Minister Boris Johnson sought a trade deal with the EU there would still be opportunities to influence proceedings.

Sinn Féin's Alex Maskey said the result would take the &quot;dead hand&quot; of the Tory-DUP relationship away from the political process in Northern Ireland.

He predicted it would make it more likely that the DUP would do a deal with his party to restore devolved government.

The power-sharing executive at Stormont collapsed in January 2017 after a bitter row between the DUP and Sinn Féin over a flawed green energy scheme.

New talks aimed at restoring the executive are due to start on Monday.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50766004</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: What happens after the results? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/C658/production/_110067705_ukparliament_jessicataylor.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Getting elected is only the beginning.

The victors will be exhausted, but they will need to hit the ground running in Westminster, with a Queen's Speech expected within days - if a majority government is elected - and possibly a debate on the key Brexit legislation, the Withdrawal Agreement Bill, before Christmas.

And all that will happen alongside the boring administrative grind of getting the Commons up and running, as well as their own political operations.

How will it unfold? Here's a possible timeline:

The winning candidate gets given a personal &quot;welcome letter&quot; by the returning officer from the clerk of the Commons, setting out the arrangements for them to take up their role as an MP.

This covers things like the reception area that will be set up for new MPs, a &quot;buddy&quot; system giving each new member a named official who will be their first point of contact, and details about issues such as IT access and photo passes.

Commons officials will be working through the weekend to get the newcomers started, and the arrangements will include a room set aside for new members' children, complete with Lego.

Most MPs will have temporary office arrangements for quite a while, as the delicate process of allocating offices unfolds. The process is so politically sensitive that it is left entirely in the hands of the whips - the Commons administrators have never wanted to have anything to do with the actual decisions.

Top cabinet ministers are billeted in the Victorian Palace of Westminster, behind the Speaker's chair; lesser ministers get some rather unattractive basement digs, on the basis that they won't be using them much.

When the shadow cabinet is announced, its members will get offices a little further away. But for the rest, the Commons office buildings have a pecking order set in concrete, with senior ex-ministers and similar grandees enjoying corner offices with sweeping views of the Thames or Parliament Square and rapid access to the chamber. Lowly newcomers find themselves in converted broom cupboards in distant corners of the Parliamentary Estate.

In this most status-conscious of environments, working out who gets what and placating the egos involved can take quite a while.

Just about the only person outside government who can be sure of an office is the Leader of the Opposition, who traditionally gets an office suite in the Norman Shaw South building.

The SNP (in a clear demonstration that the whips who order these things have a mordent sense of humour) were mostly located in a distant building on Parliament Street, which requires Olympic-level sprinting abilities to reach the voting lobbies when the division bell sounds.

MPs gather for their first duty: to elect a Speaker.

Black Rod summons MPs to the Lords, where the commissioners (senior peers representing the Queen) direct MPs to return to their chamber and hold the election.

Then the Father of the House presides, while MPs debate the motion &quot;that the Right Honourable Sir Lindsay Hoyle do take the Chair of this House as Speaker&quot;. The motion is divisible, which is to say it can be voted on, but there has never been a vote. This is the only issue on which MPs can speak or vote before taking the oath.
• Sir John Curtice: Why age not class matters most
• Six foreign policy issues the UK's new PM will face

Having been re-elected, the Speaker then goes to the Queen to seek the confirmation of the Commons' &quot;undoubted rights&quot;: freedom of speech, favourable construction (that is, the Queen must always take the actions of the House in good spirit) and direct access (the right to send an humble address).

This confirms the privileges of Parliament that are formalised in Article IX of the 1688 Bill of Rights, so it's a ritual with deep historical roots. Thus confirmed, the Speaker can begin swearing in MPs.

The names of the MPs duly elected are returned to the clerk of the Crown in Chancery (Sir Richard Heaton) to be entered into the white book, the authoritative list which identifies those entitled to take their seats in the Commons.

The white book is delivered to the Commons by Sir Richard in person - he will come to the Bar of the House, the entrance to the Commons chamber, and hand it to the clerk assistant, the second-most senior Commons clerk.

The process of administering the oath to around 650 MPs then begins.

Normally they start with the most senior members - the cabinet and shadow cabinet - after which the oath is administered by intake, so the longest-serving go first, and the new arrivals last.

This can be rushed a bit if they want to get it all done in a day, but the alternative is that the timing becomes less clear, and some families and friends may not be in the gallery at the moment when someone swears in.

Keep an eye out for jockeying for position among the new intake - the order of swearing in may determine who is Father or Mother of the House in a few decades' time.

And it's worth remembering that MPs who speak or vote without having taken the oath are automatically deprived of their seat &quot;as if they were dead&quot; under the Parliamentary Oaths Act of 1866. There's an additional penalty of £500, which really was a penalty in 1866.

MPs can, of course, affirm rather than swear an oath to God on any of the selection of holy books held for the purpose in the Chamber.

This is the earliest possible day for a State Opening, when the new government will announce its programme of legislation for the coming year.

Inevitably the early months will be dominated by Brexit. And if the Conservatives get a majority - and depending on how rapidly the new government wants to move - that could mean the debate on a new Queen's speech continuing into Friday 20 December - perhaps with an interruption on the Friday, or even on Monday 23 December, for a second reading debate on the Withdrawal Agreement Bill.

The advantage of getting the second reading done before Christmas is that it would allow amendments for the committee stage to be drawn up over the Christmas and New Year break, which would hasten the moment when the Commons could sit as a &quot;committee of the whole House&quot; to consider the detail.

The House would also need to move rapidly to elect deputy speakers. There will probably be a short temporary fix to name a couple of acting deputies until the elected ones are in place, so the Speaker does not have to be in the chair for every minute of the sitting - this would probably be done on State Opening day.

Particularly important will be the senior deputy, the chairman of ways and means - the post just vacated by the new Speaker, Sir Lindsay Hoyle. The chairman of ways and means is in charge of selecting amendments for consideration in committee stage, when MPs look at the detail of a bill.

He or she will immediately face the crucial task of sifting through possibly hundreds of amendments that will be proposed for the Withdrawal Agreement Bill - and they can also expect to preside over a budget fairly early in the new year, thanks to the ancient rule that the Speaker does not chair budget debates.

One of the deputies will be Labour and one must be a woman. It has never yet happened, but it is possible that the gender rule could see a woman deputy being appointed ahead of a man who received more votes.

There will also be pressure to get select committee chairs elected and in place as rapidly as possible, to ensure that the government is properly scrutinised -but it may be a while before ministers are prepared to press the starting button.

The first step is to agree a carve-up between the parties to decide which party gets to provide chairs for which committees. The share-out will be broadly proportional to the make-up of the new Commons, but the key issue is the distribution of the plum committee posts.

Typically, a government party will wish to provide the chair of the Treasury Committee - arguably the single most important committee corridor job - but the distribution of home affairs, foreign affairs, defence, health, education and the rest will depend on the relative strength of the parties.

One complication is that a couple of senior figures (if re-elected on 12 December) may have reached the term limits which cap the number of parliaments in which someone can chair a committee. Sir Bill Cash (European scrutiny) Sir Bernard Jenkin (public administration and constitutional affairs) and David TC Davis (Welsh affairs) could fall foul of these rules- but there might be some negotiation, because the last two parliaments have been unusually short.

Of course all this depends on there being a clear winner of the election - failing that, we could well see the state opening postponed until January, while horses are traded and souls sold.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50718972</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>Will UK provide light bulb moment for US Democrats? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>US &amp; Canada</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/E69A/production/_110143095_gettyimages-1165233337.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>For the most part American politics exists in its own bubble with its own preoccupations. But every now and then something that happens in a foreign country intrudes. And pokes its nose in. Big time.

The 12 December 2019 UK General Election might be such a moment for the US Democratic Party - just as British politics imposed itself on the US presidential election on 23 June 2016, when the British people voted for Brexit. Coincidentally, Donald Trump arrived in Scotland the following day (not the day before as he has repeatedly claimed) and what the British people had just done was a galvanising moment in his campaign, a light bulb moment, as he prepared to face the American people five months later.

So what should Democrats learn from the misery that befell the Labour Party last Thursday night? And more particularly can they afford to have Bernie Sanders or Elizabeth Warren as their candidate and stand a chance of defeating Donald Trump in 2020 after the shellacking meted out to Jeremy Corbyn and his brand of radical, left-wing policies?

Let me start in Sedgefield in County Durham, an old mining constituency, whose pits closed in the 1970s and 1980s. It is a largely white, working class area. It has been rock-solid Labour since the dinosaurs roamed the Earth. It is not unlike any number of towns you could find in the Appalachians in Pennsylvania.

I've spent a bit of time there from when I was writing a long forgotten biography of Tony Blair in the mid-1990s through to when he became prime minister.

In the village of Trimdon is the Labour Club. The last time I was there, Tony Blair was pulling the winning numbers out in the raffle: main prize a turkey (plucked), second prize a pound of sausages. The people I met there were decent, hard-working, straight-talking - and small &quot;c&quot; conservative. They had chosen Tony Blair as their candidate for the 1983 election because he wasn't on the &quot;loony left&quot; wing of the party, as his election agent explained to me over a pint in the Dun Cow Inn in the constituency.

I reported from the nearby leisure centre in 2005 when Tony Blair won the seat for Labour with a huge majority, and won his third successive general election. The people of Sedgefield had delivered him a majority of over 18,000 and 58% of the vote. No-one else came close.

But last Thursday night incredibly, unbelievably, ground-shakingly, Sedgefield went Conservative. Sedgefield. Conservative. It is mind-boggling.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics
• BREXIT: What happens now?

Remember, when Blair won with that gargantuan majority in 2005 he was at the height of his unpopularity - or the nadir of his likeability (whichever way you want to put it). The controversial Iraq War had been two years earlier and there was a strong feeling that Britain had gone to war on a false prospectus. No weapons of mass destruction had been found, and - hugely uncomfortably for Blair - the father of a British soldier who had died in conflict there stood against the prime minister as an anti-war candidate.

Blair, by now, was no longer seen as the great hope, but as smarmy, President George W Bush's poodle, in the pocket of big business - and a war criminal. It was ugly. And yet he romped home on his &quot;third way&quot;, left of centre, progressive ticket. And he was returned as prime minister with a comfortable majority: a third successive election victory, a feat that no other Labour politician in history had achieved.

But the policies of Labour in the 2019 election are very different from what they were in 2005 when Tony Blair and the so-called &quot;modernisers&quot; held sway. Labour last Thursday went into the election with an unashamedly socialist set of policies, promising a massive increase in government spending, and big tax increases for the well-off. Nationalisation of some industries was back on the agenda. There would be massive increase in spending for the National Health Service - and an offer of free broadband for everyone. Why no offer of free puppies for all, one wag asked derisively.

The problem is that the pragmatic, working-class people of Sedgefield - and any number of other constituencies across the industrial towns and cities of the UK - held their collective noses and said you must be joking. These are smart, savvy people. They know that you don't get something for nothing.

Electoral districts that all my life have been Labour - Blyth Valley, Bolsover, Rother Valley, Newcastle-under-Lyme, Dudley, Grimsby - are now held by the Conservatives. It is hard to overstate just how seismic this is. And remember social class in the UK has always been a bigger determinant of how people vote than it has been in the US. Just like the whole class system, frankly. Some of these constituencies have never, ever flirted with the right.

Of course, there is a massive caveat that makes reading across from what happened in the UK to what might happen in the US precarious. Brexit, no deal, the European Union Withdrawal Agreement will not be on the ballot in the 2020 US presidential election. Brexit did play a big part in this general election - how could it not given the turmoil in Britain of these past three-and-a-half years?

But as Phil Wilson, the man who succeeded Tony Blair as the Labour MP in Sedgefield - and who lost his seat on Thursday night - pointed out, Brexit was nothing like as big an issue on the doorstep as Jeremy Corbyn and Labour's socialist policies.

Democrats would be wise to dig deeper into the reasons for such wholesale rejection of the UK Labour Party. If you are plotting a path to victory in 2020 that takes you through Pennsylvania, Michigan and Wisconsin - the three states that the Democrats lost in 2016 by a teeny, weeny number of votes and that guaranteed Donald Trump victory - then there are many similarities between these states and the industrial heartlands that Labour have just lost.

Michigan's Democrats swept the board in the midterms in 2018, and the newly-elected Governor, Gretchen Whitmer, is admirably straightforward about why they were able to turn around the fortunes of the Democratic Party after the shock of 2016. They didn't promise the earth, they promised to fix the roads. Kitchen table issues.

But among the radical/socialist/progressive/liberal (choose your epithet) wing of the Democratic Party there is an ambition, a hunger for earth-shaking pledges. The bold Green New Deal, Medicare for all (which to those of us who are European may not seem such a giant leap) - these are big ticket policy ambitions with even greater price tags attached.

But will they fly in a country where the centre of political gravity is much further to the right than it is in the UK? Promising bigger government and higher taxes may not be impossible. But it's not going to be an easy sell.

I saw two sets of statistics that really struck me. In last Thursday's election, it seems 58% of 18-24 year-olds voted Labour. Only 16% of those over 60, it's estimated, voted Labour. Similarly, the percentage of Democrats under 30 and qualified to vote in the primaries who are backing either Bernie Sanders or Elizabeth Warren is massive. Something like 70%. Everyone else in the field is an also ran. But look at any statistics on election turnout, and you will see it is those infuriating oldies who vote in the highest numbers.

And to Democrats in the US who look at their Twitter feeds and see the &quot;likes&quot; and retweets mounting up as they advance this or that position, let the 2019 UK election be a warning to you.

For some Labour activists the result of the election seems to have come as a massive shock, because in the echo chamber world that we all now to a greater or lesser extent live in, you come away with the impression that everyone thinks like you. Twitter is not the real world. Nowhere near.

In the 1980s and 1990s when protestors would take to the streets of London over the Poll Tax or the siting of American cruise missiles at Greenham Common or more recently the Iraq War, and most recently the huge protest marches backing Remain, the participants would often claim that because so many people had come out onto the streets this was the view of the British people. But for the million who may have protested (still a huge number), there were 59 million who had stayed at home.

American Democrats need to be mindful of this. People like Congresswoman Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez may be a social media genius (and she is), and she may have a massive number of followers (and she has), and be charismatic (and she has that by the bucketload) - but America is a big country with an awful lot of voters who are not signed up to all the &quot;woke&quot; things she and others might be advocating.

The best voice on this is from a pre-tweeting, pre-electronic media, pre-opinion poll age - and it is from the 18th-Century Anglo-Irish philosopher, Edmund Burke. He wrote:

&quot;Because half a dozen grasshoppers under a fern make the field ring with their importunate chink, whilst thousands of great cattle, reposed beneath the shadow of the British oak, chew the cud and are silent, pray do not imagine that those who make the noise are the only inhabitants of the field.&quot;

Labour in the UK lost the working class, but gained the woke. And that will give the party sleepless nights over the coming months and years. It was their worst defeat since 1935.

I watched the UK election on Thursday night from the British Embassy in Washington, where the toast of Washington society met and mingled as the results came through. A smart friend of mine had to leave early to go to another event. She contacted me the next day to say that she went to a dinner and was seated next to a Democrat senator.

As she sat down he leaned over to her and said &quot;Are you following what's going on in Britain? Labour getting clobbered? We Dems in the US had better pay close attention.&quot;

Who will take on Trump in 2020?
• Find out who else is running and who might join them</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-50785442</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-24</ID>
      <TITLE>General Election 2019: How computers wrote BBC election result stories - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/17221/production/_110135749_mediaitem110135745.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>For the first time, BBC News published a news story for every constituency that declared election results overnight - all written by a computer.

It was the BBC's biggest test of machine-generated journalism so far.

Each of nearly 700 articles - most in English but 40 of them in Welsh - was checked by a human editor before publication.

The head of the project said the tech was designed to enhance the service provided rather than to replace humans.

&quot;This is about doing journalism that we cannot do with human beings at the moment,&quot; said Robert McKenzie, editor of BBC News Labs.

&quot;Using machine assistance, we generated a story for every single constituency that declared last night with the exception of the one that hasn't finished counting yet. That would never have been possible [using humans].&quot;

Several news organisations are testing automated journalism as a way of covering data-driven stories more efficiently.

The technology can quickly produce stories focused on numbers, such as football scores, company financial reports - and general election results.
• Check any constituency to see the machine-generated article

Overnight, the BBC generated 649 news articles in English - one constituency has yet to declare its results - and 40 in Welsh.

Florence Eshalomi has been elected MP for Vauxhall, meaning that the Labour Party holds the seat with a decreased majority.

The new MP beat Liberal Democrat Sarah Lewis by 19,612 votes. This was fewer than Kate Hoey's 20,250-vote majority in the 2017 general election.

Sarah Bool of the Conservative Party came third and the Green Party's Jacqueline Bond came fourth.

Voter turnout was down by 3.5 percentage points since the last general election.

More than 56,000 people, 63.5% of those eligible to vote, went to polling stations across the area on Thursday, in the first December general election since 1923.

Three of the six candidates, Jacqueline Bond (Green), Andrew McGuinness (The Brexit Party) and Salah Faissal (independent) lost their £500 deposits after failing to win 5% of the vote.

This story about Vauxhall was created using some automation.

Mr McKenzie said the articles reflected a &quot;BBC style&quot; because the choice of phrases could be programmed in advance by BBC writers.

&quot;As a journalist, you try to think of every conceivable permutation of a story in advance,&quot; he said.

&quot;Then you write a template. The machine selects particular phrases or particular words in response to precise pieces of data. So you can write everything if you want to, in 'house style'.&quot;

Journalists at BBC offices in Belfast, Cardiff, Glasgow and London checked the articles before publication.

Mr McKenzie said one limitation of the system was that it could not add analysis to articles.

So, in a small number of significant seats such as the Kensington constituency, human journalists added additional context.

&quot;This clearly only works on stories that are grounded in data. It is not a technology that allows you to do any kind of analysis,&quot; said Mr McKenzie.

&quot;None of the stories have any quotations in, none of them have any analysis of what happened or what the significance is. It is purely a written version of what has happened based on the data. So that's quite a big downside in terms of quality of journalism.&quot;

The BBC has run several automated journalism experiments, generating dozens of localised stories about A&amp;E waiting times and publicly funded tree planting.

However, Mr McKenzie said the BBC was still in the &quot;very early stages of understanding what audiences want from the technology&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-50779761</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-25</ID>
      <TITLE>Election results 2019: Lib Dem leader Jo Swinson to step down - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07xstv5.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Jo Swinson will step down as Liberal Democrat leader after losing her seat to the SNP by 149 votes.

Ms Swinson, who started the campaign saying she could become the next prime minister, gained 19,523 votes compared with 19,672 for the SNP's Amy Callaghan in Dunbartonshire East.

Sir Ed Davey and Baroness Sal Brinton will be acting co-leaders for the party, now she is no longer an MP.

Ms Swinson said the election results would bring &quot;dismay&quot; for many.

She said she was &quot;proud that Liberal Democrats were the unapologetic voice of Remain&quot; in the election, adding that she did &quot;not regret trying everything&quot; to avoid Brexit.

Under party rules, the Lib Dem leader must have a seat in the Commons. A leadership contest will be held in the new year.
• Corbyn: I will not lead Labour at next election
• LIVE: Updates and reaction as results come in

With all seats now declared, the party has 11 seats, one fewer than at the 2017 election.

News of Ms Swinson's defeat was cheered by Nicola Sturgeon, who was caught on camera celebrating the SNP's victory in Dunbartonshire East.

The SNP leader, who was waiting to speak to Sky News when the election result was read out, could be seen cheering as she found out that Ms Callaghan had won the seat.

Ms Sturgeon later offered her commiserations to Ms Swinson on a personal level, but said she was delighted by the SNP's performance.

Baroness Brinton, president of the Liberal Democrats and the new co-leader, said it was a &quot;disappointing night&quot; for the party.

&quot;The voices of nationalism and populism both north and south of the border beat both her [Ms Swinson] in her seat and nationally as well.&quot;

She said there were some &quot;nuggets of gold&quot; the party could take from the election, such as increasing its share of the vote by 4.2% and getting &quot;some good new MPs&quot;.

&quot;All is not lost,&quot; she added, pledging that the party's MPs would &quot;continue to fight, if not for our place in Europe, then for the best deal possible&quot;.

Earlier, Baroness Brinton thanked Ms Swinson, who only became Lib Dem leader in July, for what she called her honest and fearless leadership of their party.

The Liberal Democrats entered this election buoyed by a revival in the polls and the addition to their ranks of numerous MPs who defected from other parties, including Chuka Umunna and Luciana Berger from Labour, and the former Tory minister Sam Gyimah.

All three, however, were defeated.

Earlier, Sir John Curtice, professor of politics at Strathclyde University, said the polls suggested the party's support declined during the election and indicated that the strongly anti-Brexit party did not make any progress at all among Leave voters.

On the night, the Conservatives won a big majority and the SNP took 48 of Scotland's 59 seats, as Labour suffered heavy losses.

One highlight for the Lib Dems was the party's candidate in Richmond Park, Sarah Olney, winning the seat from the Conservatives' Zac Goldsmith.
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• MAPS AND CHARTS: The election in graphics
• BREXIT: What happens now?

Speaking at the Bishopbriggs count outside Glasgow following her defeat, Ms Swinson said the results were &quot;very significant&quot; for the future of the country.

&quot;For millions of people in our country these results will bring dread and dismay and people are looking for hope.

&quot;I still believe we, as a country, can be warm and generous, inclusive and open and that by working together with our nearest neighbours we can achieve so much more.

&quot;Liberal Democrats will continue to stand up for these values that guide our Liberal movement - openness, fairness, inclusivity. We will stand up for hope.&quot;

The SNP's Ms Callaghan told BBC Scotland she was &quot;delighted&quot; to have unseated the Liberal Democrat leader.

The new MP said: &quot;It's quite a momentous achievement, both for me personally but also in terms of the people of East Dunbartonshire, completely rejecting the politics of austerity and also giving the people a chance to choose their own future - I think that is incredibly important.&quot;

Live: All the latest as results come in around the country

Ms Swinson became her party's first female leader in a landslide victory over Sir Ed Davey earlier this year, succeeding Sir Vince Cable.

She had served as a minister in the coalition government and was among the party's MPs who paid the price for the tie-up with David Cameron's Tories in the 2015 election - which saw the Lib Dems reduced to a rump of just eight in the Commons.

Ms Swinson fought back when then Prime Minister Theresa May called another election in 2017, and she regained her Scottish seat from the SNP.

She attracted criticism from some quarters for her policy to revoke Article 50 and cancel Brexit, and for her previous record in the coalition government.

The Lib Dems backed Boris Johnson's call in October for an early election, arguing it was the best way of stopping Brexit.

Mr Johnson focused relentlessly on a single message - &quot;get Brexit done&quot; - promising to take the UK out of the EU by 31 January 2020 if he got a majority.

If you cannot see the lookup tool, click here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50771123</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-26</ID>
      <TITLE>The nerves and excitement of an MP's first day - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Election 2019</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p07y5yln.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The first day of any new job leaves your stomach churning, even if you are ready and raring to go.

Throw in a bunch of cameras and an expectant public, and perhaps the pressure could be too much.

But not for the class of 2019 (not that they will let on anyway) - the 140 brand new MPs striding their way into Westminster.

MPs are spending the week picking up their passes, finding their offices, electing a new Speaker, and swearing in, ahead of the Christmas recess.

But how did they prepare? What are their hopes and fears? And who do they want to avoid in the corridors?
• Ten names to keep an eye on in Parliament
• Youngest MP had been looking for temp work
• What's it like to lose your seat as an MP?

The first seat to change hands on Thursday night was Blyth Valley, which saw the long-time Labour constituency turn blue.

Ian Levy was the man to take it for the Tories. His preparation for his journey from his north east constituency included going for a curry with his family - the Sunday Special at the Maharaj's Lounge to be precise.

But come Monday morning, tying up his shoelaces before heading out for the train, the nerves kicked in and he admitted he had butterflies in his stomach.

&quot;The whole thing is exciting, the whole day,&quot; he said. &quot;I'm most excited to meet the new MPs. Once I get in and see some familiar faces the butterflies will stop.&quot;

There will be a large number of Conservative colleagues to get to know - 365 in fact - but who is he looking forward to meeting the most?

&quot;Well, I already met Boris Johnson at the weekend when he came up,&quot; he said. &quot;But I'm looking forward to meeting him again and carrying on the work.

&quot;He told me he was overwhelmed we'd done so well.&quot;

While he is already planning his maiden speech in the Commons around the themes of crime and anti-social behaviour, he may have something more practical to sort out first.

&quot;I haven't started looking for somewhere to stay in London yet,&quot; he admitted.

'People notice when you get it wrong'

Fleur Anderson made the only gain of the night for Labour, taking the seat of Putney in west London.

She won't be facing a new house hunt, having lived in Wandsworth for 25 years, and instead will just need to &quot;recce the route&quot; so she can cycle into Westminster.

The former councillor has nerves too - but what about?

&quot;Doing the right thing,&quot; she said. &quot;There are lots and lots of rules and procedures to get your head around.

&quot;I am getting a lot of support from my Labour colleagues, but I have a very big book to read and people notice when you get these things wrong.&quot;

Fleur won't be drawn on who she can't wait to meet as she doesn't want to show favour, but she is worried about being &quot;star struck&quot;.

But having worked closely alongside fellow London Labour candidate Faiza Shaheen to unseat Iain Duncan Smith in Chingford and Woodford Green, she's not keen to meet the former Tory leader in Westminster's corridors.

&quot;I have already bumped into him and I am not at all happy about it,&quot; she said, thinking about what could have been. &quot;Seeing him here in the corridors is just depressing.&quot;

But at the top of her agenda is starting a Roehampton fan club.

&quot;People know Putney for the boat race and being leafy, but there is a wonderful community in the Roehampton council estate that gets ignored,&quot; she said.

&quot;I want it to be celebrated and people in the area to get what they need.&quot;

Amy Callaghan took a high profile scalp in the election, winning the seat held by the now former Lib Dem leader Jo Swinson.

She's got a long journey down from East Dunbartonshire on the train - four hours and 20 minutes - so what will she be doing on the commute?

&quot;Obviously I will have a lot of work to do and emails to reply to, but Netflix is top of my agenda as well,&quot; she said smiling.

&quot;I've almost run out of things to watch but I love podcasts too and there is a new true crime one based in Australia I want to listen to.&quot;

She has been in the Commons once before in her early twenties when campaigning for the Teenage Cancer Trust - Amy herself was diagnosed with skin cancer at 19 - but how did it feel to be back as an MP?

&quot;It is just surreal to be honest,&quot; she said. &quot;But I just want to hit the ground running.&quot;

A school in her constituency has been on the phone after the election; and she wants to concentrate on the NHS, and Scottish independence.

So, any other MPs outside of her party she is looking forward to meet or avoid?

&quot;There are none outside the SNP that I have admired from afar,&quot; she says, and with a smile adds: &quot;There are plenty I would want to dodge in the corridors, but I am not going to name names quite yet.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/election-2019-50811186</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-27</ID>
      <TITLE>General election 2019: What the Conservatives' win means for your money - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/137F7/production/_110136897_santahatonbeach.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>As the country contemplates the election results, people's thoughts will turn to the potential effect on their finances.

Money matters are often to the fore at this, expensive, time of year. The December election is likely to mean some changes to the pound in your pocket before the winter is out, with other changes more long-term.

Here are some of the key issues, based on the Conservative Party's manifesto, its plans before the campaign and its promises during it.

Those who are heading abroad for Christmas will see their holiday money go a little further.

The value of the pound improved against the US dollar and the euro when the Conservative victory became clear, and this will now have fed through to the rates at bureaux de change.

However, travelling overseas at this time of year can be very expensive, so this will only bring a little relief.
• Exchange rates: Why has the value of the pound jumped?

The big set-piece financial event of the year had been planned for November, but was postponed as the prime minister pushed for an election.

During the campaign, Boris Johnson promised a Budget within 100 days of the polling day if the Conservatives were elected. This is likely to mean a Budget in February or March, setting any changes to taxes, benefits and allowances in time for the start of the new financial year in April.

Mr Johnson promised that a tax break for workers, through a change to National Insurance, would be confirmed in that first Budget.

The current threshold sees workers paying National Insurance contributions once they earn £8,628 a year. The Conservatives said this would rise to £9,500.

Economists at the Institute for Fiscal Studies (IFS) calculated this would be worth about £85 a year for all those with earnings above £9,500 a year.

This Budget - and any subsequent ones during this five-year Parliament - will see no income tax or VAT rises (nor any National Insurance rises), according to a promise in the Conservative Party's manifesto. However, this was described as &quot;ill-advised&quot; by the IFS owing to the potential lack of room for financial manoeuvre it creates.
• SCROLL AND SEE: The results that sealed it
• ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW: The night's key points
• BREXIT: What happens now?
• WHO WON IN MY CONSTITUENCY? Check your result

The Budget is likely to confirm the biggest increase in the state pension since 2012, with pensioners expected to receive a 3.9% boost.

The full, new state pension is expected to go up from £168.60 a week to about £175.20 in April. However, most pensioners get the older basic state pension, which is likely to go up from £129.20 to £134.25 per week. They may also get a Pension Credit top-up.

The rise is the result of the triple-lock system, which means that the state pension rises in line with inflation, earnings or 2.5% - whichever is the highest. The Conservatives have pledged to keep this in place, as it has with the winter fuel payment and free bus passes for older people.

A Pensions Bill is, to use one of Mr Johnson's phrases, oven-ready. It had been prepared before the election was called and includes new protection for those with workplace pensions, and reforms to allow a new type of shared-risk pension scheme to be made available.

There is also a longer-term promise in the manifesto to look at a pension &quot;loophole&quot; that has seen workers, disproportionately women, who earn between £10,000 and £12,500 missing out on pension benefits.

Despite a number of pension changes in the offing, it is hard to see how they will include any compensation for women born in the 1950s who believe they unfairly missed out on the state pension.

There have been no promises made to the so-called Waspi (Women Against State Pension Inequality), although they will continue to put pressure on the government to address the issue.

The separate Backto60 group, which campaigns on the same issue, recently lost a high-profile court case.

At the Conservative Party conference in September, Chancellor Sajid Javid pledged to raise the National Living Wage to £10.50 an hour within the next five years. The current rate for over 25s is £8.21.

The age at which workers qualify for the National Living Wage - the highest level of minimum wage - is set to drop from 25 to 21 within five years.

Commentators have suggested that there is pent-up demand in the UK housing market - particularly in London. Buyers and sellers have been put off making such a big financial commitment owing to political and economic uncertainty.

Now the first of those is off the table, to a degree, given the size of the Conservative majority, there may be more transactions. More demand could push up prices - which is good for sellers, but bad for first-time buyers.

However, one commentator says it may be a short-term phenomenon.

&quot;We suggest only modest price growth in 2020 on the basis that, despite domestic political uncertainty receding, some economic uncertainty will remain until a trade deal is agreed with the EU,&quot; says Lucian Cook, director of residential research at Savills.

&quot;This could mean a bounce in demand in the first part of 2020 proves difficult to sustain through the summer months and into the autumn market.&quot;

There is a promise in the manifesto to look carefully at the &quot;thoughtful&quot; suggestions in the review into student finance and university and college funding, led by Philip Augar.

In the short term, this suggests the current freeze of tuition fees in England at their current level of £9,250 will continue.

Universal Credit has been one of the most controversial benefit reforms of a generation. A Conservative victory means the roll-out across the country will now continue.

Universal Credit is a benefit for working-age people, replacing six benefits including Income Support and Housing Benefit and merging them into one payment.

The Department for Work and Pensions announced in November that working-age benefits such as Universal Credit and Jobseeker's Allowance would rise by 1.7% from April.

It ends former chancellor George Osborne's decision to introduce a freeze which, according to the IFS, has cut an average of £560 per year from the income of the country's poorest seven million families since 2016.

The Conservative manifesto promised free parking at hospitals for people with disabilities, those who attend outpatient departments frequently, parents of sick children staying overnight and staff working night shifts.

It also promises to pave the way for longer-term mortgages, more similar to a US system, although there will be some regulatory and practical hurdles to clear before that becomes reality. There are questions too over whether there would be demand for such products among people who may wish to move more frequently.

Mr Johnson also spoke a during the campaign, and prior to it, of a plan to abolish the 5% VAT rate on sanitary products once the UK has left the EU, which he called the &quot;tampon tax&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50778312</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-04 00:00:00-28</ID>
      <TITLE>Sir David Attenborough: 'Now is the moment' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science &amp; Environment</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13FE8/production/_110769818_p0827z1y.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The broadcaster and naturalist Sir David Attenborough has said &quot;now is the moment&quot; for action on climate change.

His comments came at a launch event for the COP26 climate summit which is to be held in Glasgow later this year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-51368482</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
