<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Rough Trade: We're selling more records than ever - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/54B3/production/_110538612_hot_dog.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>At the Rough Trade East record shop in London's Brick Lane, a man dressed as a giant hot dog is on stage introducing a song.

&quot;Put your hands up if you're afraid of spiders,&quot; says frontman Murray Matravers of fast-rising band Easy Life, before launching into one of their typically quirky compositions.

Easy Life's in-store live appearance has attracted a throng of enthusiastic teenage fans, all clutching newly purchased copies of their new album, Junk Food. The majority of the audience pre-ordered the album online and admission to the gig is included in the price.

Perhaps you thought young people didn't buy records and CDs? Or that streaming is killing the physical album? Well, welcome to the new reality of music retail.

&quot;The idea that physical and digital are incompatible, I think, is outdated,&quot; says the shop's assistant manager, Alex Bailey. &quot;We're selling more records now than we ever have.&quot;

Rather than seeing digital music as the enemy, Rough Trade embraces podcasts and playlists, keeps a keen eye out for new talent and promotes its stores as community hubs.

The Rough Trade Edit podcast, newly launched in the past week, is billed as &quot;your first stop for new music&quot;, featuring staff picks, recommended albums and guest appearances by bands.

Customers who visit Rough Trade shops are also invited to sign up to its Rough Trade Edit playlist on the Apple Music platform.

&quot;We proudly and warmly endorse streaming as an affordable way to discover and enjoy music, it being very much a driver of vinyl sales,&quot; says Rough Trade Retail director Stephen Godfroy. &quot;If someone develops a love for a recording, the best way to cherish that is to follow up the discovery by owning and enjoying it on vinyl.&quot;

Thanks to a mini-tour of Rough Trade shops, including the chain's outlets in Bristol and Nottingham, Easy Life have sold enough physical albums to earn them a place in the top 10 albums of the week.

And many of the people singing along with the band's songs at Rough Trade East have travelled specially to London for the performance.

Receptionist Conor Austin and waitress Rebecca Foulger have come up to town for the day from their home town of Sandwich, in Kent.

Conor, 18, explains that he got a record player for Christmas and is keen to expand his vinyl collection, even though he has Spotify on his phone. &quot;I think it sounds different, it's a different sort of vibe,&quot; he says.

Rebecca, 17, bought the CD to listen to in her car. &quot;I don't have Spotify Premium, so I get all the ads,&quot; she says. &quot;It's easier to have just CDs.&quot;
• UK music consumption grows for fifth year in a row

As the runner-up artists in the BBC's Sound of 2020 poll, Easy Life are still building their fanbase, and Murray Matravers, speaking before donning his hot dog suit, sees Rough Trade as the ideal place to do it.

&quot;People go to Rough Trade just to see what's happening, and nine times out of 10, they curate a really good record,&quot; he says. &quot;In this shop, there will be at least 20 or 30 people who have no idea who we are and who are hearing us for the first time.&quot;

Stephen Godfroy recalls that when he opened the Rough Trade East store in 2007, many people thought it was &quot;commercial suicide&quot;.

The MP3 and Apple's iPod were already dealing a decisive blow to physical music formats and many record shops were closing down.

But more than a decade later, business is booming. &quot;I'm pleased to say that Rough Trade is positively thriving, with our like-for-like 2019 UK sales up 25% overall,&quot; says Mr Godfroy.

Vinyl is Rough Trade's top seller these days, accounting for three-quarters of all sales. &quot;Rough Trade can represent 75% of total release week vinyl sales for a top 10 UK album chart entry, with just four stores and roughtrade.com,&quot; Mr Godfroy adds.

Even so, Rough Trade East's Alex Bailey says CDs still have their market.

&quot;We've got a few customers that will come in without fail every Friday and buy a pile of CDs,&quot; he says. &quot;I notice that more than with people coming in to get vinyl releases. CDs are still a viable product, 100%.&quot;

Rough Trade seems to be riding high at the moment, but can its success last?

Mr Godfroy freely admits that his stores are &quot;not emblematic of wider music retail&quot; and that the chain occupies a &quot;unique position&quot; in a &quot;very cautious, very fragmented, very distorted&quot; retail climate.

But according to music industry observer Graham Jones, of Proper Music, who has written two books about record shops and the vinyl revival, Rough Trade is still the benchmark by which other shops are judged.

After the publication of his book Last Shop Standing, Mr Jones says he was approached by a number of people who wanted to ask him about opening a record shop.

&quot;My advice was always, 'Go and visit some other shops,'&quot; he says. &quot;But the one I always advised them to visit was Rough Trade. As a model, they're the best. They're the ones you should definitely seek out before you open a record shop.&quot;

In Mr Jones's view, Rough Trade has flourished because &quot;they've managed to stay fashionable - they're an independent brand that music fans like to be associated with&quot;.

But as he recalls, Virgin Records in the 1970s enjoyed similar cachet as a hip place to go before it expanded and lost that insider status.

As long as Rough Trade has its integrity, its place in people's affections seems assured. But credibility is hard to win and easy to lose - a truth that must surely weigh on Mr Godfroy's mind as he steers Rough Trade Retail through a changing music industry landscape.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51132884</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Pretty Little Thing: 'Overly sexualised' advert banned - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/772B/production/_110770503_f2b213e5-beec-40a2-8da8-3985d49fca6d.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>An advert for fashion retailer Pretty Little Thing which featured women wearing exposing lingerie has been banned for being &quot;offensive&quot;.

The YouTube ad presented the firm's products in an &quot;overly-sexualised way&quot; and depicted women as sex objects, the Advertising Standards Authority said.

The retailer is one of several online fast fashion companies to have been rapped for their racy marketing.

Pretty Little Thing said it &quot;in no way meant to cause any offence&quot;.

The advert began with a woman looking over her shoulder in a seductive manner wearing black vinyl, high-waisted chaps-style knickers.
• Online fashion twice as 'racy' as High Street
• Fast fashion: Can it ever be ethical and cheap?

It then showed other scantily clad women in seductive or &quot;highly sexualised&quot; poses, including one wearing a transparent mesh bodysuit.

A viewer complained and the regulator agreed, saying the ad was &quot;irresponsible&quot; and likely to cause offence.

Pretty Little Thing said it &quot;celebrates all women&quot; and promotes body diversity. But the ad, which aired in October last year, must not be shown again.

A previous Pretty Little Thing advert was banned in 2017 for portraying a model who appeared to be under 16 in a &quot;sexually suggestive&quot; manner.

The regulator also recently banned an ad for rival Missguided that featured &quot;highly sexualised&quot; images that objectified women.

Another online fashion retailer, Boohoo - which owns Pretty Little Thing - had its email advert banned for using the phrase &quot;send nudes&quot;, which a viewer complained made light of a potentially harmful social trend.

It may seem surprising for an advert targeted at women to be banned for objectifying women, but the defence used by Pretty Little Thing in this case touches on an increasingly contested grey area.

The company says the advert promoted diversity through &quot;bold and distinctive fashion of all shapes and sizes&quot;, and that they worked hard to promote &quot;a healthy body image that was inclusive and empowered women&quot;.

But the line between empowerment and objectification of women is a subjective one.

Fast-fashion retailers are more likely to push those boundaries. Research we conducted last year found that online-only brands were twice as likely to use more overtly sexualised pictures when selling their clothes than High Street retailers' websites.

It also seems that there's also a growing generational divide. While talking to young people, who these adverts are targeted at, it seemed they were more likely to see them as positive images of women being body-confident whatever their shape. Many in older generations view the same images very differently.

Are you a Pretty Little Thing customer? What do you think of the advert? Get in touch by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk.

Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist. You can also contact us in the following ways:
• Please read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51370851</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit preparations: 'We've stockpiled 10,000 wine bottles' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/8B5F/production/_110697653_p081qjtv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Worries for the future over settlement scheme

Guillermo, who is Spanish but was born and raised in the UK, has applied to stay via the EU settlement scheme and has concerns about the future.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51302765</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Travelex: Bank currency services still offline after hack - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/71FE/production/_110428192_gettyimages-528778960.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sainsbury's Bank, Royal Bank of Scotland, Lloyds and Barclays are among major High Street banks still unable to offer online currency services.

The problem stems from provider Travelex, which is still working to bring back services more than a month after it suffered a major cyber attack.

Customers are able to buy in branches, but cannot order money online or over the phone.

It is understood the currency firm aims to start restoring services this week.

Travelex had to take down its website after the hack was discovered on New Year's Eve.

A gang called Sodinokibi claimed to have accessed reams of sensitive customer data and demanded that it pay a $6m (£4.6m) ransom to retrieve it.
• Travelex being held to ransom by hackers
• Travelex customer: My money is in limbo

Cashiers resorted to using pen and paper to keep money moving at bureau de changes in airports and on high streets but orders online were suspended.

Meanwhile, banks reported that their supply of notes from Travelex had dried up and were forced to apologise to customers.

Lenders that use Travelex also include Virgin Money and HSBC.

On Monday, RBS confirmed it was still not offering foreign currency services online but declined to comment on when its services would be restored.

A spokeswoman for Sainsbury's Bank said: &quot;We're continuing to work closely with Travelex in order to resume our online money ordering service soon.&quot;

Travelex, which declined to comment, has said there is no evidence customer data was been compromised by the cyber attack.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51364102</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>AirAsia's Tony Fernandes steps aside amid bribery probe - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/6E38/production/_110761282_6baad1ea-9d60-48a1-ad81-a6fbe189f27b.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Tycoon Tony Fernandes has stepped aside as the chief executive of AirAsia while authorities probe bribery claims.

He will stand down for least two months from the company he turned into Asia's biggest budget airline.

AirAsia has been pulled into investigations which have seen European planemaker Airbus fined a record €3.6bn (£3bn).

Mr Fernandes, who co-owns Queens Park Rangers (QPR) football club in the UK, will remain as an adviser to AirAsia.

Educated at Epsom College, one of Britain's top fee-paying schools, Mr Fernandes bought AirAsia from the Malaysian government for less than a dollar in 2001.

He is now one of the wealthiest men in Malaysia, with a net worth of $530m, according to the Forbes rich list.

Both Mr Fernandes and chairman Kamarudin Meranun have said they will step aside while authorities investigate allegations that Airbus paid a bribe of $50m to AirAsia.

In a statement, the pair announced that they were stepping aside &quot;to facilitate a full and independent inquiry&quot; and would be ''relinquishing our executive roles with immediate effect''.

AirAsia has said it will fully co-operate with Malaysia's Anti-Corruption Commission, which is working alongside Britain's Serious Fraud Office (SFO) to investigate the claims.

Along with a majority stake in QPR, the sports-loving entrepreneur co-founded the now-defunct Caterham Formula 1 racing team.

Since Mr Fernandes bought AirAsia, he has built a company with a market valuation of more than $1bn.

AirAsia's share price tumbled 11% on Monday after the Malaysian investigation was launched. It slipped again on Tuesday on the news that Mr Fernandes is standing aside.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51353498</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Disney+ takes on Netflix as 28 million subscribers sign up - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10079/production/_110775656_gettyimages-1187551494.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sign-ups for Disney's new streaming service have shot past expectations, as audiences respond to the offering of Star Wars, cartoons and other classics.

Walt Disney said about 28.6 million people had signed up for Disney+ since it started in November.

The on-demand video service, which costs $6.99 per month, is Disney's attempt to challenge industry leader Netflix, which has 170m subscribers.

Disney+ now has almost as many subscribers as the firm's earlier on-demand streaming service Hulu, which was founded in 2007 and offers shows from US television.

&quot;The launch of Disney+ has been enormously successful, exceeding even our greatest expectations,&quot; Mr Iger said on a call with analysts after the release of the company's quarterly earnings.

Disney also warned investors that its operating income in the next quarter could take a nearly $300m hit due to the closure of its parks in China.

That figure assumes the coronavirus outbreak keeps Disney's resorts in Shanghai and Hong Kong closed for two months, and takes into account the fact that visitors to Hong Kong had already dropped significantly due to protests there.

Disney announced in 2017 that it would create its own streaming service, aiming to combat the declining audiences for its traditional business as viewers move online.

Shortly after, it announced a deal to buy the bulk of Rupert Murdoch's 21st Century Fox entertainment empire, as it looked to bulk up its catalogue to compete.

&quot;I'm enormously proud of what we have accomplished in a relatively short period of time and believe we are well positioned to not only withstand the disruptive forces ... but to thrive,&quot; Mr Iger said.

Most of the current subscribers come from the US and about half signed up directly through the website, he said. He attributed part of the appeal to Disney's &quot;very accessible&quot; price.

International expansion of Disney+ is the firm's next priority, he added.

The service is currently available in five countries, including the US and Canada. It is due to launch in the UK and other countries in western Europe next month. Mr Iger said the service will also launch in India in March.

Disney said revenues in the quarter were up 36% year-on-year. However profits declined 25% from $2.8bn to $2.1bn, amid heavy spending on its on-demand offerings.

Revenues in its direct-to-consumer unit - which includes Hulu and Disney+ - increased to $4bn, from $0.9bn, but operating loss widened from $136m to $693m.

Disney shares rose more than 2% in after-hours trade.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51379064</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Aviation not the enemy in climate battle, says Heathrow boss - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EFDE/production/_110760416_gettyimages-973359948.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Flying is not &quot;the enemy&quot; in the fight against climate change, the chief executive of Heathrow Airport has said.

John Holland-Kaye told the BBC's Today programme: &quot;The answer is not to stop people flying. It has to be about decarbonising aviation.&quot;

The UK's aviation industry is promising to reduce its net carbon emissions to zero by 2050.

Cleaner engines, new fuels and planting trees will all help, according to the industry group Sustainable Aviation.

Mr Holland-Kaye said: &quot;The enemy is carbon, not aviation. We need to protect the ability to fly in a world without carbon.

&quot;When the government blocked Heathrow expansion 10 years ago, people started flying through Amsterdam and Paris instead, taking two flights instead of one and not a single tonne of carbon was saved.&quot;

He said synthetic fuels were the way forward. &quot;It has been around for about 100 years and is becoming more affordable. It needs a real push on investment.&quot;

'Crisis is here and now'

Sustainable Aviation says the industry's plan will mean airlines can cut pollution even as passenger numbers grow by an expected 70%.

But campaigners say the only way to cut airline pollution is by reducing air travel and cancelling new airports and runways.

&quot;We need to restrict flying,&quot; said Muna Suleiman, from Friends of the Earth. &quot;We can't have airport expansion at the same time.&quot;

Rail travel and buses are greener alternatives and taxes should be applied to frequent fliers, she said.

Biofuels, which Sustainable Aviation say will be part of the industry's plan, still pollute, Ms Suleiman added. &quot;The crisis is here and now.&quot;

The aviation sector is under increasing pressure to come up with a plan to cut emissions, especially as it has no commercial comparator yet to the electric car, which is seen as the auto industry's hope for cutting emissions.

While other forms of transport produce more carbon, individual journeys on planes produce large amounts of CO2.

Sustainable Aviation says the UK industry can reduce its emissions of CO2 from 30 million tonnes a year to zero, without restricting growth.

An economy-class return flight from London to New York emits an estimated 0.67 tonnes of CO2 per passenger, according to the calculator from the UN's civil aviation body, the International Civil Aviation Organization.

That is equivalent to 11% of the average annual emissions for someone in the UK or about the same as all of those caused by someone living in Ghana for more than a year.

US firm Wright Electric said last week it had started electric engine development for a 186-seater plane, and hoped to begin test flights in 2023.

British Airways is investing in a project to make fuel from rubbish.

&quot;We are going to have to do this through many projects,&quot; Alex Cruz, chief executive of British Airways, told the BBC.

&quot;Biofuels will give us a greener alternative and we are attracted by that,&quot; he said, while conceding that they will still produce carbon dioxide and that they are expensive at the moment.

&quot;We do believe we will reach a point where the price will be compatible with the rest of fuel prices.&quot;

BA will also retire old planes, with the double-decker Boeing 747 being phased out in 2024.

Other plans include planting trees - so-called carbon offsetting - and investing in renewable power sources, said Matt Gorman, a council member of Sustainable Aviation.

&quot;Aviation is one of the more difficult sectors to decarbonise but we are absolutely confident it can be done,&quot; said Mr Gorman. &quot;We have to do it&quot;

The aviation sector has a problem. On one level, it is extremely successful. Passenger numbers in the UK are higher than they've ever been, and massive growth is expected worldwide over the next couple of decades.

More passengers means more planes, and all else being equal that means an awful lot more emissions. The sector only accounts for about 2.5% of global CO2 output at the moment, but the obvious risk is that share could rise significantly.

You don't have to be Greta Thunberg to realise where that could lead. There's a risk that faced with growing public pressure to act on climate change, regulators could start to clamp down on the sector in a meaningful way - and that could hit growth.

So here in the UK, businesses are taking pre-emptive action. Action they claim will reduce emissions to zero without curbing growth.

So how effective will the plans be? Boeing and Airbus are already selling a new generation of aircraft that are much more efficient than their predecessors, and it's fair to say that there are plenty of benefits to be gained from investing in new technology.

But the value of &quot;market-based measures&quot; such as carbon offsets is harder to calculate and hotly debated. People within the industry claim the projects they support are carefully chosen and reap real benefits.

Climate campaigners say that's greenwash - and they'd rather we simply decided to fly a lot less.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51364103</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What does it mean for my business? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Suffolk</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EF39/production/_110714216_p081vkyl.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Preparations, port delays and planning for a potential no-deal - these are some of your big Brexit questions.

BBC East business correspondent Richard Bond has been answering some of the queries from businesses in Suffolk.

The UK formally leaves the European Union (EU) at 23:00 GMT on Friday, 31 January.

It will immediately enter an 11-month transition period.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-suffolk-51318721</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Tesla: Is the car firm really worth $150bn? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16415/production/_110775119_gettyimages-1192349155.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When Tesla's market value crossed $100bn (£76.7bn) two weeks ago, overtaking Volkswagen, sceptics scoffed.

But on Tuesday, it zoomed past $150bn as shares gained more than 13%, rising to more than $887 apiece.

The jump means the firm's share price has more than tripled in the last three months, outpacing the predictions of even some of the most optimistic analysts tracking the company.

It now ranks as the world's second most valuable car company. So what's behind the turnaround?

Less than two years ago, things weren't looking quite as rosy for the carmaker.

The firm, which has reported losses every year since its start, faced a cash crunch amid production delays and heavy spending.

Doubts about performance also dogged chief executive Elon Musk, who had a reputation for making promises but failing to deliver.

Tesla's numbers have since improved. The firm has now reported two quarters of profit and its new factory in Shanghai was up and running more quickly than expected.

Signs also suggest buyer demand has remained healthy, despite fears of a slowdown. Its new Cybertruck drew in about 200,000 orders, even after an embarrassing incident where its &quot;tough&quot; windows smashed during an on-stage demonstration.

The firm has also avoided self-inflicted mistakes, like the tweets from Mr Musk in 2018, which drew allegations of price manipulation, forcing him to step down as chair of the company.

&quot;It has become very clear to investors that Tesla has a number of long-term sustainable growth drivers that are very difficult to dispute,&quot; says Rolf Bulk, an analyst at New Street Research.

Wolfe Research analysts also said they were &quot;a little surprised by the magnitude&quot; of the share price increase but &quot;the abundance of positives explains the move&quot;.

In a note to clients last week, they wrote: &quot;There may be ups and downs, but our view is the stock has found a new range.&quot;

Rolf Bulk believes that the recent share price increase suggests that some investors betting against the firm have been squeezed. Or forced to &quot;close out positions&quot;, a process that involves buying shares, which drives up prices.

But S3 Partners, which tracks such activity, said its research shows that recent buying has mostly been done by a mix of everyday investors and big firms.

Tesla's stock has however been subject to big swings historically.

Some analysts said prices could dive again, especially given the investment it is making in a new factory in Europe and the fact that the outbreak of coronavirus has forced its Shanghai factory to shut down temporarily.

The prospect of a weak first quarter is &quot;something that is not fully appreciated by Wall Street today,&quot; Mr Bulk added.

What about other carmakers?

Tesla delivered more than 367,500 cars last year - up 50% from 2018. It has forecast sales of about 500,000 this year and analysts project that Tesla could hit two million by 2030.

Its deliveries remain far smaller than its rivals.

Volkswagen delivered almost 11 million vehicles last year, while Toyota - which has a market value of more than $230bn - sold more than nine million in the first 11 months of 2019.

However, experts say Tesla's electric car technology continues to lead the industry. The firm might be able to sustain that lead for longer than they had expected, even as demand for electric vehicles grows.

There is even speculation that the company's investment in battery power could put it in a position to be a supplier to other leading automotive companies.

In a recent note to clients Adam Jonas, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, said if Tesla could achieve all those outcomes, it might be worth about where it is trading today.

He added that that was &quot;an aggressive 'blue sky' scenario that could take 10 to 20 years to achieve, if it could even be done at all&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51379061</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>HMV faces the music in Christmas crunch test - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16FE5/production/_108918149_doug_hmv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Since Doug Putman rescued UK music retailer HMV in February, he has thrown himself wholeheartedly into running a transatlantic retail empire.

The Canadian businessman has found himself jetting back and forth between his Ontario-based Sunrise Records chain and his newer acquisition.

On average, he spends one week a month in the UK. &quot;I must do about 500,000 air miles a year,&quot; he says.

Now he faces his latest challenge, the all-important Christmas period.

&quot;That's crunch time,&quot; he says. &quot;All the hard work you do for 10 months of the year, that period is when you see it come to fruition and you see how good a job you did.&quot;

A lot is riding on the chain's performance over the festive season. HMV has twice fallen into administration, in 2013 and 2018, and Mr Putman acknowledges that many people didn't expect his relaunch to last six months.

After all, there have been plenty of casualties in the sector. At the start of the 21st Century, there were a number of other big retailers selling records and CDs, including Virgin, Our Price, Tower and Fopp.

But now, although many local independent shops are still in robust health, HMV is the only national chain standing, with Fopp as its wholly-owned subsidiary.

Poor Christmas sales have capsized many a High Street retailer in recent years, but Mr Putman is pinning his hopes on the chain's &quot;loyal fan base&quot; and the changes he has been making.
• Did streaming cause HMV to fail?
• Is this the end of owning music?

As he sees it, many shops have run into trouble by trying to be all things to all people.

&quot;I think stores trying to appeal to everyone are really getting left behind,&quot; he told the BBC.

&quot;If your goal in life is to make everyone like you, that's not going to happen. We have to identify the core customers, make sure we know what they expect from us and deliver on that.&quot;

So who are those core customers? Young or old? &quot;It's not about their age, it's about what they're into,&quot; he says. &quot;We have a younger generation coming in to buy K-Pop and vinyl.

&quot;It's about people who want something tangible, who appreciate physical formats and talking to the staff - it's the personal touch. They want something physical, whether it's for gift-giving or collecting.&quot;

Under Mr Putman's ownership, stores have given more space to vinyl albums and displayed them prominently, although he admits that CDs are still bigger than vinyl for HMV.

In a music industry that is increasingly dominated by streaming, record shops have to be attuned to changing trends in physical formats.

Reflecting the vinyl revival is one of a number of &quot;easy wins&quot; that Mr Putman says he has achieved in the past seven months.

Others include displaying staff picks in stores and allowing individual stores to go their own way in terms of choosing the right stock for their local customers.

&quot;I don't believe in taking away too much control from stores and micro-managing from head office. If your customers want more metal, let's get more metal,&quot; he says.

&quot;It's about allowing stores to create their own assortment mix. When I'm doing my store visits, I'm seeing it change.&quot;

Looking ahead, Mr Putman wants to establish HMV as the trusted gatekeeper in a crowded cultural environment.

&quot;We need to be the expert in the entertainment field. We need to cut through the noise,&quot; he says.

&quot;We can say, here are the 100 songs that are really interesting, here are the albums that are worth listening to.

&quot;It's a bit overwhelming at times: what movie, what show do I want to watch? These are small things that we need to do better.&quot;

HMV now has 113 shops, but is suffering from the lack of a big central London outlet since the closure of the heavily loss-making flagship store in Oxford Street in the wake of Mr Putman's takeover.

&quot;We're just trying to find a location that makes sense. Oxford Street was a very, very big location, but we couldn't make the financials work. If we can find that right location, we will certainly be back,&quot; he says.

New shops are already coming to other cities, with a 25,000 sq-ft store known as the HMV Vault now open in Birmingham.

This boasts &quot;an unrivalled range&quot; of music and DVDs, plus a permanent stage area and PA sound system, in line with Mr Putman's intention to &quot;make the stores more exciting&quot;.

Also in the run-up to Christmas, HMV's online store and its Purehmv loyalty card scheme are being revived.

&quot;We're lucky to be in an industry that you're either passionate about it or you're not. That's been its strength from day one. It attracts people who love talking about film or music,&quot; he says.

But even if HMV is making progress, Mr Putman knows he cannot afford to become complacent.

&quot;The minute you feel you're exactly where you need to be and nothing needs to change, that's when you start falling into problems,&quot; he says.

&quot;You need to be always changing, while staying authentic to what you are.&quot;

However, retail analyst Richard Hyman questioned whether the business would continue to progress when having to fight against online giants such as Amazon.

&quot;The challenges facing HMV are that the product is the same wherever you buy it from,&quot; he said. &quot;Increasingly in retail, it's going to be difficult selling someone else's product.

&quot;Things like scale become the main differentiator. Only one person can be the cheapest and have the best and most convenient delivery.&quot;

Mr Hyman said the trouble with offering a wide range of products and having &quot;fantastic&quot; customer service was that &quot;they will kill your trading economics because they are both very expensive&quot;.

&quot;Back in the day, when retail was less cut-throat and before the internet came along, that was a viable store,&quot; he said. &quot;That has become increasingly difficult when your main competitor has got the scale to blow you out of the water.&quot;

He added that the UK retail market was the &quot;toughest on the planet&quot;, in part due to the ease with which retail firms could enter the market by buying an off-the-shelf website and partly due to softer consumer demand.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49787061</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Airbus to pay SFO €1bn in corruption settlement - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/B2C2/production/_98326754_airbusplanes.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Airbus will pay nearly €1bn (£840m) to settle corruption cases with UK authorities.

The deal follows a lengthy investigation by the Serious Fraud Office (SFO) into the aircraft maker's use of middlemen to secure plane deals.

The settlement is part of a €3.6bn (£3bn) deal that also involves payments to US and French authorities.

The payments are being made under a deferred prosecution agreement (DPA) - a type of corporate plea bargain.

The French national prosecutor, the Parquet National Financier, (PNF), will receive about €2.1bn, while Airbus will also pay the US Department of Justice some €500m.

The settlement was announced earlier this week and was approved by courts in the three countries on Friday.

The European planemaker, based in Toulouse in south-west France, employs more than 130,000 people globally, including about 10,000 in the UK.

The SFO, and later its French counterpart, opened investigations into Airbus in 2016 after the firm reported itself and asked regulators to look at documentation about its use of overseas agents.

In the run-up to the SFO's investigation, UK, French and German authorities froze export credit applications by Airbus, but reversed that decision in 2018.

Export credits are used by many governments to support exporters, often by giving their backing to bank loans offered to overseas buyers of UK products.

In the past, they have proved useful in giving cash-strapped airlines the ability to afford new Airbus planes.

The investigations followed concern that Airbus had failed to disclose the use of middlemen in such deals.

These settlements will cost Airbus a lot of money - and cause a fair amount of embarrassment - but the company will at least avoid prosecution. The UK part of the deal gives the Serious Fraud Office a much-needed success as well.

The statement of facts published alongside the deferred prosecution agreement is certainly eyebrow-raising. It describes how, in one case, Airbus paid $50m (£38m) in sponsorship to a sports team owned by airline executives, to help win a contract for 180 aircraft.

In another, the wife of an airline executive was used as a consultant on an aircraft contract, despite her having no experience in aviation. It later misled the UK's export credit agency about her identity when it was applying for assistance in funding the deal.

The punishment could have been a lot more severe - but Airbus received credit for reporting the wrongdoing to the authorities itself.

Since then, there's been a management clearout, and a major overhaul of Airbus' sales operations. A new regime has emerged under CEO Guillaume Faury. He clearly sees the settlements as uncomfortable medicine the company has no choice but to take.

And he wants the bribery allegations themselves filed squarely under &quot;sins of the past&quot;.

The US also requested information from the UK and French investigations, amid suspicions that arms export rules could have been violated.

This is by far the biggest DPA settlement the SFO has made.

It is the seventh DPA agreed between the SFO and a company since they were introduced in 2013. The total value of all seven is about £1.53bn.

In 2017, engineering giant Rolls-Royce paid £497m plus costs to the SFO to settle a corruption case.

The SFO had found conspiracy to corrupt or failure to prevent bribery by Rolls-Royce in China, India and other markets. The firm apologised &quot;unreservedly&quot; for the cases spanning nearly 25 years.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51328655</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Bubble tea: A sweet treat that went global - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12216/production/_110726247_p081ykvv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Bubble tea - also called pearl tea or boba tea - is a sweet drink that combines milk, flavoured tea and tapioca pearls that are sucked up through an extra-large straw and chewed.

Invented in Taiwan in the 1980s, it has now become popular worldwide. The BBC's Sarah Toms went to a recent exhibition in Singapore to find out more.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312934</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>CEO Secrets: Can you be the boss if you're in chronic pain? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1136C/production/_110780507_p0829kgg.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When Shazia Ginai took over as the boss of Neuro-Insight, she thought CEOs had to be &quot;bulletproof&quot;. She has a medical condition which causes her chronic pain, and wondered if she could do the job.

But being open didn't lower her standing with her staff. Instead it's drawn them closer to her.

Find more business tips at CEO Secrets. You can also follow the series on the BBC News app by adding the topic 'CEO Secrets' in My News.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312928</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Australia fires: Vineyard owner's grief and determination - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/46A5/production/_110458081_tilbrook.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Australia's deadly wildfires have devastated huge swathes of territory and left thousands homeless. Many businesses have also been destroyed, among them vineyards which have taken generations to grow, as the BBC's Peter Hoskins writes.

&quot;It's a bit like losing a parent, a mother or father,&quot; says James Tilbrook.

He is no stranger to wildfires. The Adelaide Hills region, where his winery and vineyard once stood, had twice been hit by major blazes in the two decades he's tended this land.

When smoke appeared on the horizon on the morning of 20 December he knew it was going to be bad but could only hope his 20 acres (8 hectares) would again be spared.

As the flames grew closer there was nothing that could be done but flee the fire. He returned to a scene of almost total devastation.

&quot;I started looking around me, and all the land was black.&quot;

For him, the emotional impact was akin to losing a close family member and the grieving process that follows.

&quot;You know, the very first day that it happens, or maybe up to a week afterwards, you're absolutely in shock and then you go to the funeral... and it's another shock.&quot;

Within a matter of hours the Tilbrook family had been left without a livelihood, as well as facing the huge cost of replacing what had been lost in the fire.

&quot;From the business point of view, we've lost our income, we've lost our livelihood.&quot;

&quot;I'm reckoning that two years-worth of income, plus the equipment, conservatively, is about half a million (Australian) dollars (£262,800; $344,000).

&quot;Then there's all the cost of the vineyard... potentially another $200,000... You're talking about $700,000.&quot;

Mr Tilbrook's story is one that has been seen time and time again as the bushfires swept across Australia, hitting large parts of the wine industry.

Since September, at least 27 people have died in fires, which have destroyed more than 10 million hectares across the country.

The fires, and the severe drought that contributed to them, is seriously affecting producers, according to industry lobby group Australian Grape and Wine.

Tony Battaglene, the group's chief executive told the BBC that the situation may not improve any time soon.

&quot;I wish the worst was behind us. Our bushfire season in Australia traditionally starts around December and will go on for three or four months. We have started very early this year, so it's very early days indeed.&quot;

&quot;From the photos and the pictures you'll see, it doesn't seem like there's a lot more to burn, but I can assure you there is.&quot;

Australian Grape and Wine says Queensland and the Adelaide Hills region have been hit particularly hard.

In Queensland it predicts that production for 2020 is likely to be a fraction of last year's due to water shortages.

The fires have also potentially wiped out a third of wine production in the Adelaide Hills region, according to the area's industry association.

Of the region's 3,300 hectares of vineyards, around 1,100 hectares have been directly affected by the bushfires.

Producers don't just face the direct impact of the blazes but also smoke damage, or so-called &quot;smoke taint&quot;.

Bushfire smoke can permeate the skin of the grapes as they ripen, causing wine to have an unpleasant smoky taste.

'Battle on... keep trying'

Geoff Weaver owns a vineyard at Lenswood, high in the Adelaide Hills, which was also damaged in December.

He told the BBC: &quot;We've lost all our sheds and equipment. We've also lost about 30% of our vines.&quot;

He said, for that third of his vines: &quot;We've lost this year's crop, the 2020 crop. We'll also lose the 2021.&quot;

But Mr Weaver sent a defiant message to his fellow winemakers, telling them: &quot;Battle on. Keep trying to make the best wine you possibly can and challenge the world markets with the best wines we can make in Australia.&quot;

That spirit of determination was echoed by James Tilbrook.

He said he'd been overwhelmed by how many people had rallied round to help rebuild his vineyard and winery.

&quot;A mixture of anger getting angry about stuff that you shouldn't really get angry about, tears when you get upset about stuff but joy at the same time that you've got these little wins, and also faith in humanity that people are there to help.&quot;

Much of that support has come through the vineyard's Facebook page, with professionals from electricians to lawyers offering expertise, and materials, as well as people who just came along to help out.

&quot;I've basically put out posts that have been shared and shared and shared and shared again. As a result we've had a lot of volunteers, we've had about a hundred so far.&quot;

&quot;We definitely couldn't have done it without all these people.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50979489</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Ikea announces first big UK store closure - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11FB8/production/_110765637_ikeacoventry2_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Ikea has announced that it will shut down its Coventry city centre store this summer, in its first big closure of a UK outlet.

The Swedish flat-pack furniture giant said the store had made &quot;consistent losses&quot; since it opened in 2007, with fewer people visiting it than expected.

It said it would be consulting the 352 workers affected and would try to find them jobs at other stores.

The Usdaw union said it was &quot;devastating news&quot; for staff.

Ikea, which has 22 stores in the UK, said that it remained committed to growth in the UK.

It said the Coventry site, which cost it £35m, had been built in the city centre as one of its earliest examples of testing a new format to meet customers' changing needs.

&quot;However, given its location and the size of the land available at the time, the store was built over seven levels, which resulted in a significant impact on the operating costs of the store and the shopping experience for customers,&quot; the firm added.

&quot;In addition, the changing behaviour of customers in the area who prefer to shop in retail parks and online has resulted in visitor numbers being substantially lower than expected and continuing to decrease over time.&quot;

After the closure, customers will have to journey to Birmingham, Nottingham or Milton Keynes to find their nearest Ikea branch.

Local people have been reacting to the move on social media.

Dave Gill, national officer for the Usdaw union, said: &quot;Our priorities are to seek redeployment opportunities, minimise compulsory redundancies and secure the best deal we can for our members.&quot;

Ikea stores are generally in out-of-town locations and the firm has made various attempts to bring its outlets to city centres.

In 2018, it closed three smaller inner-city collection-point stores in Norway, which had been a test for a new format that it hoped to roll out worldwide.

Other retailers have been harder hit by the rise of online shopping, resulting in the disappearance of a number of well-known UK High Street brands.

Already this year, department store chain Beales has fallen into administration, while John Lewis has warned that its staff bonus may be in doubt after it reported lower Christmas sales at its stores.

Ikea is trying to respond to changing customer tastes, says Patrick O'Brien, GlobalData's retail research director.

&quot;When the Coventry Ikea was opened, it was still very much about imposing the 'Ikea way' on customers; you walk this way round the maze, you pick it up yourself, you put it together yourself.

&quot;Things have moved on in UK retail now, it's all about how best to serve the customer, and Ikea has had to adapt and change their model.

&quot;This is about Ikea adapting how it uses physical spaces rather than a beginning of a retreat.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51369413</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>British Steel: France in threat to veto sale - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/139D4/production/_109604308_scunthorpe.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The sale of British Steel to Chinese firm Jingye could be scuppered by French intervention.

Jingye agreed in November to buy the collapsed business for £50m and save about 4,000 jobs.

However, the approval of the French government is required because British Steel has a plant in France that is considered a strategic national asset.

Now French Finance Minister Bruno Le Maire has threatened to veto the deal, as first reported by Sky News.

Mr Le Maire told Chancellor Sajid Javid of his intentions last week during a meeting in Brussels, government sources confirmed to the BBC.

The Anglo-French row centres on British Steel's plant in Hayange, which supplies the French railway network, including state-owned train operator SNCF.

France has the power to block the sale of the Hayange plant, which has already been advertised for sale separately from the UK operation, apparently with the blessing of the French authorities.

When British Steel collapsed more than seven months ago, control of the holding company passed to the UK Insolvency Service, which is responsible for selling the assets.

Although the service is the beneficial owner of Hayange, day-to-day operational control of the factory remains in France.

There is another potential bidder for British Steel waiting in the wings.

Earlier this week, Turkish construction conglomerate Cengiz Holdings confirmed its &quot;intention and ability to make an offer for the whole of British Steel, should the current talks with Jingye Group fall away&quot;.

Cengiz chief executive Omer Mafa said the company was &quot;ready and waiting to engage with the UK government and British Steel's receivers to progress towards a full offer&quot;.

Mr Mafa added that Cengiz enjoyed a &quot;strong trading relationship with French industries such as energy, mining and aviation&quot;.

Government sources confirm that the French finance minister has indicated to Chancellor Sajid Javid that he is opposed to Chinese ownership of what the French consider strategically important assets.

As a major supplier of steel to state-owned rail company SNCF, the French government considers the British Steel owned plant at Hayange in north-east France to fall into that category.

The French position is different to that of the UK government, despite the fact that British Steel is a major supplier to state-owned Network Rail.

Sources within the steel industry also confirm knowledge of the French objections.

There is also widespread unease within the UK steel industry of the scale of Chinese ambitions within the UK.

Jingye's ambitions to significantly increase production at Scunthorpe, along with the acquisition a week ago of UK steel trading company Stemcor, have caused alarm among other steel producers at the increasing penetration of Chinese interests in an important primary industry.

French objections were widely anticipated and a process to carve out the French plant from the rest of British Steel if necessary has been under way for several months.

The government remains hopeful that the deal with Jingye can still be completed and talks to seal that deal are ongoing.

Carving out the profit-making French business is thought to make the overall deal less attractive to Jingye and for that reason, a deal with Turkish group Cengiz has been lined up as a potential fallback option if the deal with Jingye collapses.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51325915</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: 'You have to be optimistic as a fisherman' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F9BB/production/_110713936_p081vhnd.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Fishing is set to play a big role in post-Brexit trade negotiations between the UK and EU.

Fisherman Andy McLeod from Brixham voted Leave in the referendum, in the hope that British boats would get a bigger share of fishing rights after Brexit.

But he fears that he and his colleagues will just end up being &quot;pawns to be sacrificed, for the greater good of the country&quot;.

Video produced and edited by Oliver Smith. Filmed by Tony Smith.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312932</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Thomas Cook: 'They told me the money was safe' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16AD2/production/_110028829_alan_diane_holmes.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Customers of collapsed tour operator Thomas Cook have been getting in touch with the BBC to voice their frustration at delays in processing their refunds for holidays that never took place.

The Civil Aviation Authority (CAA) originally said all valid claims made on the first day of its refund programme would be paid within 60 days, or by Friday 6 December. But now it says only two-thirds will be paid on time.

Retired teachers Alan and Diane Holmes from Ripon in north Yorkshire booked a two-week holiday in Egypt, but initially thought their money was safe because the booking was made through another firm, Freedom Holidays.

&quot;My wife always wanted to do the Egypt Nile cruise. It's been quite peaceful there these last two years, so we thought we'd best do it before it all takes off again,&quot; Mr Holmes told the BBC, referring to the possibility of civil unrest in the country.

But as they later found out, the cruise itself and the hotel accommodation had been booked through Thomas Cook.

The couple had paid £3,200 for the holiday, but were then told they would have to pay another £2,200 upfront if they wanted the holiday to go ahead.

&quot;They had told me the money was safe in a trust fund, but it turned out that Thomas Cook had already taken it,&quot; said Mr Holmes.

They decided to cancel and are now waiting for the initial £3,200 to be refunded.

&quot;I filled in the CAA form and never heard anything back,&quot; said Mr Holmes. &quot;Then two days ago, I got this email saying they wanted more information.&quot;

Mr Holmes has now provided details of the booking and the credit card payment.

&quot;I realise the people dealing with it have got a lot of work to go through. It's just the poor communication,&quot; he said.

&quot;Travel companies are very happy to take your money, then as soon as anything goes wrong, they don't want to know.&quot;

'We were in turmoil'

Bank employee Deborah Hulme and her husband Stephen, from Staffordshire, paid Thomas Cook £3,060 for &quot;the holiday of a lifetime&quot;.

They planned to spend a week in New York and a further two in Las Vegas.

As well as the package holiday itself, they had booked excursions and other extras with third-party companies, which made things extremely complicated.

&quot;When they went bust, we were in turmoil,&quot; Ms Hulme told the BBC. &quot;We would have had to cancel every single thing. It was a complete nightmare to even start doing.&quot;

As a result, they decided to pay out another £3,500 to re-book the same holiday with another travel agent, expecting to be reimbursed promptly by Thomas Cook. But they too are still waiting.

&quot;We had no choice but to replace our holiday, because we would have lost so much otherwise,&quot; said Ms Hulme. &quot;We thought we would get it back pretty much straight away.&quot;

Maggie Eveleigh of Highbridge in Somerset, who works at Asda, booked a £3,500 10-day all-inclusive holiday in Turkey for herself, her partner Terence Beasley and his son and grandson.

When Thomas Cook collapsed, she booked another holiday in Cyprus at a cost of £3,800.

What annoys her most is that two days before the firm went under, when the extent of its problems had started to come to light, she spent another £50 to secure a late check-out at the Turkish hotel and the payment was processed the same day.

&quot;I asked if there were problems and I was told it was just scaremongering,&quot; she told the BBC.

Now she is anxiously waiting to be reimbursed. &quot;I can't afford to lose that money,&quot; she said. &quot;Christmas is looming and I'm still £3,500 out of pocket.&quot;

'Everything was gone'

But not everyone has had the same bad experience. Vape shop salesman Jason Henderson, from Lancaster, booked a Thomas Cook package holiday to Cuba and paid for it in instalments on direct debit.

As the news emerged that the company was in trouble, he continued to check with his local branch and was told that nothing had changed.

&quot;Then I woke up on 23 September and boom, everything was gone,&quot; he told the BBC.

Fortunately, he was able to borrow money to book another Cuban holiday with a different firm.

&quot;I ended up having to go via Amsterdam and staying in a different hotel at the other end of the island,&quot; he said.

In the end, his final direct debit payment didn't go through, because the bank stopped it when Thomas Cook collapsed.

But after he put in his claim for a refund, he received five separate instalments of £109.56 back within two weeks, while his initial deposit of £700 was refunded on Thursday, just before the deadline.

&quot;I had no problems with them. The communication with them was great,&quot; he said.

&quot;But Thomas Cook hadn't provided the correct information for a lot of people, and that's why some people are having so many problems.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50684434</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>YouTube shines but Google ads continue to slow - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/B4A4/production/_106644264_googlenew.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Google's parent company has published details of its YouTube and cloud business for the first time, as the firm's advertising business continues to slow.

YouTube's ad sales in the last three months of 2019 rose 31% year-on-year to $4.7bn (£3.62bn), Alphabet said.

Overall Alphabet revenue increased by 17% year-on-year to $46bn - the slowest rate in more than two years.

For years the business did not publish revenue figures for its various divisions, to the concern of investors and regulators.

When Sundar Pichai took over as Alphabet chief executive last year the policy changed, although it is still not releasing profit figures for individual units.
• Who is Sundar Pichai and what does Alphabet do?

Alphabet said it earned $2.6bn in cloud revenue for the most recent quarter - compared to almost $10bn at Amazon. However it is fast-growing, rising more than 50% year-on-year.

Alphabet and others make money in cloud computing by charging companies to host their data remotely, rather than firms maintaining their own servers.

Alphabet shares fell more than 4% in after-hours trade.

Although growth missed analyst forecasts, Alphabet's business remains strong, said Nicholas Hyett, equity analyst at stockbroker Hargreaves Lansdown.

&quot;It's always important to put these sorts of misses into perspective,&quot; he said. &quot;The core businesses, like Search and YouTube, continue to generate prodigious quantities of cash.&quot;

Alphabet reported quarterly profits of almost $10.7bn, up 19% year-on-year, while costs rose 18% to $36.8bn, as the firm invested in data centres and hired new staff.

YouTube now counts about two million paid subscribers, Mr Pichai said.

At more than $15bn for 2019, YouTube's ad business accounted for almost 10% of Alphabet's overall revenues last year - but the firm also said it shares a large portion of YouTube ad revenue with people posting videos.

Mr Pichai said the firm sees opportunity to make even more money off its YouTube adverts, including by targeting them more precisely.

&quot;We see that as a big opportunity and are investing for it,&quot; he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51364853</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>Aston Martin: F1 billionaire owner leads rescue deal - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12694/production/_110421457_ai87rasy.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A consortium led by billionaire Lawrence Stroll will put in £182m, with the rest of the money coming from existing investors.

Mr Stroll partly owns the Racing Point Formula 1 team, which will be branded Aston Martin from 2021 under the deal.

The move comes hours after a board meeting held to discuss how to prop up the ailing firm.

Aston Martin's best known customer is fictional spy James Bond and the company recently revealed that four of its cars will feature in the next Bond movie, No Time To Die.

The carmaker said its latest financial moves were aimed at strengthening its balance sheet after its &quot;disappointing performance&quot; in 2019.

Mr Stroll's consortium will take a 20% stake in the company and he will become its executive chairman.

As a result, Penny Hughes will be stepping down as Aston Martin's chairman once the deal is completed.

It's all very well to build James Bond's company cars, but Aston Martin can't rely on a flashy brand alone.

Many of its troubles can be traced to the decision to build a new factory at St Athan in South Wales, where it will produce its long-anticipated sports utility vehicle, the DBX.

An ambitious move, it could have big long-term benefits for the carmaker.

But in the short term, it has been struggling to generate enough cash to pay its bills, including the costs of setting up the factory.

Dealers have been reducing stock rather than ordering new cars, while average selling prices have been falling, weighing on profits.

Last year, the company was forced to borrow £120m at a steep interest rate in order to prop up its operations. It had been facing the prospect of borrowing even more.

The new funding from Lawrence Stroll will give Aston Martin some much-needed stability. It now has breathing space in which to get the DBX into production, and implement a cost-cutting programme.

Meanwhile the Canadian billionaire will be able to put an Aston Martin badge on his F1 cars - opening up new opportunities both to burnish the brand and to exploit its petrol-scented cachet.

She said: &quot;The difficult trading performance in 2019 resulted in severe pressure on liquidity which has left the company with no alternative but to seek substantial additional equity financing.

&quot;Without this, the balance sheet is not robust enough to support the operations of the group.

&quot;Notwithstanding recent weak trading, the strength of the Aston Martin brand and our expanding portfolio of cars has allowed us to attract a strong new partner in Mr Stroll to support the turnaround of the business.&quot;

Earlier this month, the 106-year-old firm issued a profit warning, saying annual earnings were expected to fall by nearly half from a year earlier.

It said core retail sales - which covers sales from Aston Martin dealers to consumers - were up 12% from a year earlier. However, wholesale volumes - which covers how many cars the dealers are ordering from Aston Martin itself - were down 7% to 5,809.

The company said it was expecting earnings of between £130m and £140m, well below the £247.3m it reported last year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51323241</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-03 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>Work romance: 'I was sacked for falling in love' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/9CEB/production/_109517104_img_8461.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Australian businessman Gary Lyon still thinks it was &quot;bizarre&quot; that he lost his senior management job for dating a junior colleague.

But it all turned out for the best in the end - he has been married to Tamra for 12 years and they have an 11-year-old daughter, Charlotte.

Now Mr Lyon and his wife have their own company in Brisbane and he says he would be perfectly happy if two of his employees fell in love.

&quot;It wouldn't bother me in the slightest,&quot; he says, &quot;as long as it didn't affect their work.&quot;

Mr Lyon contacted the BBC after reading that McDonald's had fired its chief executive Steve Easterbrook after he had a relationship with an employee.

The US fast food giant said the relationship was consensual, but Mr Easterbrook had &quot;violated company policy&quot; and shown &quot;poor judgement&quot;.

The issue has shed light on the difficulties that staff can face if they find romance at work, especially if one is more senior than the other.

In Mr Lyon's case, he was an operations manager at a firm making doors and windows. He met the future Mrs Lyon when she joined his team as a project co-ordinator. After three or four months, they got together at an office function.

&quot;I always liked her and she made it known that she liked me as well,&quot; he said. &quot;It went from there.&quot;

At the time, he was 41 and she was 14 years younger. They initially kept the relationship secret, but eventually made it known that they were an item.

&quot;You don't believe it's an issue for other people, but it transpires that it is, and you don't see why, because it doesn't impact your work,&quot; he says.

&quot;You spend a lot of time with people at work, so you get to know them quite well.&quot;

After the couple had been seeing each other for about three months, he was called in and, as he puts it: &quot;Then the hammer dropped.&quot;

He lost his job, but she kept hers. &quot;She was pretty upset, but there's not much you can do. You've just got to keep going.&quot;

Mr Lyon says there was no clear workplace code in place about dating colleagues. He describes the decision as &quot;very arbitrary&quot; and says it represents &quot;a very archaic view of the world&quot;.

&quot;Should managers be banned from dating subordinates? Not if it is consensual,&quot; he says.

&quot;You can't choose where you find love, so why penalise both parties by firing one of them?&quot;

According to various studies, between a quarter and a third of all long-term relationships start at work.

But of course, not all liaisons between co-workers are long-term. Some are flings, affairs, one-night stands - whatever you want to call them.

And a number of high-profile cases serve as a reminder of just how tricky life can get when human passions collide with corporate culture:
• Chipmaker Intel's chief executive Brian Krzanich stepped down in June 2018 because he had contravened company rules by having a consensual relationship with an employee
• The boss of travel booking website Priceline.com, Darren Huston, resigned in April 2016 after an investigation uncovered his relationship with an employee
• But in October 2009, Aviva boss Andrew Moss kept his job despite admitting to a potentially compromising affair with an employee who was married to one of his senior executives. He eventually left the firm in May 2012.

At the same time, the sexual harassment allegations against disgraced film producer Harvey Weinstein have made HR departments wary of any sexual activity between staff, especially in the US.

However, Ben Willmott, head of public policy at the Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development, says only a minority of employers have specific stand-alone policies on relationships at work.

&quot;Most employers tend to take a different approach,&quot; he says. &quot;They will have policies on dignity and respect at work and preventing bullying and sexual harassment, setting out clear policies for dealing with complaints about inappropriate behaviour.&quot;

Mr Willmott points out that under the Human Rights Act in the UK, employees have a right to privacy and a family life, so firms need to strike a balance.

&quot;If you have a very prescriptive approach, it can suggest that you don't trust your employees to act as adults in the workplace,&quot; he says.

Of course, there is the potential for conflicts of interest if staff are not careful.

&quot;If one of the parties in the relationship is responsible for the other's appraisals, pay reviews, promotion opportunities and even work allocation, then there is danger of favouritism and from team members, perceived bias,&quot; says Rebecca Thornley-Gibson, partner at City of London law firm DMH Stallard.

&quot;There may also be issues where the more junior employee feels as though they cannot say no to amorous advances, and this creates a real risk of later sexual harassment claims against the manager and employer.&quot;

Stopping relationships is not likely to be practical for employers, she says, but having policies to minimise any fallout from the relationship should be considered.

&quot;This will involve having in place and communicating workplace policies on conduct at work, equality and diversity policies with a clear zero-tolerance towards sexual harassment, and also requiring employees to declare relationships that are likely to result in a potential conflict.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50287158</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
