<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: Chinese Grand Prix in doubt as Shanghai suspends sports events - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12BCC/production/_110784767_shanghai_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sports authorities in Shanghai have recommended the suspension of all sporting events in the city as a result of the coronavirus outbreak.

The move casts further doubt on the Chinese Grand Prix, scheduled to be held in Shanghai on 19 April.

Its viability will be discussed by Formula 1 bosses on Wednesday.

The Shanghai Sports General Association instructed sports bodies to suspend events until the threat from the virus is over.

They were told to &quot;formulate a plan for epidemic prevention to avoid internal infections&quot; and to &quot;implement a daily hygiene management system and strengthen health education to urge employees to protect themselves&quot;.

F1 was not immediately available for comment but, within the sport, there is a growing belief that the Chinese Grand Prix will have to be at least postponed from its scheduled date.

And with a record 22-race programme this season, finding a new date for it in an already crowded calendar would not be easy.

At an F1 event on Tuesday evening, unveiling the second series of the sport's collaboration with Netflix, some senior team insiders were even questioning whether the inaugural Vietnamese Grand Prix could be at risk.

That race is scheduled to be held on 5 April in the Vietnamese capital Hanoi, about 100 miles from the Chinese border.

However, there have been only 10 cases of the virus in Vietnam - two fewer than Australia and Germany - so the risk appears remote for now.

Chinese health authorities are stepping up efforts to control the spread of the virus, with approximately 18 million people in the east of the country now required to stay at home.

In Wuhan, the epicentre of the virus, 11 large public venues including sports arenas are being turned into makeshift hospitals to provide an additional 10,000 beds for the sick. Two new hospitals have been built there since the outbreak started.

The World Health Organisation has declared a global health emergency over the outbreak but said it did not yet constitute a &quot;pandemic&quot;, or the worldwide spread of a new disease.

However, the number of cases in China jumped by nearly 4,000 on Tuesday to more than 24,300, with another 65 deaths bringing the total to 490.

The virus outbreak has led to the cancellation of a number of sporting events in China, including the World Athletics Indoor Championships in Nanjing, scheduled for 13-15 March, and a race of the all-electric Formula E series in Sanya the following weekend.

Olympic organisers also say they are &quot;seriously concerned&quot; about the spread of the coronavirus and the impact it could have on the Tokyo Games in Japan this July and August.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51388857</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula 1: Renault's Pat Fry set to start in new role - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1208A/production/_110666837_patfry.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Pat Fry is to start work at Renault as their new chassis technical director on 5 February.

The announcement of his start date and official title follows the team's confirmation last November the 55-year-old engineer was joining them.

Fry, who has been on gardening leave from McLaren since last July, is a direct replacement for Renault's ousted former technical director Nick Chester.

Chester left after a disappointing 2019 season for the French team.

Renault started last season aiming to build on their fourth place in 2018 and move closer to the top three teams, but instead fell to fifth in the constructors' championship behind their engine customer McLaren.

Fry, who will attend the launch of Renault's 2020 F1 car in Paris on 12 February, brings a wealth of experience. Most recently, he played a significant role in McLaren's revival last season after joining them in the summer of 2018.

Fry has spent most of his career at McLaren, joining them in 1993 and rising to a role leading car design under technical director Paddy Lowe until he left the team in 2010 to join Ferrari.

He went to Ferrari as assistant technical director at the start of 2011, rising to director of chassis in May that year after the sacking of technical director Aldo Costa, who subsequently moved to Mercedes and became a leading figure in their domination of the last six years of F1.

Fry then in turn left Ferrari at the end of 2014, their first winless season since 1993.

He spent some time as a consultant for the now defunct Manor team in 2016-17 before returning to his most recent role at McLaren.

Joining Renault marks a return to his roots for Fry, who started his F1 career with what was then called the Benetton team in 1987 and stayed there until 1993, when he joined McLaren.

Fry will team up again with Renault sporting director Alan Permane, who worked with Fry during his first period at the team based in Enstone, Oxfordshire, and who has stayed there through its various guises since.

What started as Toleman in the early 1980s has since been known Benetton, Renault, Lotus and now Renault again since 2015.

Permane's current role puts him in charge of all race team operations under Renault F1 managing director Cyril Abiteboul, and executive director Marcin Budkowski.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51271577</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Charles Leclerc's Belgian GP win: 'Success comes with a darker side' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/6ED9/production/_108577382_lec-win_2_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Charles Leclerc demonstrated on Sunday - on the way to his long overdue maiden Formula 1 victory - the strength of character and psychological toughness that is an indispensable part of the make-up of a grand prix driver.

The 21-year-old took a win - at the Belgian Grand Prix under intense pressure from Lewis Hamilton - that should have come many months before against the backdrop of the death of a man he has known and raced against for much of his young life.

When Leclerc took part in his first ever motor race, one of his rivals was Anthoine Hubert, who was killed in an accident of horrific violence in Saturday's Formula 2 race at the daunting Spa-Francorchamps circuit.

Leclerc said - of himself, Toro Rosso driver Pierre Gasly and Mercedes reserve Esteban Ocon - &quot;we were four kids dreaming of F1 and we have grown up together. To lose him was a very big shock for me and everyone in motorsport and a very sad day&quot;.

Inevitably, it took the shine off what should have been one of the happiest days of Leclerc's life. To say the least.

&quot;It is very difficult to enjoy this first win with the situation we had yesterday. Overall it means just a dream come true. Since a child, I have been looking up to F1, dreaming of being first a Formula 1 driver, which happened last year and then driving for Ferrari this year and the first win today.

&quot;It is a good day but on the other hand losing Anthoine yesterday brings me back to 2005, my first French (karting) championship was him. It is very difficult to enjoy it fully today but hopefully in two or three weeks I will realise what happened today.&quot;
• Leclerc dedicates first win to Hubert in Belgium
• Hubert 'was one of the good guys'

How do the drivers do it?

Dealing with these sorts of events is part of the job description for a racing driver, as explained in my article on Saturday. But that does not make it easy or trivial.

For Leclerc, it is not the first time he has suffered a loss of someone close to him in his career. As is well documented, he was the godson of the former F1 driver Jules Bianchi, who suffered fatal head injuries in an accident at the Japanese Grand Prix nearly five years ago.

Leclerc has described many times how the death of Bianchi - who, at just eight years older than him, was more like a big brother, and who had been instrumental in guiding him through his formative years in the sport - simply made him more determined to succeed.

But it is one thing to say that, and quite another to actually go out and do it, and risk your own life in the same activity that killed someone so close.

On Sunday, after the race, Leclerc, Hamilton and Valtteri Bottas offered some insight into how they do that.

&quot;For everyone, I guess, but for me it was the first situation like that where we lose someone on a track where you need to race the day after,&quot; Leclerc said. &quot;It is obviously quite challenging to close the visor and go through this exact same corner at the same speed you did before, but that is what you have to do in the end.&quot;

Hamilton said: &quot;You compartmentalise it, move forwards, get in and do your job. From a racer's and an athlete's point of view, you switch into a zone, and it is quite easy to switch into that zone.&quot;

&quot;When you go to the zone,&quot; Bottas added. &quot;There are no distractions.&quot;

Their answers were short and subdued, and delivered uncomfortably, understandably in the circumstances. Perhaps it pays not to have to talk about it too much, especially when the wounds are so raw, the emotions so tangled and conflicted.

On Saturday, Hamilton had posted an eloquent message on social media, underlining the ever-present dangers of his profession, and how it can never be safe. After the race, his team boss Toto Wolff explained the background to the world champion's decision to do that.

&quot;It is very difficult to relate to what is happening in a car if you have never driven a race car at these speeds,&quot; Wolff said.

&quot;Whether it is in junior formulae, all the way to F1, in GT cars, or prototypes, it is still a gladiators' sport. It is still about courage, ability, risk-taking. But through a camera lens you will never realise what it feels like.

&quot;We were fortunate enough for many years to not have these kinds of accidents and maybe forgotten how dangerous the sport is. And this is what Lewis wanted to express. I can totally relate to it.

&quot;If you drive towards Eau Rouge with 260-270km/h, which looks like a 90-degree corner and you take it flat, it is beyond understanding that these guys do what they do and it can end fatally, like it did yesterday.&quot;

Leclerc would certainly not have chosen such circumstances for his first win, and he could probably have done with an easier race, for this was a victory hard won, against the toughest opposition there is.

Ferrari had dominated qualifying, their prodigious straight-line speed easily making up for their relative weakness compared to Mercedes in the corners of Spa's middle sector.

But their greater tyre wear was always likely to make things difficult in the race, and, as expected, Hamilton mounted an assault on the red cars that very nearly came off.

As Leclerc built a small lead over team-mate Sebastian Vettel in the first 10 laps, Hamilton remorselessly turned up the pressure on the German, who was struggling with his pace and his tyres.

Hamilton's proximity forced Ferrari into pitting Vettel earlier than they might have wanted, and from that moment his race was doomed, given Ferrari's tyre management.

It gave Vettel the on-track lead when Leclerc and Hamilton pitted a few laps later, and briefly Leclerc wondered if - yet again - a win would slip through his fingers, after previous disappointments in Bahrain, Azerbaijan and Austria.

But it soon became apparent that Vettel was in no fit state to hold him off. As Leclerc closed in at close to a second a lap, Ferrari ordered him to let his team-mate go.

Still, though, Vettel was able to have a hand in his team-mate's win. He managed to hold Hamilton off for four laps, giving Leclerc a chance to build a small advantage over the Mercedes, which it soon became clear he needed.

Had either Vettel not held Hamilton back for as long as he did, or had Mercedes pitted Hamilton a lap earlier, on the same lap as Leclerc, the world champion might have won the race, given he ended it on Leclerc's tail. But the Monegasque did just enough.

&quot;If you would have given me a second and third in Spa,&quot; Mercedes team boss Wolff said, &quot;I would have taken it before the race because we know that our package compared to the Ferraris with the straight-line speed is inferior.

&quot;Having said that, if we had really optimised our race, which you can only do post-race by being super-intelligent and saying what could have been, maybe we could have pitted one or two laps earlier. Maybe the pit stop could have been a little bit quicker and we would have been in his gearbox for the last two laps.

&quot;But there are so many ifs that I am satisfied with second and third.&quot;

Traditionally, a first win is the moment that an F1 driver really announces themselves as a true contender in F1. For Leclerc, though, it's different. That came long ago.

It has been clear for some time that this was a man who was likely to become a major part of F1 over the next decade. His debut season for Sauber last year was outstanding, and although he has made a few too many mistakes, and his ability is clearly still raw in certain aspects, his second in the white-heat pressure of Ferrari has been no less so.

Many suspected that he would give Vettel a serious run for his money this year and so it has proved.

Leclerc has now out-qualified the four-time champion for the last six races in a row. Over the season so far, he is faster than Vettel over one lap on average by 0.13secs. He has three pole positions to Vettel's one, and now he has become the first Ferrari driver to win a race.

Admittedly, Vettel should have won in Canada, but for his error and subsequent controversial penalty, but had his season gone slightly differently this could have been Leclerc's third or even fourth victory.

He is slowly but surely establishing himself as Ferrari's lead driver, a situation that is extremely uncomfortable for Vettel, given his statistical success and general status in the sport. And Vettel now faces a very serious task sustaining his standing.

As the season has progressed, the respect between Hamilton and Leclerc has been clear. Leclerc clearly admires Hamilton for his ability and his success. And Hamilton, who has treated the younger man with warmth, has not troubled to hide his regard for Leclerc's talent and potential.

&quot;His results speak for themselves, really,&quot; Hamilton said. &quot;It's not easy for any driver to jump into a top team, let alone Ferrari, against a four-time world champion, God knows how much more experience. Then to continuously from race one, out-perform, out-qualify and out-drive a four-time world champion is not easy to do.

&quot;He's been really unlucky in quite a few races this year. Could easily have been the third win today. So, there's a lot more greatness to come from him and I'm looking forward to seeing his growth and racing alongside him. It was fun today, trying to chase him. He was just a little bit too quick.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/49545988</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: F1 governing body will 'take action' on race calendar after outbreak - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1152F/production/_110695907_chinesegrandprixindex_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Formula 1's governing body says the Chinese Grand Prix is at risk in the wake of the coronavirus outbreak in the country.

A statement from the FIA said it was &quot;monitoring the evolving situation&quot;.

It said it would &quot;evaluate the calendar of its forthcoming races and take any action required to help protect the global motorsport community and the wider public.&quot;

The Chinese Grand Prix is scheduled to be held in Shanghai on 19-21 April.

Before that, the FIA is responsible for a race of the all-electric Formula E series in Sanya on 21 March.

Shanghai is about 500 miles from the centre of the coronavirus outbreak in Wuhan, while Sanya is around 1,000 miles away.

Chinese health authorities have said there were 7,711 confirmed cases in the country as of 29 January. Infections have also spread to at least 15 other countries.

The World Health Organization will meet on Thursday to again consider whether the virus constitutes a global health emergency.

The death toll from the coronavirus outbreak has risen to 170, and a confirmed case in Tibet means it has reached every region in mainland China.

On Wednesday, the UK Foreign Office adjusted its travel advice to warn against all non-essential travel to China and British Airways cancelled all flights to the mainland of the country.

The FIA's statement comes a day after the F1 Groups said it was &quot;monitoring the situation in China closely&quot; in tandem with the race promoter and motorsport's governing body the FIA and that the move came &quot;in light of official advice from the British Foreign Office&quot;.

On past evidence, the F1 authorities will wait as long as possible before making a decision to call off or postpone the race.

They will be hoping that the virus outbreak is under control before they have to make a call on whether the race should be held as scheduled.

The last grand prix to be cancelled as a result of an emergency situation in the host country was the 2011 Bahrain Grand Prix, after protests erupted in the Middle Eastern state as part of the Arab spring.

Hundreds of British citizens are being flown back to the UK from Wuhan on Thursday and will be put in quarantine for up to two weeks following their arrival.

Australia, Japan, the US and European Union nations are also repatriating citizens.

The Chinese Grand Prix is not the only sporting event under threat from the virus outbreak.

On Wednesday, The World Indoor Athletics Championships, which had been due to be held in Nanjing on 13-15 March, was postponed for a year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51294416</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula 1: Williams sign Aitken as reserve driver - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12346/production/_110766547_jackaitken.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Briton Jack Aitken has joined Williams as its reserve driver this year.

The 24-year-old, Renault's reserve and test driver for the past two years, will run in one practice session at a grand prix during the year.

He will attend all the races in his role, and could replace drivers George Russell and Nicholas Latifi if one of them is injured or ill and cannot race.

Aitken, who will also work in Williams' simulator through the year, described joining Williams as &quot;a great honour&quot;.

Deputy team principal Claire Williams said: &quot;It is obvious from what Jack has achieved so far he is a young driver with a great career ahead of him and we believe he has the right credentials to reach the top in the sport.

&quot;Jack has proved his ability in FIA Formula 2 and GP3 and we look forward to seeing what he can achieve as the team's official reserve driver.&quot;

Aitken won three races in F2 last year on his way to fifth in the championship, and before that was runner-up in GP3 in 2017.

Williams team have been struggling for the past two seasons, finishing last in both 2018 and 2019, and last year were well adrift of the rest of the field.

Their aim for this season is to improve at least to the point where they can race regularly with other cars, which was usually not the case last year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51374260</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula 1: Red Bull &amp; Honda title contenders in 2020? Jolyon Palmer - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/14158/production/_109746228_verstappenandgasly.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former F1 driver Jolyon Palmer is part of the BBC team and offers insight and analysis from the point of view of the competitors.

Only a hit from Lewis Hamilton put a taint on Red Bull's day at the Brazilian Grand Prix.

As Alexander Albon was sent spinning out of second place behind team-mate Max Verstappen on the penultimate lap, it ruined the team's chance of a double podium, or perhaps even a one-two finish.

Albon's misfortune, though, did promote former Red Bull driver Pierre Gasly - now back at Toro Rosso after his demotion mid-season - into second place. That gave Red Bull's junior team their second podium of the year, after Daniil Kvyat's third place in Germany, and engine partner Honda the biggest boost of all.

Not only did Honda get a one-two, but they achieved the second place in the best manner possible for an engine manufacturer - a drag race to the line, against the formerly dominant Mercedes power.

Gasly hung on around the outside against Hamilton on the flat-out sprint from Juncao corner to the finish line, against the odds, and claimed his first Formula 1 podium. In doing so, Gasly showed Honda are well and truly in the fight now.

Of course it counted for very little in Brazil, but if Red Bull can do what they've so far failed to do in the hybrid era - start the following season as competitive as they finish the last - then the Verstappen/Red Bull/Honda package could be a force to be reckoned with in 2020.

For Honda in particular, this was a moment that must have caused such joy. It was only four years ago that McLaren drivers Fernando Alonso and Jenson Button publicly mocked them by ironically stepping out onto the Interlagos podium after yet another woeful qualifying display, to the amusement of fans and the bemusement of Honda.

In truth, Honda were poor back in 2015. They took a lot of stick, but the unreliability and lack of performance were clear for all to see.

Four years later, they are back with two drivers on the same podium, only with none of the mocking irony, just pure ecstatic emotion. A turnaround complete.

Honda were dragged through the mud during the Alonso and McLaren years, but since teaming up with Toro Rosso last year, and now Red Bull in 2019, their performance improvements have been vast.

I bet if you had told Alonso this would happen when he parted ways with the engine manufacturer at the end of 2017, he would have laughed in your face.

So with the regulations staying stable for 2020, there should be every chance that Red Bull can challenge over the course of the season.

Albon - good but can still do better

Verstappen is driving absolutely at the top of his game right now. A year ago, he was already well on this trajectory, and displayed it by comfortably getting the better of then team-mate Daniel Ricciardo.

Ricciardo is a top driver, proven by his seven career race wins. He won twice for Red Bull last year and took two pole positions as well.

But aside from those pole positions, he actually out-qualified Verstappen only twice more all year, in Baku and in the Abu Dhabi season finale.

This illustrates why some suggested last year that when Ricciardo signed for Renault he was running away from the Verstappen fight - the Dutchman out-paced Ricciardo in qualifying by a fraction under 0.2 seconds on average.

Red Bull have had a headache in replacing him.

They initially chose Gasly, but, after he struggled in the first half of the season, he was replaced by Albon, who it has now been confirmed will keep the seat in 2020.

Albon has undoubtedly been stronger in the Red Bull than Gasly, and would have been on the podium in Brazil had it not been for Hamilton's overzealous passing attempt into Bico de Pato on the penultimate lap. But his qualifying deficit to Verstappen is 0.42secs - more than twice that of Ricciardo.

Albon has been impressive in race conditions, to an extent. His race-craft has been particularly strong since he joined Red Bull, often charging from the back of the grid after a penalty to finish on the back of the main race, and he has made some sumptuous overtakes - including around the outside of Ferrari's Sebastian Vettel in Brazil.

But at the moment he still seems unable to make any inroads into the 'A' race. While Verstappen took pole position and was heading to victory in Brazil, Albon qualified sixth and was heading for a finish there until Valtteri Bottas' Mercedes engine expired and mixed up the race.

All the while Albon has been doing OK - but perhaps not quite progressing as well as Red Bull would have hoped after a strong opener in Belgium - Gasly has been sensational back in the Toro Rosso.

Since being demoted after the summer break, Gasly has been in the points in five out of eight races, which would have been six without a late incident in Austin two weeks ago.

He has out-qualified Kvyat in every race bar Mexico, where he lost out by 0.1secs. His average qualifying pace is now 0.3secs faster than the Russian and he has made it through into the top 10 qualifying shootout in the past four races.

Had Gasly never been called up to Red Bull in the first place, he would seem a shoo-in for a 2020 berth at the team. Sadly for him, his dismal start to the season meant Albon was the obvious choice.

But for Red Bull to be truly competitive in 2020, they will need two cars in the fight, which has never really happened since Ricciardo left at the end of last year.

Time and time again, when the field is closely matched, we see races won or lost on strategy. In Hungary, Gasly was a lap behind Verstappen, and so too far back to stop Mercedes doing the extra pit stop that led to Hamilton attacking and eventually passing for the win.

In Brazil, Albon was at least within a pit-stop distance of Hamilton for much of the race, meaning the Briton would have to pass him and lose out on track position if he pitted in his attack on Verstappen for the win. But in all honesty he was no true deterrent because he was too far back and would have been a sitting duck for Hamilton on fresh tyres anyway.

Albon has definitely got some potential, and finishing on the podium in Brazil would have done him a world of good before he begins next season with the main team.

Right now, though, there is still work for him to do on the whole if he is going to get himself into the main fight with the five other drivers from the big teams.

With Kvyat and Gasly being quickly discarded by Red Bull, Albon will probably feel under some pressure, particularly with Gasly coming back into fine form in the Toro Rosso.

But Red Bull themselves will be desperate for Albon to be a success in the main team. After two demotions from their past three promotions, there are question marks over their once formidable junior driver programme.

The question marks about Red Bull's second driver are not helped by the superb form of their former employee Carlos Sainz, who also claimed his first F1 podium in Brazil following Hamilton's post-race penalty - and did so after starting dead last following an engine issue in qualifying.

They won't admit it, but I'm sure there are many at Red Bull who are not only ruing the fact Ricciardo left, but also not taking Sainz in the first place as replacement for the Aussie.

Sainz is comfortably best of the rest behind the top teams this season. He is in a battle with both Albon and Gasly for sixth in the championship, and must be favourite to finish there, despite the others being in the far superior Red Bull for half a season apiece.

Sainz pushed Verstappen hard when they were together at Toro Rosso in 2015 and 2016. If only he was there doing that now, the Red Bull team would be a lot more formidable than the Verstappen show it currently is.

But there is still a chance for Albon to prove Red Bull motorsport boss Helmut Marko and the rest of the hierarchy right.

After all, he is still a rookie for another race. And perhaps now having a future guaranteed - in the short term at least - can provide him a bit more comfort and confidence heading into a winter break that will be so critical to both him and the team if they are to be genuine 2020 challengers.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50455347</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Lewis Hamilton has weaknesses, says Fernando Alonso - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/121CB/production/_110678147_lewishamiltonandfernandoalonso.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lewis Hamilton has &quot;raised his level&quot; in the last two seasons but still has weaknesses others are not exploiting, according to Fernando Alonso.

Alonso, who left F1 at the end of 2018 and is pondering a return in 2021, says it would be &quot;nice&quot; to test Hamilton.

The Spaniard told F1 Racing magazine: &quot;He's made a step forward - he is more competitive, more prepared.

&quot;He still has some weak points that have not been stressed yet - no-one is pressing that button, that weakness.&quot;

The two-time F1 champion said Hamilton's superiority over his Mercedes team-mate Valtteri Bottas was obvious from the weekends when the car was not competitive.

He added that Hamilton had not been tested under moments of extreme pressure in recent seasons.

&quot;He's raised the level the last couple of years, especially in 2019 when the car has not been as dominant as other seasons,&quot; said Alonso, who tied on points with Hamilton when they were McLaren team-mates in a tumultuous 2007 season.

&quot;If he cannot win, he's a very close second - not 20 seconds further back, which is what happens a little bit with Valtteri.

&quot;A weekend when the car is not as competitive, Bottas is fifth or sixth or a minute behind - but Lewis is not.

&quot;If you study Lewis' season, there is always a common trend. He starts the year slowly and no-one takes the benefit of that. We all get excited that it will be the year of Bottas, but it's not.

&quot;It would be nice to compete against him in a proper fight. Maybe his weak points are not real and everything is calculated but it would be nice to discover.

&quot;When you have a good package and the other guys crash and you extend your championship lead, everything seems calm.

&quot;If you are only one point behind or 10 points behind, the stress is different. The mistakes are different and your radio communications are different. We need to see him when the pressure is on.&quot;

This last remark can be seen as a veiled criticism of Ferrari driver Sebastian Vettel, who was Hamilton's main title rival in 2017 and 2018 but whose campaigns were damaged by a series of driver errors.

Alonso, who lost out on the 2010 and 2012 titles to Vettel at the last race of season in agonising circumstances, does not rate the German on as high a level as he does Hamilton.

The 38-year-old, whose last four seasons in F1 were spent in an uncompetitive McLaren, has made it clear he is open to a return to F1 in 2021 if the right opportunity arises, and believes the new rules being introduced next year should close up the field.

However, his chances of finding a seat at one of the top three teams look slim - Red Bull and Ferrari have recently signed Max Verstappen and Charles Leclerc to long-term contracts and have invested in them as their main hopes for the next few seasons.

Hamilton, who turned 35 this month and is aiming to equal Michael Schumacher's all-time record of seven world titles this year, is expected to sign a new deal to stay at Mercedes for at least another two years after the end of his current contract this season.

That leaves Renault as Alonso's most likely option should he decide to return to F1 in a year in which he will turn 40 in the summer.

Alonso this month finished 13th on his debut at the Dakar Rally desert endurance event and is next likely to be seen in competitive action on the world stage at the Indianapolis 500.

Insiders say he is close to securing a deal to race for the Andretti team in his third attempt at the race in May.

Alonso drove for Andretti, in a McLaren-branded car, when he made an impressive debut at Indy in 2017, qualifying seventh and leading for 24 laps before retiring with an engine failure in the closing stages.

He returned to Indy last year with a new McLaren team, but the escapade turned into an embarrassment for McLaren, who admitted a series of mistakes and are entering Indycar racing with a dedicated team this year. Alonso's contract as a McLaren ambassador, which forbade him racing for rival teams, ended on 31 December 2019.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51283816</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula 1 2020 car launch &amp; testing schedule - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12D45/production/_110552177_mercedes.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Formula 1 teams are putting together their new cars before the first race of the new season in Australia on 15 March.

The teams kick off pre-season testing at Barcelona in Spain on 19 February before returning for a second session later in the month.

There will be live BBC Sport live text commentary on all six days of the two tests.

Teams will launch their cars at different points up to testing - check back for pictures and insight into each team's 2020 designs.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50978002</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Chinese Grand Prix: Red Bull boss Christian Horner 'trusts' F1 bosses over coronavirus decision - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1824F/production/_110759889_gettyimages-1142590155.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Red Bull team boss Christian Horner says he &quot;trusts the judgement&quot; of the Formula 1 authorities over whether to cancel the Chinese Grand Prix.

The race, due to be held in Shanghai on 19 April, is in doubt as result of the coronavirus outbreak in China.

Horner said he was confident F1's bosses would &quot;make the necessary due diligence about maybe delaying, postponing or cancelling the race&quot;.

He added: &quot;But we keep a very close eye on the situation.&quot;

Horner said he expected the coronavirus outbreak, which has been declared a global health emergency, would be on the agenda of Wednesday's meeting of F1's strategy group, a forum at which governing body the FIA and commercial rights holder Liberty Media discuss active issues in the sport.

He said that if the situation remained as it is now, teams could not attend the race &quot;because we couldn't get there&quot;.

The UK Foreign Office is advising against all non-essential travel to the Chinese mainland and British Airways have cancelled all flights.

Red Bull driver Max Verstappen said: &quot;At the moment, it doesn't look good but it is a long way away. I am not too worried about it. We just wait for the decision and see what happens.&quot;

On Sunday, the all-electric Formula E series became the latest sporting competition to be affected by the outbreak when it called off its race scheduled for Sanya in southern China on 21 March.

The 2020 World Athletics Indoor Championships in Nanjing have been postponed for 12 months, while badminton's China Masters is to be rescheduled from its original February date.

The FIA said last week it was &quot;monitoring the evolving situation&quot; and that it would &quot;evaluate the calendar of its forthcoming races and take any action required to help protect the global motorsport community and the wider public&quot;.

UK Health Secretary Matt Hancock said on Monday that the coronavirus would &quot;be with us for at least some months to come&quot;.

There have so far been more than 17,000 confirmed cases of the virus in China and some 361 people have died there.

Outside China, there are more than 150 confirmed cases of the virus and one death, in the Philippines.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51362823</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Red Bull's Max Verstappen says he can beat Lewis Hamilton with the right car - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/EE4E/production/_110760016_gettyimages-1185808102.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Red Bull's Max Verstappen says he can beat Lewis Hamilton to this year's world championship as long as his car is good enough.

The Dutchman, 22, thinks his team can &quot;mount a challenge to Mercedes&quot;.

&quot;Lewis is very good. He is definitely one of the best out there but he is not God. Maybe God is with him, but he is not God,&quot; Verstappen said.

Asked if he could beat Hamilton, he said: &quot;Yes. It is very car-dependent, of course.&quot;

Verstappen said he believed Hamilton and Mercedes were vulnerable if Red Bull could put them under more pressure.

&quot;When you can put the pressure on, of course it is a lot harder for the guy in the lead,&quot; Verstappen said.

&quot;If you never really have pressure, you can drive at 97-98% and you never make mistakes, or maybe one weekend out of 21-22.

&quot;Even if we start within 0.2secs, you can really mount the pressure and I would like to start straight away there because then it is really on.

&quot;I know that when everything is put together, as a team, under pressure situations like in Brazil for example - but also other difficult situations like in Germany [where Verstappen won in the wet and Hamilton and Mercedes made a series of errors] - you can see that the team is really excelling compared to the others.

&quot;I am looking forward to when we get that fight and we are really close; I am pretty sure we can do better.&quot;

Last year, Hamilton admitted he gave Verstappen more room when they were racing closely together because of the Dutchman's reputation for aggressive driving.

But Verstappen said he did not believe that necessarily gave him an advantage over Hamilton.

&quot;If you looked at Brazil, we just raced hard and very cleanly,&quot; Verstappen said.

&quot;From my side, I know I race hard but it is because I always want to try to get the best result out of it, and I have always done so.

&quot;But when you fight for a title it is a different mentality. We were not in that fight so you know you have a few races when you can possibly win so you try everything to win that.

&quot;It is a different mindset you have to be in and Lewis has been really good at that to judge when you have to go all out, when you have to be more conservative. So it depends a bit on the situation you're in.&quot;

Red Bull believe that stability in the rules going into 2020 will give them the chance to pick up from a strong finish to last season.

Verstappen won three races in 2019, their first season with engine partner Honda, and finished third in the championship behind Mercedes drivers Hamilton and Valtteri Bottas.

Red Bull finished the year on a high: Verstappen took pole position in Mexico, before losing it to a penalty for ignoring yellow flags; finished a strong third close behind the Mercedes in the USA; and then took pole and victory in the penultimate race in Brazil, where he passed Hamilton twice on track. Verstappen then finished second to Hamilton in the season finale in Abu Dhabi.

Verstappen added: &quot;We have to wait and see in winter testing but I am very much looking forward to it. Everyone is very fired up and motivated, especially coming off the end of last year.&quot;

Their new car will run for the first time in a shakedown test at Silverstone on 12 February ahead of the start of pre-season testing in Spain a week later.

Verstappen heads into 2020 with his future secure having agreed in December a new contract with Red Bull until 2023. The situation mirrors that of his fellow young star Charles Leclerc at Ferrari, who extended his deal to 2024 a few days later, while Hamilton is out of contract at the end of this season.

Verstappen adds: &quot;I always felt very comfortable in the team, and it all went very quickly.

&quot;I never really thought about it too much last year and we solved it over the winter time, and that's a good thing because it takes away any doubts.

&quot;There are no question marks, because when you go into a season when your contract is up at the end of the year, at one point it is going to be maybe a bit awkward [when you are looking] towards the next car and I didn't want to have any of that.

&quot;For me this is the right place. I feel really good in the team. There are a lot of good people in the team and I see the motivation and hunger to fight for victories and a championship possibly.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula-one/51362822</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Miami Grand Prix: Formula 1 makes further changes to plans for Florida race - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1E2D/production/_109252770_miami_f1_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Formula 1 has made further changes to its plans for a Miami Grand Prix in the hope of overturning objections to the race from locals.

F1 was forced to abandon the original location for the race, which was in the downtown area and over a bridge.

But the latest attempt to secure a deal for a race around the Miami Dolphins' NFL stadium has also hit snags.

The changes come before a crucial meeting of Miami-Dade county commissioners on Wednesday.

At that meeting, commissioners will vote on a proposal to change the stadium's zoning rights and withdraw its rights to hold motor racing, which would have the effect of preventing the grand prix from taking place.

F1 has been consulting residents and various stakeholders in Miami as it seeks to persuade locals to back the grand prix.

Those talks have led to another new track configuration, and alters the race weekend schedule so there is no on-track action before 15:00 local time on the Friday of the race weekend, to avoid disrupting local schools.

F1 said in a statement it had &quot;provided substantial scientific evidence proving there are no credible health threats to local residents caused by the racing&quot;.

It added: &quot;However, a primary concern voiced by residents related to the use of a stretch of Northwest 199th Street for a portion of the racetrack and the disruption it would cause to local traffic on 199th Street.&quot;

Tom Garfinkel, the Miami Dolphins and Hard Rock Stadium vice-chairman and CEO, said: &quot;Like the Super Bowl, an event like this provides a unique opportunity to proudly showcase our region to the world. We want these events to benefit everyone in the region, including local Miami Gardens residents.&quot;

The developments on Tuesday are the latest steps in a long-running saga as F1 seeks to establish a race in what departing commercial boss Sean Bratches calls a &quot;destination city&quot; in America.

Bratches, one of three senior executives appointed when US group Liberty Media took over the sport in 2017, leaves his post at the end of this month and will not be directly replaced.

F1 chairman and chief executive Chase Carey said at the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix at the end of last season the sport had other possibilities in America if Miami fell through.

Carey said: &quot;We are engaged in other opportunities in the US and that's not a negative statement about Miami. We are in the final stages of getting over the line or not. We have the luxury of demand that exceeds supply.&quot;

One of the other possibilities is known to be Las Vegas, where F1's former boss Bernie Ecclestone sought on and off for nearly 30 years to hold a race on a track that includes the famous strip but never managed to pull it off.

Ecclestone also failed in his attempts in the last decade to secure a race in New Jersey overlooking the Manhattan skyline.

F1 already has one race in America - the popular and successful US Grand Prix at the Circuit of the Americas in Austin, Texas.

But Liberty is determined to establish at least one further race in the States as F1 seeks to strengthen its position in a marketplace where it has for decades struggled to break through into the national consciousness.

Carey has said he would also like to have a race in Africa, and F1 is also looking for a second race in China to add to the existing Chinese Grand Prix in Shanghai.

This year, the calendar features two new races - one, the revival of the Dutch Grand Prix at Zandvoort, which was last held in 1985, and another the inaugural race in Vietnam, to be held in the capital Hanoi.

That takes the schedule to a record 22 Grands Prix, but new rules now give Liberty the option to extend the calendar to as many as 25 races.

Many teams are not keen on expanding the calendar further - some feel it is already too long - and there have been warnings about the risks of damaging F1's exclusivity by holding too many races.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51201068</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Lewis Hamilton yet to talk to Mercedes over contract - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/11F62/production/_110707537_lewishamilton.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lewis Hamilton says he is yet to start talks with Mercedes over a new contract with the team beyond 2020.

The six-time world champion's deal with Mercedes runs out at the end of this season and Ferrari have admitted they have held talks with the Briton.

Hamilton said on Instagram that he and Mercedes F1 boss Toto Wolff &quot;have not even spoken about contract yet. Nothing is being negotiated currently.&quot;

He was responding to reports that negotiations had broken down.

Hamilton, referring to a report in Italy that talks had stalled over his demands, added: &quot;Papers making up stories.&quot;

The 35-year-old is still on his winter break and has been posting videos on his social media in recent days of him training and enjoying time with his father, Anthony, on what looks like a tropical island.

Hamilton has previously given equivocal statements about his future, saying at the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix at the end of last season: &quot;I love where I am, so it is definitely not a quick decision to go and do something else.

&quot;But it is only smart and wise to sit and think about what I want if it is the last phase of my career. Naturally I want to keep winning, I can't tell you what will happen going forwards.&quot;

In Abu Dhabi, Wolff put the chances of Hamilton staying at Mercedes at 75%, saying: &quot;From the rational side everything speaks for continuation of the relationship from both sides. But equally there is a 25% chance we are not in control of. So we see how the next months pan out.&quot;

Negotiations over a new contract have to be done face to face and, in the past, Hamilton has only started talks with Wolff once he returned from his pre-season training regime ahead of winter testing, which starts in Spain on 19 February. The season begins with the Australian Grand Prix on 13-15 March.

That is expected to be the case again this year, with the timing for any meetings dependent on their collective responsibility to ensure the team are as well prepared for the new season as possible.

Hamilton has the chance to equal Michael Schumacher's all-time record of seven drivers' titles this year.

Both are understood to have the intention to continue working together and it should be a question of refining the details of the contract until both are happy.

But it is inevitable that the situation will drag on for some months as Hamilton and Wolff navigate the busy schedule of an F1 season and their commitments.

If Hamilton had any thoughts of potentially leaving Mercedes, his views may be affected by the decisions by Ferrari and Red Bull to sign Charles Leclerc and Max Verstappen on to long-term contracts over the winter.

Leclerc is committed to Ferrari until 2024 and Verstappen to Red Bull until 2023, suggesting both teams see the drivers - the two biggest young stars in the sport - as their future.

Meanwhile, Ola Kallenius, the chairman of Mercedes' parent company Daimler, has dismissed reports that its board is poised to discuss pulling out of F1.

Reuters asked Kallenius at a Germany Auto Industry reception in Berlin on Wednesday if Mercedes were planning to leave F1. He replied: &quot;Not true.&quot;

The report was by the British car-industry magazine Autocar and the racefans.net website, who said the issue would be discussed at a board meeting which it said would be on 12 February.

BBC Sport understands there is no board meeting scheduled for that date.

Mercedes, like nearly all F1 teams, has a contract with the sport that lasts only until the end of 2020.

The teams and F1 have been in negotiations for more than two years over the future shape of the sport.

New technical, sporting and financial regulations for 2021 were finalised last year but the terms of a new revenue distribution and governance system have yet to be agreed.

Mercedes have won the last six drivers' and constructors' titles in F1.

The car company said this month that its earnings halved in 2019 and that it faced charges of up to €1.5bn (£1.269bn) related to the diesel emissions scandal.

The company this year made its official debut in the all-electric Formula E series.

However, Kallenius said in an investor call last November that F1 was good value for the brand.

&quot;F1 has been an activity in terms of our marketing and branding strategy that has paid off handsomely in the last few years,&quot; he said.

&quot;You have to look at these investments in a rational way.

&quot;We weigh all our marketing and media investment in terms of reach, impact and cost.

&quot;If you use the Nielsen method to measure the media value of our F1 activities, they are north of €1bn a year, so an extreme reach and impact from this activity and the costs that we would not like to disclose publicly are surprising low because there is a cost and revenue side in F1. We are committed.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51312738</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Davos 2020: Can Formula 1 really go 'carbon neutral' by 2030? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12220/production/_110627247_8fbd9c4a-877e-4550-b085-fa8dbf542679.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It is no secret that Formula 1 racing is a polluting sport, or that its previous owner Bernie Ecclestone wasn't particularly interested in sustainability.

But things have changed since the elite motor-racing series was taken over by US media giant Liberty Media in 2017. Last year F1 announced its first ever sustainability plan, with an ambitious goal to make itself &quot;carbon neutral&quot; by 2030.

When I meet Yath Gangakumaran - the man responsible for leading the plan - at the World Economic Forum in Davos, he is keen to distance himself from sport's old guard, although he won't comment on Mr Ecclestone's tenure.

&quot;Up until 10-15 years ago sport wasn't run in a mature way - typically by ex-players not business professionals. It's become much more professional and is catching up with other industries, and that includes on sustainability.&quot;
• Lewis Hamilton on his mission to be 'carbon neutral'

Formula 1's carbon footprint is &quot;material&quot;, he says, but it has little to do with the cars, which are among the most fuel efficient on the planet thanks to their lightweight design and innovative hybrid engines.

The main problem are the races themselves - 22 in total this year - which require large amounts of equipment, cars and people to be shipped around the world, often by aircraft. In 2019, the sport's 10 teams each notched up an average of 110,000 air miles.

Then there is the huge amount of C02 emissions generated by F1's 500 million fans globally who will travel far and wide to see the sport.

It makes the 2030 target seem wildly ambitious, but as F1's director of strategy Mr Gangakumaran is bullish: &quot;There is no point just throwing out a target and having it as a marketing gimmick. Ultimately you will be held accountable, and so you should.&quot;

The former Sky Sports executive, who is only 31, seems sincere, but there are parts of Formula 1's plan that raise questions.

First to note is that the plan will only target emissions generated by the activities of the F1 business - which manages the series - and the individual teams who compete.

That amounts to some 256,000 CO2 equivalent tonnes per year, according to Liberty Media, which calculated F1's carbon footprint for the first time ever last year.

But the plan won't cover emissions generated by fans - the much bigger part of the problem. When they are accounted for, F1's footprint rises to some 1.9 million CO2 equivalent tonnes.

&quot;We think it is just too difficult to control what our fans do because they are ultimately their own custodians. So we think it is most appropriate and achievable to focus on what we do have control over,&quot; says Mr Gangakumaran.

That said, Liberty will encourage fans to use public transport to get to Formula 1 events, or to offset their air travel if they fly. It has also pledged to make races sustainable by 2025, including banning single-use plastics.

The sport will also continue to fly its operation around the world, and while Mr Gangakumaran says its absolute carbon footprint will decrease, it will have to rely on some carbon offsetting.

This may anger the fiercest environmental campaigners, who view offsetting - for instance, by planting trees to compensate for your emissions - as a cop out.

But Mr Gangakumaran says the business will keep it to a minimum and has to be realistic. &quot;We are a global sport and we have fans around the world who want to see F1. That requires travel.&quot;

The business also plans to spend more on transferring its own sustainable technologies to the wider world - something it has a strong record of.

In its 70-year history, Formula 1 has pioneered ground-breaking aerodynamics and efficient brake systems that have found their way into everyday road cars.

Other industries have benefited too. Take the way an F1-inspired aerofoil attached to chiller cabinets has cut refrigeration costs by about 15% in some supermarkets.

The strip, the result of a collaboration between Williams Advanced Engineering and Aerofoil Energy, was rolled out by Sainsbury's across its 1,400 supermarkets and convenience stores in 2017.

Professor Mark Jenkins, an F1 expert at Cranfield University, says Liberty Media's 2030 goal is highly ambitious and should be lauded. &quot;But whether it is achievable is another question.&quot;

He notes that Formula 1 has increased its number of races from 21 to 22 this year, while Mr Gangakumaran concedes there are plans for several more.

Prof Jenkins says: &quot;One of the obvious ways to reduce the carbon footprint would be reduce the number of races. But F1 also needs to increase its sales so there is a tension there.&quot;

In addition, the sport will introduce a cost cap in 2022 as it looks to even out competition between teams. The three that dominate - Mercedes, Red Bull and Ferrari - will be hit the hardest.

&quot;It will limit what they can spend at a time when they are also being asked to become more sustainable. Is that really wise?&quot; says Prof Jenkins.

Liberty Media's contracts with its F1 teams are up for renewal at the end of this year.

But Mr Gangakumaran says the firm is in advanced discussions and he is quietly confident the teams will re-sign.

He adds that Liberty has factored in the growing number of races into its carbon reduction plan, and that there will only one or two more. Becoming more sustainable could actually save F1 money, he adds.

All eyes will be on F1 as it works towards its goal. It also faces stiff competition in the sustainability stakes from events such as the World Cup, which could become carbon neutral by 2022.

&quot;You can't say anything is 100% but we wouldn't be putting these targets out there if they weren't ambitious enough or we didn't think we could achieve them,&quot; Mr Gangakumaran says. &quot;Most importantly our fans are totally behind us on this.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51226066</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Heather Watson column: Fed Cup player on feeling 'confident' with her game - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Tennis</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/14AF8/production/_110782748_heatherwatsonindex.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>British number two Heather Watson writes in her BBC Sport column about preparing to lead Great Britain's Fed Cup team for the match against Slovakia on 7-8 February.

This time last year I was watching the Fed Cup from my bed - it was a really bad experience for me.

It was such a shame - after playing Fed Cup for all those years I had never been part of a home tie. And then we were finally at home in Bath but I was literally bed-bound for the whole week with illness, even afterwards as well.

I was live-streaming all the girls' matches every day, they just did so well. Then in April I was part of the team that won the tie against Kazakhstan at the Copper Box in London, and that was an amazing experience.

A year on from Bath, I am coming into this week's tie against Slovakia feeling really happy. It will be my 32nd tie and if we win, we will get through to April's first ever Fed Cup Finals in Budapest.

This time round I am playing as the number one player for Great Britain because Johanna Konta won't be there. I've played number one before a few times so it doesn't feel too different, and I'm just really excited about the matches this week.

I know the girls in the team really well. We're all equal and we're good friends, so being number one doesn't make it any different in that sense.

Jo is a really good friend of mine so I was sad when she said she wasn't playing this year but I totally understand her reasons. From a selfish perspective I would have loved her here but all the other girls are great and there's a brilliant atmosphere in the group.

Since August-September last year I have been playing some really good tennis, I've just been consistent with my results and have been climbing the rankings again. I'm really happy and I'm really enjoying my tennis and I think it is really showing.

I'm 74 in the world at the moment and I'm feeling super confident. I've had a lot of matches this year - including reaching the semi-finals in Hobart last month - and on the practice court I am hitting the ball well.

I feel like I'm on a good run and I hope I can carry it into our matches on Friday and Saturday.

As a professional tennis player you do a lot of travelling and are away from home a lot, but that's one of the sacrifices you have to make.

I've just come back from Melbourne, which is 12 hours ahead of Bratislava where I am now. The jet lag hasn't been too bad though. In fact, when I come back from Australia I am always super tired at night and I wake up fresh as a daisy in the morning because I've had an early night.

It was nearly 40 degrees in Melbourne and now I'm in around eight degrees here, but even that is fine.

We are just so used to it, we bring all the right clothes and we've got a really good support team here from the LTA, who do a brilliant job on the physio, strength and conditioning and medical side of things, so we know we're going to be in the best possible shape for the matches.

I didn't lose any luggage this time round but it has happened to me quite a few times where my bags haven't arrived.

One year I flew to Australia, they lost my bag and I had to borrow my friend's clothes for the next two days. Luckily, it was just over Christmas so I just had those two days off and didn't need to find any tennis clothes. They've never lost my racquets which is lucky, it's always just my case.

Apart from the time zone and the temperature, we've also had to get used to playing on a clay court instead of a hard court, which is what we were playing on in Australia.

It's hard to adjust in a short space of time but it's the same for everyone and I'm sure the matches will be really tight come the weekend.

We hit on clay a few times in London before we got here which was a good start, but the clay is different here. The court is really nice, I like it more, so that's a good thing.

There's a good team spirit naturally within the group but we do also play games in Fed Cup weeks to keep everyone laughing in the team room.

This morning we filmed a feature for LTA's social media channels where we were shown some old social media posts and we had to guess which player had posted them.

There were some shockers in there so it was really funny - apparently you could hear us laughing from next door! The best one was a picture Annie K posted from when she met Craig David a few years ago. It was very corny, so we knew it was her.

We all have a good time on the court during practice as well - the warm-ups are always good fun and get people going well. Anne has been really positive and she's been motivating us all week, so everyone's feeling good and looking forward to getting started.

We always get great support at Fed Cup both in the arenas and at home, so I'm sure we'll get that again and hopefully we can give you all something to shout about.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/tennis/51384252</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Scotland v England: Courtney Lawes says senior players must 'step up' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/C7C2/production/_110783115_lawes_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>England's experienced players need to &quot;step up&quot; and help the side win in adversity, says lock Courtney Lawes.

England could not reel in France after slipping 24 points adrift in their Six Nations opener on Sunday and similarly struggled to wrestle back momentum in November's World Cup final defeat by South Africa.

&quot;It's about winning when the opposition has got your number,&quot; said Lawes, 30.

&quot;It's about being able to assert yourself when things aren't going your way, when the strategy and tactics aren't working.

&quot;We have some serious experience. [Head coach] Eddie [Jones] has given us the opportunity to be a part of that, and it is something we need to step up and do.&quot;

Speaking to BBC Radio 5 Live, Lawes added: &quot;We know we are good when we get the gameplan right and we are executing. But now we need to work on when things aren't going to plan, where we go to next.

&quot;We need to be better at identifying where we are struggling and adapting to that situation to get momentum back - where you are struggling to get anything from the referee, or a bounce of a ball, how can you gain back that control.

&quot;That's what New Zealand do so well so often. So many times they are on the back foot for the first 20, 30 minutes maybe, and they can find a way to swing it around and get momentum and get their gameplan going.

&quot;That's something we need to be better at - definitely.&quot;

England captain Owen Farrell endured a difficult afternoon in the Stade de France as his side trailed 24-0 before a second-half rally.

Lawes, one of a host of players with more than 50 caps in the England squad, believes those experienced men must help out the skipper.

&quot;We have a leadership group in place and they are responsible for making decisions on the field. You don't want too many people talking, especially when you are under pressure,&quot; he said.

&quot;Owen has got his role as skipper, and then we as lieutenants - or whatever you want to call it - have our role trying to figure out how he can do his role best.&quot;
• 'Eddie will be hyping them up'
• Listen: Rugby Union Weekly: Does Owen Farrell need more help?

Lawes says Edinburgh, where England face Scotland on Saturday, is the ideal place to prove the squad are learning their lessons after the Paris setback.

&quot;It's the perfect place to go for us, because there is going to be some adversity without a shadow of a doubt,&quot; he added.

&quot;It will be great for the maturity of our squad, and the players in it and the leadership group to show what we can learn from the weekend to take into this game.

&quot;They don't really like us there but it's something we kind of like to embrace and get out there and play some fiery rugby.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51389454</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Lewis Hamilton's 'most impressive season' in Formula 1 - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/113F1/production/_109514607_hamiltonsixth_epa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>After clinching his sixth world title, Lewis Hamilton talked in abstract rather than concrete terms about the scale of his achievement.

&quot;I am working on a masterpiece,&quot; he said, &quot;and I haven't quite finished it yet. I am trying to understand. It takes a long time to master a craft and while I feel like I am mastering it, there is still more to master, still more to add to it, still more pieces of the puzzle to add.

&quot;There will be more ups and downs along the way, but I feel I have the best tools now to be able to deal with those.&quot;

Hamilton's achievement moves him ever closer to becoming the most successful Formula 1 driver of all time, as Michael Schumacher's record of seven world titles is within reach next year.

It comes towards the end of arguably Hamilton's most dominant year, but that in itself raises questions about how to assess where it stands in his career.

Hamilton's 2019 has lacked the stand-out 'wow' moments so often associated with him, such as happened last year with his out-of-nowhere pole lap at Singapore, or his stunning race victory in Italy.

On the other hand, he has been more seamless, more remorseless, more consistent than ever before.

And inside his Mercedes team, they have no doubts about just how high a level Hamilton has reached this season.

Mercedes chief engineer Andrew Shovlin says: &quot;It's perhaps not been his most spectacular season but in many ways it's been his most impressive season. Making mistakes, I can't really think of any things he's done wrong.&quot;

Technical director James Allison adds: &quot;He's just been a points machine, getting them wherever. He's won a lot of races.

&quot;[He's been] every bit as strong as last year, just not quite as flashy. It doesn't have that single stand-out appeal of the Singapore lap sort of plucked from nowhere, or the inch-perfect positioning of his car to force Vettel into a mistake in Monza. But go look at his Mexico race if you want to see a professional driver at the peak of his power.&quot;
• Hamilton becomes second most successful F1 driver of all time
• I don't know how I am supposed to feel - Hamilton

In the past two weeks, Hamilton has produced two drives emblematic of a year in which the 34-year-old has arguably been more complete than ever before.

There was the victory in Mexico Allison referred to, founded on the controlled way he managed his pace after the team made an early pit stop to jump him into the lead.

And then in Austin on Sunday, he clinched the title with a race that mixed a clinically aggressive first lap, including a stunning overtaking move around the outside of Ferrari's Sebastian Vettel, and then a risky one-stop strategy in an attempt to win from a disadvantageous position that came so close to coming off, as he again managed his tyres with expertise.

But those are just two of a series of top-drawer drives. What has impressed Allison most about Hamilton in 2019 has been &quot;just the metronomic consistency of his race performances all year. He and the car have not clicked in qualifying in quite the way he did with last year's car, but boy oh boy does he make it stick on a Sunday.

&quot;From the beginning of the season, he has been really strong. Despite the fact that Valtteri [Bottas, his team-mate] has had a more consistent and more competitive year, Lewis has built up a very big points advantage by being race after race after race the strongest out there.&quot;

The standard view of Hamilton is of a mercurial driver who hits incredible peaks, but also has weekends where, as his former team-mate Jenson Button has said, &quot;you wonder where he'd gone&quot;. There have been none of those this year, just a relentless drive towards success.

This change, it transpires, has come of an active choice Hamilton made before the season.

&quot;He said of himself to us that he was determined for 2019 to start the year with the strength he'd finished 2018,&quot; Allison says. &quot;That was his promise to himself, that he wasn't going to start weakly and then amaze everyone when he put the pedal down later in the year, because we have all seen that Lewis who switches on like a rocket in the second half of the season, that's happened more than once.

&quot;But he stated at the end of last year that he was going to be operating at his best from the start of this year and that's what he's done.&quot;

Shovlin adds: &quot;You notice it in the conversations with him, where previously the goal for every weekend was stick it on pole and win the race and when that wasn't achievable, that would often lead to over-trying.

&quot;And you notice it in the conversations you have in the office, where he is thinking a bit more of the long game.

&quot;When you look at the good drivers, and certainly the multiple world champions, there is quite a process where they sort of reinvent themselves a bit over the winter and come back stronger.

&quot;It's almost like when you get a new operating system for your phone, and it's not that different, but there are a few bug fixes and a few improvements and stuff, and you don't notice it until you go back three or four versions and you think: 'Wow, that's changed a lot.' And I think that's the case with good drivers and certainly the case with Lewis.

&quot;Every year, he has come back as this more complete driver. There is more that he is capable of. There are areas he starts trying to exploit to find performance.

&quot;The last few years a lot of that has all been out of the car - what he's looking at doing in terms of the work in the factory, and how hard he's developing that area. Also how he's dealing with races that don't go how he'd hoped they would go, how quickly he re-engages and gets back focused on the next race and those are all areas where he has just got better and better and better.

&quot;A lot of people like to have this image of what Lewis was like as a driver, it was all natural ability, not the working hard bit. But he has evolved enormously in his time with us, and he's one of the hardest working drivers I've seen.

&quot;So much has come from when he made a mistake, he was very critical of what he could have done better. But now he puts so much analysis into making sure he doesn't make the same mistake twice and 'how can I avoid mistakes, and where do these situations start to go away from me and start to go wrong?'

&quot;That's something that has led to this championship. He has really had it under control for a long, long time. And I think it's been perhaps the one he has played more than any other as the long game.&quot;
• Is Hamilton already the greatest ever?

In the car, too, the breadth of Hamilton's abilities is often under-recognised. Yes, he's blisteringly fast, but there is an immense subtlety to his technical understanding of the car, and the range of skills he has to adjust to what it needs as it changes in real time.

&quot;One of the key things is you're trying to balance the workload on the front and rear axle,&quot; Shovlin says. &quot;So is it a race where we're hurting the front tyres; are we overheating the rears?

&quot;Lewis has a very good feel for which tyres he has to look after. Of the four, it might be one or two he has to look after, and he feels that very early in a stint. He's able to tune the car and how he drives to be able to do that. He thinks about how he's extracting the lap time around the circuit. Which of the corners are going to be hurting those tyres.

&quot;It's something every driver can do; it's just that Lewis can go so much further in terms of really getting that right and being successful. And then you've got mixed conditions and all of those things he deals well with.&quot;

Allison gives the example of the first sector of the lap at Barcelona, where the long, high-speed, right-hander of Turn Three punishes the left-front tyre, which therefore becomes the limiting factor in performance, over both a single lap and, especially, a race distance.

&quot;In that first sector there are some left-handers as well,&quot; Allison says, &quot;and Lewis will float round the right-handers and then hammer the lefts because the front left is getting hard used, and the front right is under-used.

&quot;So he can smash the front right and know that overall it is going to be OK because the front left is the limiting tyre. And his instinctive ability to feather one and hit the next and then feather the third is really impressive - remarkable.&quot;

Another example is how Hamilton manages what is known as 'lift-and-coast', when a driver has to lift off the throttle at the end of the straight before the normal braking point, allow the aerodynamics to slow the car, and then brake later than he would normally do, to save fuel or brakes or both.

Allison refers to the telemetry graphs teams use to analyse performance, which feature lines along an axis that go up and down corresponding to the speed of the car.

&quot;If you imagine, the line would go up to the end of the straight, hit the brakes and there'd be a downward line (as the speed decreases). Instead, he's lifted off and then he'll hit the brakes.

&quot;When Lewis puts the brakes on, he always intercepts perfectly the line he would have been on if he'd carried on full beans to the end of the straight and then hit the brakes. He'll be exactly on that same line, as if he'd never done the lift-off, as if he was perfectly in that same braking moment.

&quot;It's really interesting to be able to hit that every single time exactly the same. And just the delicacy of his right foot. He doesn't break traction unless he wants to, and yet he can make the car fast without spinning up the wheels.&quot;

'He will not go quietly into the night'

Ask Allison if there was one moment that stood out for him about Hamilton's season and he does not pick a victory, or a qualifying lap, but something that reveals the intense competitiveness driving the 34-year-old.

&quot;It would be nothing to do with his driving; it would be a character thing,&quot; Allison says. &quot;And that was Japan. We won the [constructors'] championship in Japan and for a whole series of reasons we took decisions that were right for the team and a tough pill to swallow for Lewis - securing the championship for the team in a way that was best for the team.

&quot;He swallowed it with good grace. So he didn't throw the dummy out of the pram in public. He didn't make a big scene about it. But the pain it caused him… For every normal mortal, you're looking at a bloke with an enormous lead in the championship, who is going to be champion.

&quot;For Lewis, the pain of finishing one position, maybe two positions, lower than he might have done as a result of other factors caused him a pain that I think would have been no less large than it would have been for the 19-20-year-old Lewis with everything to prove and no points on the table and a hunger to become champion.

&quot;The extent to which that distressed him just shows how much he cares about winning - with all his plaudits, with nothing to prove to anyone in the world, but for himself. He will not go quietly into the night without taking everything that's available when he gets behind the wheel of a car.

&quot;And if you want to understand why Lewis is the champion he is, just look how upset he was at that.

&quot;And by the way not upset with us - he could understand why we did it. Upset just because he could have had more points that race.

&quot;And for a normal, reasonable person, it would have been: 'Ah well, I'll get it done at the next race, or the one after that.'

&quot;But that isn't who he is. He's a champion and it matters to him so much that you can understand why he is as driven as he is - and why I think he will finish his days in a racing car as the most successful driver ever.&quot;
• Full results and reports from the 2019 season</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50284993</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Aston Martin: F1 billionaire owner leads rescue deal - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12694/production/_110421457_ai87rasy.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A consortium led by billionaire Lawrence Stroll will put in £182m, with the rest of the money coming from existing investors.

Mr Stroll partly owns the Racing Point Formula 1 team, which will be branded Aston Martin from 2021 under the deal.

The move comes hours after a board meeting held to discuss how to prop up the ailing firm.

Aston Martin's best known customer is fictional spy James Bond and the company recently revealed that four of its cars will feature in the next Bond movie, No Time To Die.

The carmaker said its latest financial moves were aimed at strengthening its balance sheet after its &quot;disappointing performance&quot; in 2019.

Mr Stroll's consortium will take a 20% stake in the company and he will become its executive chairman.

As a result, Penny Hughes will be stepping down as Aston Martin's chairman once the deal is completed.

It's all very well to build James Bond's company cars, but Aston Martin can't rely on a flashy brand alone.

Many of its troubles can be traced to the decision to build a new factory at St Athan in South Wales, where it will produce its long-anticipated sports utility vehicle, the DBX.

An ambitious move, it could have big long-term benefits for the carmaker.

But in the short term, it has been struggling to generate enough cash to pay its bills, including the costs of setting up the factory.

Dealers have been reducing stock rather than ordering new cars, while average selling prices have been falling, weighing on profits.

Last year, the company was forced to borrow £120m at a steep interest rate in order to prop up its operations. It had been facing the prospect of borrowing even more.

The new funding from Lawrence Stroll will give Aston Martin some much-needed stability. It now has breathing space in which to get the DBX into production, and implement a cost-cutting programme.

Meanwhile the Canadian billionaire will be able to put an Aston Martin badge on his F1 cars - opening up new opportunities both to burnish the brand and to exploit its petrol-scented cachet.

She said: &quot;The difficult trading performance in 2019 resulted in severe pressure on liquidity which has left the company with no alternative but to seek substantial additional equity financing.

&quot;Without this, the balance sheet is not robust enough to support the operations of the group.

&quot;Notwithstanding recent weak trading, the strength of the Aston Martin brand and our expanding portfolio of cars has allowed us to attract a strong new partner in Mr Stroll to support the turnaround of the business.&quot;

Earlier this month, the 106-year-old firm issued a profit warning, saying annual earnings were expected to fall by nearly half from a year earlier.

It said core retail sales - which covers sales from Aston Martin dealers to consumers - were up 12% from a year earlier. However, wholesale volumes - which covers how many cars the dealers are ordering from Aston Martin itself - were down 7% to 5,809.

The company said it was expecting earnings of between £130m and £140m, well below the £247.3m it reported last year.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51323241</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Odion Ighalo: Manchester United striker took pay cut to make loan deal happen - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Man Utd</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/11D2B/production/_110730037_ighalo-2.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Odion Ighalo says he was so desperate to join Manchester United he took a pay cut to make the deal happen and did not sleep the night it was agreed.

The 30-year-old Nigeria forward has joined United on loan from Shanghai Shenhua until the end of the season.

The ex-Watford player says his mum cried at the news and there were parties on the street where he grew up.

&quot;A few other clubs had shown interest, I said: 'Please, just pick United, if it's going to be possible,'&quot; he said.

Speaking to the club website, he added: &quot;At 11pm in Shanghai, my agent called me [to say] that United want to do the deal, so I woke up that night and started looking for a translator to go to the directors' room and hit his door.

&quot;'My agent wants to speak to you. United are coming for me, you have to make this happen.'&quot;

Ighalo, his agent and the clubs spent the night negotiating and signing paperwork to get it through before the deadline at 7am Shanghai time.

Meanwhile, other clubs were calling asking Ighalo to sign for them.

&quot;I told my agent 'this is what I want. I want to come here',&quot; added Ighalo.

&quot;He said: 'You're going to get a pay cut to go to United.'

&quot;I said: 'I don't care. Make this deal happen. I want to go to United. I don't care how much is the pay cut, I know that, make it happen.'&quot;

Ighalo says he has been a United fan since he was a child and is pleased to be able to make the his dream of playing for the Old Trafford club a reality.

&quot;I called my mum and she was happy, crying,&quot; he said.

&quot;I know many people used to say when they join a team, they say that they dream of playing for that team. Mine was not the case. I supported the team when I was young.

&quot;People that know me, even back in Nigeria, and even when I was playing at Watford, my team-mates knew that I loved Manchester United, I support them.&quot;

With Marcus Rashford recovering from a stress fracture and Anthony Martial having scored once in his past five Premier League games, Ighalo hopes his physicality can aid the United forward line.

&quot;I'm very fast, I'm skilful, I'm strong, I have good techniques, so I can find my way in the field of play,&quot; he said.

&quot;They have a striker that stays mostly in the middle, but Martial likes to come from the side, even Rashford, so you need someone in the middle that can keep the ball, hold the ball.

&quot;They need a physicality up front to keep the ball, to give and to make some movement, which I believe if everything goes well I can add to the team.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51383589</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>Mo Farah: Olympic champion withdraws from London half marathon with injury - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Athletics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/16CEA/production/_110781439_gettyimages-1175594282.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Four-time Olympic champion Mo Farah has withdrawn from 'The Big Half' race on 1 March with a minor Achilles injury.

Farah, winner of the half marathon event in London for the past two years, suffered the injury in training.

The 36-year-old, who will defend his 10,000m title at the Tokyo 2020 Olympics, will now continue the build-up to the summer season in Africa.

&quot;My priority is to be fit, healthy and competitive for the summer season,&quot; Farah said.

&quot;For that reason I have had to make the tough decision not to race this year. I definitely hope to be back again in 2021.&quot;

Farah quit track events in 2017 to concentrate on the marathon.

But having won gold in the 5,000m and 10,000m at the 2012 and 2016 Olympics, he announced in late 2019 his decision to return to the track.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/athletics/51384253</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>Australian bushfires: Formula 1 to raise money for victims - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/164CC/production/_110604319_australianbushfires.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Formula 1 is to hold an auction of valuable memorabilia and experiences to raise money to help those affected by the Australian bushfires.

Australia suffered its worst bushfire season this summer; at least 30 people and one billion animals have been killed, primarily in the south-east.

F1 said it &quot;felt the need to help those affected in the worst-hit areas&quot;.

An online auction starts on 22 January with proceeds going to four organisations helping support victims.

All non-profit organisations or charities, the four are: Red Cross Australia, County Fire Authority Victoria, the Foundation for Rural and Regional Renewal and the WWF Australian Wildlife and Nature Recovery Fund. The auction takes place at f1authentics.com.

Although heavy rain and golf ball-sized hail hit parts of New South Wales and Victoria this week, the fires remain a major threat.

Qualifying for the Australian Open tennis tournament had to be halted last week because of the poor air quality in Melbourne and F1 says it continues to monitor the situation before the 2020 season starts in the Victorian capital, with the season's first Grand Prix on 15 March.

Australian Renault driver Daniel Ricciardo's racewear will be among the merchandise on offer in the F1 auction. So too will be the helmet to be worn by Haas driver Kevin Magnussen at the Australian Grand Prix.

Donors can buy the chance to meet a number of top drivers, including Mercedes' Lewis Hamilton and Valtteri Bottas, Red Bull's Max Verstappen and Alexander Albon and McLaren's Carlos Sainz and Lando Norris.

They can also buy a meeting with any of three team bosses: Mercedes' Toto Wolff, Ferrari's Mattia Binotto and Williams' Claire Williams. Dinner with F1 sporting boss Ross Brawn is available too.

Six-time champion Hamilton has already given £380,000 to help those affected by the bushfires.

Despite the efforts to help, F1 may still face criticism in the weeks ahead in relation to the environment.

The climate crisis has had a direct effect on the severity of the bushfires - last year was the hottest since records began and there has been a prolonged drought.

There could be criticism, then, for a sport flying its teams, drivers and officials halfway around the world to spend three days burning carbon.

F1, though, would point to the steps forward in thermal efficiency created by its turbo hybrid engines, the trickle down effect of such technology in road cars, its plan to be carbon neutral by 2030 and its intention to use carbon-neutral synthetic fuel once it introduces a new engine formula in 2025.

The FIA and Formula 1 also today announced they have become signatories of the United Nations' Sports for Climate Action Framework.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51206884</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula E: China race called off amid coronavirus outbreak - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Motorsport</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/8325/production/_110737533_china_e_prix_getty_01.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The all-electric Formula E Championship has called off next month's race in China amid the coronavirus outbreak.

The sixth race of the 2019-20 season was due to be held in Sanya - around 1,000 miles from the centre of the outbreak in Wuhan - on 21 March.

Formula E said it was looking at the viability of postponing the event until a later date.

More than 300 people have died in the outbreak so far and more than 14,000 have been infected.

&quot;Formula E has taken the necessary measures to ensure the health and safety of its travelling staff, championship participants and spectators, which remains of paramount importance,&quot; a statement read.

&quot;We are working closely with our regional partner and the local authorities in Hainan Province and Sanya Municipal Government, to continue monitoring the situation as it develops. All parties will take the appropriate amount of time to study the viability of potential alternative dates should the situation improve.&quot;

The move raises further questions about the Chinese Formula 1 Grand Prix, due to be held on 17-19 April in Shanghai, which is 500 miles from Wuhan.

Motorsport's governing body the FIA has previously admitted the Chinese GP - the fourth scheduled race of this year's World Championship - is at risk and says it is &quot;closely monitoring the evolving situation with relevant authorities&quot;.

F1 has a tendency to wait as long as possible before making decisions to call off a race, but the sport's hand may be forced by the global situation in this case.

Last week, the British Foreign Office changed its travel advice to warn against all non-essential travel to China, and British Airways cancelled all its flights to the country's mainland.

Countries have begun closing their borders to arrivals from China as officials work to control the spread of the virus.

The US and Australia are the latest countries to say they would deny entry to all foreign visitors who had recently been in China, after similar moves from Russia, Japan, Pakistan and Italy.

A number of sporting events have already been affected by the outbreak.

The World Indoor Athletics Championships and snooker's Chinese Open have been postponed, World Cup skiing events and Olympic boxing qualifying events have been cancelled, and the women's Olympic basketball qualifying event has been moved from China to Serbia.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/motorsport/51344513</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>F1 2019 highs &amp; lows: Lewis Hamilton dominates - but what was best fight, best race, best lap? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/BB40/production/_109963974_hamtrophyepa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lewis Hamilton ended 2019 with a dominant victory in the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix, a fitting end to possibly the most impressive season of his career.

The Mercedes driver has won 11 races - just over half - and has had a lock on his sixth championship since the early summer. But the predictability of Hamilton's confirmation as king of F1 yet again was a stark contrast from the often vivid and compelling on-track action of the individual races.

The impression given by the results that Mercedes have had everything their own way was belied by the reality of some intensely competitive action throughout the season, as new stars emerged, and fast-paced narratives aplenty kept interest high.

As F1 2019 disappears into the rear-view mirror, it seems timely to look back on the moments that made the season, and try to put it all into some kind of perspective, with a bite-size review of the year.
• What was voted the best moment of the season?

Lewis Hamilton won 11 races, produced a series of superb performances and made winning the championship look a lot easier than it really was. But he so nearly didn't win this.

Had this article been written at half-distance, Max Verstappen would have got it. The Dutchman has been absolutely outstanding this year, carrying on the rich vein of form he found from Canada in 2018. But in the end Hamilton just edges him.

For Verstappen, there are still a few too many rough edges. He made mistakes at the start in Belgium and Italy, and the combination of foolhardiness and thoughtlessness that cost him pole - and victory - in Mexico because he did not lift for yellow flags in qualifying almost rules him out on its own.

On top of that, after a slow-ish - for him - start over the first four races, Hamilton put his foot on the throat of the season and never let it off. And he was outstanding in so many races - Bahrain, Canada, France, Silverstone, Hungary, Belgium, Mexico and Austin were all terrific drives.

OK, he made a couple of mistakes in Germany, and misjudged a passing move in Brazil. He's still the gold standard. But Verstappen this year ran him very close.

A lot of contenders for this one. Charles Leclerc was brilliant in Bahrain, as dominant a performance as anyone produced all year in only his second race for Ferrari - and it was a terrible injustice that he lost that win to an engine wiring problem. He was also ice-cool under pressure in both Belgium and Italy, although he gets a black mark for pushing Hamilton wide in Monza.

Verstappen won three races, all of them top-drawer in their own way - his cool control in the wet in Germany when so many others were losing their cars and their heads; his relentless charge through to victory when he came alive late in the race in Austria was awesome; Brazil was a great display of racing and race-craft in the best car on the day.

But Hamilton's victory in Hungary was perhaps the best of a number of great drives by the world champion. Tracking Verstappen for so long, almost pulling off what would have been the overtake of the season around the outside of Turn Four, and then closing 20 seconds in as many laps after a late pit stop to pass the Red Bull for the win.

A toss-up between Brazil and Germany. Hockenheim was amazing, with so many incidents and twists and turns - the drag strip skating rink at the final two corners that caught out Hamilton, Leclerc and Nico Hulkenberg, a comedy pit stop from Mercedes, Vettel climbing from the back to second and Daniil Kvyat taking an unlikely podium for Toro Rosso.

But Brazil edged it for drama. It had everything - passes for the lead, great overtakes, safety cars, the two Ferraris colliding, brilliant drives (Carlos Sainz third from the back of the grid - wow) and a fairytale second place for Pierre Gasly.

In fact, there were many great races - six in a row from Austria to Italy. And Mexico and Austin were pretty damn good, too.

No contest - it has to be Leclerc v Verstappen at Silverstone. It was utterly epic. Verstappen tried everything, and Leclerc - still angry at the way he had been barged out of victory in Austria a week before - defended as if his life depended on it, and took things right to the edge in doing so.

There was one moment - when Verstappen was actually in front going into Stowe, only for Leclerc to shoot back ahead as they entered the corner - that you can't quite believe happened no matter how many times you watch it.

There's no bigger compliment than to say that it was reminiscent of the famous scrap between Gilles Villeneuve and Rene Arnoux at Dijon in 1979, except it went on for 20-odd laps, not three.

Leclerc has been pole position king this year, so this has to be one of his seven pole positions, right? The best of them was surely Belgium, where he was a gob-smacking 0.748 seconds quicker than team-mate Sebastian Vettel.

Not so fast, though. I asked Ferrari team boss Mattia Binotto what he thought was the best lap by a Ferrari driver all year, expecting him to pick one of Leclerc's. But the answer was a surprise - he said Vettel's pole in Japan.

Binotto admitted it was &quot;difficult&quot; to say it was better than Leclerc's at Spa. But after some thought he stuck to his guns. It was a &quot;perfect lap,&quot; he said - and when you watch the onboard footage, he's not wrong - and it was also &quot;unexpected&quot;.

It came after a run of nine races in which Leclerc had out-qualified the German and in the midst of the huge pressure that was putting on Vettel. And Binotto paid Leclerc a huge compliment, too, with a statement that says a lot more about the situation at Ferrari than just the words themselves: &quot;For him to beat Charles in a qualifying means it was a special lap.&quot;

So Vettel in Japan it is.

Honorary mention, too, for Hamilton's performances in splitting the Ferraris in Singapore and Russia, in both of which he was more than 0.6 seconds clear of team-mate Valtteri Bottas.

Best driver outside the top three teams

Carlos Sainz had a brilliant first season at McLaren. Team-mate Lando Norris edged him in qualifying in the first half of the year, but the Spaniard generally owned the second half of the season and has raced with maturity, cool and controlled aggression all year.

The highlight of a number of superb drives was climbing from last to third - once Hamilton was penalised - in Brazil. It's just a shame he did not get to enjoy the podium for real. Even Fernando Alonso - the man he replaced - would have been proud of that one, and that's really saying something.

Has to be the crash between the two Ferrari drivers in Brazil. It had been coming for a while, but still the shock/disbelief of it was huge. How Ferrari handle them is going to be one of the big stories of 2020.

For the second year in a row, Vettel gets this. In fact, he wins gold, silver and bronze.

In third place, Canada, where he went off under pressure from Hamilton, and then rejoined in a manner that was adjudged to be dangerous, earning a five-second penalty that cost him victory. The penalty was controversial but he would not have got it if he hadn't made the mistake in the first place.

The silver medal is for ramming Verstappen up the back at Silverstone when completely misjudging an attempt to re-pass the Dutchman at Vale.

Gold medal - and worst by far - was for Monza. It was bad enough that he spun on his own at Ascari, a completely unforced error. But to then rejoin and collide with Lance Stroll's Racing Point was a misjudgement that would have been embarrassing for a pay-driver rookie, let along a four-time world champion.

There is the collision he caused with Leclerc in Brazil to throw into the mix, too.

Leclerc also made a clanger - costing himself a potential win in Baku by crashing in qualifying. &quot;Stupid,&quot; he scolded himself, and it was, even if Ferrari didn't help by sending him out on medium tyres for that run.

There have been some stunners this year - Leclerc pulled off two crackers in Monaco, on Norris into Loews and on Haas' Romain Grosjean at Rascasse, before getting over-ambitious and coming to grief when he tried the Grosjean one again on Renault's Nico Hulkenberg.

On the first lap of Monaco, Sainz went side by side with Alexander Albon through Sainte Devote, out-dragged him up the hill and then did Daniil Kvyat around the outside of Massenet. That was pretty special.

As was Leclerc's move around the outside of Pierre Gasly at Village during the British Grand Prix.

But the winner is Alexander Albon for his cut-back on Daniel Ricciardo out of Rivage at Spa and then passing the Renault around the outside of the fast downhill left-hander that follows, in his first race for Red Bull. No-one overtakes there. But Albon did.

This is such a tough one, because Albon, Norris and Williams' George Russell have all been excellent in their own ways.

Albon's highs have been spectacularly good. His drive in the wet at Hockenheim was one of the performances of the year - he had the Toro Rosso up in fourth place on merit and he was racing with Hamilton's Mercedes. It was a grave injustice that team-mate Kvyat was the Toro Rosso driver who ended up on the podium thanks to a lucky late stop for slicks, when Albon had outclassed him all day.

Albon's qualifying lap in Japan, matching Verstappen to the thousandth of a second on his first visit to Suzuka, was equally superb. But overall he has been too far off Verstappen since joining Red Bull.

Russell has blitzed Robert Kubica at Williams, completely overshadowing the Pole's comeback after eight years out, out-qualifying him at every single race by nearly 0.6secs a lap on average and generally proving way quicker in the races, too. And there were a handful of races when Russell hauled the Williams into the back of the midfield.

But it's hard to judge Russell because Kubica's level is an unknown - he appeared a shadow of the driver he once was - and the Williams was too slow, so he rarely had any competition against which to measure himself.

On balance, then Norris edges it. He, too, has been fantastic. McLaren's internal data of absolute pace across race and qualifying shows there is almost nothing to choose between him and Sainz on pure speed - they are separated by tiny fractions on average. And Sainz is a tough team-mate. Norris was comfortably behind Sainz in the championship but his race results would look better were it not for some poor reliability.

All three appear to have bright futures ahead of them.

Over the season, the Mercedes was demonstrably the best car, as 15 wins and an average qualifying advantage of 0.116secs over Ferrari and 0.388secs over Red Bull attest, even if some of the victories were Hamilton wins rather than Mercedes ones, and some were handed to them on a plate by Ferrari.

But by the end of the year the impression was that Red Bull had caught them up.

Ferrari clearly had the most powerful engine all year. Their advantage was so great from Spa to Japan that it got tongues wagging, and provoked rivals into fishing for what might be going on, which led to some technical clarifications from the FIA.

Mercedes and Red Bull saw a reduction in Ferrari's straight-line speed advantage after that and overall competitiveness - although Ferrari said that was down to them running more downforce at the races in question and that nothing had been changed in their engine.

But even then their power-unit was still the best; it was just a question of by how much.

Two of these - F1 lost two of its greatest figures in the course of 2019, with the deaths of triple world champion Niki Lauda and FIA F1 director Charlie Whiting.

The loss of Whiting, on the eve of the season-opening race in Australia, was a devastating blow to many in the sport.

Whiting, 66, was a monumental character, steeped in F1, the go-to man on all matters to do with the rules, and yet one of the most popular people in the paddock. He was checking out improvements to the track on Wednesday evening in Melbourne, chatting to Vettel, but suffered an embolism overnight, and the sport lost an unsung hero.

Lauda - F1 great, pilot, businessman, Mercedes non-executive director, TV pundit - succumbed to lung problems before the Monaco Grand Prix. So much has been written about him, there is no need to repeat it here. Suffice it to say that Lauda was a uniquely heroic figure, and F1 is unlikely to see the likes of him again.

McLaren were unrecognisable from the team that finished 2018 with the second slowest car in the field. After blaming Honda engines for their poor performance for three years, the belated realisation of how far they had fallen, following their switch to Renault engines, precipitated a major restructuring at the team.

Great work was done through the last months of 2018 on the new car and they hit the ground running in 2019 and never looked back.

The arrival of impressive new team boss Andreas Seidl in May increased the momentum.

The driver line-up of Carlos Sainz and Lando Norris is young and impressive and there is a new lightness and purpose about McLaren, who look well on the road to recovery.

Easy. Mercedes' 56-second pit stop with Hamilton in Germany, as they ran around like Laurel and Hardy, wearing their 1950s replica uniforms, celebrating 100 years of Mercedes in motorsport, trying to change his front wing and tyres.

France - F1 got a lot of stick in the first part of the year because of Mercedes' dominance, even if the individual races were not too bad and it was nowhere near as one-sided as the results made it look.

Had Ferrari delivered on their potential, it should have been four wins to Mercedes and three to Ferrari after Canada, and then there would have been no talk of domination.

Either way, whether it came after seven consecutive Mercedes wins or not, France was a dire race - just as it had been in 2018, when the Paul Ricard track made its return.

Almost totally uneventful, apart from a bit of scrapping for the minor points places, Hamilton miles clear of Bottas, on a track whose layout is demarcated solely by paint. As the birthplace of grand prix racing, France deserves a place on the F1 calendar. But it and the sport deserve better than Ricard.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50623512</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula 1: Wins, spins and controversy - take the F1 2019 quiz - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/A671/production/_109990624_ver_getty.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>There were cheers, tears and a whole lot of talking points in Formula 1 2019.

Lewis Hamilton bagged a sixth world title, Ferrari had another campaign to forget and Max Verstappen underlined his future title credentials.

While we all wait for the lights to go out on a new season in 2020, have a go at the BBC Sport F1 2019 quiz.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50624768</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-24</ID>
      <TITLE>Rory McIlroy: Four-time major winner to return to world number one - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Golf</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/230F/production/_110757980_rors.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Rory McIlroy will replace Brooks Koepka as world number one despite not playing this week.

The four-time major winner from Northern Ireland will leapfrog Koepka when the rankings are updated following this week's AT&amp;T Pebble Beach Pro-AM.

Koepka and world number three Jon Rahm are also missing the event and the two-year rolling format of the ranking system will see McIlroy go top.

McIlroy will be back as world number one for the first time since 2015.
• McIlroy says he will play 'carefree' golf in 2020
• Experience at Royal Portrush was a 'turning point' for McIlroy
• McIlroy says he is a victim of his own success

The complicated nature of the ranking system will push the 30-year-old up from 0.2 points behind Keopka to three-hundredths of a point in front.

McIlroy said last month that returning to world number one would &quot;take care of itself&quot;.

He added: &quot;It's all about the process, it's all about the game, it's all about trying to make improvements.

&quot;If I do that and I achieve those goals, then hopefully inevitably I get to that position. It's a by-product of playing consistently good golf and I've been doing that for a while now.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/golf/51362971</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-25</ID>
      <TITLE>Lewis Hamilton's sixth F1 world title: the stats - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/F08C/production/_109408516_f1_hamilton_promo_v1.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Who would have thought anyone would have come close to Michael Schumacher's record of seven Formula 1 world championships?

Lewis Hamilton made it six at the United States Grand Prix, but a drill down into the statistics of his career reveals in some areas he has already surpassed the sport's true greats.

He's not quite surpassed Schumacher's titles and race wins total, but check out his win ratio and pole positions record - often the purest test of a driver's speed - and you'll see he is already a leading light in Formula 1.

How he compares to the best ever
• Hamilton is now the second most successful driver of all time, one title behind all-time record holder Michael Schumacher who won seven.
• A sixth win means Hamilton has overtaken Argentine legend Juan Manuel Fangio on the all-time leaderboard. Fangio won five titles in the 1950s.
• This is a third consecutive title for Hamilton (2017, 2018, 2019). The record of consecutive F1 championships belongs to Michael Schumacher who swept all before him in securing five title wins on the bounce between 2000 and 2004.
• It is also Hamilton's fifth title in six years. Hamilton's dominance was interrupted by Nico Rosberg - his Mercedes team-mate - pipping him to the championship by five points in 2016.
• The only other driver currently racing who has won more than a single championship is Sebastian Vettel on four.
• Hamilton has won 83 races. Only Michael Schumacher has won more, with 91. They are head and shoulders above the rest. Vettel is in third place with 53 wins, but the German won only one race this campaign.
• Hamilton's 83 race wins have come at a better win rate than Schumacher's. In each of the last six campaigns, Hamilton has won on average 10 GPs. If he is to continue that trend next year, he will overtake Schumacher as the driver with the most race victories and will have done so in fewer races.
• Hamilton has won one in every three races (33.5%) he has participated in his career (83 wins from 248 GPs started). Of all drivers who have taken part in at least 50 grands prix, only Juan Manuel Fangio (with almost one in two - 47%) and Jim Clark (35%) have a better win rate than Hamilton. However, Hamilton has been involved in at least three times as many races as both Clark and Fangio, sustaining his win rate over a much longer period of time. Hamilton has a marginally better win percentage than Schumacher, whose 91 victories came in 306 races (30% win percentage).
• Alain Prost and Ayrton Senna both won one in four of the GPs they took part in. Frenchman Prost recorded 51 wins from 199 races, while Brazilian legend Ayrton Senna secured 41 wins from 161 grands prix before tragedy struck in Imola in 1994.

What about the other race-weekend stats?
• Hamilton is way out in front in terms of pole positions - he has an all-time record of 87. Schumacher is in second place with 68.
• Hamilton is in joint second place in terms of fastest laps, with 46 - the same number as Kimi Raikkonen. However, he has a long way to go if he is to catch Schumacher on 77.
• Hamilton is just one behind Ayrton Senna in terms of races won leading from first to last lap - having done so 18 times.
• Lewis Hamilton has completed a 'hat-trick' of securing pole position, winning the race and recording the fastest lap on 14 different occasions. Michael Schumacher is ahead with 22 hat-tricks.
• Hamilton is in joint-second place in the list of drivers to have completed the most 'grand-slams'. The 2019 champion has achieved the rare feat of taking pole position, winning the race having led every single lap as well as claiming the fastest lap in five grands prix, the same number as Schumacher. British driver Jim Clark, who won two titles in the 1960s, has the most grand slams with eight.

Where does he shine?
• Hamilton's favourite circuits are Canada, where he won his first ever race in 2007, and Hungary. He has seven wins at each of these two GPs. Only Schumacher has won more wins at the same grand prix, winning in France eight times.
• Hamilton has the won more British GPs than any other driver, with six wins on his home circuit. Jim Clark and Alain Prost each have five victories. Hamilton has finished on the podium every British GP since 2014.
• He has a great record in China as well, with six wins and a total of nine podium finishes.

Where are his least successful tracks?
• Hamilton has fared badly in Malaysia, recording just a single win. Luckily for him given his dismal record there, Malaysia was removed from the race calendar after 2017.
• Melbourne has been the land of second place for Hamilton as he finished behind the leader in the last four Australian GPs, winning only in 2008 and 2015.
• Hamilton struggled in Brazil in the early part of his career, failing to win in any of his first nine races in Interlagos. He has since recorded two wins there in 2016 and 2018, with this season's Brazilian GP taking place later in November.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50176043</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-26</ID>
      <TITLE>Brazilian Grand Prix: Ferrari's 'silly' problem is a rather large one - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/AF2A/production/_109724844_vet_2_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It took 20 races, but finally the inevitable happened at Ferrari at the Brazilian Grand Prix. Their drivers Charles Leclerc and Sebastian Vettel collided, taking both out of the race and leaving the team with a rather large problem on their hands.

&quot;Silly&quot; was the word team boss Mattia Binotto used to describe the incident. In his cool, detached way, he deflected a series of opportunities to lay the blame, and said he would reconvene with Vettel and Leclerc at the factory in Maranello this week to analyse what happened, come to some form of judgement and decide on next steps.

The question now for Binotto is what he does next and how he manages what has become the most combustible driver pairing in F1, not so much for the one remaining race this year, but to prevent the internal competition from derailing their 2020 campaign.
• Listen: &quot;Come on guys!&quot; Hamilton feels the heat in Brazil

The collision occurred on lap 66 of a frenetic race, with five to go, as the two Ferrari drivers found themselves at the back of a queue of cars being held up by Lewis Hamilton's Mercedes, running second to Red Bull's Max Verstappen on much older tyres than those behind.

Ahead of them, and behind Hamilton, was Red Bull's Alexander Albon, who was trying to pass the Mercedes while also holding back Vettel, who in turn had Leclerc behind him.

Leclerc saw an opportunity and dived for the inside of Vettel into Turn One. It was a daring move, aggressive certainly, but absolutely clean. But not one that Vettel was likely to take lying down.

The German had use of the DRS overtaking aid on the run towards Turn Four, and Leclerc moved to the inside to defend his position, leaving just enough room for Vettel - but not an inch more - on the outside.

Approaching the corner, Vettel then moved across on his team-mate, his left rear tyre touching Leclerc's front right. Although light, the contact broke Leclerc's suspension and ripped the tyre off the rim, and also gave Vettel a right-rear puncture.

Both cars retired from the race, prompting the final safety car that triggered a bonkers last two laps, in which Mercedes did what technical director James Allison described as &quot;plain dumb&quot; in pitting Hamilton for fresh tyres, the world champion collided with Albon, costing the Anglo-Thai a first podium, and Toro Rosso's Pierre Gasly finished a wholly unexpected second.

What did the Ferrari drivers say?

Vettel did what he always does in controversial situations and kept his public pronouncements to a limit, repeating the same few sentences in every interview.

Whose fault was it?

&quot;It doesn't matter now,&quot; Vettel said. &quot;We both didn't finish the race, which is bad for us as a team.&quot;

&quot;There is not so much to say, I think it's pretty clear. But obviously it's bitter and a shame for the team to lose both cars. I didn't have much space on the right. I had a better run out of the chicane and tried to pass and then we touched.&quot;

Leclerc was a little more forthcoming.

&quot;We will have to analyse better the crash,&quot; he said. &quot;I overtook in Turn One, then on the run to Turn Four I closed the door.

&quot;I was aware he was on the outside. I left little space but enough for him and then I think he tried to squeeze me a little bit towards the inside and we were very close so we touched straight away. Very disappointing to end a race like this.&quot;

The stewards - to the surprise of some, given that Vettel had clearly changed his line and instigated a collision - ruled it a racing incident and took no further action.

How did it happen?

How the two Ferrari drivers came to this juncture is a rather longer story than the events of this weekend.

To those on the outside, it was only a matter of time before something like this happened. The pressure inside Ferrari has been building all year as Leclerc has established himself as a star and threatened - and perhaps usurped already - Vettel's seniority in the team. Vettel, meanwhile, is a proud man who, in the car, is as stubborn as they come when it comes to protecting his competitive position.

All year, Binotto has been doing his best to manage the inevitably tense situation.

Ferrari started the season with Binotto saying Vettel, as the senior driver, would have priority in any &quot;50-50 decisions&quot;, and the first few races passed with a series of team-order calls, the majority in Vettel's favour.

Leclerc said he accepted the situation but also that he would do his best to change it. And as soon as the second race in Bahrain, he dominated Vettel and everyone else and was on the way to a superb victory when his engine developed a problem in the closing stages.

Tensions cooled after the first few races, as it became apparent that Ferrari did not have the pace to mount a title challenge, and Vettel established the upper hand as Leclerc's chances were comprised by a few too many mistakes in qualifying, usually by him, but sometimes also by the team.

But at the French Grand Prix in June, Leclerc turned a corner and went on a run of nine races in which he out-qualified Vettel, while the German continued to make the sort of pressure errors that have blighted his last three years at Ferrari.

Leclerc won twice in Belgium and Italy as Ferrari made a flying start to the second part of the season. In Monza, there was a controversy when Leclerc failed to do his part of a prearranged team strategy for the drivers to give each other tows in qualifying, which angered Vettel.

Vettel then won in Singapore, but only after the team inadvertently got him ahead of Leclerc, who had been leading from pole position, by pitting Vettel first to try to pass Hamilton for second place.

Then in Russia Vettel directly refused team orders to let Leclerc by - which had been agreed pre-race following a decision to get Leclerc, again on pole, to let Vettel past with a slipstream into the first corner, so both Ferraris could be running one-two in front of Hamilton.

Since then, Vettel has been on a bit of a run, and has out-qualified Leclerc in the last two races, and the battle for primacy at Ferrari has taken another twist. And now this.

It's not hard to work out what has happened here. Vettel will not have taken kindly to being passed by his team-mate. He has then made what many will see as a misjudgement in trying to reclaim the position and been too aggressive in moving over on Leclerc.

As Leclerc put it: &quot;The result was a huge disaster but the incident itself was a very small touch. It's unfortunate.&quot;

Vettel has form at this sort of thing. Those with long-ish memories will recall the Turkish Grand Prix in 2010, when in trying to pass Red Bull team-mate Mark Webber, he moved over and the two touched, handing a one-two to McLaren drivers Lewis Hamilton and Jenson Button.

And in the past two years, Vettel has become infamous for making a series of errors in racing situations. Many will see this as the latest example.

After Russia, the two Ferrari drivers were sat down by Binotto to discuss the situation. But the issue for Ferrari is that in the past Vettel has proven time and again that he is reluctant to be managed - unless the situation is in his favour.

What will Binotto do about this aspect of his former number one driver, he was asked?

&quot;It is not a matter of managing,&quot; Binotto said. &quot;It is a matter of recognising what has been the actions and mistakes. Whether you are a driver or engineer or whatever, recognising mistakes is important because it can only make you better.

&quot;It is not for me to blame them, it is for them to recognise it.&quot;

On the other hand, while Vettel undoubtedly triggered the incident, Leclerc - who was making his own point in the psychological and on-track battle between the two - may come to conclude that in pinching his team-mate so close to the grass, he was making himself vulnerable to exactly the kind of move Vettel made.

&quot;We need to clarify within the team what is silly and what is not,&quot; Binotto said, &quot;where is the limit of the actions. But when you have a crash, something was wrong, no doubt. When you are free to fight, it is a driving matter how much you can take the risk but today the risk was not necessary.&quot;

In Brazil, the two Ferrari drivers were free to race because the team had secured second place in the constructors' championship and all that was left was to decide which finished ahead in the drivers'.

Heading into Brazil, Leclerc was third in the championship, ahead of Red Bull's Max Verstappen and Vettel. Verstappen's superb win at Interlagos, coupled with the retirement of the Ferrari drivers, has promoted the Dutchman to third and given him an 11-point cushion on Leclerc, a margin that the Monegasque will not find it easy to overhaul at the final race of the season in Abu Dhabi on 1 December.

More important for Binotto, though, is how he handles the Vettel-Leclerc situation going into 2020.

Leclerc is likely to finish this year ahead of Vettel on points, on race wins, on pole positions, and on their qualifying head-to-head, despite the advantages Vettel had at the beginning of the year, and despite the fact that he is in his first year with the team and only in his second in F1, against a four-time champion with 53 wins.

To all intents and purposes, Leclerc is now Ferrari's lead driver, and Binotto cannot go into next year giving Vettel priority. But nor will Vettel accept it being given to Leclerc. He just doesn't work that way. He believes his status in the sport demands more.

As for Binotto, he has a number of times this year described having two such closely matched and competitive drivers as &quot;a luxury&quot;. Does he still think that way?

&quot;I am still convinced it is a luxury because they are both very good drivers,&quot; he said. &quot;They both represent a benchmark for each other and they have improved during the season.

&quot;Seb in the second half has been very fast. What happened today, I would say it was even lucky it happened this season because there will be an opportunity to clarify with them for it not to happen next year.

&quot;Currently they have a good relations and are going well together. Certainly what happened today may not help. But I don't think there is a drama at all and I see it more as an opportunity in view of next year to clarify what is needed.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50455068</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-27</ID>
      <TITLE>Lewis Hamilton on a tough season, the risks of racing and his future - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/88C0/production/_109780053_gettyimages-1134764489.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lewis Hamilton is explaining what keeps him hungry - how, despite six world championships, 83 grand prix victories and more money than he probably ever dreamed of, his desire for success in Formula 1 burns as bright as ever.

&quot;The thing is I never got into it for money,&quot; the Mercedes driver says. &quot;Of course it is great that that piles up - no problem. That is a bonus. As long as those things don't become the lead factor of what I do.

&quot;The core of what I do is that I love racing. I love the challenge. I love arriving knowing I have got these incredibly talented youngsters who are trying to beat me and outperform me, outsmart me, and I love that battle that I get into every single year.

&quot;And I am working with these guys [his Mercedes engineers] who are so much smarter than me and they make me feel smarter. When I am challenging them and proving them wrong so many times, it is unreal.&quot;
• Hamilton becomes second most successful F1 driver of all time
• I don't know how I am supposed to feel - Hamilton
• Is Hamilton already the greatest ever?

Hamilton laughs and refers to the conversations he has with chief engineer Andrew Shovlin and his colleagues about the complexities of the car.

&quot;It happens a lot,&quot; Hamilton says. &quot;I say something to Shov, and he will say: 'No, the numbers say this', and I will say: 'It's this and this and this.' And he will say: 'Oh you are right.' It feels so good. There are a lot of things like that.&quot;

Hamilton is in expansive form as he discusses his 2019 season and all matters involved in it. Over the course of the interview he covers:
• Why this season was tougher than it looked
• The demands of F1 and his lifestyle outside the sport
• Personal struggles and his climate-crisis messages on Instagram
• Rationalising the risks in the wake of the death of Formula 2 driver Anthoine Hubert

One of the most fundamental questions any human being can ask themselves is what their life is worth, what risks they are prepared to take to do what they enjoy.

While Formula 1 drivers are confronted with this to some degree every time they get in their car, it became very real for them at the Belgian Grand Prix this year when Formula 2 driver Hubert was killed in a crash shortly after F1 qualifying had finished.

Hamilton was doing his television interviews at the time, and the footage of his reaction when he saw the accident on a screen nearby, the anguish on his face before he cut an interview short and walked away, is chilling.

Hamilton has mentioned the impact of Hubert's death briefly a couple of times this season. But this is the first time he has talked about it in depth.

&quot;It wasn't the first time I've seen that happen in my career,&quot; Hamilton says.

&quot;I remember quite vividly when I was young [aged eight] I won this race in Kimbolton and Daniel Spence died and that was a tragic time for me as a kid, the first time I had known someone to die. And I was just with him that day.

&quot;That was a tough one. This one, I was doing an interview and I saw it happen out of the corner of my eye and I just knew it was [bad]. And lots of things flashed through my mind.

&quot;I remember watching Ayrton [Senna] when he watched [Roland] Ratzenberger crash and seeing his face. There was a lot of deja vu in that experience.

&quot;A lot of thoughts went through my mind in the evening. I worried about the kid. I know what it's like to be in F2 and having the dream of being somewhere.

&quot;I thought to myself: 'The cars are still unsafe.' Particularly lower down the ranks it's probably even less safe than it is for us.

&quot;And then there is the question of how much more do you need, how much more do you want? And finding all those balances.

&quot;I'm not chasing because I have to have it, because I love what I do. And I was like, 'Jeez, I could spend more time with my family' and all these things that you can look back on.

&quot;I'm sure when it comes to your last day and you're at the pearly gates - I like to think you're at the pearly gates - you're looking back on your life, you're never asking: 'I wish I had more money.' You always wish you had more time. And you probably have a ton of regrets: 'If only I'd made that decision on that day, I could have spent more time with my loved one' or whatever it is.

&quot;All those things were going through my mind. But there was never a second I thought I wasn't going to keep racing. The fear factor never crept in.

&quot;That was an important factor for me. Because I remember when that kid died, when I was eight, one of my best friends at the time quit racing. Fear crept into him and he just quit. For me, I was like, if that ever creeps into me, I know that's the last legs of my career.&quot;
• Why the motorsport 'family' races on after the death of a driver

'I would say I have a very complex life'

That was not the only time the wider questions of existence have crept into Hamilton's professional life this season. After arriving home from the Japanese Grand Prix in October, he took to Instagram to post some messages reflecting his despair over the climate crisis, saying the world was &quot;messed up&quot; and he felt like &quot;giving up on everything&quot;.

He defended his intervention on arriving at the subsequent race in Mexico. But he never addressed whether there was a wider personal context to it.

&quot;There is,&quot; he now admits, &quot;but I don't really wish to go into that.&quot;

He adds: &quot;Most of the time, I wear my heart on my sleeve, so it was an emotional post, which is not always good to do. It just felt like I was banging my head against the wall and not gaining ground.

&quot;There is a lot of push-back on a lot of things I do, and a lot of questioning of everything I do and say. You live your life under a magnifying glass. And the pressure for anyone that's in the limelight… we're only human, so at some stage you're going to buckle a little bit.

&quot;But I always say it's not how you fall, it's how you get back up. And I really turned that negativity into a positive and came back and won that next race. And you'll probably see if you look back in the history of the times I've often had those difficult phases, I've often won the next races. That's where my strength lies.&quot;

How does he feel to have his personal views - and his right to express them - questioned?

&quot;I just understand it's just the way of life,&quot; Hamilton says. &quot;But the fact that is the way it is doesn't make it any easier.

&quot;I would say I have a very complex life. I'm sure we all have complex lives. But I can't talk about absolutely how complex it is.

&quot;I am trying to be more open about that, as you'll see on my social. But there is a line where it's the limit and for me personally that one there was slightly over the limit.

&quot;But I don't regret it. Because I think for those who are following me and are on this journey with me, I don't think showing vulnerability is always a bad thing. They can just see I'm human at the end of the day.&quot;

Hamilton has been keen for some time to pursue outside interests, such as his growing interest in fashion, and he and Mercedes have always insisted that giving him the freedom to pursue his other ambitions revitalises him and ultimately makes him perform better.

But Hamilton admits he has to be careful not to take too much on.

&quot;I would say just the energy load, there is a lot; I have to take a lot of weight. I don't go to the races and just go home, and [be at] home all week just training, which would be so much easier. I have so many commitments. And I would say that in many areas that's a strength but if I'm not careful that can easily tip over and be a weakness.

&quot;I am constantly monitoring that. I run a tight ship with Marc [Hynes, his adviser and close friend] and my guys. I don't plan to be the easiest person to work with. I tell you how it is.

&quot;And if I ever feel that I need to back away, I've got people around me who [are supportive]. Like [last] Monday, for example, I was, like, 'Bono, I can't be there Monday but let's catch up on Tuesday because I'm overloaded. I need to sleep.' It's about understanding your body and making sure you stay centered.&quot;

'I can stay focused in meetings for, like, 23 minutes'

'Bono' is Hamilton's race engineer Peter Bonnington, one of the key figures at Mercedes - along with technical director James Allison, Shovlin, chief strategist James Vowles and others - who have helped shape the team into such a formidable force.

Just before this interview, Hamilton was deep in conversation with Allison and Shovlin about some technical matter, and he says his growth in this area has been critical to his continuing success.

&quot;I've just sat with James, and these guys are so smart; their intelligence level is on another stratosphere compared to mine,&quot; Hamilton says.

&quot;However, their minds can't compute what I can do in the car. We're just tuned differently. Trying to understand them, sitting at the table and speaking to them about what they can take from me to apply to the car, is really the key.

&quot;We're always working on that relationship, that rapport,&quot; Hamilton continues. &quot;We know each other so well.

&quot;I go in a meeting with them at the factory and those guys can sit in meetings for hours and stay focused. I have a window of, say, 23 minutes or something like that. As soon as I get there, it's all going over my head. They know. I say: 'Look, I gotta get up, go for a pee, have a coffee or something and I can come back.' And they get another 23 minutes.&quot;

The 2019 season and its challenges

At Mercedes, they believe this has been Hamilton's most impressive season. He has won half the 20 races so far, and had put a lock on the championship with seven victories in the first 10 grands prix.

If that looks like it was easy, Hamilton says it has been anything but. He says the 2019 Mercedes, while very strong, has been a difficult car to understand, it has taken time to get to grips with the intricacies of Pirelli's latest tyres, and team-mate Valtteri Bottas has been a stronger adversary than before.

But if Hamilton's season has been awesome in its consistent excellence, it has lacked the standout 'wow' moments that have come to be associated with him - a stunning pole lap out of nowhere, for example.

And while Hamilton is up 13-7 on Bottas in their qualifying head-to-head, and comfortably quicker on average, the Finn has five pole positions to Hamilton's four, which clearly irks him.

But when I ask whether this change in the character of his season was a deliberate plan, Hamilton looks almost hurt.

&quot;I wouldn't say it has been a plan to be less 'wow',&quot; he says, but he admits: &quot;More consistency within the race was really important for me. So, other areas, in just health aspects, weekend-in, weekend-out delivering.

&quot;It's crazy because we got to August and I'm thinking 'Jeez, I've had eight wins.' And as a team we've had, like, 14 wins and you kind of forget those things because you're just always looking forwards and time is always ticking.

&quot;But it was not intentional not to be 'wow'. I've been searching for that 'wow' lap this year. And honestly I've had good laps but they've not shown in the order, necessarily, you know?

&quot;Some of my second places that split up the Ferraris, for me felt like relatively quite 'wow' laps, but because I wasn't on pole by half a second it doesn't appear that way for you. But for me internally it did.&quot;

On hitting peak form and staying there

Bottas' increased strength was particularly notable at the beginning of the year, something Hamilton attributes in part to his former number-two race engineer transferring over this year to become the Finn's lead engineer and taking some of the world champion's secrets with him.

Bottas hit the ground running, after four races was leading the championship by a point from Hamilton and all the talk was of him being a new man in 2019. Hamilton admits it gave him pause for thought.

&quot;First couple of races are usually not perfect for me,&quot; Hamilton says. &quot;They're still not bad, still better than average, but then there's all the outside pressures of 'Valtteri 2.0' and I'm thinking: 'We're 2-2, two wins apiece.' And for me I'm… I can't… I've got to stay solid in my mind, I can't allow the outside… but being human it's very hard not to notice those things.

&quot;But then I just started ramping up after that, and it went 3-2, 4-2, 5-2, 6-2, 8-2 and I was like: 'That's gooood.'&quot; He laughs.

How does he find that extra gear? From inside himself, and from the details of hard work, Hamilton says.

&quot;From myself - hard to explain it. Like when you wake up, you're kinda groggy and not 100%. Then you hit… we all hit perfect peak at different points in the day. Just finding a way to be more fine-tuned physically. I think I've become the most fine-tuned physically and mentally I've ever been and that's a constant - every year I'm trying to improve that.&quot;

A key strength is that Hamilton has what Shovlin calls &quot;more tools in his box&quot; as a driver to adapt instantly in the car to changing conditions, such as weather or handling balance.

That, Hamilton says, is &quot;conscious&quot;.

&quot;I've always been able to adapt. One of my strengths is I think I am probably one of the most adaptive drivers there is. I'll jump into almost any scenario and figure my way through,&quot; he adds.

&quot;And that's why it works so well in the rain, for example, because you have to be dynamic in those places. Constantly shifting your driving style.

&quot;I have also studied other athletes. I listen to Valentino [Rossi] and how he feels he's had to change his driving style to keep up with the newer generation and I question myself whether that's necessary. That's his journey. He was so great, you know? But I look at that and try and figure out how I would position that.

&quot;If you look at tennis players and how they change their swing. I speak to Serena [Williams] and the nuances she goes into. I watch golf and see how Tiger [Woods] has slowly come back after improving his swing.

&quot;It is very similar to a driver. You can change these small things that just give you a wider platform and a wider foundation to be able to pull laps together. But, man, it's millimetres, or micrometers, and it's very, very hard to see the differences always.&quot;

'It still sucks to lose'

As he talks, Hamilton's love for the sport and determination to succeed is obvious. But he says that he has learned to deal better with the disappointment of losing as he has got older.

&quot;I remember, like, 2007 and 2008, in those times I couldn't leave my hotel room for three days. Through my whole young karting [career], I was so hard on myself.

&quot;In my mind, that is just how I deal with things. And people couldn't understand it: 'You finished second, or finished third or fifth' or whatever it may be. And they couldn't understand the turmoil that I would drop into - a really, really dark place, and I couldn't get myself out of it.

&quot;And that applied to a lot of things in my life. And as I've grown older I've just understood how to stay centred, get myself out of these dark holes, and I am less… even in the worst cases, they are not really that dark. That is just growth.

&quot;There was no quick, short route to doing it. But it still sucks to lose.&quot;

At 34, Hamilton knows he is closer to the end of his career than the beginning, but retirement is still some way off.

&quot;I don't fear it,&quot; he says. &quot;Naturally for athletes, it has to be the saddest day, to hang up and stop doing something you've loved your whole life and as long as you can remember.

&quot;But that is why I have all these other things in place that I can fall back on. The fashion side, for example. I've found another business that I can do for a long time if successful. Currently that is going really, really well but I don't know how long it will go. But at least I have another interest.

&quot;There are a lot of different things I can be interested in. I know my life is not going to be over when I retire. And that gives me a lot of comfort.

&quot;But right now I feel physically good enough to continue so I'm going to try to eke that out as long as I can.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/50494619</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-28</ID>
      <TITLE>Israel Folau: Super League votes for greater authority to stop controversial signings - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/4E5A/production/_110785002_folau_pa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Super League has voted unanimously to have &quot;greater authority&quot; to stop future &quot;controversial signings&quot; such as Israel Folau's move to Catalans Dragons.

The clubs held crisis talks over the signing of Folau, 30, at a Super League board meeting on Wednesday.

Folau, the sacked Australia rugby union international, has not played a match of any kind for 10 months since writing a homophobic post on social media.

Several clubs have backed Hull KR's threat of legal action over the deal.

&quot;With the season under way, we now feel it is important for Super League to separate what is an off-field matter from what is happening on the field,&quot; said Robert Elstone, Super League's chief executive.

Elstone said the Super League board &quot;accepts the legalities&quot; around the Rugby Football League's decision to register Folau.

But he added: &quot;The board has voted unanimously to put in place measures that ensure the Super League has greater authority to stop controversial signings such as this in the future.

&quot;As a sport, we have an impressive and enviable track record when it comes to equality, diversity and inclusion and we will continue our great work in those areas.&quot;

Folau was sacked by Australia Rugby for saying &quot;hell awaits&quot; gay people in a social media post in April 2019 and subsequently reached a settlement with the governing body.

He has begun training with Catalans, but the date of his Super League debut remains unclear as he has numerous fitness tests.

Dragons chairman Bernard Guasch did not attend Wednesday's meeting but a representative said Folau will not make his Catalans debut at Wakefield on Sunday.

The RFL and Super League both previously said they &quot;deplored&quot; Folau's comments and it was &quot;a difficult decision&quot; to allow him into the competition.

On Tuesday, the BBC obtained an email, written by Hull KR owner Neil Hudgell, putting the Dragons &quot;on notice&quot; if his club suffered &quot;financial loss&quot; because of the signing of Folau.

Dragons coach Steve McNamara said he &quot;stands by&quot; the decision to give Folau a one-year deal.

Halifax prop Keegan Hirst, Britain's first openly gay rugby league player, said the decision is &quot;disappointing and frustrating&quot;.

Shortly after the Folau deal was made public, Wigan announced that their match against Catalans at the DW Stadium on 22 March would be &quot;Pride Day&quot;.

Folau's signing comes after the National Rugby League ruled out his return to Australia's top-flight competition.

He played in the NRL for Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos and earned representative honours as a Queensland State of Origin player and Australia international.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-league/51390591</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-29</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula 1: Sean Bratches to leave commercial role - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/11807/production/_110578617_seanbratches.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Formula 1 commercial boss Sean Bratches is to leave his role at the end of the month.

Bratches, one of three executives appointed when US group Liberty Media bought the sport in January 2017, will not be directly replaced.

A statement from F1 said he would &quot;continue to support the business in an advisory role from the United States&quot;.

F1 chairman and chief executive Chase Carey said Bratches had &quot;transformed the commercial side of Formula 1&quot;.

The move, first reported by BBC Sport in August last year, comes as part of a reorganisation of the commercial side of F1.

When Liberty took over F1 and ousted former boss Bernie Ecclestone, it set up a management structure under Carey that saw former Mercedes team boss Ross Brawn head the sporting side and Bratches the commercial.

A statement from F1 emphasised the transformation of the sport since that time.

It said F1 had &quot;broadened its sponsor portfolio, improved the reach and scope of the sport's global media rights, renewed key race promotion agreements and announced two new races to the Formula 1 calendar (in the Netherlands and Vietnam, both of which debut this year).

&quot;Formula 1's digital business was revamped under his leadership, launching a new responsive web platform and extending the brand into areas such as direct to consumer, fantasy, podcasting, licensing and betting.

&quot;All key metrics including race attendance, television viewership, and digital and social media engagement and usage have increased during his tenure.&quot;

However, Bratches has not been successful in one of his headline ambitions, which was to set up a new race in what he calls a &quot;destination city&quot; in the USA.

Bratches had earmarked Miami but an initial proposal for a race downtown and over a bridge foundered on local opposition.

F1 is now trying to set up a race in a less dramatic location around the Miami Dolphins NFL stadium, but this has yet to materialise.

Bratches said: &quot;I am proud that I leave Formula 1 in a better position than when I joined in 2017 and I know that the foundation we have put in place as a team will continue to serve our fans around the world and reach new audiences.&quot;

Head of marketing Ellie Norman and Frank Arthofer, global head of digital media and licensing, will now report directly to Carey.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51179259</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-04 00:00:00-30</ID>
      <TITLE>Darren Lehmann to have heart bypass surgery - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Cricket</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/153EA/production/_110781078_gettyimages-1198814602.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former Australia batsman and coach Darren Lehmann will have a heart bypass operation after falling ill on Wednesday, his 50th birthday.

Lehmann suffered chest pains while watching his son Jake, 27, captain a Cricket Australia XI against England Lions on the Gold Coast.

Lehmann, who played in 27 Tests, will have surgery in Brisbane on Saturday.

&quot;I would like to thank everyone in the Australian cricket family for their concern,&quot; he said.

&quot;I am receiving the best of medical care and am confident I'll be back on my feet soon.&quot;

Lehmann, who also played in 117 one-day internationals and helped Australia win two World Cups, coached the national team from 2013 to 2018.

He returned to coaching for the latest Big Bash League, which concludes on Saturday, but failed to lead Brisbane Heat into the play-off phase.

Lehmann was also appointed coach of the Northern Superchargers, based in Leeds, for the inaugural season of The Hundred, which begins on 17 July.

He was Yorkshire's overseas player from 1997 to 2006 and helped them to their first County Championship title in 33 years in 2001.

Yorkshire director of cricket Martyn Moxon added: &quot;He's been a great servant for Yorkshire County Cricket Club over the years and we wish both him and his family well in the coming weeks.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/cricket/51384089</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
