<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-12 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Technology | German admits creating Sasser</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-12</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sven Jaschan is charged with computer sabotage, disrupting public services and illegally altering data.

The 19-year-old is being tried as a minor behind closed doors as he was 17 when he wrote the worm.

Sasser wrought havoc in many companies when the Windows worm struck in May 2004, swamping net links and making computers unusable.

As the day's legal proceedings started, Mr Jaschan &quot;admitted to the alleged offences in every detail,&quot; said a court spokeswoman.

Defendants under German law do not enter formal pleas so the trial continues despite Mr Jaschan's confession.

The trial in Verden in northwest Germany is expected to last three days, with a possible verdict on Thursday.

He is likely to escape the maximum sentence of five years in prison since he is being tried as a juvenile.

He now works for a German security software company called Securepoint.

A $250,000 bounty offered by Microsoft produced a tip-off that led German police to Sven Jaschan in May 2004.

The German authorities have called a public broadcaster and three German city councils as witnesses to describe the disruption that the worm caused.

Check-in for some British Airways flights was also delayed thanks to Sasser.

Around the world, the Australian Railcorp trains stopped running because computer problems caused by Sasser made it impossible for drivers to talk to signalmen.

In Taiwan, more than 400 branches of the post office were forced to use pen and paper because Sasser crashed desktop PCs.

Soon after being arrested in May 2004 at his home in Waffensen, Mr Jaschan reportedly confessed that he was the creator of Sasser and some versions of the Netsky virus.

Anti-virus firm Sophos estimates that 70% of all the virus infections in the first half of 2004 could be blamed on Mr Jaschan's creations.

Statistics gathered by Sophos show that in the first six months of 2005 there were four variants of Netsky in the top 10 viruses and they accounted for 25.5% of all infections.

Unlike many other viruses, Sasser made its way from computer to computer without help from users. It got into Windows computers by exploiting a programming bug in the operating system.

Although Microsoft had released a patch for this loophole on 13 and 28 April 2004, many companies had not applied this protection before Sasser struck.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4649361.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-12 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Technology | Net fuels Live 8 extravaganza</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-12</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Almost 27 million people texted in their support for a petition asking G8 leaders to double aid and cancel debts for the world's poorest countries.

Millions watched the event online and recordings of Sergeant Pepper were on sale an hour after being sung live.

But videos and audio of many of the acts were also available via BitTorrent file-sharing software.

The greater use of technology was one of the many ways that the Live 8 distinguished itself from the Live Aid concerts 20 years ago.

Those attending the gigs and watching on TV were asked to text their support to an online petition. The 26.4 million names collected is thought to be a world record and far outstrips the 5.8 million gathered for one episode of American Idol.

As well as asking G8 leaders to cancel debts and boost aid, the petition also calls for a change to trade laws to give poor nations a better chance to prosper.

The events also prompted many bloggers to comment on what was going on. Blog watching service Technorati listed more than 30,000 blog entries for the concerts and said &quot;Live 8&quot; and &quot;Live8&quot; were among its top searches.

This time round there were 10 gigs, not just two, and many turned to the net to pick and choose which acts they watched.

AOL said that a total of five million people dipped in during the day to watch the different Live 8 gigs via its portals.

The peak number of viewers was 175,000, far more than the past record of 100,000 for the Pope's funeral.

At the peak, AOL said it was serving up more than 50 gigabits of traffic every second.

Technology also helped to get the version of Sergeant Pepper's Lonely Heart's Club Band sung by U2 and Sir Paul McCartney into online stores within an hour of it being performed.

Proceeds from the sale will go to Live 8.

The technology theme was continued when Microsoft chairman Bill Gates took to the stage in London to add his support.

&quot;If you show people the problems and you show people the solutions they will be moved to act,&quot; said Mr Gates.

If Live 8 proves successful, he said it could be the &quot;best thing humanity has ever done&quot;.

Many people have dodged the charges to get their Live 8 experience for free by turning to file-sharing site with BitTorrent links, where many recordings of the acts taking part were available to download.

According to one BitTorrent search site, top of the downloads was Pink Floyd's set at the London Live 8 event.

Other popular performances included Coldplay, Dido, Green day and The Who.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4648003.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-12 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Technology | Mobiles head for sales milestone</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-12</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Research firm Gartner said that the world's appetite for mobile phones had exceeded even the most optimistic expectations.

&quot;Mobile phones could go on to be the most common consumer electronics device on the planet,&quot; said Gartner analyst Ben Wood.

By the end of 2009, some 2.6 billion mobiles will be in regular use around the world, Gartner predicts.

The findings are based on a study that looked at sales figures from 62 countries around the globe.

It is expected that some 779 million mobile handsets will be sold by the end of this year, 50 million of which will be smartphones.

Prices of handsets are likely to fall and while this is good news for consumers, the future for phone manufacturers is less certain.

&quot;The technology inside phones has increased at an astonishing rate but prices haven't reflected this,&quot; said Mr Wood.

With some manufacturers already facing difficulties in certain countries, it will be survival of the fittest.

&quot;Vendors not selling 10 million phones a year will definitely struggle,&quot; he said.

The nature of the mobile in our pocket is likely to evolve.

In mature markets such as the UK, Germany and the US there will be more mobiles catering to specific functionality, whether it be music, photography or video.

And in less developed markets phones will again be targeted to specific needs.

&quot;In sub-Saharan Africa phones will be small, simple and with very good battery life,&quot; said Mr Wood.

By 2009, Asia/Pacific will account for a third of all mobile sales.

&quot;China and India alone will account for nearly 200 million units in 2007, with the Indian market surpassing China in 2009 to reach 139 million units,&quot; said Gartner analyst Ann Liang.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4697405.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-12 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC News - Fake Tube safety e-mail spreads</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-12</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mobiles do not work on the London Underground at all London Transport and mobile firms are warning people about an e-mail spreading rapidly containing inaccurate safety information. The message claims that passengers on the London Tube system can contact emergency services via a satellite signal from their mobiles underground. Mobiles do not work in the London Underground, and satellite signals cannot reach there either. A Vodafone spokesperson said it had had numerous enquiries about the &quot;hoax&quot;. &quot;This e-mail is incorrect. The 112 number does link people through to 999, but it only works if you have a signal on your mobile phone. If you have no signal bars on your phone, it will not work,&quot; a spokesperson from London Transport said. &quot;It will not divert to a satellite signal. &quot;Even with a satellite mobile phone (which very few people have), you would need to have a clear line-of-sight to the satellite. You would have to be outside, not in a building or a tube tunnel.&quot; A Vodafone spokesperson told the BBC News website that, at a time of heightened tension and security fears on the Underground system following the recent bomb attacks, it was clear people wanted to pass on useful information. But, he added, people unthinkingly pass on e-mails without analysing the information contained in it. Important Number you should note 25/Jul/05 09:24 If you travel to work on the tube please note the following information: If your mobile phone has no signal (so even if you were in a tunnel) if you dial 112 it diverts to a satellite signal and puts you through to the 999 call centre. ALL phone companies have signed up and as it is a satellite service it also gives them a trace to you if you don't know where you are. 

 &quot;By forwarding false information they can panic people and also create vast amounts of work for people who have to deal with it and enquiries about it,&quot; he said. Although the 112 number is indeed the European-wide standard number that will connect people to emergency services wherever they are in Europe, it is not accessible from mobiles underground in London. A spokesperson from mobile operator Orange reiterated that if you do not have a signal on your mobile you simply cannot make a call. If you are not in the Underground system and do not have a signal from your network operator, emergency calls can be made as your phone will automatically detect the next available network. Orange and Vodafone both added that the line in the e-mail which says: &quot;ALL phone companies have signed up&quot; to some sort of satellite link up service was also inaccurate. Vodafone said that often &quot;hoax&quot; e-mails contain accurate information, such as the 112 number's existence, to attempt to add credibility to the mail. It is unknown however, whether the e-mail has been devised as a hoax, intended to misguide people, or whether it is a result of misunderstood mobile technology. &quot;The e-mail originates either from ignorance or malicious intent, but the bottom line is that recipients should ignore its content and should resist the urge to pass on this information to others,&quot; Daniel Hepner, from web monitoring firm SurfControl, told the BBC News website. &quot;Either someone is attempting to cause confusion amongst commuters, or they have a very sick sense of humour. &quot;It's possible that it could stem from an individual that is unaware of the misinformation, but in the current climate all such e-mails will be treated with suspicion,&quot; he said. Shortly after the bomb attacks in London, e-mail hoaxers tried to disrupt a campaign, In Case of Emergency (ICE), which aimed to get people to store next-of-kin details in their mobile phones. The hoaxers claimed that the campaign was in fact a mobile phone virus. A further e-mail hoax circulated warning Underground travellers of further imminent attacks. &quot;The 'In Case of Emergency' virus hoax has heightened people's suspicions over this kind of traffic, and it is important that we all exercise caution before disseminating these messages further,&quot; said Mr Hepner.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4724101.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-04-12 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Technology | Mobiles capture blast aftermath</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-04-12</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Mobile video footage shot by commuters from inside London Underground carriages appeared quickly on global news networks and across the net.

As video mobiles grow more popular in Europe, they are letting people capture the first scenes of chaos before TV.

The attacks on the London Underground and a double-decker bus killed more than 50 and left 700 injured.

Hundreds of mobile photos and several mobile videos have surfaced documenting the moments after the four blasts.

Blogs, photo sharing websites, online news sites, and TV news used their images in the minutes and hours immediately following the attacks.

Within minutes and hours, news of explosions filtered through other blog sites and many moblogs - blogs which use mobile phone photos - collected the images.

The BBC News and Sky News websites, among others, immediately responded and called for readers to send in their images, footage and accounts of the events.

Around 1,000 photos and 20 pieces of amateur video were sent in to the BBC News website, with many being featured on the site.

&quot;Within minutes we were receiving people's written accounts and their still pictures,&quot; said BBC News Interactive editor Pete Clifton.

&quot;An image of the bus with its roof torn away was sent to us by a reader inside an hour, and it was our main picture on the front page for a large part of the day.

&quot;By the end of the day many of the images on the site had been provided by our users, and many of them were subsequently used by many other BBC services and national newspapers as well.

&quot;It certainly showed the power of what our users can do when they are close to a terrible event like this,&quot; said Mr Clifton.

Although data transfer and calls cannot be made on a mobile in most of the London underground network, photo, video and other such functions do work.

Third-generation (3G) and second-generation phones that can shoot video are becoming more popular in the UK, where mobile penetration is more than 80%.

The use of mobile reporting in mainstream news is a sign of the changing relationship between journalists and non-journalists, and is proving a powerful way to report events before TV cameras arrive.

It has been called &quot;open source news&quot; or citizen journalism and was well-used during last year's US election campaign.

News organisations in Japan were the first to recognise the power of mobiles, and often turn to such electronic newsgathering to get the first images.

In the aftermath of the Asian tsunami last December, mobile footage of the moments the waves crashed in were beamed all over the world.

In November last year, the dead body of Dutch film maker Theo van Gogh was snapped by a passer-by on a mobile before professional photographers reached the scene.

The picture appeared on the pages of Telegraaf, a daily Amsterdam newspaper, and made the news globally.

The BBC also tested mobile technology formally in a trial broadcast last year.

Unlike TV cameras, mobile phones only need a functioning network to send back moving images. This can be done at the touch of a couple of buttons.

TV crews often need feed links and complex set-ups to file back their high-quality images.

The grainy quality of the moving mobile images will improve over time, but news organisations say viewers forgive the quality as they understand the circumstances in which such footage is often shot.

Websites and moblogs have also started to appear with images of support for those affected by the blasts.

One such moblog, We Are Not Afraid, features dozens of images of people, many from the US, holding up messages reading &quot;We are not afraid&quot;.

Such images have also been appearing Flickr, which quickly became an easily searchable depository for images of the events.

Mobiles are also proving crucial investigative tools too. Authorities will be scouring mobile records in the bid to find who was responsible for the attacks.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/technology/4663561.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
