<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Keeping rats out of kitchens and bedbugs out of hotels - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F7AD/production/_110750436_rat.sewere.g.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When construction work disturbed a pack of rats near his commercial kitchen business in County Wicklow, Ireland, Shane Bonner knew he needed a savvier approach to pest control.

His existing contract, which used a no-frills bait box and regular site inspections, was falling short at Newmarket Kitchen, a rented facility shared by 17 food producers, and giving the wrong impression.

&quot;It's not great business having pest controllers on site regularly - people assume there's a problem rather than an inspection; plus we found they were either around when not needed or if there was an issue, the response wasn't fast enough,&quot; says the entrepreneur.

&quot;If an animal was caught (in the trap) we also had no idea how long it had been there, or when or how it got into the building - which affects our peace of mind when running a food business.&quot;

So he opted for a more hi-tech approach.

Pest Pulse traps use pressure sensor technology to identify a catch and alert the company straight away over the internet.

Pest Pulse is just one of many businesses looking to disrupt an industry worth £463m and $13.9bn (£10.6bn) annually, in the UK and US respectively.

&quot;By knowing exactly when something was caught you can then start look at the bigger picture by checking cameras to see if one of the loading bay doors was left open,&quot; says Mr Bonner.

&quot;It also means our annual pest management charge has come down by 20% because we're not paying for the labour involved in the usual service; and we don't have people coming around unnecessarily.&quot;

Tim O'Toole, who co-founded Pest Pulse after working at Google and Ebay, believes the makeover is long overdue in an industry he describes as &quot;reactive, rudimentary and stuck in 1987&quot;.
• What can you use instead of Google and Facebook?
• Robot tanks: On patrol but not allowed to shoot

&quot;All other compliance-based industries, for example, food storage using smart fridges, have embraced the IoT [internet of things]. But with pest management we still had a guy checking a box in the corner every 12 weeks and writing the result down on a piece of paper which isn't good enough - rats can multiply very fast.

&quot;We've got rising levels of infestation so traditional pest control contracts are having to increase the number of visits from controllers - additional labour costs that will be passed onto the customer,&quot; he says.

&quot;Plus, we're seeing much tighter legislation on the use of biocides [poisons]. Increasingly, its use has to be based on evidence of infestation. So a cost-effective, targeted, tech-led approach with reduced environmental impact becomes much more critical.&quot;

But what if the infestation is harder to find?

Thermal imaging cameras have become a popular tool to detect pests at night or in cavity walls, floors and roofs, illuminating their outline and pinpointing the source for faster, efficient removal.

Pest controller Thomas Bonny in Noyers, France, became aware of the technology's potential in his previous role as a firefighter where it was used to improve visibility in heavy smoke. Using a solution from US manufacturer, FLIR systems, the camera has transformed how he removes wasp nests, by cutting costs and time.

&quot;In the past, we relied on sound rather than sight to find a nest, but locating this very faint noise can be very difficult and time consuming,&quot; he says.

&quot;For a single inspection, a thermal imager can save you one or more hours depending on how difficult it is to reach. But it also allows you to quickly find the exact spot of the nest, which means that you only do the minimum required damage. There is no need to rip out entire walls or ceilings to find the right location.&quot;

It explains the growth of thermal imaging in the hotel sector, where the need to detect bedbugs the size of an apple seed, is an increasing problem. Here, the impact of stringent pesticide controls is making it harder to eradicate bed bugs - affecting hotels' reputations and their profits.

A 2016 study by pest control company, Orkin, of US hotels found that eight of 10 had dealt with an infestation over the previous year, with the average cost per outbreak of $6,383 in replacement of soft-goods, treatment and lost business.

The traditional reliance on a diligent housekeeping is no longer cutting it, says Robert Fryers, the chief executive of Spotta, a Cambridge-based business which has developed a more advanced way of tackling such infestations.

Designed by entomologists, the Spotta pod, is positioned in the bedbug's sweet spot between the mattress and bedframe, the pod contains a synthetic pheromone that draws the insects into the trap usually within hours of their arrival.

&quot;Bedbugs have always been a problem for hotels but with climate change and the rise in international travel from hot countries it has become much worse - although it isn't talked about much in the industry.

&quot;Historically, hotels could only deal with this reactively, when a guest complained, and by that point the damage is done,&quot; says Mr Fryers.

Algorithm analysis identifies the insect, distinguishing between a tropical bedbug, carbon beetle or silverfish and a camera takes a picture with all data emailed to the hotel. The contents of the pod are then sealed in and returned to Spotta's laboratory for sterilization.

&quot;People assume these bugs are down to a hotel's poor cleanliness. But they are brought in by people from their clothes and bags, which is why we're finding the greatest traction with city and airport hotels that have a high turnover of international guests,&quot; says Mr Fryers.

&quot;In the US, lawsuits and compensation claims on the issue are becoming more prevalent. Hotels need to be able to demonstrate they are doing everything they can.&quot;

So while it might seem expensive to employ hi-tech pest control, it could save some even bigger legal bills.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51019178</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: 'We may have no clothes left to sell' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/6225/production/_110752152_image-v1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>&quot;At the moment, we'll have no products to sell and we could miss Fashion Week in Europe,&quot; says Xuzhi Chen, a fashion designer who runs just one of the UK businesses affected by the coronavirus outbreak.

The London-based designer is best known for his luxury womenswear collections.

He employs 10 workers in Shanghai who focus on operations and creating samples. The brand shifted all of its production to China in 2017.

But following on from the coronavirus outbreak in December, many Chinese factories have suspended their operations as officials try to contain the deadly disease.
• Coronavirus: How worried should we be?

&quot;Even when the factories reopen, not all of the workers will return immediately, so we're not sure they'll be working at full capacity,&quot; Mr Chen says.

He expects a two to three week delay to deliveries, throwing off product launches that were due to take place in March and April.

He says there's also uncertainty around whether or not Shanghai Fashion Week in March could be postponed, or cancelled.

&quot;This is a key moment for us, where we would usually sell most of our Autumn-Winter 2020 collection.

&quot;Store buyers come from all over China and the world to our showroom and place orders for their shops,&quot; Mr Chen says.

He adds that the outbreak has caused him to rethink the next six months for the fashion label, which sells most of its garments in China.

&quot;As a wholesale business for boutiques, we're now having to be more creative in a business sense.

&quot;We're thinking of launching our own e-commerce platform, and developing our online reach. While the government and the world is trying to contain this, we'll need to use it as an opportunity to try something new.&quot;

There have been more than 17,000 confirmed cases of coronavirus and 361 deaths. Many Chinese cities are in full or partial lockdown.

Over in the UK the disruption is affecting not only smaller businesses but larger operations, too.

With more than 7,000 employees and a turnover of £1bn annually, Tulip Ltd is one of the UK's largest fresh pork producers.

China is also one of its fastest-growing export markets.

Nick Purnell, head of corporate communications at Tulip Ltd, told the BBC that British pork exports to China &quot;have more than doubled&quot; in recent months.

&quot;This is largely a result of shortages due to an outbreak of African swine fever. We've seen an increase in sales to China of about 80% year-on-year,&quot; he said.

Tulip's sales to wholesale businesses and restaurants located in China have seen a boost, where pork is often a staple in diets.

But Mr Purnell said the company anticipates congestion in Chinese ports could see a &quot;short-term impact&quot; on trade, potentially putting a dampener on strong sales.

Extra safety measures are in place at Chinese ports. The coronavirus originated in the port city of Wuhan in the Hubei province.

As for consumer demand being impacted, Mr Purnell said: &quot;Things are changing day by day, and we're working under the assumption that the outbreak will be bought under control at some point.&quot;

&quot;Usually, we factor in the Chinese New Year and plan our production around that,&quot; says Tracey Dawson, the managing director of Daletech Electronics.

The company is based in Pudsey outside Leeds, and makes circuit boards.

&quot;But, we were surprised to hear that that the factory that was due to send us materials this week is in one of the affected provinces - and is on lockdown,&quot; she says.

Many UK technology firms depend on suppliers in China for electronics, but the coronavirus outbreak has disrupted production for some.

Ms Dawson told the BBC's Today programme that most of the materials the company uses are imported from China and other Asian countries.

She said that her team were sourcing some products from elsewhere, increasing costs and adding a &quot;business pressure&quot;.

She said: &quot;The impact is of course, on our customers. We're fighting to maintain delivery, and we will absorb the costs in the short term.

&quot;But, if this isn't resolved in a timely manner, we anticipate there could be problems.&quot;

Charlie Netherton, UK managing director at Marsh Risk Consulting, said smaller firms often don't have the resources to map out their supply chains and think of alternatives should something go wrong.

Mr Netherton said: &quot;Now is the time to be proactive, now is the time to plan.

&quot;That way, it might be unpleasant but it's not as much of a shock.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51357030</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Disney+ takes on Netflix as 28 million subscribers sign up - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10079/production/_110775656_gettyimages-1187551494.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sign-ups for Disney's new streaming service have shot past expectations, as audiences respond to the offering of Star Wars, cartoons and other classics.

Walt Disney said about 28.6 million people had signed up for Disney+ since it started in November.

The on-demand video service, which costs $6.99 per month, is Disney's attempt to challenge industry leader Netflix, which has 170m subscribers.

Disney+ now has almost as many subscribers as the firm's earlier on-demand streaming service Hulu, which was founded in 2007 and offers shows from US television.

&quot;The launch of Disney+ has been enormously successful, exceeding even our greatest expectations,&quot; Mr Iger said on a call with analysts after the release of the company's quarterly earnings.

Disney also warned investors that its operating income in the next quarter could take a nearly $300m hit due to the closure of its parks in China.

That figure assumes the coronavirus outbreak keeps Disney's resorts in Shanghai and Hong Kong closed for two months, and takes into account the fact that visitors to Hong Kong had already dropped significantly due to protests there.

Disney announced in 2017 that it would create its own streaming service, aiming to combat the declining audiences for its traditional business as viewers move online.

Shortly after, it announced a deal to buy the bulk of Rupert Murdoch's 21st Century Fox entertainment empire, as it looked to bulk up its catalogue to compete.

&quot;I'm enormously proud of what we have accomplished in a relatively short period of time and believe we are well positioned to not only withstand the disruptive forces ... but to thrive,&quot; Mr Iger said.

Most of the current subscribers come from the US and about half signed up directly through the website, he said. He attributed part of the appeal to Disney's &quot;very accessible&quot; price.

International expansion of Disney+ is the firm's next priority, he added.

The service is currently available in five countries, including the US and Canada. It is due to launch in the UK and other countries in western Europe next month. Mr Iger said the service will also launch in India in March.

Disney said revenues in the quarter were up 36% year-on-year. However profits declined 25% from $2.8bn to $2.1bn, amid heavy spending on its on-demand offerings.

Revenues in its direct-to-consumer unit - which includes Hulu and Disney+ - increased to $4bn, from $0.9bn, but operating loss widened from $136m to $693m.

Disney shares rose more than 2% in after-hours trade.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51379064</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>CEO Secrets: Can you be the boss if you're in chronic pain? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1136C/production/_110780507_p0829kgg.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When Shazia Ginai took over as the boss of Neuro-Insight, she thought CEOs had to be &quot;bulletproof&quot;. She has a medical condition which causes her chronic pain, and wondered if she could do the job.

But being open didn't lower her standing with her staff. Instead it's drawn them closer to her.

Find more business tips at CEO Secrets. You can also follow the series on the BBC News app by adding the topic 'CEO Secrets' in My News.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312928</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Software boss hands himself in on fraud charge - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://m.files.bbci.co.uk/modules/bbc-morph-news-waf-page-meta/4.1.2/bbc_news_logo.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Co-founder of Rockstar Games, Dan Houser, is leaving the firm he started with his brother Sam in 1998.

Mr Houser was a main creative force behind two of the firm's biggest series, Grand Theft Auto and Red Dead.

His departure comes after an &quot;extended break&quot;, Rockstar's parent company Take-Two Interactive said.

Rockstar's series have often courted controversy, but are among the best-selling and most critically-acclaimed games of the past two decades.

Mr Houser will officially depart in March, according to a notice Take-Two sent to US financial regulators. His brother Sam Houser will remain as the company's president.

Click here to read more</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/business-51324473</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Ad-targeting should be made transparent, data ethics body says - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EC7A/production/_110783506_mediaitem110778662.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Major online companies should be required to host publicly accessible archives of certain targeted adverts, a government-commissioned report says.

Political ads and those for housing, credit, jobs and age-restricted products should be included, it says.

It follows controversy over the targeting of political adverts during the 2019 general election.

Web users want &quot;meaningful control&quot; over how their data is used to target advertising, the report says.

The Centre for Data Ethics and Innovation (CDEI)'s report also suggests the forthcoming online harms regulator should have the power to:
• give independent experts secure access to online businesses to audit their use of people's data
• compel online companies to give access to independent researchers &quot;for research of significant potential importance to public policy&quot;
• make companies take steps to protect vulnerable people and be accountable for the effects of ad-targeting systems

This regulator should also establish a code of practice for businesses that buy or sell targeted ads online, the reports says.

&quot;We have reviewed the powers of the existing regulators and conclude that enforcement of existing legislation and self-regulation cannot be relied on to meet public expectations of greater accountability,&quot; it says.

A spokeswoman for the UK's Internet Advertising Bureau said: &quot;We welcome the CDEI's recognition that online targeting is an important driver of economic value and a core element of many business models, as well as the fact that people do value the benefits of targeting.&quot;

She added that the bureau, for one, was committed to increasing ad industry transparency.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-51384858</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Gambling in football: Bookmakers considering ban on shirt and pitchside advertising - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/113F7/production/_110774607_gettyimages-1203399162.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Bookmakers are &quot;considering&quot; a voluntary ban on football shirt sponsorship and pitchside advertising, a parliamentary committee has heard.

It would expand on the whistle-to-whistle ban on television gambling adverts introduced last year.

Half of Premier League clubs and 17 of 24 Championship clubs are sponsored by bookmakers.

That had led to concerns about the potential impact on young fans and vulnerable people.

Brigid Simmonds, chair of the The Betting and Gaming Council (BGC), which represents 90% of the betting and gaming industry, told the House of Lords' Gambling Industry Committee that the whistle-to-whistle ban has reduced gambling advertising on television by 85%.

However, she conceded that some of the advertising may have moved online and added: &quot;We may well need to do more and we are absolutely open to that.&quot;

Asked whether her organisation was considering banning gambling logos from football shirts and perimeter stadium advertising, she said: &quot;We are certainly looking at the whole issue of sponsorship.

&quot;I think, as one of us said earlier, there are good messages. All the sponsorship that goes with clubs is about putting responsible messages on shirts as well as the name.

&quot;We can consider this going forward, we are active in considering it.

&quot;But I would also say, as someone who has worked a lot in sport in the last 50 years, that actually grassroots sports benefit from a lot of the money that is put into sport.

&quot;We want that sponsorship to be used responsibly.&quot;

GVC, the parent company of Ladbrokes and Coral, has already withdrawn its sponsorship in football.

Its chief executive Kenny Alexander called for a wider industry move in this area, saying: &quot;I think it needs to be seriously cut down.&quot;

He added: &quot;Is the industry too much in the face of the consumer at the moment?

&quot;Is there too much TV advertising, is there too much sponsorship? I think that is undoubtedly the case and something I feel should be looked at.

&quot;There are probably too many gambling adverts and too much noise about gambling in front of consumers in the UK at the moment.&quot;

John Coates, joint chief executive of Bet365 and vice-chairman of Stoke City, said &quot;I do hear the concerns&quot; about the amount of advertising and said he &quot;welcomes&quot; the review of the Gambling Act.

However, he also said: &quot;Stoke City survives on the money we put into it.&quot;

Meanwhile, Conor Grant, chief operating officer of Sky Betting and Gaming, which sponsors the EFL, said: &quot;I think it is important that we do have the opportunity to advertise as a business and I think it is really important we do that responsibly.

&quot;The tone with which we do it, and the frequency, is all up for discussion. We welcome the review that is happening.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51377202</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit preparations: 'We've stockpiled 10,000 wine bottles' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/8B5F/production/_110697653_p081qjtv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Worries for the future over settlement scheme

Guillermo, who is Spanish but was born and raised in the UK, has applied to stay via the EU settlement scheme and has concerns about the future.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51302765</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What does it mean for my business? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Suffolk</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EF39/production/_110714216_p081vkyl.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Preparations, port delays and planning for a potential no-deal - these are some of your big Brexit questions.

BBC East business correspondent Richard Bond has been answering some of the queries from businesses in Suffolk.

The UK formally leaves the European Union (EU) at 23:00 GMT on Friday, 31 January.

It will immediately enter an 11-month transition period.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-suffolk-51318721</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>How will the petrol and diesel car ban work? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10BCC/production/_110765586_charging_crop.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A ban on the sale of new petrol, diesel and hybrid cars is to be brought forward, the government says.

So how could the move help the UK meet its target of emitting virtually zero carbon by 2050? And what does it mean for drivers?

When will petrol and diesel cars be banned?

The ban is being introduced in 2035 - five years earlier than previously planned.

Experts said the original target of 2040 would be too late if the UK wanted to achieve its target of emitting virtually zero carbon by 2050.

The ban is also being expanded to hybrid cars and plug-in hybrids, which had not been included under the original proposals.

As a result, people will be able to buy only electric or hydrogen cars and vans.

What difference will it make to climate change?

About a third of CO2 emissions in the UK come from transport.

So the ban on conventional car sales will certainly help move the UK towards the net-zero target the government announced in 2019.

The Committee on Climate Change, which advises government, said if other countries followed the UK, there was a 50-50 chance of staying below the recommended temperature rise of 1.5C by 2100. This is considered the threshold for dangerous climate change.

However, banning new petrol, diesel and hybrid cars won't be enough on its own.

The government will also need to tackle the emissions coming from energy generation. These are almost as high as from transport and come from things such as industry and people's homes.

How will it help reduce pollution?

Emissions of nitrogen oxides (Nox) - which come from car exhausts - regularly exceed safe levels in many cities.

Diesel vehicles produce the overwhelming majority of roadside Nox gases. So removing petrol and diesel vehicles from the roads should help bring air quality within the guidelines set out by the World Health Organization (WHO).

Air pollution has been a concern for decades. But the issue gained renewed urgency when the UK government lost court cases over its plans to reduce nitrogen-dioxide levels.

As a result, ministers were ordered by the courts to produce a new plan to tackle Nox levels.

The discussion was complicated when carmakers were found to be cheating emissions tests.

But in recent years, scientists have become more certain about the ways air pollution harms people. Studies have linked it to heart disease and lung problems, as well as other conditions.

How much does an electric car cost?

The Committee on Climate Change believes the cost of electric cars will be similar to that of petrol or diesel vehicles by 2024-25.

But for now, electric cars are more expensive than their petrol or diesel counterparts.

That's because battery technology is still developing and production requires expensive raw materials and engineers.

The UK's most popular electric car, the Nissan Leaf, costs £26,000 for a basic model. The government does provide a £3,500 subsidy but for many motorists, the cost is still too high.

Some experts say a more radical approach, such as no VAT on electric cars, would create a surge in demand.

A scheme like this exists in Norway, where 2019 saw a huge increase in people opting for electric cars.

At present, there is a very small second-hand market for electric cars.

That's because they make up less than 1% of the total number of cars on UK roads.

If we're to switch to electric cars, the speed of installing charging points will have to radically increase, to cope with demand.

It has been estimated the UK needs to have 25 million charging points for electric vehicles.

There are now nearly 11,000 places in the UK where you can charge electric vehicles.

While there are parts of the country where the number of charging points is keeping up with demand, more are needed in many places.

And there are other potential problems.

For example, where will power points be sited? Will roads have to be dug up for cabling? Will drivers have to share power points, and so be restricted to certain charging times?

People who live in flats, or houses without driveways, could struggle to charge their electric cars at home.

It is hoped charge points installed in lampposts next to parking bays could help but rollout so far has been limited.

There is also a need for more rapid-charging points, for people on long journeys and those who haven't charged overnight.

What will happen to old petrol and diesel cars?

There is currently no UK-wide scrappage scheme in place for petrol and diesel cars and it is unclear if the government is considering this.

In London, the city's Mayor, Sadiq Khan, announced a £25m scrappage scheme to take older polluting cars and motorbikes off its streets, to reduce CO2 pollution.

You will still be able to buy a second-hand petrol or diesel car in 2035 and drive one you currently own.

There could even be a boom in petrol or diesel sales in 2034, as motorists prepare to buy combustion engines for the final time.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-40726868</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>'My African name stopped me getting job opportunities' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/14530/production/_110784238_funkeprofessionalphoto.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lawyer and diversity campaigner Funke Abimbola says she suffered &quot;bias&quot; when she tried to get into the profession.

About a third of FTSE 100 companies have no ethnic minority representation on their boards, a report has revealed.

The Parker Review Committee found 31 of the 83 firms which provided relevant information fell into this category.

Ms Abimbola said: &quot;I found a number of barriers to entering the profession because I had an African name and am a black woman, without any doubt.&quot;

She told the BBC: &quot;I had to make over 100 phone calls to get a foot in the door.

&quot;I have experienced bias and situations where, being a black woman, I was judged more harshly over other colleagues. You are more likely to be noticed and are far more likely to have negative judgements made about you if you are part of an ethnic minority.&quot;

The Parker report also found even lower representation at board level across FTSE 250 companies, where 119 out of 173 (69%) had no ethnic diversity.

Ms Abimbola said: &quot;The report doesn't surprise me. There are so many barriers to senior roles for minority ethnic clients to be considered.&quot;

The Parker committee, formed to consult on the ethnic diversity of company boards, published its first report into the subject in 2017.

At the time, 51 of the FTSE 100 companies had no ethnic representation on their boards, in comparison with about 33% today. Data was not collected from the FTSE 250 firms.

That report recommended that each FTSE 100 company should have at least one director of colour by 2021, and that each FTSE 250 board should do the same by 2024.

Speaking on BBC's Today programme, committee chairman Sir John Parker admitted that with two years still to go, achieving the target &quot;still looks a pretty tall climb&quot;.

&quot;On the other hand I recall well when I was on the Davies Committee on women on boards, about the halfway stage we had a not dissimilar situation and we met the 25% [target] in that case by the end of the five-year period.

&quot;There are some leaders who want to wait and see and let others take the lead and thankfully there are those who take the lead and I think there will be a few who will wait till the bitter end because they're not totally convinced that it's the right thing to do, but they will move as they did on women on boards when they see widespread adoption,&quot; he added.

To help speed up the process, the new report has recommended that companies should:
• Report on the ethnic diversity of their boards
• Report on their ethnic diversity policies and activities with the aim of delivering the Parker Review's recommendations

Ms Abimbola believes that introducing an action plan to help with targets of ethnic minority representation is the key.

&quot;There are a few agencies in the UK who specifically recruit diverse talent. They set up power lists every year across many talents, so if you want to look for BAME candidates, you need to work your way through these lists.&quot;

Business Secretary Andrea Leadsom said the report showed &quot;firms have much more to do&quot; to attract employees from black, Asian and ethnic minority (BAME) backgrounds.

Ms Leadsom said: &quot;I want the UK to be the best place in the world to work and to grow a business. Research consistently shows that diversity in businesses is not only essential for good working practice but makes them more successful.

&quot;This government backs business and wants it to succeed in becoming more diverse.&quot;

Arun Batra, a partner at Ernst and Young and an adviser to the review said: &quot;We recognise that meaningful change takes time, but the data tells us that the current pace of change is not quick enough to meet the targets set by the review.

&quot;Businesses need to continue to challenge traditional ways of working and legacy issues, and really investigate the talent that they have available in their business.&quot;
• 'Little sign of change' for number of women in top roles
• Companies told women must make up third of senior directors by 2020

Dr Jill Miller, from the Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development (CIPD), said: &quot;The lack of ethnic diversity at the top of organisations is unacceptable in 2020 and although we are seeing movement in the right direction, the speed of progress reported today is disappointing.

&quot;Systemic change is needed to ensure businesses are building diverse talent pipelines all the way through their organisation to support long-term change. Action is long overdue and must be a business priority.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51371670</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Mobile operators clash on 'notspots' costs - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/6E6A/production/_110766282_mobilemast2.gif</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>An agreement to share network equipment in order to improve phone coverage in rural areas has hit a stumbling block over costs.

Rival operators are unhappy at the price BT-owned EE is asking them to pay to share its equipment.

O2's chief said the fees being sought by its rival &quot;may undermine the viability of the project&quot;.

BT said the costs were based on the value of the masts and other investments it had made over the years.

A key meeting is due to take place on Wednesday to hammer out the details, the BBC has learned.

The £1bn Shared Rural Network (SRN) agreement was announced in October and aims to get the mobile operators working together to extend the geographic coverage of 4G to 95% of the UK by 2025.

Many rural areas have only patchy service, and some have none at all.

The government is contributing £500m towards the costs, with the other half of the bill being footed by the mobile operators.

The Conservatives want the deal done as soon as possible - ideally in time for the Budget on 11 March - and has threatened to intervene if the operators cannot reach agreement.

The BBC understands that if the mobile operators do fail to agree, the government will consider other ways of achieving its 95% coverage goal.

It will, said one industry insider, make delays to improving rural mobile coverage inevitable.

The Financial Times reported that BT wants to include 320 yet-to-be-built masts in the agreement and to charge 250% more than the existing commercial rate for rivals to access them.

One insider told the BBC it would be cheaper for operators to build their own masts.

BT has not revealed the commercial agreements it is hoping to sign with other operators but it is believed it will offer rivals a cheaper rate for masts on its emergency service network, which was partially funded by the government. There are several hundreds of these in rural locations.

Previously BT's chief executive Marc Allera has said the costs of sharing equipment needed to reflect the fact that EE has 4G coverage in &quot;significantly more places than any other network&quot;.

&quot;Finding an analogy here is tricky because this is complex, but I sometimes think of it like Sainsbury's building a new superstore in a rural area and being made to give away shelf space to Tesco, Lidl and Asda,&quot; he said in a blog.

Of the meeting this week BT told the BBC that it was &quot;ready to go&quot;.

&quot;We've proposed a far simpler and more pragmatic way for SRN to succeed, plus a way to reduce any taxpayer money by also including new sites that are being built by us in the future.

&quot;It's now down to the industry to finalise the deal to get it done.&quot;

All the operators said they were committed to getting an agreement.

In a blog, O2 chief executive Mark Evans said: &quot;The SRN requires all four mobile network operators to deliver additional investment and an unprecedented level of infrastructure-sharing; it requires the government to deliver planning policy reform and a modest level of funding.&quot;

Dave Dyson, chief executive of Three, said: &quot;Enhancing mobile connectivity for the 9.3 million living in the UK's countryside requires a joined-up approach between the industry and government.

&quot;A Shared Rural Network is the best way to do that, bringing mobile coverage to more places in the UK and giving people in rural areas a similar choice to those living in towns and cities.&quot;

And Vodafone told the BBC: &quot;We remain committed to the Shared Rural Network scheme and are working towards reaching a final agreement.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-51372017</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>The medieval knight who went into space - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/9A4A/production/_110689493_gettyimages-83233279.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The BBC's weekly The Boss series profiles different business leaders from around the world. This week we speak to Richard Garriott, computer games veteran, and space tourism pioneer.

Blasting into space on a Russian Soyuz rocket, Richard Garriott says it was &quot;the most intense eight and a half minutes&quot; of his life.

Launched from the Baikonur space centre in Kazakhstan, it took just that amount of time for the rocket to hit 28,000 km/h (17,000mph) and reach orbit.

This was back in October 2008, when Richard became only the sixth person to go into space as a paying traveller. He spent 12 days on the International Space Station. &quot;It was a truly profound and life-changing experience,&quot; says the 58-year-old.

The trip was the fulfilment of a lifelong ambition for Richard, who, thanks to making a fortune in the computer games industry, could afford the price - a whopping $30m (£23m). It also allowed him to follow in the footsteps of his father Owen, an astronaut who twice went into space with Nasa, in 1973 and 1983.

Richard had wanted to join Nasa, too, as a younger man, but his ambition was blocked because his eyesight was not good enough. Instead he started to design computer games as a teenager.

Raised near Houston, Texas, Richard remembers his high school getting its first computer in the mid-1970s. As he was an excellent science student, he says that the teachers let him use it as often as he liked.

&quot;They basically said 'well, we have this computer that we don't know what to do with - it's yours, do what you want with it'.&quot;

Discovering that he was something of a natural at computer programming, he started to design his own games. In 1979, aged 18, one of his games was released commercially.

Working part time in a computer store, Richard had shown his role-playing game - Akalabeth: World of Doom - to his manager. The man was so impressed that he asked Richard to make copies that he could sell from the shop.

It caught the eye of one of the first gaming distributors, who said he wanted to ship them nationwide. Some 30,000 copies were sold, from which Richard was paid $150,000 in royalties &quot;for a few weeks of afterschool time at high school&quot;.

That amount of money was nearly three times his father's annual Nasa salary. &quot;I sat down with the rest of the family, who said 'well, this is a good idea, maybe you should do more of these', and I started my career.&quot;

His parents did, however, insist that he still went to university, and so he enrolled on a degree at the University of Texas at Austin. While at college he released the first instalment of his fantasy world, role-playing game series Ultima. Think dungeons and dragons, medieval knights, and wizards.

With Ultima 1 selling 50,000 copies, Richard ultimately dropped out of college to focus on making computer games full time. And together with his brother he set up a business called Origin Systems to release the later versions of the game.

The Ultima series went on to sell millions of units, and gained a dedicated following within the growing gaming community. Richard would connect with devotees by going to fan conventions dressed in medieval costume, as a character from the game called Lord British.

However, on one occasion things took a dark turn when a crazed fan broke into his Texan house, and Richard had to fire off warning shots from his Uzi machine gun to defend himself before the police arrived.

In 1992, Richard and his brother sold Origin to gaming giant Electronic Arts for $35m. Richard stayed with Electronic for eight years, before leaving to create a new business called Destination Games. A number of other gaming firms then followed, with his current company - Portalarium - formed in 2008.
• Dan Aykroyd: From battling spirits to selling them
• The billionaire retailer whose shops had no stock

Considered a pioneer within the gaming community, it is widely accepted that Richard was the first person to use the term &quot;avatar&quot; to apply to the on-screen representation of a person playing a computer game.

He says he still loves working in the industry. &quot;I am a very light-hearted person,&quot; he says.

&quot;I'm a devout believer in work should be fun. If work is not fun, you are doing the wrong work.

&quot;Maybe that's idealistic, and it's not fair to presume everyone in life can have that opportunity. [But] if you can enjoy the work you're doing, it makes life better, and so that's one of the markers of success, being able to do that.&quot;

To help get himself into space, Richard co-founded a company called Space Adventures in 1998. Unlike the continuing efforts of Virgin Galactic and Elon Musk's Space X, Space Adventures didn't set out to build its own spacecraft. Instead it would arrange for its customers to hitch a ride on the flights of the Russian space agency Roscosmos. Nasa was also asked, but said &quot;no&quot;.

The first person to get into space thanks to Space Adventures was American businessman Dennis Tito, who in 2001 became the world's first space tourist. Richard's trip came seven years later, and although he co-owns the company he still had to pay the full price. Space Adventures has so far put seven people into space.

Fred Schmidt, a Texan technology consultant, says that &quot;Richard's number one trait in his ongoing entrepreneurial journey is how his boundless imagination plays in tandem with his insatiable curiosity&quot;.

Meanwhile, Richard Wiese, president of the Explorers Club, a professional society that promotes scientific exploration, says that Richard &quot;is often the smartest and most creative person in the room&quot;.

He adds: &quot;The idea that Richard would figure a way to get himself into space when ordinary paths proved impossible speaks volumes on how he views the possible. I often wonder if Richard gets the proper credit for being one of the first pioneers in private space.&quot;

Looking ahead, Richard says he wants to return to space. &quot;I dream about my past and future space flights,&quot; he says. &quot;Having travelled once to space only deepens your desire to spend more time there.

&quot;I experienced what many astronauts refer to as 'the overview effect', which makes your bond and care of the Earth greatly deepen.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50757073</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: 'You have to be optimistic as a fisherman' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F9BB/production/_110713936_p081vhnd.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Fishing is set to play a big role in post-Brexit trade negotiations between the UK and EU.

Fisherman Andy McLeod from Brixham voted Leave in the referendum, in the hope that British boats would get a bigger share of fishing rights after Brexit.

But he fears that he and his colleagues will just end up being &quot;pawns to be sacrificed, for the greater good of the country&quot;.

Video produced and edited by Oliver Smith. Filmed by Tony Smith.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312932</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Tesla: Is the car firm really worth $150bn? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16415/production/_110775119_gettyimages-1192349155.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>When Tesla's market value crossed $100bn (£76.7bn) two weeks ago, overtaking Volkswagen, sceptics scoffed.

But on Tuesday, it zoomed past $150bn as shares gained more than 13%, rising to more than $887 apiece.

The jump means the firm's share price has more than tripled in the last three months, outpacing the predictions of even some of the most optimistic analysts tracking the company.

It now ranks as the world's second most valuable car company. So what's behind the turnaround?

Less than two years ago, things weren't looking quite as rosy for the carmaker.

The firm, which has reported losses every year since its start, faced a cash crunch amid production delays and heavy spending.

Doubts about performance also dogged chief executive Elon Musk, who had a reputation for making promises but failing to deliver.

Tesla's numbers have since improved. The firm has now reported two quarters of profit and its new factory in Shanghai was up and running more quickly than expected.

Signs also suggest buyer demand has remained healthy, despite fears of a slowdown. Its new Cybertruck drew in about 200,000 orders, even after an embarrassing incident where its &quot;tough&quot; windows smashed during an on-stage demonstration.

The firm has also avoided self-inflicted mistakes, like the tweets from Mr Musk in 2018, which drew allegations of price manipulation, forcing him to step down as chair of the company.

&quot;It has become very clear to investors that Tesla has a number of long-term sustainable growth drivers that are very difficult to dispute,&quot; says Rolf Bulk, an analyst at New Street Research.

Wolfe Research analysts also said they were &quot;a little surprised by the magnitude&quot; of the share price increase but &quot;the abundance of positives explains the move&quot;.

In a note to clients last week, they wrote: &quot;There may be ups and downs, but our view is the stock has found a new range.&quot;

Rolf Bulk believes that the recent share price increase suggests that some investors betting against the firm have been squeezed. Or forced to &quot;close out positions&quot;, a process that involves buying shares, which drives up prices.

But S3 Partners, which tracks such activity, said its research shows that recent buying has mostly been done by a mix of everyday investors and big firms.

Tesla's stock has however been subject to big swings historically.

Some analysts said prices could dive again, especially given the investment it is making in a new factory in Europe and the fact that the outbreak of coronavirus has forced its Shanghai factory to shut down temporarily.

The prospect of a weak first quarter is &quot;something that is not fully appreciated by Wall Street today,&quot; Mr Bulk added.

What about other carmakers?

Tesla delivered more than 367,500 cars last year - up 50% from 2018. It has forecast sales of about 500,000 this year and analysts project that Tesla could hit two million by 2030.

Its deliveries remain far smaller than its rivals.

Volkswagen delivered almost 11 million vehicles last year, while Toyota - which has a market value of more than $230bn - sold more than nine million in the first 11 months of 2019.

However, experts say Tesla's electric car technology continues to lead the industry. The firm might be able to sustain that lead for longer than they had expected, even as demand for electric vehicles grows.

There is even speculation that the company's investment in battery power could put it in a position to be a supplier to other leading automotive companies.

In a recent note to clients Adam Jonas, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, said if Tesla could achieve all those outcomes, it might be worth about where it is trading today.

He added that that was &quot;an aggressive 'blue sky' scenario that could take 10 to 20 years to achieve, if it could even be done at all&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51379061</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: LG pulls out of Mobile World Congress - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Technology</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13751/production/_110779697_gettyimages-1128846835.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>LG has pulled out of one of the world's biggest tech shows citing fears over the spread of coronavirus.

The South Korean tech firm has cancelled its appearance at Mobile World Congress (MWC), which is held every year in Barcelona.

MWC opens on 24 Feb and is the world's largest mobile-focused tech expo.

China's ZTE has also dropped plans for a press conference at the event due to the illness, but it will still host a stand.

Separately, Sony has said coronavirus could negatively affect production in its factories, which make components for Apple and Huawei products.

Telecommunications trade body the GSMA, MWC's organisers, said of the virus yesterday: &quot;There is minimal impact on the event thus far&quot;. However, within hours, LG announced it was pulling out.

&quot;With the safety of its employees and general public foremost in mind, LG has decided to withdraw from exhibiting and participating in MWC 2020 later this month in Barcelona, Spain,&quot; LG said in a statement.

&quot;This decision will prevent needlessly exposing hundreds of LG employees to international travel, which most health experts have advised.&quot;

The firm added that it would hold &quot;separate events in the near future&quot; instead.

&quot;You have to say it's probably an entirely sensible response given the situation,&quot; said Simon Forrest, tech analyst at Futuresource.

To date, there has been just one confirmed case of coronavirus in Spain.

&quot;We have spoken to LG and regret not seeing them at this year's MWC20 Barcelona,&quot; a spokeswoman for the GSMA said.

She added that MWC was still due to proceed as planned.

Previously, the GSMA organisation said it had taken extra precautions for this year's conference, including putting in place a &quot;no-handshake policy&quot;, as well as increased cleaning and disinfection, and the provision of more sanitising materials for public use.

&quot;They have to be taking this seriously,&quot; said Mr Forrest, who is currently planning to attend MWC himself.

There was confusion after multiple tech sites reported that Chinese tech firm ZTE had followed LG and also pulled out of MWC.

Spanish newspapers El Pais and La Vangardia said ZTE told them it would not host a press conference that had originally been scheduled for 25 February.

ZTE then published a statement saying that the firm's appearance at MWC would go ahead &quot;as planned&quot;

A spokeswoman told the BBC: &quot;The handset launch event is cancelled - but the product will be demonstrated at the booth.

&quot;There is no other change, no other cancellations.&quot;

A spokeswoman at the GSMA appeared to be unaware of ZTE's press conference decision, and denied that it had been cancelled.

There have been more than 24,000 cases of coronavirus in China to date but only a handful of cases - by comparison - elsewhere in the world. Globally, nearly 500 people have now died because of the virus.

The UK Foreign Office has advised all British citizens to leave China if they can.

Hon Hai, the Chinese manufacturer which produces iPhones for Apple, has cut its sales forecast for the year, thanks to the spread of coronavirus.

This is because the virus may affect supply chains in Asia, where factories make components and hardware for tech firms around the world.

Hon Hai's chairman told Bloomberg that he expected sales growth between 1% and 3%, rather than a previously projected 3-5%.

And Sony, which also produces components for Apple and other tech firms, including Huawei, told investors on an earnings call that coronavirus may also affect its production lines for image sensors.

Although the firm raised its overall revenue outlook for the year, chief financial officer Hiroki Totoki said: &quot;We cannot deny that our production and sales supply chain for the image sensor and electronics business could be affected enormously.&quot;

Learn more about the new virus
• How worried should we be?
• The city now in lockdown
• Can wearing masks stop the spread of viruses?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-51384304</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Pretty Little Thing: 'Overly sexualised' advert banned - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/772B/production/_110770503_f2b213e5-beec-40a2-8da8-3985d49fca6d.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>An advert for fashion retailer Pretty Little Thing which featured women wearing exposing lingerie has been banned for being &quot;offensive&quot;.

The YouTube ad presented the firm's products in an &quot;overly-sexualised way&quot; and depicted women as sex objects, the Advertising Standards Authority said.

The retailer is one of several online fast fashion companies to have been rapped for their racy marketing.

Pretty Little Thing said it &quot;in no way meant to cause any offence&quot;.

The advert began with a woman looking over her shoulder in a seductive manner wearing black vinyl, high-waisted chaps-style knickers.
• Online fashion twice as 'racy' as High Street
• Fast fashion: Can it ever be ethical and cheap?

It then showed other scantily clad women in seductive or &quot;highly sexualised&quot; poses, including one wearing a transparent mesh bodysuit.

A viewer complained and the regulator agreed, saying the ad was &quot;irresponsible&quot; and likely to cause offence.

Pretty Little Thing said it &quot;celebrates all women&quot; and promotes body diversity. But the ad, which aired in October last year, must not be shown again.

A previous Pretty Little Thing advert was banned in 2017 for portraying a model who appeared to be under 16 in a &quot;sexually suggestive&quot; manner.

The regulator also recently banned an ad for rival Missguided that featured &quot;highly sexualised&quot; images that objectified women.

Another online fashion retailer, Boohoo - which owns Pretty Little Thing - had its email advert banned for using the phrase &quot;send nudes&quot;, which a viewer complained made light of a potentially harmful social trend.

It may seem surprising for an advert targeted at women to be banned for objectifying women, but the defence used by Pretty Little Thing in this case touches on an increasingly contested grey area.

The company says the advert promoted diversity through &quot;bold and distinctive fashion of all shapes and sizes&quot;, and that they worked hard to promote &quot;a healthy body image that was inclusive and empowered women&quot;.

But the line between empowerment and objectification of women is a subjective one.

Fast-fashion retailers are more likely to push those boundaries. Research we conducted last year found that online-only brands were twice as likely to use more overtly sexualised pictures when selling their clothes than High Street retailers' websites.

It also seems that there's also a growing generational divide. While talking to young people, who these adverts are targeted at, it seemed they were more likely to see them as positive images of women being body-confident whatever their shape. Many in older generations view the same images very differently.

Are you a Pretty Little Thing customer? What do you think of the advert? Get in touch by emailing haveyoursay@bbc.co.uk.

Please include a contact number if you are willing to speak to a BBC journalist. You can also contact us in the following ways:
• Please read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51370851</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Ryanair rapped over low emissions claims - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1230B/production/_110770547_mediaitem110770546.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Claims made by Ryanair about its carbon emissions have been banned by the UK's advertising watchdog.

Europe's biggest airline by passenger numbers had billed itself as the region's &quot;lowest emissions airline&quot; and a &quot;low C02 emissions airline&quot;.

But the Advertising Standards Authority ruled Ryanair's claims in press, TV and radio adverts could not be backed up.

Ryanair hit back in a statement saying consumers could halve their carbon footprint if they switched to it.

In adverts last year, the Dublin-based operator claimed to have &quot;the lowest carbon emissions of any major airline&quot; and to be a &quot;low fares, low CO2 emissions&quot; carrier &quot;based on the top 27 European airlines&quot;.

Complainants to the UK's Advertising Standards Authority (ASA) said the adverts were misleading and could not be substantiated. By their nature, airlines do not have low emissions, critics said.
• Aviation 'not the enemy' in climate battle
• Climate change: Should you fly, drive or take the train?
• The challenges for us all in flying green

In evidence to the ASA, Ryanair argued its green credentials were based on it having the youngest aircraft fleet using the newest most fuel-efficient engines, and flying 97% full on average.

Ryanair said its claims were supported using data from the European aviation organisation Eurocontrol and airline efficiency rankings published by Brighter Plant, a provider of carbon and energy calculations.

Clearcast and Radiocentre, used by companies to review adverts before they go public, both gave their backing.

However, the ASA took issue with some of the figures and the definition of &quot;a major airline&quot; for the purposes of assessing emissions comparisons.

An airline efficiency ranking used by Ryanair was dated 2011, &quot;and was therefore of little value as substantiation for a comparison made in 2019,&quot; the ASA said.

&quot;Consequently, we concluded that the claims 'Europe's… Lowest Emissions Airline' and 'low CO2 emissions' were misleading,&quot; the regulator said.

The adverts must not be repeated &quot;in their current form,&quot; the ASA ruled, adding: &quot;We told Ryanair to ensure that when making environmental claims, they held adequate evidence to substantiate them and to ensure that the basis of those claims were made clear.&quot;

Ryanair said it would comply with the ruling, but in a statement underlined its claim that emissions per passenger are 25% lower &quot;than other major airlines&quot;.

The airline said: &quot;Ryanair is delighted with its latest environmental advertising campaign, which communicates a hugely important message for our customers.

&quot;The single most important thing any customer can do to halve their carbon footprint is switch to Ryanair.&quot;

The airline also said it would be making changes to claims on its website, which is not regulated in the UK but by the Advertising Standards Authority for Ireland (ASAI).

The ASAI said in a statement it &quot;is assessing the advertising in question. In line with due process, we will not be commenting further at this stage.&quot;

Aviation has become a target of environmental activists, and there are signs so-called &quot;flight shaming&quot; is starting to have an impact on travel habits.

Against this backdrop, the industry has become more proactive about what it is doing to cut its carbon footprint.

On Monday, a group called Sustainable Aviation, whose members include Heathrow Airport, British Airways, EasyJet, Rolls Royce, Airbus and air traffic controller Nats, promised to cut its net carbon emissions to zero by 2050.

In 2018, Ryanair launched a voluntary carbon offset scheme, which has so far raised €2.5m (£2.1m) according to the airline's website. The money is invested in environmental projects in Ireland and abroad.

But last April, Ryanair was named as the only airline included in a list of Europe's top 10 polluters, according to data from the EU's Transport &amp; Environment group.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51372780</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>Bubble tea: A sweet treat that went global - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12216/production/_110726247_p081ykvv.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Bubble tea - also called pearl tea or boba tea - is a sweet drink that combines milk, flavoured tea and tapioca pearls that are sucked up through an extra-large straw and chewed.

Invented in Taiwan in the 1980s, it has now become popular worldwide. The BBC's Sarah Toms went to a recent exhibition in Singapore to find out more.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51312934</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-01 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>How McDonald's revolutionised business - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11456/production/_110624707_gettyimages-534244996.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The way Ray Kroc tells the story, when he first encouraged the McDonald brothers to open more hamburger restaurants, they winced.

The year was 1954. The place: San Bernardino, California, then a quiet town on the edge of the desert, some 50 miles east of Los Angeles.

Kroc sold milkshake machines and Richard and Maurice (Mac) McDonald were among his best customers.

Their restaurant was small, but sold lots of milkshakes. Clearly, they were doing something right.

But they did not want to do more of it, and Mac explained why: &quot;We sit out on the porch in the evenings and watch the sunset. It's peaceful.&quot;

Opening more branches would be a headache - travelling around, finding locations, vetting managers, staying in motels. Why bother? They were already making more money than they could spend.

This made no sense to Kroc. &quot;His approach was utterly foreign to my thinking,&quot; he later recalled.

So he convinced the brothers to let him expand their restaurant chain. By the time Kroc died, three decades later, McDonald's had thousands of restaurants bringing in billions of dollars.

Which goes to show that successful entrepreneurs are not all the same. They have different talents, and want different things.

50 Things That Made the Modern Economy highlights the inventions, ideas and innovations that helped create the economic world.

It is broadcast on the BBC World Service. You can find more information about the programme's sources and listen to all the episodes online or subscribe to the programme podcast.

Take Dick and Mac. They were brilliant at figuring out more efficient ways to make hamburgers.

As John F Love notes in his book McDonald's: Behind the Arches, the brothers worked with a local craftsman to invent a new kind of spatula, a new dispenser that squirted the same amount of ketchup and mustard every time, and a rotating platform to speed up the process of assembling of burger, bun and condiments.

What Henry Ford had done for cars, the McDonald brothers did for hamburgers and French fries: they broke down processes into simple, repetitive tasks.

This meant they could churn out food quickly, cheaply and consistently. There was nothing else like it.

But when it came to the wider world, the brothers seem to have been fairly clueless.

When competitors started peering through the windows, taking out notepads and sketching plans, Dick and Mac laughed about it. When anyone asked about those ingenious condiment dispensers, they cheerfully named their craftsman friend. None of them had bothered to patent the design.

Some people wanted more than snatched sketches, so the brothers sold franchises - after a fashion.

For a one-off fee, you could buy blueprints to their building, with the golden arches, a 15-page description of their &quot;Speedee Service System&quot;, and a week's training. After that, the franchisees were on their own.

Dick and Mac did not expect that their trainees would serve the same menu, or even use the same name. When their very first franchisee mentioned that he would also call his new restaurant &quot;McDonald's&quot;, Dick replied: &quot;What the hell for?&quot;

Into this smooth-running kitchen and half-baked franchising operation walked a man with different skills and desires.

Ray Kroc was in his 50s, and managing health problems from diabetes to arthritis.

But he was keener on money than peaceful sunsets, and he loved life on the road.

Kroc later wrote that &quot;finding locations for McDonald's is the most creatively fulfilling thing I can imagine&quot;.

Where the brothers had rethought French fries, Kroc would rethink the franchise concept.

The idea itself was not new. The word &quot;franchise&quot; comes from the old French &quot;franche&quot;, meaning &quot;free&quot; or &quot;exempt&quot;.

In ages past, a monarch might have granted you a franchise which would have given you the exclusive right to do a certain thing - to sell armour, or run a cattle market - in a defined area for a set time.

In the 19th Century, for instance, you might have bought the exclusive right to sell Singer sewing machines in your local area.

Nowadays franchise operations are everywhere. Stay in a Hilton or Marriott hotel, rent a car from Hertz or Europcar, or shop at a 7-Eleven or Carrefour grocery store, and you are likely to be dealing with a franchise owner.

The idea of the business format franchise seems to have started in the 1890s with Canadian Martha Matilda Harper.

She built an international network of beauty salons. A former servant, her franchises transformed the lives of many other servant girls.

But it was 1950s fast food that gave the franchise its modern form, with not only McDonald's but Burger King, Kentucky Fried Chicken and many now-forgotten brands.

Kroc's big insight was the importance of conformity.

You were not just selling the right to use the company's name and learn its methods - you were imposing an obligation to do things in a certain way.

McDonald's opened a full-time training centre, &quot;Hamburger University&quot;, which drilled students in subjects such as which kind of potatoes to buy.

Inspectors wrote 27-page reports on whether franchisees cooked food at the right temperatures and kept the bathrooms clean.

More things that made the modern economy:
• TV dinners: The hidden cost of the processed food revolution
• How much do we really know about why we give to charity?
• What can bees teach us about how to make money?

At first glance, the appeal to the budding restaurateur is not obvious.

Wouldn't you want to design your own branding and develop your own menu? Why pay the McDonald's corporation $45,000 (£34,000) plus 4% of gross sales, just so it can send an inspector to watch you scrub your own toilets?

Well, much of what you are paying for is the benefit of the brand - and if you are being monitored to make sure you do not cut corners that damage the brand, you can feel reassured that your fellow franchisees are too.

As for the franchisor, why not own and operate new branches yourself? Many companies do both - McDonald's owns about 15% of its 36,000-odd outlets.

But franchisees bring a lot to the company, like hard cash: a McDonald's restaurant can cost more than $1m (£768,000) to launch.

Franchisees also provide local knowledge, especially important if you are expanding into a new country with an unfamiliar culture.

And there is motivation: an owner-manager with their own money at stake might put more effort into keeping costs down than a manager on a corporate salary.

The economist Alan Krueger found evidence that may support this idea: workers and shift supervisors apparently earn more in company-owned fast food outlets than franchised ones.

Of course, both sides bear some risk. The franchisor has to trust that the franchisee will work hard; the franchisee has to trust that the franchisor will create and advertise exciting new products.

When both sides worry about the other side shirking, it's known as &quot;double-sided moral hazard&quot;. A branch of economics called agency theory tries to understand how franchise contracts solve this problem through their mix of upfront fees and percentage payments.

But it seems to work, perhaps because - like Kroc and the McDonald brothers - different entrepreneurs want different things.

Some people want the freedom to run their own business, day-to-day, but are not interested in developing products or building a brand.

One of the McDonald brothers' early franchisees decided he did not much like their golden arches, so he got his builders to make them pointy and named his restaurant &quot;Peaks&quot; instead.

Those were freewheeling times. These days, the division of entrepreneurial labour is more likely to be as regimented as a carousel full of hamburgers.

The author writes the Financial Times's Undercover Economist column. 50 Things That Made the Modern Economy is broadcast on the BBC World Service. You can find more information about the programme's sources and listen to all the episodes online or subscribe to the programme podcast.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51208592</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
