<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: Cement mixers become celebrities in China lockdown - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>China</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/0EED/production/_110712830_007f480qly1gbexvjqlndj31jk1jkn6i.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Unlikely heroes have arisen in China's coronavirus crisis - a group of construction vehicles building two new hospitals in the city of Wuhan, where the outbreak emerged.

With all regions in the country affected by the virus, people have been told to stay indoors - except where absolutely necessary.

Perhaps understandably, they are struggling to keep themselves entertained.

So they're turning to livestreams of two hospitals being built - and have created characters and heroes on the building site.

The 25,000 square metre Huoshenshan Hospital in Wuhan will be ready by 2 February. The Leishenshan Hospital will be in use by 5 February.

China's official CCTV broadcaster has been hosting livestreams so people can watch the hospitals being built in real-time - and they have proved an unlikely hit.
• How can China build a hospital so quickly?
• How quarantine has fought disease through the ages

The Global Times newspaper says more than 40 million people have been watching the livestreams in China..

And they've also proven popular overseas. Both YouTube and Periscope have been running livestreams for viewers outside the country, which are consistently bringing in hundreds of thousands of views.

The popularity of this footage has led to the construction vehicles at the Huoshenshan Hospital earning unusual fame.

Cement mixers have found themselves with nicknames like &quot;The Cement King&quot;, &quot;Big White Rabbit&quot; and &quot;The White Roller&quot;.

Some of the diggers are given affectionate names based on their colour, such as &quot;Little Yellow&quot; and &quot;Little Blue&quot;.

Others have coined more imaginative names for the vehicles, with one cement mixer being named Song Huizong, after an ancient emperor.

The official CCTV has set up an &quot;epidemic 24/7&quot; page built into mobile messenger WeChat, where users can vote for their favourite vehicle.

The undipsuted stars of the show are the small, yellow forklift trucks, which are collectively known as &quot;folkchan&quot;.

Searches of &quot;folkchan&quot; on the popular Sina Weibo microblog bring up fan art and tributes to the little vehicles.

Users call them &quot;the cutest and most hard working little forklifts&quot; and call them, &quot;the loveliest little world guardians&quot;.

The fans themselves have formed online fan groups, and collectively call themselves the &quot;online overseers&quot;.

With much of the country in lockdown, it's perhaps not surprising that &quot;alternative&quot; entertainment has popped up.

Transportation links have been suspended in a number of major cities, and companies throughout the country are suspending their opening hours.

Arenas and cinemas have closed. On Tuesday, China's top regulator announced that it would be reducing entertainment TV programming &quot;to strengthen publicity on epidemic prevention&quot;.
• Coronavirus Wuhan diary: Living alone in a city gone quiet
• Wuhan: The London-sized city where the virus began

High engagement in the government's activities has obviously been a win for the Chinese Communist Party.

But as Shi Wenxue, a teacher at the Beijing Film Academy told Global Times, the livestreams are helping people feel more involved in what is going on.

&quot;The 'overseers' participation shows young Chinese people's concern over the epidemic,&quot; Shi said, adding that it helps people feel they have &quot;warriors in any battle situation&quot;.

BBC Monitoring reports and analyses news from TV, radio, web and print media around the world. You can follow BBC Monitoring on Twitter and Facebook.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-51315238</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Entertainment quiz of 2019 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11FF4/production/_110361737_quiz.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-50504497</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Veteran Scots entertainers join for Tom Alexander farewell - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Glasgow &amp; West Scotland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/002E/production/_110464000_tomalexander.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Some of Scotland's best-known entertainers have gathered to bid a final farewell to a veteran of the industry.

The funeral of Scottish traditional music star Tom Alexander took place in Clydebank on Wednesday.

The 85-year-old was one half of The Alexander Brothers who toured the world in a career spanning more than 50 years.

Mr Alexander's death was announced by the Gaiety Theatre in Ayr last week.

Tom and his 79-year-old brother Jack, who died in 2013, started their professional career in 1958.

The pair, from Cambusnethan in North Lanarkshire, were awarded MBEs for services to entertainment.

The brothers were both classically trained and played from a young age, with Jack on the piano and Tom on the accordion.

Among their career highlights was a show at the Sydney Opera House in the mid-1980s and co-starring with Shirley Bassey at the London Palladium in 1967.

Among the mourners was variety veteran Johnnie Beattie and his daughter Maureen, who saw it as &quot;the end of an era&quot;.

Johnnie said: &quot;When they were at their peak, they were bigger in Scotland than The Beatles. People think I am making that up but they were enormous in terms of box office.

&quot;We had some happy memories together. We formed HUGS - the Heid Up Golf Society and even got ties made.

During the service singer Alasdair Gillies recounted a tale from their time touring America.

He said: &quot;When they went through immigration in Detroit and the immigration officer said: 'Where you guys from?', Jack said: 'We're from Cambusnethan'.

&quot;Then Tom said: 'Jack, he'll no' know where Cambusnethan is, tell him we're from Wishaw.&quot;

Scottish theatre star Sally Logan and her husband Joe Gordon were happy to pay their respects and share their memories.

Ms Logan said: &quot;I went on the first overseas trip to Canada and America with them and Andy Stewart in 1964. I have worked with them so many times and they were wonderful to work with - so easy-going.

&quot;They had so many wonderful events in their life. They just called themselves two painters and decorators. They were so well-loved and always good with their fans. They won't be forgotten - their music will live on.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-glasgow-west-51214134</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Lego movie falls flat for Merlin Entertainment - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1394C/production/_108140208_lego2.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The success of the Lego movie franchise has failed to strike twice for Merlin Entertainment which saw &quot;disappointing&quot; sales at its Legoland theme parks.

Merlin Entertainment said trade had been affected by &quot;limited momentum&quot; from The Lego Movie 2 as well as poor weather earlier this year.

The company said like-for-like sales for the first half of the year fell by 0.7% at Legoland.

But new Peppa Pig attractions abroad helped lift overall sales.

Merlin operates 127 attractions, 19 hotels and seven holiday villages in 27 countries.

The Lego Movie 2: The Second Part was released in February and has so far taken $191.3m at the box office.

However, Merlin Entertainment said that during the six months to 29 June, there has &quot;been limited trading momentum as a result of the film itself&quot;.

By comparison, the first Lego film took $469.1m and significantly boosted at sales at Merlin in 2014.

The firm, which also owns Alton Towers and Madame Tussauds, said sales for businesses open at least a year rose by 2.3% on improving tourist numbers in its key London market.

Overall, pre-tax profits at Merlin Entertainment fell to £34m from £43m on sales 8.1% higher at £763m.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49189375</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Hasbro to buy Peppa Pig owner Entertainment One for $4bn - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p04xj4m6.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>US toy maker Hasbro will acquire Peppa Pig owner Entertainment One for around £3.3bn ($4bn), the firms said in a statement.

Hasbro said the deal would expand its entertainment and &quot;family-oriented storytelling&quot; portfolio.

The deal is the latest in a string of foreign acquisitions of UK-listed firms including the £4.6bn buyout of pub chain Greene King.

Under the all-cash transaction, Entertainment One shareholders will receive £5.60 for each common share.

&quot;Hasbro will leverage Entertainment One immersive entertainment capabilities to bring our portfolio of brands that have appeal to gamers, fans and families to all screens globally,&quot; the firms said in a statement.

The American toy giant is behind a diverse range of titles including the My Little Pony and Transformers franchises, as well as the Monopoly board game and Play-Doh.

Entertainment One makes a series of film and television titles including the Peppa Pig cartoon.

The firm said the top performing preschool programme has been translated into more than 40 languages and broadcast in over 180 territories.

It is particularly popular in China, where it was first exported in the early 2000s. The cartoon has attracted some 34 billion views on domestic online video platforms.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-49443785</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Disney+ takes on Netflix as 28 million subscribers sign up - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10079/production/_110775656_gettyimages-1187551494.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sign-ups for Disney's new streaming service have shot past expectations, as audiences respond to the offering of Star Wars, cartoons and other classics.

Walt Disney said about 28.6 million people had signed up for Disney+ since it started in November.

The on-demand video service, which costs $6.99 per month, is Disney's attempt to challenge industry leader Netflix, which has 170m subscribers.

Disney+ now has almost as many subscribers as the firm's earlier on-demand streaming service Hulu, which was founded in 2007 and offers shows from US television.

&quot;The launch of Disney+ has been enormously successful, exceeding even our greatest expectations,&quot; Mr Iger said on a call with analysts after the release of the company's quarterly earnings.

Disney also warned investors that its operating income in the next quarter could take a nearly $300m hit due to the closure of its parks in China.

That figure assumes the coronavirus outbreak keeps Disney's resorts in Shanghai and Hong Kong closed for two months, and takes into account the fact that visitors to Hong Kong had already dropped significantly due to protests there.

Disney announced in 2017 that it would create its own streaming service, aiming to combat the declining audiences for its traditional business as viewers move online.

Shortly after, it announced a deal to buy the bulk of Rupert Murdoch's 21st Century Fox entertainment empire, as it looked to bulk up its catalogue to compete.

&quot;I'm enormously proud of what we have accomplished in a relatively short period of time and believe we are well positioned to not only withstand the disruptive forces ... but to thrive,&quot; Mr Iger said.

Most of the current subscribers come from the US and about half signed up directly through the website, he said. He attributed part of the appeal to Disney's &quot;very accessible&quot; price.

International expansion of Disney+ is the firm's next priority, he added.

The service is currently available in five countries, including the US and Canada. It is due to launch in the UK and other countries in western Europe next month. Mr Iger said the service will also launch in India in March.

Disney said revenues in the quarter were up 36% year-on-year. However profits declined 25% from $2.8bn to $2.1bn, amid heavy spending on its on-demand offerings.

Revenues in its direct-to-consumer unit - which includes Hulu and Disney+ - increased to $4bn, from $0.9bn, but operating loss widened from $136m to $693m.

Disney shares rose more than 2% in after-hours trade.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51379064</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>News Daily: Trump's big speech, BBC licence fee and business diversity - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/2177/production/_110776580_gettyimages-1198673110.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>If you want to get this briefing by email, sign up here

It's always a moment of political theatre, but this year's State of the Union address had more moments of drama than most.

US President Donald Trump used his annual address to the nation to hail the &quot;great American comeback&quot; - as compared with his lament of &quot;American carnage&quot; in his 2017 inaugural address. He pointed to economic success, especially a &quot;blue-collar boom&quot;, and claimed to have taken millions out of poverty.

This is, of course, an election year and Mr Trump made sure to appeal to his Republican base. He gave an award to right-wing talk show host Rush Limbaugh, vowed to protect gun rights and promised a ban on what he called &quot;late-term abortion&quot;. The environment was barely mentioned, while the threat Mr Trump says &quot;socialists&quot; pose to &quot;American healthcare&quot; came up several times.

As he entered the room, the president refused to shake the outstretched hand of Speaker Nancy Pelosi, one of his fiercest critics. She, in turn, skipped the tradition of welcoming him as a &quot;distinct honour&quot;. She could be seen twice mouthing &quot;not true&quot; during the speech, and at the end, America's most powerful elected Democrat ripped up a copy of the president's remarks.

The setting for all of this was the US House of Representatives, where President Trump was impeached in December. On Wednesday he will almost certainly be cleared of corruption charges in a party-line vote. Read more on what that means here. You can also read our fact-check on the whole speech.

For more on US politics, check out our new podcast, Americast. The first episode covers the still-to-be resolved chaos in Iowa.

The government is launching a public consultation on whether failure to pay the TV licence fee should no longer be a criminal offence. Culture Secretary Baroness Morgan will say in a speech later it's time to think about keeping the fee &quot;relevant&quot; in a &quot;changing media landscape&quot;. She'll also announce a new way of paying the licence fee in instalments to help those struggling, including the over-75s.

The BBC's media editor, Amol Rajan, says the PM and his allies believe the system is unjust and a waste of court time. But decriminalisation would have a considerable impact on BBC funding, and the corporation argues the enforcement system is an important part of making its public service model work. Last week, the BBC News announced 450 job cuts as part of an £80m savings drive.

Get news from the BBC in your inbox, each weekday morning

About a third of the 100 largest companies listed on the London Stock Exchange have no ethnic minority representation on their boards, a report has revealed. Representation is even worse in the next 250 firms, where 119 out of 173 (69%) had no ethnic diversity. Lawyer and diversity campaigner Funke Abimbola told the BBC the figures came as no surprise given the &quot;many barriers&quot; people of colour face. &quot;You are far more likely to have negative judgements made about you,&quot; she said.

The Parker report has recommended ways to improve things, including making more effort to develop a pool of high potential, ethnic minority leaders and senior managers.

The short gap between the Baftas and the Oscars this year has barely left Joaquin Phoenix enough time to wash his multi-use tux. The Joker star is just one Hollywood actor currently hot-footing it from London to Los Angeles in time for the Academy Awards on Sunday. This year's ceremony is being held earlier than usual in an attempt to combat falling ratings. The slew of other awards ceremonies over several months was thought to be damaging interest in the Oscars, which mark the conclusion of awards season. Oscar-ologists have been closely studying the nominations list for trends, patterns, quirks and clues about who might win what.

What the papers say

A mixed bag of headlines on Wednesday. Several papers react to the independent inquiry into the actions of jailed breast surgeon Ian Paterson. The Times says victims were &quot;failed&quot; by those in charge to investigate him, while the Daily Mirror warns &quot;fresh horrors may be discovered&quot; when the cases of 11,000 patients he treated are recalled for assessment. The Sun and the Daily Mail lead with a security alert on board a transatlantic flight, reportedly caused by David Cameron's bodyguard, who left his gun in the toilet. The Mail describes the incident as a &quot;major embarrassment&quot; for the police. The new chief executive of the Premier League has told the Guardian clubs will resist attempts to ban adverts for betting companies on their shirts. Richard Masters argues sport and betting &quot;have a long association&quot; and the Premier League is &quot;not sniffy or judgemental&quot; about gambling.

If you see one thing today

The woman who found my baby's grave

If you listen to one thing today

If you read one thing today

Sign up for a morning briefing direct to your phone

Today The families of severely epileptic children begin legal action against the NHS and health regulator NICE for failing to prescribe medical cannabis.

14:00 The Duke of Cambridge launches the Heads Up Weekends campaign, billed as the biggest ever conversation around mental health through football.

Can the world's strongest mammal survive? (New York Times)

Why can't Britain build its own 5G network? (Politics.co.uk)

Is Venice at war with itself? (CNN)</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51377240</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Remembering the entertainment and arts figures we lost in 2019 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16E17/production/_110291739_compo2_976bbcgettypa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>As the year draws to a close, it is time to remember the figures from the worlds of arts and entertainment who died in 2019. Here is a look back at some of those to whom we said farewell.

The year was still young when we said goodbye to Broadway star Carol Channing, It Ain't Half Hot Mum actor Windsor Davies and BBC presenter Dianne Oxberry. We also lost:

In February the curtain fell on acclaimed actor Albert Finney, much-loved comedian Jeremy Hardy and fashion designer Karl Lagerfeld. We also lost:

March was the month we bid a sad farewell to Keith Flint of The Prodigy, Beverly Hills 90210 actor Luke Perry and rock enigma Scott Walker. We also lost:

Star Wars actor Peter Mayhew, EastEnders actress Sandy Ratcliff and film-maker John Singleton were among those who left us in April. We also lost:

May saw actress and singer Doris Day, comedian Freddie Starr and newsreader Nan Winton depart at the ages of 97, 76 and 93 respectively. We also lost:

Blake's 7 actor Paul Darrow, fashion icon Gloria Vanderbilt and Italian director Franco Zeffirelli were among those who took their leave in June. We also lost:

The sudden death of Disney star Cameron Boyce at the age of 20 was one of a number of sad farewells in a month which also saw Blade Runner actor Rutger Hauer and Broadway producer Hal Prince depart. We also lost:

Easy Rider actor Peter Fonda, author Toni Morrison and Home and Away actor Ben Unwin were among those who departed in August. We also lost:

September saw the lights go down on playwright Peter Nichols, opera singer Jessye Norman and The Cars' Ric Ocasek. We also lost:

Emmerdale actress Leah Bracknell, Chinatown producer Robert Evans and newsreader Peter Sissons were among October's dearly departed. We also lost:
• Last of the Summer Wine actress Juliette Kaplan

On a single day in November, it was confirmed that Australian broadcaster Clive James, theatre director Jonathan Miller and celebrity chef Gary Rhodes had died. We also lost:
• Last of the Summer Wine actress Jean Fergusson

In the last month of 2019, we said goodbye to nature broadcaster David Bellamy, actor Tony Britton and singer Kenny Lynch. We also lost:
• Do The Right Thing actor Danny Aiello

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-46745072</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Sport Relief: AP McCoy recalls 'living the dream' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Northern Ireland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p0828z7x.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>After breaking almost every bone in his body during a glittering professional career, you might think Sir AP McCoy would relish gentle paddle boarding on a calm lough.

But the retired jockey admitted feeling &quot;vulnerable&quot; as he carried his board to the waters of Enagh Lough, just outside Londonderry, for the launch of Sport Relief in Northern Ireland.

McCoy, from Moneyglass, County Antrim, was renowned for his determination and dedication over the course of his record-breaking career.

He won more than 4,000 races, and was crowned champion jockey 20 years in a row.

But despite his many accolades, he feared &quot;making a fool of himself&quot; when he took to the water with paddle boarders from Youth Action Northern Ireland.

&quot;When I was standing out in the water and I was trying to stand up, you know there's that fear element,&quot; he says.

Youth Action Northern Ireland is one of the charities that has benefited from Sport Relief.

Sport Relief is a charity event from Comic Relief, in association with BBC Sport, which brings together the worlds of sport and entertainment to raise money to help vulnerable people.

Youth Action NI was set up to engage vulnerable young women in sport and outdoor pursuits to help build resilience.

McCoy reveals that he had his own vulnerabilities during his career despite his success.

&quot;I was lucky to be champion jockey 20 years in a row, but I was never really content in those 20 years,&quot; he says.

&quot;I always thought that I should have done better.&quot;

The former champion jockey admitted he missed the pressures associated with &quot;big time racing&quot;.

&quot;That's the thing about a sports person if you are lucky to perform on a big stage,&quot; he says.

&quot;You know when you walk away from that, nothing can ever replace it.&quot;

Recalling his races at the Cheltenham Festival or the Grand National, he says: &quot;You think that you're the one they are there to watch and you have to perform for them.&quot;

'It's never going to be the same'

&quot;When that's over, no matter what you do for the rest of your life, it's never going to be the same.

&quot;It will never come back again, that's the way it is. I was very lucky to live the dream.&quot;

He says it was fulfilling as a sportsman to &quot;give a little bit back and help others&quot; through Sports Relief.

The former champion jockey befriended Anna, a 26 year-old single mother of two, while paddle boarding.

He learned how Youth Action Northern Ireland had helped Anna return to education and rebuild her confidence when she struggled with depression and dropped out of school after losing her mother when young.

&quot;I'm not the most confident of people and I find it really hard to go out and meet people,&quot; she says.

&quot;I was able to meet people my age and it was good for my boys too.&quot;

McCoy says he was lucky he &quot;lived the dream in terms of sport&quot; and says it was good to see young people who weren't as lucky as him benefit from new sporting opportunities.

He says young people also faced additional challenges of social media.

&quot;You know everyone at some point in their lives will have some difficult times, no matter how much they've got or what they've got, it won't always be easy for them,&quot; he said.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-northern-ireland-51356974</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-07 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Jay-Z explains his and Beyonce's Super Bowl 'protest': 'It just happened' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-07</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Newsbeat</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10B5/production/_110777240_gettyimages-1202008249.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Jay-Z says he and Beyonce were not staging a protest when they stayed seated during the US national anthem at the 2020 Super Bowl.

He says the couple were in &quot;artist mode&quot; when they didn't stand while Demi Lovato sang The Star Spangled Banner.

It lead to speculation they were sending a message of support to former NFL player Colin Kaepernick who first kneeled during the anthem in 2016.

He was protesting racial injustice and has been without a team since 2017.

In a video, obtained by TMZ, Jay-Z and Beyonce can be seen sat down while others around them are stood during Demi's performance.
• Colin Kaepernick: From one man kneeling to a movement dividing a country

But during a Columbia University lecture on Tuesday 4 February - two days after the Super Bowl - the rapper insisted it &quot;just happened&quot;.

In 2018 Demi Lovato was hospitalised after a suspected drug overdose.

&quot;We were talking about how beautiful she looks and how she sounds and what she's gone through in her life for her to be on the stage and we're so proud of her,&quot; he said.

At the lecture, Jay-Z also explained that he produced all the musical performances at the Super Bowl as part of his deal with the NFL as its live music entertainment strategist.

He said he was also preoccupied wondering if the sound levels were too low and what the TV cameras were picking up.

Referring to Shakira and Jennifer Lopez performing the half time show, he said a &quot;silent protest&quot; from him was unnecessary as the diverse group of performers was &quot;the biggest, loudest protest of all&quot;.

When Kaepernick began protesting in 2016 it encouraged other players to do the same - but divided the country and sparked the anger of US President Donald Trump, who accused those kneeling of disrespecting the flag and called for them to be sacked.

Listen to Newsbeat live at 12:45 and 17:45 weekdays - or listen back here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-51382994</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
