<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Six Nations quiz: How much can you remember from the past 20 years? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/4579/production/_110758771_6nquiz.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Apologies to the Royal Family, captains causing a stir and strange try celebrations - the past two decades in the men's Six Nations have provided no shortage of drama.

The tournament turned 20 years old at the weekend, marking the moment Italy joined the party.

But how much can you remember of all that has happened since the Five Nations became six in 2000?

We have picked out some of the tournament's best and strangest moments to test you.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51364730</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Christian Eriksen: I was the black sheep at Spurs - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>European Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/72AD/production/_110775392_christian_eriksen_epa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Christian Eriksen says he was &quot;the black sheep&quot; at Tottenham for being &quot;very honest&quot; over running his contract down at the club.

Denmark midfielder Eriksen joined Inter Milan for £16.9m last month, ending six and a half years with Spurs.

The 27-year-old's admission he wanted to leave in the aftermath of the Champions League final defeat by Liverpool led some fans to turn on him.

&quot;I did get the blame for a lot of stuff, for being the bad guy,&quot; he said.

His contract at Spurs had been set to expire this summer.

By the time Inter boss Antonio Conte offered an exit route, Eriksen says he had grown tired of the speculation about his future and weary of the finger-pointing from the stands.

In an exclusive interview with BBC Sport, Eriksen outlined his frustrations. In addition, he explained why he feels the treatment he received came because he wanted to be honest, the excitement he feels at joining Inter and Sunday's derby with AC Milan at the San Siro.

Is there a sense of relief to get all the talk of your future over and get playing at a club without all the background noise?

Eriksen: &quot;Yes. England, for the last few years, was very hectic. After what I said in the summer, it was just about 'when is he going to leave?' Every game it was 'Is he leaving? Is he not leaving?' Of course, a lot of people were speaking about it.

&quot;Even the fans you see on the street were like 'Thank you, goodbye and good luck'. But I was still there. It was a bit weird. In my head and for my body, it is good that I am in a new place and I can start again.&quot;

Can you wind back to the Champions League final? That was obviously a disappointing night. (Mauricio) Pochettino raised doubts about your future. You gave the interview when you said you were thinking about a fresh challenge. The conjecture went on for weeks. Did it play on your mind? Did that bother or affect you?

&quot;I wouldn't say it affected me. In England, when your contract is shorter, it is like you have to leave now. You are gone. In the end I played about 30 games that were like goodbye games. It was like 'this might be his last game', 'this might be his last game'. It kept rolling.

&quot;In my head I was ready to try something new but felt if nothing came, I was still ready to play for my place. I was not a different player in that sense. But I was in and out of the team. However, even if I had a four-year contract, this season would have been difficult after the Champions League final.&quot;

It seemed the problems Tottenham had were pushed back to you and your form...

&quot;But that is the thing. If you have a short contract, you will be the black sheep. Of course, I did the interview. I was very honest. I felt I had to be honest. I didn't want to hide like a lot of players do. Everyone is different. I was honest. I wanted to say it out loud.

&quot;I did get the blame for a lot of stuff, for being the bad guy. I read I was the bad person in the changing room, that ever since I said I wanted to leave, it was no good me being there. To be honest, over the last few years, if anything came up, any player would think about leaving but I was the guy who said it publicly.&quot;

Jose Mourinho didn't really settle the situation down. In a very Jose way, he was nice but there was always a 'but'. Did that affect things at all?

&quot;No. When the window is not open, there can only be talk. There cannot be anything concrete. I think Mourinho did well. He could have said 'he wants to leave, so he is not going to play any more'. He didn't do that.

&quot;After I told him where my feelings were and what I would like to do, he told me just to be happy and if I was needed I would play. I was needed in a few games where I did make a difference. It was more as an extra rather than in the starting XI of course.&quot;

When you talk about Tottenham, it does seem to have unravelled very quickly after finishing last season on such a high...

&quot;Yes. It did. The Champions League final was such a special moment. In the history of Tottenham, it was the first time. To be there was so nice and beautiful. But you lose and the next day it is the end of the world. That is how it goes.

&quot;Afterwards it was difficult. People were still sad from the Champions League final when the season started. After you get a few bad results, then you go into a spiral you are not used to and it was difficult to come back up.

&quot;But if you look at the Premier League, there is only one team that is really flying. All the others are trying to find their place, not only Tottenham. Some seasons are like that.

&quot;The history of the last five years is of Tottenham being where they have not been before for a long time. It was not a time to end but, in a way, it just came along which was something we didn't expect and didn't want.&quot;

So we get to January. When did you find out, when did you think, you would be leaving?

&quot;Not until it got serious. In the end it comes down to what Tottenham wants to have and what Inter, or any other club, want to pay.

&quot;In the end you are controlled by Tottenham. You are controlled by [chairman Daniel] Levy. He says yes or no. You try to be as professional as you can be and not to force anything through in any way.&quot;

Was it always Inter Milan? There were a few clubs mentioned. Manchester United were routinely mentioned...

&quot;For a few years but it was never really likely. We did speak to them of course and we did hear what was possible and what wasn't possible. But, in the end, me personally, I wanted a new challenge. To stay in the Premier League would have been an easy solution.

&quot;Of course, staying at Tottenham would also have been a solution but, for me, it just came down to wanting to try a new challenge in a new country. Once Inter came up it really wasn't a difficult choice.&quot;

It is amazing how many former Premier League players are here...

&quot;Yes. And a bit of the English culture straightaway and a bit of the English language. I am not the only one who can't understand everything in Italian. It is funny that so many players have come over - and also at the same club.

&quot;That doesn't happen often. I don't know if it makes it easier. You can speak with them about where you are going to live, what kind of house you are going to look for, what has happened, what hasn't happened. You speak more with them and you can speak the language with them.

&quot;But it doesn't really matter. It depends on the group you come into. So far, it is a very nice group of people and players.&quot;

It is an exciting time to join Inter Milan. They are challenging for the title, have got Europe are still in the Coppa Italia...

&quot;Yes. Historically, it is not that easy to come in January. Everyone is at the same fitness level because they have trained together all season. I need to fit in with how they play and learn the different things they do.&quot;

And this weekend, you couldn't have a much bigger game to play in and any team with Zlatan Ibrahimovic has a bit of star quality about it...

&quot;He brings a name with him of course. And there is (fellow Dane) Simon Kjaer. I have spoken to him, even before, when he was over here and we were speaking to Inter back then.

&quot;He was not that far away at Atalanta. It will be the first time I have played against him so that will be fun. Hopefully we will show where we are in the league.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51380652</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Scotland v England: Courtney Lawes says senior players must 'step up' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/C7C2/production/_110783115_lawes_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>England's experienced players need to &quot;step up&quot; and help the side win in adversity, says lock Courtney Lawes.

England could not reel in France after slipping 24 points adrift in their Six Nations opener on Sunday and similarly struggled to wrestle back momentum in November's World Cup final defeat by South Africa.

&quot;It's about winning when the opposition has got your number,&quot; said Lawes, 30.

&quot;It's about being able to assert yourself when things aren't going your way, when the strategy and tactics aren't working.

&quot;We have some serious experience. [Head coach] Eddie [Jones] has given us the opportunity to be a part of that, and it is something we need to step up and do.&quot;

Speaking to BBC Radio 5 Live, Lawes added: &quot;We know we are good when we get the gameplan right and we are executing. But now we need to work on when things aren't going to plan, where we go to next.

&quot;We need to be better at identifying where we are struggling and adapting to that situation to get momentum back - where you are struggling to get anything from the referee, or a bounce of a ball, how can you gain back that control.

&quot;That's what New Zealand do so well so often. So many times they are on the back foot for the first 20, 30 minutes maybe, and they can find a way to swing it around and get momentum and get their gameplan going.

&quot;That's something we need to be better at - definitely.&quot;

England captain Owen Farrell endured a difficult afternoon in the Stade de France as his side trailed 24-0 before a second-half rally.

Lawes, one of a host of players with more than 50 caps in the England squad, believes those experienced men must help out the skipper.

&quot;We have a leadership group in place and they are responsible for making decisions on the field. You don't want too many people talking, especially when you are under pressure,&quot; he said.

&quot;Owen has got his role as skipper, and then we as lieutenants - or whatever you want to call it - have our role trying to figure out how he can do his role best.&quot;
• 'Eddie will be hyping them up'
• Listen: Rugby Union Weekly: Does Owen Farrell need more help?

Lawes says Edinburgh, where England face Scotland on Saturday, is the ideal place to prove the squad are learning their lessons after the Paris setback.

&quot;It's the perfect place to go for us, because there is going to be some adversity without a shadow of a doubt,&quot; he added.

&quot;It will be great for the maturity of our squad, and the players in it and the leadership group to show what we can learn from the weekend to take into this game.

&quot;They don't really like us there but it's something we kind of like to embrace and get out there and play some fiery rugby.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51389454</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Kempton Park: New smaller development proposal could save racing - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Horse Racing</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/11132/production/_110783996_gettyimages-1191901906.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Racing at Kempton Park could be saved after course owner the Jockey Club reduced the scale of its plans for a housing development on the site.

A 2017 proposal for 3,000 homes would have seen the bulldozing of the track, home to the King George VI Chase.

The Jockey Club and developer Redrow Homes have now offered a revised plan, which would not affect the racecourse.

&quot;We have put forward another option,&quot; said Sandy Dudgeon, the senior steward of the Jockey Club.

&quot;This would involve just a proportion of the available land there and allow racing to continue.&quot;

The Jockey Club's initial proposal for the Surrey track was submitted to Spelthorne Borough Council - the local authority that decides on planning applications - in January 2017.
• Kempton Park racecourse faces closure to make way for 3,000 homes

As part of the plan, the proceeds of selling the course to a developer, at the time thought likely to be in excess of £100m, were to be reinvested in other courses, including nearby Sandown.

But the chances of those plans being approved were reduced significantly after a 2018 assessment by the council suggested the track was &quot;strongly performing&quot; as part of the green belt.

The council's policy on planning applications is covered by its Local Plan. All local authorities are required by law to have such a plan to guide decisions on planning developments.

Dudgeon added: &quot;We have respected the position of Spelthorne Borough Council throughout their Local Plan process with relation to Kempton Park.&quot;

The suggestion that Kempton might be bulldozed rates among racing's most contentious issues of recent years.

Whatever the Jockey Club insisted about ensuring funding for its remaining courses, it wasn't a good look for the organisation founded in the mid-18th century as a custodian of racing to be shutting down a course, and one of the sport's premier National Hunt venues at that.

With the local council never having been a fan of the plans, they probably wouldn't have happened anyway, but campaigners will be cock-a-hoop at this news. They will be carefully monitoring the alternatives, however.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/horse-racing/51387497</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Lions tour 2021: Scottish Rugby bids to host match at Murrayfield - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scottish Rugby</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/14E7B/production/_110772658_lions.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Scottish Rugby has made a bid for Murrayfield to host a British and Irish Lions match before the tour of South Africa in 2021.

It would be the first time a Lions team has ever played on Scottish soil.

The Welsh and Irish unions have also bid to host the match against an as yet unnamed opponent, which would be a warm-up before the squad flies out.

Twickenham is set to be unavailable with the Premiership final set to take place there on Saturday, 26 June.

The SRU wants to make the event a weekend festival of rugby at the end of June 2021.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51375528</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Tokyo 2020: Olympic organisers 'seriously concerned' by coronavirus spread - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Olympics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1246E/production/_110726847_olympicrins.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Olympic organisers are &quot;seriously concerned&quot; about the spread of coronavirus and the impact it could have on the Tokyo Games this summer.

Several qualification events have already been impacted due to the virus.

Tokyo Organising Committee chief executive Toshiro Muto hopes it will be &quot;eradicated as quickly as possible&quot;.

&quot;We are extremely worried in the sense that the spread of the infectious virus could pour cold water on momentum for the Games,&quot; said Muto.

More than 24,300 cases of the virus have been recorded in China and 490 people have died, with 10 cases also confirmed on a quarantined Japanese cruise ship.

Two people have died of the disease outside of mainland China - one in Hong Kong and one in the Philippines.

The World Health Organization (WHO) has declared the outbreak as a global health emergency but said it did not yet constitute a &quot;pandemic&quot;, or the worldwide spread of a new disease.

Japanese government officials, including prime minister Shinzo Abe, say they will work hard to minimise any impact on the Games, which start on 24 July.

Saburo Kawabuchi, mayor of the Athletes' Village where an expected 11,000 athletes will stay, says he hopes for a &quot;smooth Olympics&quot;.

&quot;We will do our everything we can to protect the athletes to allow them to produce their best performances,&quot; he added.

The International Olympic Committee (IOC) says it is in contact with the WHO and its own medical experts and has confidence the relevant authorities will take &quot;all necessary measures to address the situation&quot;.

An IOC spokesperson said: &quot;Countermeasures against infectious diseases constitute an important part of Tokyo 2020's plans to host a safe and secure Games.

&quot;Tokyo 2020 will continue to collaborate with all relevant organisations which carefully monitor any incidence of infectious diseases and will review any countermeasures that may be necessary with all relevant organisations.

&quot;Preparations for Tokyo 2020 continue as planned and we look forward to returning for the next Project Review in February.&quot;

A number of sporting events in China have been cancelled or postponed, including the World Athletics Indoor Championships, Chinese domestic football season and golf's LPGA event on Hainan Island.

Some countries have also introduced entry restrictions on Chinese athletes, however the Badminton World Federation said on Wednesday it would not be doing so for its global events.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/olympics/51383584</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Tom Banton: Big Bash side Brisbane Heat re-sign England batsman - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Cricket</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/13747/production/_110778697_gettyimages-1197821870.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Brisbane Heat have re-signed Somerset and England batsman Tom Banton for the next two years of Australia's Twenty20 Big Bash League.

The right-hander, 21, hit three half-centuries while playing for Heat in the first half of the 2019-20 competition.

Banton made his one-day international debut for England on Tuesday in their seven-wicket defeat by South Africa.

&quot;He's a good young lad and we think his cricket will only get better from here,&quot; said Heat coach Darren Lehmann.

It is hoped Banton - who has also played in three T20 internationals - will be available for the whole of next winter's Big Bash, having played in seven games this year.

He scored 50 from only 16 balls, including five sixes in an over, against Sydney Thunder last month, the BBL's second-fastest half-century.

Brisbane Heat missed out on the play-off stage, with Sydney Sixers to face either Melbourne Stars or the Thunder in Saturday's final.

Listen to commentary on the Big Bash League play-off matches and final on BBC Radio 5 Live Sports Extra, and on the BBC Sport website and app.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/cricket/51384143</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Scotland v England: Anthony Watson out of Six Nations match - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/0472/production/_110783110_watson_pa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>England winger Anthony Watson has suffered a setback in his recovery from a calf injury and will miss Saturday's match with Scotland in the Six Nations.

The Bath back trained on Tuesday but suffered a recurrence of the problem and sat out Wednesday's session.

England forwards coach Matt Proudfoot confirmed Watson has been ruled out of the Calcutta Cup match at Murrayfield.

&quot;We'll give him the opportunity to get over it 100% before we give him the go,&quot; Proudfoot told BBC Radio 5 Live.

&quot;He won't be available for the weekend.&quot;

Lions winger Watson missed England's 24-17 defeat by France on the opening weekend with the same injury.

Northampton full-back George Furbank made his debut in Paris with Elliot Daly switching to the wing and Jonny May completing the back three.

&quot;We were very happy with how they went,&quot; added Proudfoot when asked about the trio's performance against France.

&quot;Anthony is a world-class player so you do miss it, but I thought the back three played well, we controlled the air pretty well, but we didn't give them enough platform up front to be able to attack with.&quot;

Uncapped Ollie Thorley of Gloucester is the other specialist wing in England's squad.

Head coach Eddie Jones has to change his backline from the one that started against France, with another Lions back Manu Tuilagi ruled out of the trip to Edinburgh with a groin strain.

While England need to make at least one change in the midfield, the deployment of Tom Curry, a flanker, as number eight seems likely to continue.

Curry struggled at points in Paris to replicate Vunipola's heavy-duty ball-carrying and control at the base of the scrum.

Proudfoot admits it is a difficult transition for Curry, but, comparing him to Springbok back row Francois Louw, says he has the ability to switch between positions successfully.

&quot;I have to coach him better, prepare him better. He is an unbelievable player, great, strong personality and physically unbelievable.

&quot;It's crazy to think of the heights he can reach as a player. So we need to up-skill him and I need to prepare him better at the base of the scrum.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51387605</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Heather Watson column: Fed Cup player on feeling 'confident' with her game - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Tennis</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/14AF8/production/_110782748_heatherwatsonindex.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>British number two Heather Watson writes in her BBC Sport column about preparing to lead Great Britain's Fed Cup team for the match against Slovakia on 7-8 February.

This time last year I was watching the Fed Cup from my bed - it was a really bad experience for me.

It was such a shame - after playing Fed Cup for all those years I had never been part of a home tie. And then we were finally at home in Bath but I was literally bed-bound for the whole week with illness, even afterwards as well.

I was live-streaming all the girls' matches every day, they just did so well. Then in April I was part of the team that won the tie against Kazakhstan at the Copper Box in London, and that was an amazing experience.

A year on from Bath, I am coming into this week's tie against Slovakia feeling really happy. It will be my 32nd tie and if we win, we will get through to April's first ever Fed Cup Finals in Budapest.

This time round I am playing as the number one player for Great Britain because Johanna Konta won't be there. I've played number one before a few times so it doesn't feel too different, and I'm just really excited about the matches this week.

I know the girls in the team really well. We're all equal and we're good friends, so being number one doesn't make it any different in that sense.

Jo is a really good friend of mine so I was sad when she said she wasn't playing this year but I totally understand her reasons. From a selfish perspective I would have loved her here but all the other girls are great and there's a brilliant atmosphere in the group.

Since August-September last year I have been playing some really good tennis, I've just been consistent with my results and have been climbing the rankings again. I'm really happy and I'm really enjoying my tennis and I think it is really showing.

I'm 74 in the world at the moment and I'm feeling super confident. I've had a lot of matches this year - including reaching the semi-finals in Hobart last month - and on the practice court I am hitting the ball well.

I feel like I'm on a good run and I hope I can carry it into our matches on Friday and Saturday.

As a professional tennis player you do a lot of travelling and are away from home a lot, but that's one of the sacrifices you have to make.

I've just come back from Melbourne, which is 12 hours ahead of Bratislava where I am now. The jet lag hasn't been too bad though. In fact, when I come back from Australia I am always super tired at night and I wake up fresh as a daisy in the morning because I've had an early night.

It was nearly 40 degrees in Melbourne and now I'm in around eight degrees here, but even that is fine.

We are just so used to it, we bring all the right clothes and we've got a really good support team here from the LTA, who do a brilliant job on the physio, strength and conditioning and medical side of things, so we know we're going to be in the best possible shape for the matches.

I didn't lose any luggage this time round but it has happened to me quite a few times where my bags haven't arrived.

One year I flew to Australia, they lost my bag and I had to borrow my friend's clothes for the next two days. Luckily, it was just over Christmas so I just had those two days off and didn't need to find any tennis clothes. They've never lost my racquets which is lucky, it's always just my case.

Apart from the time zone and the temperature, we've also had to get used to playing on a clay court instead of a hard court, which is what we were playing on in Australia.

It's hard to adjust in a short space of time but it's the same for everyone and I'm sure the matches will be really tight come the weekend.

We hit on clay a few times in London before we got here which was a good start, but the clay is different here. The court is really nice, I like it more, so that's a good thing.

There's a good team spirit naturally within the group but we do also play games in Fed Cup weeks to keep everyone laughing in the team room.

This morning we filmed a feature for LTA's social media channels where we were shown some old social media posts and we had to guess which player had posted them.

There were some shockers in there so it was really funny - apparently you could hear us laughing from next door! The best one was a picture Annie K posted from when she met Craig David a few years ago. It was very corny, so we knew it was her.

We all have a good time on the court during practice as well - the warm-ups are always good fun and get people going well. Anne has been really positive and she's been motivating us all week, so everyone's feeling good and looking forward to getting started.

We always get great support at Fed Cup both in the arenas and at home, so I'm sure we'll get that again and hopefully we can give you all something to shout about.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/tennis/51384252</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Six Nations: Can you name Eddie Jones' first England selection? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby Union</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/2E75/production/_110639811_quiz-index-imagery-cant-show-face-generic--3f7a6937-9196-4bd6-9a15-8e4db7cc3cfe.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Eddie Jones was hired to lead England in the wake of a dismal pool-stage exit from the 2015 Rugby World Cup.

As he prepares for his first match since their more impressive run to the 2019 final, can you remember the Australian's debut England selection?

Your challenge is to name his starting XV that overcame Scotland 15-9 in their opening match of the Six Nations four years ago.

You have four minutes...</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51243512</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Six Nations 2020: Wales call up Dewi Lake and Taine Basham - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Welsh Rugby</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/3910/production/_110780641_cdf_120619_wales_v_fiji_u20_22.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Wales have added hooker Dewi Lake and back-rower Taine Basham to their Six Nations squad.

The former Wales Under-20 pair have been training with the squad and have now been formally called up.

This is a first senior call-up for 20-year-old Osprey Lake, while the Dragons' Basham, also 20, was in the Wales squad for last November's uncapped match against Barbarians.

No players have been released from the squad, the Welsh Rugby Union confirmed.

Wales are scheduled to name their team to face Ireland on Thursday, 6 February at 11:00 GMT.

Lake has made two appearances as an Ospreys replacement this season, one in the Heineken Champions Cup and the other in the Pro14.

Basham has made 29 appearances for the Dragons over three seasons.

For the latest Welsh rugby union news follow @BBCScrumV on Twitter.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51388215</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Israel Folau: Super League votes for greater authority to stop controversial signings - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Rugby League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/4E5A/production/_110785002_folau_pa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Super League has voted unanimously to have &quot;greater authority&quot; to stop future &quot;controversial signings&quot; such as Israel Folau's move to Catalans Dragons.

The clubs held crisis talks over the signing of Folau, 30, at a Super League board meeting on Wednesday.

Folau, the sacked Australia rugby union international, has not played a match of any kind for 10 months since writing a homophobic post on social media.

Several clubs have backed Hull KR's threat of legal action over the deal.

&quot;With the season under way, we now feel it is important for Super League to separate what is an off-field matter from what is happening on the field,&quot; said Robert Elstone, Super League's chief executive.

Elstone said the Super League board &quot;accepts the legalities&quot; around the Rugby Football League's decision to register Folau.

But he added: &quot;The board has voted unanimously to put in place measures that ensure the Super League has greater authority to stop controversial signings such as this in the future.

&quot;As a sport, we have an impressive and enviable track record when it comes to equality, diversity and inclusion and we will continue our great work in those areas.&quot;

Folau was sacked by Australia Rugby for saying &quot;hell awaits&quot; gay people in a social media post in April 2019 and subsequently reached a settlement with the governing body.

He has begun training with Catalans, but the date of his Super League debut remains unclear as he has numerous fitness tests.

Dragons chairman Bernard Guasch did not attend Wednesday's meeting but a representative said Folau will not make his Catalans debut at Wakefield on Sunday.

The RFL and Super League both previously said they &quot;deplored&quot; Folau's comments and it was &quot;a difficult decision&quot; to allow him into the competition.

On Tuesday, the BBC obtained an email, written by Hull KR owner Neil Hudgell, putting the Dragons &quot;on notice&quot; if his club suffered &quot;financial loss&quot; because of the signing of Folau.

Dragons coach Steve McNamara said he &quot;stands by&quot; the decision to give Folau a one-year deal.

Halifax prop Keegan Hirst, Britain's first openly gay rugby league player, said the decision is &quot;disappointing and frustrating&quot;.

Shortly after the Folau deal was made public, Wigan announced that their match against Catalans at the DW Stadium on 22 March would be &quot;Pride Day&quot;.

Folau's signing comes after the National Rugby League ruled out his return to Australia's top-flight competition.

He played in the NRL for Melbourne Storm and Brisbane Broncos and earned representative honours as a Queensland State of Origin player and Australia international.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-league/51390591</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Darren Lehmann to have heart bypass surgery - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Cricket</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/153EA/production/_110781078_gettyimages-1198814602.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former Australia batsman and coach Darren Lehmann will have a heart bypass operation after falling ill on Wednesday, his 50th birthday.

Lehmann suffered chest pains while watching his son Jake, 27, captain a Cricket Australia XI against England Lions on the Gold Coast.

Lehmann, who played in 27 Tests, will have surgery in Brisbane on Saturday.

&quot;I would like to thank everyone in the Australian cricket family for their concern,&quot; he said.

&quot;I am receiving the best of medical care and am confident I'll be back on my feet soon.&quot;

Lehmann, who also played in 117 one-day internationals and helped Australia win two World Cups, coached the national team from 2013 to 2018.

He returned to coaching for the latest Big Bash League, which concludes on Saturday, but failed to lead Brisbane Heat into the play-off phase.

Lehmann was also appointed coach of the Northern Superchargers, based in Leeds, for the inaugural season of The Hundred, which begins on 17 July.

He was Yorkshire's overseas player from 1997 to 2006 and helped them to their first County Championship title in 33 years in 2001.

Yorkshire director of cricket Martyn Moxon added: &quot;He's been a great servant for Yorkshire County Cricket Club over the years and we wish both him and his family well in the coming weeks.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/cricket/51384089</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Armand Duplantis: Pole vault world record almost set by world silver medallist - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Athletics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12F13/production/_110778577_gettyimages-1178409728.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>European champion Armand Duplantis narrowly missed out on the pole vault world record at a World Athletics Indoor Tour meeting on Tuesday.

The American-born Swede, 20, attempted 6.17m in Dusseldorf and brushed the bar with his arm on his second effort.

But Duplantis, who won silver at the 2019 World Championships, did clear a season-leading 6.00m to win the event.

Frenchman Renaud Lavillenie, the 2012 Olympic champion, set the current world record of 6.16m in February 2014.

USA's Sam Kendricks, who narrowly beat Duplantis for world gold in Doha, finished second at 5.80m.

&quot;I thought it was possible,&quot; said Duplantis, who was competing in his opening indoor event of 2020.

&quot;You don't think everything's going to be put together in your first meet just because you're physically fit, but it came together nicely.&quot;

Five other season leads were set at the German meeting, with Norway's Filip Ingebrigtsen winning the men's 1500m in 3 minutes 36.32 seconds while Kenya's Beatrice Chepkoech won the women's 1500m in 4:02.09.

Ethiopia's Selemon Barega won the men's 3,000m in 7:35.71 while Croatia's Filip Mihaljevic led the men's shot put with 21.52m and Germany's Neele Eckhartd (14.17m) triumphed in the women's triple jump.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/athletics/51384084</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Odion Ighalo: Manchester United striker took pay cut to make loan deal happen - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Man Utd</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/11D2B/production/_110730037_ighalo-2.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Odion Ighalo says he was so desperate to join Manchester United he took a pay cut to make the deal happen and did not sleep the night it was agreed.

The 30-year-old Nigeria forward has joined United on loan from Shanghai Shenhua until the end of the season.

The ex-Watford player says his mum cried at the news and there were parties on the street where he grew up.

&quot;A few other clubs had shown interest, I said: 'Please, just pick United, if it's going to be possible,'&quot; he said.

Speaking to the club website, he added: &quot;At 11pm in Shanghai, my agent called me [to say] that United want to do the deal, so I woke up that night and started looking for a translator to go to the directors' room and hit his door.

&quot;'My agent wants to speak to you. United are coming for me, you have to make this happen.'&quot;

Ighalo, his agent and the clubs spent the night negotiating and signing paperwork to get it through before the deadline at 7am Shanghai time.

Meanwhile, other clubs were calling asking Ighalo to sign for them.

&quot;I told my agent 'this is what I want. I want to come here',&quot; added Ighalo.

&quot;He said: 'You're going to get a pay cut to go to United.'

&quot;I said: 'I don't care. Make this deal happen. I want to go to United. I don't care how much is the pay cut, I know that, make it happen.'&quot;

Ighalo says he has been a United fan since he was a child and is pleased to be able to make the his dream of playing for the Old Trafford club a reality.

&quot;I called my mum and she was happy, crying,&quot; he said.

&quot;I know many people used to say when they join a team, they say that they dream of playing for that team. Mine was not the case. I supported the team when I was young.

&quot;People that know me, even back in Nigeria, and even when I was playing at Watford, my team-mates knew that I loved Manchester United, I support them.&quot;

With Marcus Rashford recovering from a stress fracture and Anthony Martial having scored once in his past five Premier League games, Ighalo hopes his physicality can aid the United forward line.

&quot;I'm very fast, I'm skilful, I'm strong, I have good techniques, so I can find my way in the field of play,&quot; he said.

&quot;They have a striker that stays mostly in the middle, but Martial likes to come from the side, even Rashford, so you need someone in the middle that can keep the ball, hold the ball.

&quot;They need a physicality up front to keep the ball, to give and to make some movement, which I believe if everything goes well I can add to the team.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51383589</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Six Nations: Why Ireland fans want Andy Farrell to roll the dice - Stephen Ferris - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Irish Rugby</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/9C47/production/_110770004_stephenferrissixnations.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Oh how Andy Farrell would have loved to start life as Ireland's head coach with a nice little summer tour to North America.

Can you imagine the freedom he would have had to tweak his line-up if his reign began with three Tests against the USA?

Let's try Max Deegan at eight, not that effective? No bother, we'll put him at six the next game. While we're at it, let's give Andrew Porter a go on both sides of the scrum and give Billy Burns and Ross Byrne 80 minutes each to see how they link-up with John Cooney.

As it happens his head coaching baptism is being held in the greatest rugby competition in the northern hemisphere, where the scope for trying things out is a little smaller.

I know I speak for a lot of fans when I say I would happily forego one or two Six Nations wins if it meant blooding some of the talented kids at Ireland's disposal.
• Ireland's Robbie Henshaw and Peter O'Mahony to start against Wales
• Ireland know what is coming against Wales - Farrell

I want to see Ireland evolve into something more dynamic, not always so pragmatic. I want to see a team that tries to play with the shackles off a bit more.

But that is me as a fan. If I was a player in the Ireland dressing room, I would say to hell with experimentation. To hell with seeing what works.

Here's how Johnny Sexton and his team will be seeing things: we have played one game, played pretty badly, but won. The Championship is still on.

Farrell's team for the Wales game is a nod to the perceived significance of experience.

We had plenty of it in Japan and it didn't help.

Looking at Ireland's 2020 schedule and beyond, there is no perfect opportunity for experimentation but we need to see Ireland try something different, freshen things up.

It's not a jibe against Peter O'Mahony who was excellent against Scotland last week, but I'd love to have seen Max Deegan get a run out from the start, let's see what he can offer.

As a fan I want to see the team evolving, we want to see more line-breaks and higher intensity and that is going to require a new approach.

Case in point is the scrum-half debate.

I am one of the many people who believe John Cooney has earned his shot in the number nine jersey.

We don't need to go over the well-told form guide or the stats book, nor do we need to go over Conor Murray's CV.

The bottom line, as Ronan O'Gara said earlier this week, is that the noise for John Cooney is not going to go away.

It is, at some stage, going to happen and whether it will be a permanent shift in the hierarchy or not remains to be seen.

Like the rest of Ireland I want the old Conor Murray back - only he knows why his form has dipped over the last two years and it remains to be seen if he can come back again.

In retaining Murray for the Wales game, Farrell has created a potentially tricky scenario for Cooney.

If Conor fails to deliver again this weekend, John could be wheeled out against England at Twickenham in two weeks' time.

He would back himself to perform in that game every day of the week, but let's face it, England away is a tough ask for any player let alone one trying to prove why he deserves a regular starting spot.

A final thought on the scrum-half debate is a nod to the professionalism of both players.

Neither player has felt the need to talk themselves up in public, or even issue subtle hints about their place in the pecking order. Both of them are up for leaving all their talking to the training pitch.

Ireland did not click against Scotland, and they will probably know that the better team lost on the day. That won't bother them one bit though, I have played plenty of rugby matches and the better team doesn't always win.

Defensively Ireland did leave the Aviva Stadium with some credit, especially the back row whose work on the ground was exceptional.

'Soak tackles' won't be enough against England

I didn't like everything I saw from the back row though, and here the stats do them a service that masks an area of concern.

Josh van der Flier gets a lot of credit for his tackling stats, he had 15 on Saturday but I guarantee you a fair few of those were soak tackles.

A soak tackle is when you absorb the impact and pull a player down to the ground.

That's alright against Scotland, but those tackles won't be much use against the bigger, more dynamic lads Ireland will meet in the next few weeks.

When you come up against the best team you're going to have to stop them dead or push them back. At the moment Pete doesn't do it, van der Flier certainly doesn't do it and CJ Stander only does it now and again.

Curry and Underhill are sitting lads on their backside every single game - that has to be the standard.

Tackling people around the ankles against New Zealand or South Africa, or England in the Six Nations, isn't going to do it for you.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51373918</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Mo Farah: Olympic champion withdraws from London half marathon with injury - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Athletics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/16CEA/production/_110781439_gettyimages-1175594282.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Four-time Olympic champion Mo Farah has withdrawn from 'The Big Half' race on 1 March with a minor Achilles injury.

Farah, winner of the half marathon event in London for the past two years, suffered the injury in training.

The 36-year-old, who will defend his 10,000m title at the Tokyo 2020 Olympics, will now continue the build-up to the summer season in Africa.

&quot;My priority is to be fit, healthy and competitive for the summer season,&quot; Farah said.

&quot;For that reason I have had to make the tough decision not to race this year. I definitely hope to be back again in 2021.&quot;

Farah quit track events in 2017 to concentrate on the marathon.

But having won gold in the 5,000m and 10,000m at the 2012 and 2016 Olympics, he announced in late 2019 his decision to return to the track.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/athletics/51384253</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Six Nations: 'Fear' gone from Ireland pre-match preparation, says Henderson - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Irish Rugby</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/7393/production/_110778592_hendo.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Ireland lock Iain Henderson says there is a new spirit of openness about the squad's pre-match preparation under new head coach Andy Farrell.

Farrell succeeded Joe Schmidt in the role after the World Cup and led his side to a 19-12 win over Scotland in his first game in charge on Saturday.

&quot;Before the guys might have been a wee bit tentative about who they went and asked questions to,&quot; said Henderson.

&quot;For fear of people thinking they don't know their detail, didn't know stuff.&quot;

Henderson added: &quot;Now there's a very open learning system that has been put in place to ensure guys are free to get information or give clarity whenever they want.

&quot;There's a different mentality around the place - a different relationship between players and coaches and a different relationship between players and players, going over stuff together.&quot;
• Fans want Farrell to roll the dice - Ferris on Ireland
• O'Mahony and Henshaw return for Ireland against Wales
• Ireland know what is coming against Wales - Farrell

The Ulster second row explains that the changing culture in the Ireland camp is aimed at helping players push each other on to greater efforts as they prepare to play Wales in Dublin in their second Six Nations match on Saturday.

&quot;Everything that is done is done in a real positive manner to ensure we're getting the best out of each other,&quot; he said.

&quot;If I go to a player and ask him for help or he comes to me and asks me for help, we're doing it to make each other better and ultimately to get a better result at the weekend. Everyone knows that.

&quot;A lot of different things are changing and there are lots of different systems in place. All the guys are adapting pretty well and training has been pretty smooth.

&quot;The guys are excited to be out there, maybe doing something slightly different.&quot;

Prop Cian Healy agreed that the Ireland players were enjoying &quot;picking everyone's brains a little bit&quot; in a desire to get their detail right.

&quot;It's really open. You walk across to a coach and ask them to sit down with you for a few minutes and go through this with me and help me get some clarity,&quot; he said.

&quot;It's the same with players, grabbing each other and sitting at a computer or with a notebook saying 'what would you do here?' or 'what can I do to stop that?'

&quot;We've had a different kind of review process too as we've broken it up more into different areas. A lot has been put onto the mini-groups to look after the smaller details of the scrum, the lineout and the breakdown.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51383647</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>David de Gea: Name the players with 300 Premier League appearances for a single club - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12F4A/production/_110724677_degea_index.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The goalkeeper made his 300th Premier League appearance for Manchester United on Saturday, as they drew 0-0 with Wolves at Old Trafford.

Below is a list of 35 players who have also achieved 300 starts in the top flight of English football with a single club during their career.

All you have to do is read the clues and try to name as many players as you can in four minutes.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51330931</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>Liverpool 1-0 Shrewsbury: Absent Jurgen Klopp 'delighted' with FA Cup win - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Liverpool</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/3D8D/production/_110775751_hi059717721.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Absent Liverpool manager Jurgen Klopp was &quot;delighted&quot; as the youngest team in the club's history beat Shrewsbury to reach the FA Cup fifth round.

Klopp decided to miss the fourth-round replay because it fell during the Premier League's winter break.

A Reds side with an average age of 19 years and 102 days set up a tie at Chelsea with a 1-0 win.

&quot;There was a message at half-time and at full-time [from Klopp],&quot; said under-23s boss Neil Critchley.

&quot;There was a message before the game that Chelsea away could be an opportunity for one or two of them and they put in a performance tonight.&quot;

There was at least one of Klopp's senior players in the sell-out 52,399 crowd, with James Milner offering his support sat behind the home dugout.

&quot;He trained with us yesterday and he asked whether he could come along,&quot; added Critchley, who oversaw the game for Liverpool.

&quot;He was giving words of advice, he was getting right behind the players. He was vocal in the dressing room. He was animated. He was vocal behind me, I could hear him.&quot;

Ro-Shaun Williams' own goal was enough to send a Liverpool side containing seven teenage outfield players through against their League One opponents.

Liverpool right-back Neco Williams, whose long ball forward led to the goal, said it was a night that his team-mates would remember for &quot;a long time&quot;.

The result means the Reds are still in the chase for three additional trophies, having already won the Club World Cup and Super Cup.

They have a 22-point lead at the top of the Premier League and are in the last 16 of both the Champions League and FA Cup.

&quot;The lads were excellent and hopefully we will do the same against Chelsea in the next round,&quot; said 18-year-old Williams.

&quot;Our aim is to win the FA Cup. I think the [senior] lads will have been extremely proud of us and hopefully us young players will get a chance again.&quot;

Aged 19 years and five days, Toxteth-born Curtis Jones became the youngest first-team captain in Liverpool's history.

&quot;All the boys went out there and showed belief, character, showed everything that the manager looks for in his players,&quot; said Jones.

&quot;I was grateful to become the youngest captain of the team but most importantly we came away with the win with a great performance.

&quot;The boys showed heart, character and a hard decision for the next game.&quot;

'Klopp should have been there'

Former England captain Alan Shearer said &quot;it doesn't sit right with me&quot; that Klopp missed Tuesday's match.

The German said last week he &quot;decided three weeks ago we would have a mid-season break based on a letter we got [from the Premier League] in April 2019&quot;.

Top-flight teams were all due to have two weeks off in February but the 2-2 draw in the original tie meant the replay fell within that period, prompting his decision to miss the match, along with his entire senior squad.

&quot;I understand Jurgen's point in terms of his players having the break they were told they'd have,&quot; said Shearer on BBC One.

&quot;He is the manager so he can put whichever team he wants but it doesn't sit right with me - he should be there. He should be at the ground giving the support to those young players.&quot;

Former England keeper Rob Green, speaking to BBC Sport, said Klopp's decision not to field his senior players and stay away was &quot;clever mind games&quot;.

&quot;Coming from Germany, he thinks we're crazy playing all these games, so it's a really interesting quandary and one where you're thinking he's got the upper ground here,&quot; added Green.

Former Birmingham and Crystal Palace striker Clinton Morrison also believes Klopp should have been present.

&quot;If I was one of those youngsters, I would've liked Jurgen Klopp to have been there, win, lose or draw, to have put an arm around me and say I had done well,&quot; said Morrison.

&quot;But he's made his decision and he's one of those managers that has credit in the bank because he's been so good.&quot;

'This tie had the potential to be a real legacy for the club'

Shrewsbury boss Sam Ricketts said before the replay that the League One club missed out on making more money from it.

The Reds cut ticket prices to £15 for adults and £1 for children while the game was not shown live on television.

&quot;We're going to generate some money from this but nowhere near what it could've been,&quot; Ricketts told BBC Radio 5 Live.

&quot;It had the potential to be a real legacy for the club and for us to put some infrastructure in place but it's still more then what we would've got without a replay, so we'll look at that on the positive side.&quot;

Speaking about the game, Ricketts said his players &quot;could not get near&quot; Liverpool &quot;to impose ourselves&quot;.

He added: &quot;It is game 39 for us and it caught up with us. We could not get up to the physicality level.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51380211</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>Fight Talk: Kell Brook, Dillian Whyte, Andy Ruiz Jr, Tommy Coyle, Jake Paul - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Boxing</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/3809/production/_110754341_158fa3dc-0eb2-40f6-86d4-2e17720ecf55.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Can Kell Brook become world champion again?

Has Kell Brook become the forgotten man of British boxing?

On Saturday night, in his home city, the Sheffield fighter makes his return to the ring after more than a year out, taking on American Mark DeLuca.

Brook's last outing was an underwhelming points win over Australian Michael Zerafa in December 2018.

It is five and a half years since his standout career performance, when he beat Shawn Porter in America to capture the IBF welterweight world title.

The world was at his feet after that win but his career has stalled since suffering subsequent losses to Gennady Golovkin and Errol Spence Jr, as well as fracturing both his eye sockets.

So, can Brook reignite his career and world title aspirations with an impressive performance against DeLuca?

He's already said he will retire if he doesn't win.

But he's looking sharp in training…

And some fans are impressed…

While others think Brook's recent inactivity against top-level opponents could be his downfall…

Should Brook win, there's one name that will no doubt come up in the post-fight interviews - Amir Khan. It's a fight that boxing fans have been wanting for years.

But it appears that demand for the all British affair has now dwindled…

As we still wait on confirmation of Dillian Whyte's next opponent, with Russian Alexander Povetkin seemingly the favourite, the British heavyweight has had a bit of tit-for-tat with former world champion Andy Ruiz Jr this past week.

It was reported a few weeks ago that Matchroom promoter Eddie Hearn offered the Mexican a seven-figure fee to fight Whyte next, but talks have since broken down.

Ruiz Jr took to Instagram with this dig…

And this is how Twitter reacted to the spat…

Super Bowl 54 wasn't the only sporting event to take place in Miami last week as Irishman Luke Keeler lost his WBO middleweight title challenge against America's Demetrius Andrade.

Also on the card was a scrap between two social media celebrities as Jake Paul took on Britain's AnEsonGib in what was their professional debut for both fighters.

And it was American Paul who came out on top with a first-round stoppage.

The bout may not been as hyped up as the Logan Paul and KSI bout in November but boxing purists, as expected, still ridiculed the fight between two YouTubers...

Although, rather surprisingly, there was the odd tweet complimenting Jake Paul's boxing skills on Thursday night…

And for those who are hoping that this is the end of YouTubers in the boxing world, you might not be too pleased to hear that there are more to come.

Jake is looking to avenge his brother Logan's defeat by KSI - the two came face-to-face on Thursday after Jake's win, with Eddie Hearn telling IFL TV that a bout could take place in the summer.

And Hearn has also talked up the possibility of Logan taking on former American footballer Antonio Brown.

Promoters and boxers paid tribute to Tommy Coyle after the Hull fighter announced his retirement last week.

From fighting at Madison Square Garden and achieving a childhood dream to often doing his bit for the local community in Hull, Coyle was both a fan favourite and well-liked among his peers.

And let's not forget the time he pulled down the shorts of an unsuspecting Eddie Hearn during a fight week in Boston.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/boxing/51360042</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>Kolpak: PCA would back two overseas players per county post-Brexit - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Counties</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/15066/production/_110781168_harmer_olivier_abbott_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Professional Cricketers' Association would support two overseas players per club in all formats from 2021 to allow Kolpak signings chances to continue playing county cricket.

Following Brexit, the England and Wales Cricket Board has advised counties that Kolpak registrations will be terminated at the end of the 2020 season.

The agreement is in line with the deal the UK secured with the European Union.

Kolpak deals have been used since 2004 for players mainly from South Africa.

Counties are already permitted to have two overseas players in the T20 Blast - but have been restricted to one in all other competitions, including the Championship, since 2007.

Kolpak contracts are named after Slovak handball player Marius Kolpak, who won a landmark case at the European Court of Justice in 2003.

They allow sportsmen from countries with associate trade agreements with the EU, such as South Africa, Zimbabwe and Caribbean nations to be afforded the same right to free movement as EU citizens.

Kolpak players are not classed as overseas players by the England and Wales Cricket Board under the terms of their contracts, but they become ineligible to represent their country at international level.

There are currently 17 South African players under Kolpak contracts for the 2020 season.

A number of those, including Essex off-spinner Simon Harmer and Hampshire fast bowler Kyle Abbott, agreed deals beyond 2020 towards the end of last season.

Somerset have also recently signed South Africa seamer Vernon Philander on a two-year Kolpak contract and Surrey have brought in his fellow countryman Hashim Amla on a similar deal.

Overseas players who hold UK passports or who have settled or pre-settled status will continue to have their rights to play as a &quot;local cricketer&quot; protected past 2020.

PCA chairman and Worcestershire opening batsman Daryl Mitchell said Brexit has caused a &quot;number of sensitive issues&quot; for members over the past three years.

&quot;It's been a frustrating process for many, but fortunately we're now able to offer some clarity,&quot; he said.

&quot;We must acknowledge and consider the human element of those players who've made commitments and signed contracts beyond 2020 and the effect this outcome will have on those individuals.

&quot;Our view is increasing overseas players to two per county in the County Championship and One-Day Cup would be a positive outcome.

&quot;This would allow opportunities for these players to continue their careers in England and help to maintain standards in the county game.&quot;

The ECB's new competition, The Hundred, which makes its debut this summer will feature three overseas players per team.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/cricket/51387075</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>Mbwana Samatta: Name the other international Premier League goalscorers - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Premier League</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/13DE7/production/_110738318_samatta_index.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Aston Villa may have lost at Bournemouth, but their new signing scored on his Premier League debut - and created a little bit of history too.

Mbwana Samatta's 70th-minute header made him the first player from Tanzania to score a goal in the Premier League.

Who knows when someone else will join him? For now, he stands alongside 17 others as the only players from their respective nations to have found the net in the Premier League.

How many can you name? We've given you some clues to help.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51344390</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-24</ID>
      <TITLE>Can the WSL deal with pressures of growing visibility? - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Women's Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12095/production/_110777837_sophie_ingle_beth_england_getty_01.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Crowds are up, television coverage has increased and sponsorship deals are becoming more lucrative - but there are side-effects to the growth of top-level women's football.

Players in the Women's Super League are having to deal with greater levels of expectation, and with that can come stinging criticism.

England boss Phil Neville has suggested in the past that such scrutiny comes with the territory. But how do players cope when they have not been used to it?

And are Women's Super League clubs equipped to support them?

Neville said last June that his team should be &quot;brave enough&quot; to accept criticism in the build-up to the World Cup, at which his team reached the semi-finals.

&quot;There's always been this real 'nicey nicey' approach to the women's game and I'm of the opinion that if you win, you get praise, but if you do a bad pass, then you are going to get criticised,&quot; he said.

A record-breaking 28.1m people watched BBC coverage of the 2019 World Cup on television and online.

But Manchester City and England midfielder Keira Walsh told the Guardian in January she &quot;probably underestimated how much attention was going to be on the games&quot;.

She said: &quot;I really did struggle with the criticism off the back of [the World Cup]. There were times when I thought: 'Is this actually for me? Do I want to play football any more?'

&quot;Sometimes people are very critical of me, which is fine, I can learn to deal with it, but people do tend to forget that I've still got time to improve and this isn't the finished product by any means.&quot;

It is a product, though, that is attracting ever more attention - which will bring scrutiny and criticism along with a major financial lift.

Atletico Madrid forward Toni Duggan told BBC Breakfast in May last year that the game had been &quot;screaming out for sponsorship, interviews and brands coming on board&quot;.

Both the sponsors and the fans are doing just that. Last year, Barclays agreed a multi-million sponsorship deal with the Women's Super League. And after the publicity generated by the World Cup, England played in front of a record crowd of 77,768 against Germany at Wembley in November.

&quot;The product on the pitch has become better which makes fans come in and want more,&quot; departing Manchester City boss Nick Cushing told BBC Radio Manchester.

Has this level of pressure always been there?

Manchester United manager Casey Stoney, a former England captain, says &quot;the women's game isn't used&quot; to the visibility.

Asked if there is more criticism of players now, she replied: &quot;I think there is, and I think that should be what we want, because we want visibility and we want people to judge the game for the game, rather than saying: 'Oh, unlucky.'&quot;

Wales international Hayley Ladd added &quot;a little bit of criticism is normal&quot;.

&quot;You see what the men have to put up with in their side of the game,&quot; she said. &quot;If things do turn a bit negative then we have to stay focused on our jobs, so we might not read that.&quot;

A number of clubs in the WSL provide social media training in order to help players manage criticism online. They also carry out media training sessions at the start of the season.

Mental health support is provided at Everton, who employ a club chaplain, a performance psychologist and a lifestyle adviser. The Toffees' players can also use a club doctor and external clinical psychologists.

Liverpool invited a consultant in leadership, team culture and elite performance to speak to the players before the Merseyside derby at Anfield in November.

Manchester United have an external wellbeing coach, who comes into the club every day.

They have also had someone come in to talk about social media and the club provides one-to-ones with players every six weeks to discuss personal issues, as well as their football development.

Players also receive support from the Football Association.

Every club is visited by FA officials during pre-season to discuss how to report abuse or discrimination and players are made aware of self-referral mental health support programmes.

WSL academies are given workshops on mental health and there are plans in place to introduce a mental health first aider at every club.

Assistance in dealing with publicity is given too, as a BBC documentary showed last June; the programme showed the England squad taking part in media training and team bonding sessions in Qatar before the World Cup.

All of those programmes can help players deal with the criticism that comes their way.

&quot;It's not about patronising people - it's a football game, and we don't want to be treated any differently from the male players,&quot; Stoney said.

&quot;You're going to get the same judgement. The difference is: the male players are used to it. The women's game isn't used to it, and it's a big wake-up call for a lot of [the players] because they read it.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51106078</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-25</ID>
      <TITLE>Quinton de Kock hits hundred as England thrashed by South Africa - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Cricket</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/4D7D/production/_110773891_1198656575-1f5d7dc78bbe09ade4437b6e7ce5bd6a8825d438.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>World champions England were &quot;way off the mark&quot; in their heavy seven-wicket one-day international defeat by South Africa, said captain Eoin Morgan.

Quinton de Kock hit 107 and Temba Bavuma 98 as the hosts chased down England's 258-8 with 14 balls left.

The pair combined for a partnership of 173 and made the tourists' under-strength attack look toothless in their first ODI since winning the World Cup.

England's top order also failed, falling to 131-6 before Joe Denly's 87.

Denly's innings looked to have kept England in the game, but De Kock and Bavuma were ruthless where England's batsmen were not.

De Kock was eventually bowled trying to slog-sweep Joe Root and Bavuma fell agonisingly short of a second ODI hundred when he was trapped lbw by a ball that skidded on from Chris Jordan.

Those wickets slowed South Africa's victory push but they were always in control of the chase with Rassie van der Dussen scoring 38 not out.

&quot;Right from the beginning of our innings, we struggled to adapt to the conditions,&quot; Morgan told the Test Match Special podcast.

&quot;We did our best to adapt but the skill level wasn't there.

&quot;We'll identify the little reasons why we didn't gel as a team today because if we play like that again, we'll lose.&quot;

England, who have rested a handful of their World Cup winners for this series, now trail 1-0 in the three-match contest and face the prospect of losing an ODI series for the first time in three years.

It is 205 days since the greatest day in England's white-ball history, when they beat New Zealand at Lord's to win the men's World Cup for the first time. This defeat was as chastening as anything seen in recent years in a period when Eoin Morgan's side have usually dominated.

England's total proved to be well below par and the bowlers were punished comprehensively by De Kock and Bavuma.

England badly missed the pace of Jofra Archer and Mark Wood, who were both rested for the series, and were lacking the guile provided by Liam Plunkett and Adil Rashid in the middle overs. Plunkett has been dispensed with since the World Cup while Rashid is on the tour of South Africa but was not selected.

Chris Woakes, the only member of the World Cup final bowling attack to feature, was economical with the new ball and had opener Reeza Hendricks caught behind in the seventh over but the other bowlers struggled.

Sam Curran shared the new ball and was not threatening, while Tom Curran and Chris Jordan looked one-paced and were wayward for the majority.

Leg-spinner Matt Parkinson, making his ODI debut, was largely anonymous as the sole frontline spinner, going wicketless in 8.4 overs.

De Kock and Bavuma were patient early on but rotated the strike well and as the partnership grew, the pair made the most of the increasing number of opportunities they were given by the bowlers.

De Kock, playing in his first ODI since being appointed captain, compiled a mature innings that was not overly attacking. He hit boundaries all around the wicket, including an emphatic six back over Tom Curran's head and a fine cover drive off Parkinson that took him to his 15th ODI century.

Bavuma was arguably even more impressive, scoring at ease throughout, and deserved to reach three figures.

In addition to England's weakened bowling attack, World Cup winners Ben Stokes and Jos Buttler - both rested - were absent from the batting line-up.

Openers Jonny Bairstow and Jason Roy, plus Joe Root and Eoin Morgan, did feature and were all part of the top-order failure.

Roy and Bairstow had made a promising start by reaching 51-0 but were out in consecutive overs, mistiming aggressive shots to long-on and mid-off respectively as they perhaps aimed for too high a total too early.

Root and Morgan steadied England with a partnership of 30, but Root was brilliantly run out by a direct hit from Van der Dussen and Morgan edged left-arm wrist-spinner Tabraiz Shamsi to slip for 11 three balls later.

After their good start, England were quickly bogged down by South Africa's seamers' slower balls and the spin of Shamsi and JJ Smuts.

Debutant Tom Banton, the highly-rated 21-year-old batsman, showed glimpses of his promise with three boundaries - a reverse sweep, a powerful pull and a fine straight drive - but was trapped lbw for 18.

When Sam Curran was bowled around his legs in the 28th over, it looked like England would not bat out their 50 overs.

At the age of 33, Denly is a curious selection in this team as England build for the Twenty20 World Cup in October and their defence of the 50-over World Cup in 2023, but he and Woakes (40) were the only batsmen to look confident.

Denly was circumspect early on before scoring 51 off his final 39 balls, but his intelligent innings was ultimately in vain.

&quot;For us, plans B and C are when we come up on wickets like this and should adapt, manipulate what we're trying to do, and the projected total comes way down to 275 or 300,&quot; Morgan said.

&quot;We [Morgan and Root] spoke about that while we were in the middle but weren't good enough to implement it today.

&quot;You watch guys like Jason Roy and Jonny Bairstow crunching the ball and it can lead to a misconception that the wicket is better than it actually is.

&quot;If you actually look at the way they hit the ball, they were hitting it in the air off the ground whereas normally they drill the ball along the ground. Balls that they smashed didn't go for six.

&quot;Little indications like that should drip into the changing room.&quot;

The T20 World Cup in Australia in October and November is England's next white-ball priority so only five of England's World Cup-winning side featured on Tuesday.

Few of England's back-up players advanced their cause in a strangely flat performance.

Joe Denly, with his first ODI fifty for more than a decade, gave England something to defend, but the bowling attack looked toothless.

Quinton de Kock has shown throughout the South African summer that he's the class player in this line-up, and he was superb again.

Perhaps South Africa sensed it was going to be their day when Rassie van der Dussen produced a stunning piece of fielding to run out Joe Root - arguably the decisive moment in England's innings.

South Africa captain and man of the match Quinton de Kock: &quot;It was a good night. We're just glad to get a win under our belts, it feels good to get back to winning ways.

&quot;This week we've had one or two chats about how we wanted to take this ODI side forward, today was a good start. It's alright talking but to bring it out to the field I'm really pleased about.

&quot;To be honest I did feel the weight of captaincy while I was batting. I enjoyed it, it kept me in the game. That extra bit of responsibility helped me.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/cricket/51371900</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-26</ID>
      <TITLE>Quiz: Name the British &amp; Irish players to have played in Serie A - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/17EB4/production/_110727979_young_index.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The January transfer window has closed for business for another year.

One player to make the switch from the Premier League to Serie A was Ashley Young.

The former Manchester United defender signed for Italian giants Inter Milan for £1.28m on an initial six-month deal, with an option to extend for a further season.

Young, 34, joins a long list of British and Irish players to make the jump from English football to Italy's top division.

For the quiz below, we've picked out 15 players - past and present - who also played in Serie A at some point in their careers.

All you have to do is read the clues and try to name as many as you can in three minutes.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51334223</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-27</ID>
      <TITLE>Cristiano Ronaldo: South Korean fans compensated after Juventus forward fails to play - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>European Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/55CE/production/_110766912_ronaldogetty3.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A South Korean court has told a local match organiser to compensate two fans after Cristiano Ronaldo did not play in a Juventus friendly as advertised.

Fans were told the Portugal forward would play at least 45 minutes against a K-League all-star team last July, but he did not come off the bench.

Organisers The Fasta have been ordered to pay 371,000 won (£240) to two fans.

The award includes 300,000 won (£194) for &quot;mental anguish&quot; caused, lawyer Kim Min-ki said.

Kim, who filed the lawsuit, said: &quot;The Fasta misled and used the fans of Cristiano Ronaldo for their own benefit.

&quot;To the fans of Ronaldo, this is equivalent to losing the player whom they would have admired and supported their entire lives.&quot;

Kim also told news agency Reuters he was representing a further 87 plaintiffs in other cases filed in connection with the match, which finished in a 3-3 draw.

The 65,000 tickets for the match sold out in less than three minutes, with 34-year-old Ronaldo featured heavily in advertisements.

Fans became angry when he made no sign of coming off the bench, even chanting the name of his rival Lionel Messi.

South Korea's professional football governing body K League also sent a letter of protest to Juventus for violating the contract.

The Fasta are yet to comment.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51372201</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-28</ID>
      <TITLE>Great Britain basketball Olympic qualifier: It's about more than just Tokyo - Chantelle Handy - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Basketball</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1803/production/_110774160_chantelle_handy_eurobasket_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Great Britain are playing to 'keep alive' the national basketball programme by qualifying for the Tokyo Olympics, says forward Chantelle Handy.

GB basketball lost its Lottery funding after London 2012 but now have the chance to qualify a team for the Olympics on merit for the first time.

&quot;We just want to keep GB alive. It would be really sad if the programme can't continue,&quot; Handy told BBC Sport.

Three of the four teams will qualify for Tokyo.

&quot;We want to go to Tokyo but for me it's more about trying to live on and hopefully get some funding for the younger generations,&quot; added Handy.

The Belgrade event was moved to Serbia from Foshan in China due to concerns over the coronavirus outbreak.

&quot;This is the biggest tournament I'm going to participate in besides the Olympic Games and we want that ticket,&quot; said point guard Rachael Vanderwal, who like Handy, played at the London Olympics.

&quot;I think we can make history and really put GB Basketball on the big stage.&quot;

Both GB men's and women's teams have operated on what has been described as 'minimal funding' after their funding was cut in the wake of the London Olympics.

In 2018, GB basketball expressed concerns over their ability to continue their elite programme due to lack of funds.

That prompted UK Sport and the Department of Digital, Culture, Media and Sport to put together a special support package amounting to about £500,000, with a further £75,000 later released from UK Sport's Aspiration Fund.

&quot;We haven't got the support that we deserve, really,&quot; said Vanderwal. &quot;To get to the actual Olympics, if that doesn't change things what can?

It's really motivation for us to prove that GB Basketball deserves funding - so we can say 'look what what we've done already - with a little support we can do more'.&quot;

&quot;We've had obstacles in the past but we're here to fight and prove a point that we belong,&quot; said Chantel Charles, who made her GB debut in Poland in November. &quot;If we were to qualify it would have a big impact on a lot of people from the youth to women.&quot;

Great Britain's women reached this qualifying event thanks to their best ever performance at Eurobasket last year, when they finished fourth.

&quot;No-one's ever done this before; this is our time to create history,&quot; added Charles. &quot;And it's us women who are doing this first kind of vibe.&quot;

Both China and Spain are ranked in the world top 10, with Spain the reigning European champions. Great Britain and South Korea are ranked 18 and 19 respectively.

&quot;We're realistic, we know it's going to be hard,&quot; said Handy, who like Vanderwal has more than 100 caps for Great Britain. &quot;But that's our mindset going into every game. It's going to be a war - because everybody wants that ticket.

&quot;Now is just our time - a lot of us are maybe looking to retire in the next few years - we want to make a statement before we leave.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/basketball/51377810</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-29</ID>
      <TITLE>'I can win Tokyo gold' - Shelly-Ann Fraser-Pryce targets 2020 Olympics success - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Athletics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/D95F/production/_110774655_fraser_pryce_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Four-time 100m world champion Shelly-Ann Fraser-Pryce says she believes she can keep the younger generation at bay to win Olympic gold in Tokyo.

The 33-year-old became the oldest women to win a world or Olympic 100m title with victory in Doha in September.

She only came back to competition early last year after spending two years away from the sport to have her son Zyon.

&quot;I definitely believe it's possible, considering the year I had and the room to improve,&quot; the Jamaican said.

&quot;There are things that I do personally that I missed out on and have gone light on.

&quot;That time out actually gave me the time to just mentally refocus on the goals that I want to achieve and I'm going to soldier on and I'm definitely looking forward to making it to my fourth Olympic Games.&quot;

Fraser-Pryce won 100m gold at Beijing 2008 and London 2012, before taking bronze behind compatriot Elaine Thompson and American Tori Bowie at Rio 2016.

She also confirmed that she intends to double up by competing in the 200m, the event in which 24-year-old Briton Dina Asher-Smith won gold in Doha.

&quot;The plan last year was to do the double, and my coach decided he didn't want me doing the double, considering I just came back off a break,&quot; added Fraser-Pryce, who is a nominee for the World Sportswoman of the Year at the Laureus Awards in Berlin on 17 February.

&quot;So, this year we are attempting to do the 100 and the 200, and my programme has been geared towards that.&quot;

Fraser-Pryce began training ten weeks after Zyon's birth in 2017, but had to run with a special band stabilising her stomach following a caesarean section.

Zyon accompanied her on a lap of honour after her 100m triumph in Doha.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/athletics/51380002</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-30</ID>
      <TITLE>Six Nations: Ireland's Robbie Henshaw and Peter O'Mahony to start against Wales - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Irish Rugby</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1387C/production/_110769997_henshawo'amhony.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Centre Robbie Henshaw and flanker Peter O'Mahony return to Ireland's starting line-up as head coach Andy Farrell makes two enforced changes for the visit of Wales on Saturday.

Garry Ringrose and Caelan Doris drop out having picked up injuries in last weekend's win over Scotland.

Conor Murray starts at scrum-half with John Cooney again on the bench.

Leinster back row Max Deegan is set for his debut having been named among the replacements.
• Ireland 'know what is coming' against Wales - head coach Farrell
• Ireland's Ringrose out of Wales and England games

O'Mahony played 76 minutes against Scotland despite starting on the bench, having been called upon after just four minutes following a head injury to debutant Doris.

The Munster flanker was one of Ireland's best performers as a determined defensive display saw the hosts claim a 19-12 victory in Farrell's first game since replacing Joe Schmidt as head coach.

His inclusion sees CJ Stander shift to the back of the scrum having begun the opening game at blind-side flanker.

Henshaw was a half-time replacement for Ringrose, who had been ruled out of the next two matches following a procedure on a suspected broken finger.

The injury sees Keith Earls named on the bench. The Munster man has recovered from a knee injury that kept him sidelined for the first game of the tournament and will provide cover across the back line.

Earls will be joined on the bench by 23-year-old Deegan, who will become the third Leinster player to make his international debut under Farrell after Doris and hooker Ronan Kelleher gained their first caps against Scotland.

Dave Kilcoyne, who was taken off for a HIA having been brought on as a second-half replacement, is fit to retain his place in the squad.

Scrum-half Murray will win his 80th international cap on Saturday, and will hope to bounce back from a poor individual display as the five-Test British and Irish Lion continues to hold off Ulster's Cooney.

Last year's Six Nations meeting between the sides saw Wales complete a Grand Slam with a dominant 25-7 win at the Principality Stadium.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/rugby-union/51368749</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-31</ID>
      <TITLE>Celtic and Hamilton to face Scottish FA charge for not acting in 'orderly fashion' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scottish Premiership</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1300E/production/_110783877_19825380.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Celtic and Hamilton Academical will be charged by the Scottish FA for failing to act &quot;in an orderly fashion&quot; during Sunday's Scottish Premiership game.

It relates to a first-half incident when players from each team surrounded referee Nick Walsh after Leigh Griffiths stood on Accies' Sam Woods.

The clubs face a hearing at Hampden on 20 February.

Celtic have also been charged with the same offence in their Scottish Cup tie at Partick Thistle on 18 January.
• 'No debate Griffiths should have had red'

If found guilty, each could face a fine ranging from £2,500 to £20,000.

The clubs will be charged under disciplinary rule 204 which states players and staff must &quot;conduct themselves in an orderly fashion at all times&quot; and refrain from &quot;confrontation&quot; and &quot;conduct likely to lead to or to exacerbate or prolong a hostile or argumentative situation&quot;.

Premiership leaders Celtic won the match 4-1 at Hamilton's Fountain of Youth Stadium, with Griffiths avoiding further punishment for his tangle with Woods, which happened when the game was goalless.

The Griffiths incident was referred by Scottish FA compliance officer Clare Whyte to a three-man panel of former referees, who did not agree it was a red-card offence.

Hamilton were later reduced to 10 men in the first half when Jamie Hamilton received a straight red for a last-man foul on Griffiths.

Celtic won the cup tie with Thistle 2-1 to progress to a meeting with League One Clyde on Sunday.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51387705</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-32</ID>
      <TITLE>Gambling in football: Bookmakers considering ban on shirt and pitchside advertising - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/113F7/production/_110774607_gettyimages-1203399162.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Bookmakers are &quot;considering&quot; a voluntary ban on football shirt sponsorship and pitchside advertising, a parliamentary committee has heard.

It would expand on the whistle-to-whistle ban on television gambling adverts introduced last year.

Half of Premier League clubs and 17 of 24 Championship clubs are sponsored by bookmakers.

That had led to concerns about the potential impact on young fans and vulnerable people.

Brigid Simmonds, chair of the The Betting and Gaming Council (BGC), which represents 90% of the betting and gaming industry, told the House of Lords' Gambling Industry Committee that the whistle-to-whistle ban has reduced gambling advertising on television by 85%.

However, she conceded that some of the advertising may have moved online and added: &quot;We may well need to do more and we are absolutely open to that.&quot;

Asked whether her organisation was considering banning gambling logos from football shirts and perimeter stadium advertising, she said: &quot;We are certainly looking at the whole issue of sponsorship.

&quot;I think, as one of us said earlier, there are good messages. All the sponsorship that goes with clubs is about putting responsible messages on shirts as well as the name.

&quot;We can consider this going forward, we are active in considering it.

&quot;But I would also say, as someone who has worked a lot in sport in the last 50 years, that actually grassroots sports benefit from a lot of the money that is put into sport.

&quot;We want that sponsorship to be used responsibly.&quot;

GVC, the parent company of Ladbrokes and Coral, has already withdrawn its sponsorship in football.

Its chief executive Kenny Alexander called for a wider industry move in this area, saying: &quot;I think it needs to be seriously cut down.&quot;

He added: &quot;Is the industry too much in the face of the consumer at the moment?

&quot;Is there too much TV advertising, is there too much sponsorship? I think that is undoubtedly the case and something I feel should be looked at.

&quot;There are probably too many gambling adverts and too much noise about gambling in front of consumers in the UK at the moment.&quot;

John Coates, joint chief executive of Bet365 and vice-chairman of Stoke City, said &quot;I do hear the concerns&quot; about the amount of advertising and said he &quot;welcomes&quot; the review of the Gambling Act.

However, he also said: &quot;Stoke City survives on the money we put into it.&quot;

Meanwhile, Conor Grant, chief operating officer of Sky Betting and Gaming, which sponsors the EFL, said: &quot;I think it is important that we do have the opportunity to advertise as a business and I think it is really important we do that responsibly.

&quot;The tone with which we do it, and the frequency, is all up for discussion. We welcome the review that is happening.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51377202</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-33</ID>
      <TITLE>Robert Alner: Cheltenham Gold Cup-winning trainer dies aged 76 - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Horse Racing</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/1353E/production/_110766197_hi059705119.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Alner triumphed with Cool Dawn in 1998 and trained several other leading steeplechasers - including Sir Rembrandt, The Listener and Kingscliff - in a distinguished career.

He was seriously injured in a car crash in 2007, which left him paralysed and in need of a wheelchair.

&quot;He will be sorely missed,&quot; said Andrew Thornton, who rode Cool Dawn to victory 22 years ago.

Thornton said Dorset-based Alner was only given two years to live and spent 101 days in intensive care after the crash.

But he went on to continue training under a joint licence with his wife Sally until 2010, when the pair announced their retirement.

&quot;It's really sad news. I was very close to Robert. They were like a second family,&quot; an emotional Thornton told Sky Sports Racing.

He won the Welsh National in 2007 on Miko de Beauchene for Alner as the trainer recovered in hospital.

&quot;That success was on a par with the Gold Cup. It was a real tonic for Robert,&quot; he said.

It has been a sad 24 hours for the jump racing community after former jockey James Banks was found dead at his Gloucestershire home aged 36.

Banks, who had retired from race riding almost exactly two years earlier, was a popular figure with colleagues.

&quot;He was the life and soul of the weighing room, great to have around the place. It's been a terrible 24 hours,&quot; said Thornton.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/horse-racing/51369655</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-34</ID>
      <TITLE>Oxford Utd 2-3 Newcastle aet: Steve Bruce's side survive comeback to progress - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>FA Cup</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/07A5/production/_110775910_stevebruce.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Newcastle United boss Steve Bruce believes it was a &quot;significant&quot; moment for the club to reach the fifth round of the FA Cup for the first time in 14 years.

The Premier League side survived a huge scare in Tuesday's fourth-round replay against League One Oxford United, who came back from two goals down to draw 2-2 and take the game to extra time.

Neither side could then be separated and it looked like penalties would be needed until Allan Saint-Maximin's spectacular strike secured the win.

&quot;I know what it means for the city and the supporters, who have come a million miles to get here tonight, a couple of thousand of them,&quot; said Bruce.

&quot;We are into the next round. We have made hard work of it against Rochdale and now Oxford but I think we thoroughly deserved to get through.

&quot;I think it is significant for the club to get into the fifth round for the first time since 2006.&quot;

Newcastle had looked to be cruising to victory as they protected a two-goal lead given to them before half-time courtesy of Sean Longstaff's rising 15th-minute drive and Joelinton's composed finish for only his third goal of the season.

Oxford gave themselves hope with seven minutes left when Liam Kelly's 20-yard free-kick eluded the grasp of Newcastle keeper Karl Darlow before Nathan Holland's crisp volley deep into stoppage time set up the extra 30 minutes and the prospect of a shock.

The unpredictable Saint-Maximin was the difference and a huge threat in extra time, finally winning it for Newcastle and setting up a fifth-round tie at West Bromwich Albion with a magnificent finish that ripped beyond Simon Eastwood into the top corner after 116 minutes.

&quot;It was a hairy cup tie, great for the neutral but awful for myself and the fans,&quot; added Bruce.

&quot;It wouldn't be Newcastle without a story and if that's the story let's go to West Bromwich Albion and carry it on.

&quot;When you look back and put your slippers on the FA Cup final is still a huge moment in this country. It was rekindled for me when I got there as manager of Hull City against Arsenal in 2014 and I vowed that I would never play weakened teams.

&quot;A club like Newcastle can win five games and get to Wembley.&quot;

Newcastle needed something out of the ordinary to halt Oxford's remarkable recovery that saw Karl Robinson's League One promotion chasers turn the game on its head in the closing minutes.

The Magpies looked to be closing out a comfortable victory despite Oxford's endeavour but they were rocked on their heels by Kelly and Holland.

Oxford started the extra period with a spring in their step but the sheer pace and wild unpredictability of Saint-Maximin, whose power also altered the momentum as Oxford ran out of steam, provided the X-Factor.

The 22-year-old French forward, on as a first-half substitute for injured Joelinton, is an adventure every time he is in possession, mixing madcap losses of control and frustrating moments with a genuine match-winning touch.

And how he came good in that vital extra period, drawing fine saves from Oxford keeper Eastwood before producing that decisive contribution with a fierce shot that broke the hearts of the home side and spared Newcastle's blushes as they threatened to throw away a game they had under their control.

The Toon Army celebrated at the final whistle - and the toast was Saint-Maximin.

Oxford take pride - now for promotion

Oxford manager Robinson described this FA Cup fourth-round replay as &quot;a free hit&quot; but he and his players will still be bitterly disappointed to come so close to penalties only to be thwarted by a moment of brilliance from Saint-Maximin.

The Yellows have had some fine moments at Kassam Stadium this season, notably when West Ham United were thrashed 4-0 in the Carabao Cup and Manchester City were pushed all the way before winning 3-1 here in the quarter-final.

It looked for a while as if Oxford would slip away without giving Newcastle serious anxiety but how they battled and how their fans responded as they started extra time looking the more confident side after that tumultuous finale.

It was not to be but Oxford can take real pride from the resilience they showed here and now they can turn their attention back to their top priority, namely promotion to the Championship.

Manager Robinson is struggling for numbers after the departure of Shandon Baptiste and Tariqe Fosu to Brentford on transfer deadline day but there is real talent within his squad and this is a developing side.

Oxford are currently eighth in League One, three points off the play-off places, and now it is back to business on that front as they travel to Peterborough United, who are third in the table, on Saturday.

&quot;I thought we outplayed them,&quot; said Robinson.

&quot;I don't know what the stats are but we created good chances, even in the first half.

&quot;Their first goal is a worldie and the third is an outstanding finish. It is all ifs and buts unfortunately but I am really proud of my players.&quot;

Replay joy again for Newcastle - the stats
• Newcastle have won their last five FA Cup replays, scoring 17 goals across those victories.
• They have reached the fifth round of the competition for the first time since the 2005-06 season, when they were eventually knocked out at the quarter-final stage by Chelsea.
• Newcastle's Joelinton both scored and assisted in the same game for the first time since January 2019 for Hoffenheim against Freiburg in the Bundesliga.
• Team-mate Sean Longstaff also scored and assisted in the same game for the first time since November 2017 for Blackpool in the EFL Trophy against Middlesbrough Under-21s.

Oxford travel to Peterborough in League One on Saturday, 8 February (15:00 GMT) while Newcastle return to action after the winter break with a trip to Arsenal in the Premier League on Sunday, 16 February (16:30).</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51356823</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-35</ID>
      <TITLE>Distance debate in golf: R&amp;A and USGA say long hitting should be curbed - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Golf</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/14EB6/production/_110768658_ball2.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>These are turbulent times for golf and the waters could potentially become even more choppy as the game's governing bodies reveal measures are needed to limit the length balls travel off the tee.

After signalling intent to put brakes on the distance players can smash their drives, the R&amp;A and United States Golf Association (USGA), who set the sport's rules, now need more of the game's key stakeholders to buy into the project.

With club and ball manufacturers, as well as leading professional tours, having expressed long-standing reluctance to embrace such moves, rules-makers can expect significant challenges in order to win them over.

This comes at a time when organisations such as the PGA and European Tours are flexing their muscles to fight off the proposed Premier Golf League, with talk of a £183m prize fund in order to lure 48 of the world's best players.

There are currently battlegrounds throughout the sport as it seeks to identify the best way forward. But the main preoccupation of the R&amp;A and USGA is halting the ongoing growth in driving distances.

&quot;This will only be achieved if the whole industry comes together to make sure the game is thriving 50 years from now,&quot; R&amp;A chief executive Martin Slumbers told BBC Sport.

There can be no doubting the two years' worth of diligence with which the governing bodies have approached an issue that has implications for golf at every level.

Today's publication of the Distance Insights Project Report suggests potentially significant changes are under consideration.

They may lead to alterations to club and ball specifications in order to limit their future effectiveness as well as local rules potentially being introduced for certain courses and competitions.

For years distance has been one of golf's most controversial topics. Many argue the character of the game has been destroyed by saucepan-headed drivers propelling hi-tech modern balls vast distances.

The report states that in 1995 the top-20 longest hitters in elite male competition averaged 278 yards off the tee. By last year, that figure had risen to 310 yards.

Erin Hills, the Wisconsin course that staged the 2017 US Open, measured a mammoth 7,741 yards yet it did not stop Brooks Koepka's winning score being 16 under par.

&quot;Longer distances, longer courses, playing from longer tees and longer times to play are taking golf in the wrong direction,&quot; the report concludes.

&quot;Golf will best thrive over the next decades and beyond if this continuing cycle of ever-increasing hitting distances and golf course lengths is brought to an end.&quot;

Longer courses mean higher maintenance costs, greater environmental impact and rounds taking more time to complete.

The report admits a need for &quot;potential changes to the equipment rules&quot; and to &quot;consider whether any existing specifications should be adjusted or any new specifications should be created to help mitigate the continuing distance increases&quot;.

All of which will alert manufacturers - whose sales point is the distance gains their clubs and balls can offer the amateur golfer - and the tours, who view massive drives as part of their spectacle.

The R&amp;A and USGA say these bodies are now on notice that change is needed. But nothing will happen imminently, with further input to be sought over much of the next year before anything is decided.

This will be a crucial period as golf seeks a united front on the issue, but the clock is ticking.

Many classic courses have already been rendered obsolete for elite golf and the iconic St Andrews Old Course needs certain tees to be located out of bounds in order to make it long enough to host professional events.

Slumbers, though, says the exhaustive process underway is &quot;absolutely not&quot; a case of kicking the can down the road.

&quot;We now need to have a conversation about where we go. The report does not have any solutions whatsoever; from today is when we start the discussion with the industry.&quot;

These will be vital talks that go to the heart of the game's future.

&quot;There are a lot of very serious people who run this industry and working together those serious people can handle and find solutions for a difficult problem,&quot; Slumbers added.

&quot;We believe we need to find solutions because otherwise the issues of skill and footprint will just continue to grow and I think that would be detrimental to the game of golf.

&quot;As a governing body we have a real responsibility, both historical and modern, to protect the traditions of this game.&quot;

So this is a potentially significant development for the golf industry. The report states: &quot;We believe it is never too late to do the right thing for the future of the game.&quot;

However there are many interpretations on what &quot;the right thing&quot; might be and debate will rage over coming months. It seems the need for eventual consensus has never been greater.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/golf/51374200</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-36</ID>
      <TITLE>Formula E unveils new Gen2 EVO car for 2020-21 season - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Motorsport</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/132B5/production/_110771587_formulae.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Formula E has unveiled the design of their new car for next season - the Gen2 EVO, which is a redesign of the current car.

The Gen2 was introduced last season and enabled drivers to finish a race on one battery.

The new car features a 'shark fin' rear wing and revised bodywork.

&quot;The Gen2 EVO has been given re-profiled bodywork to make it look more sleek and agile,&quot; Formula E chairman Alejandro Agag said.

The car will be revealed at the Geneva International Motor Show on 3 March.

Formula E was forced to cancel the Sanya E-prix in China on Sunday because of the coronavirus outbreak.

Formula E has been given official FIA World Championships status from next season.

After three races of the current campaign, Belgian Stoffel Vandoorne leads the standings by three points from Briton Alexander Sims.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/motorsport/51374262</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-37</ID>
      <TITLE>Portsmouth Women: The team who have not played a league game since November - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Women's Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/11696/production/_110681317_portsmouthjordan.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Having one game postponed is frustrating enough for players, coaches and fans, but what about more than a dozen in just half a season?

On Sunday, Portsmouth Women had a match called off for the 14th time this campaign, and the 12th time where it was related to an unplayable pitch.

The third-tier club's latest fixture cancellation - which was supposed to be a League Cup tie at home to neighbours Southampton - came four days after a Hampshire Cup tie against Winchester was called off for a second time, following a pitch inspection more that 24 hours before the scheduled kick-off.

Fixture frustration has been nothing new for Pompey, who have not played a league fixture since 24 November, leaving them with as many as six games in hand on their league rivals in the National League Southern Premier Division.

&quot;If we turn up and a game is on, it's a bit more of a surprise for us,&quot; Portsmouth manager Jay Sadler told BBC Sport.

&quot;It is a burden on fans. We want to build an attendance and having a solid set of games helps build the fanbase.

&quot;It's very hard as the girls and the staff put all the effort in to train during the week and then all that planning goes out the window.&quot;

Stay at home or move away? The choice facing Pompey

Pompey play at PMC Stadium, the home of non-league men's club Baffins Milton Rovers, but the pitch - near to Langstone Harbour and Farlington Marshes - has struggled with drainage problems this term.

Of their 12 games called off over pitch issues, nine have been at home, with Baffins Milton's ground waterlogged.

&quot;The weather down on the south coast has been atrocious,&quot; continued Sadler, who has been in charge of the team since November 2016.

&quot;It's very difficult. You can't help the weather but we do need to start getting these games on. The league obviously aren't too impressed.

&quot;Prior to coming under the umbrella of the men's club in 2018, we played at 14 different home venues. Since having our home base, our attendances have grown, so we want to stay within the city of Portsmouth and have a central hub.

&quot;But unfortunately now we're probably going to have to look elsewhere, because it is also affecting Baffins Milton. Between us we've got to play about 20 league games in around 15 weeks, plus cup ties.&quot;

On 14 November, Pompey advertised five upcoming fixtures on social media, but none of them ended up taking place on the scheduled days because of rearranged games and postponements.

The problems mean the club are now set to go at least 11 weeks without a league game before facing Hounslow this Sunday.

Before that they will now try to play their cup tie against the Saints on Wednesday - but have moved it to Gosport Borough's Privett Park.

&quot;We've been fortunate that local teams have helped us with friendlies, just to keep the match fitness up,&quot; Sadler added.

&quot;But we have to discuss a plan B. We've got a fantastic link with Baffins Milton. They're really lovely people there, and we want to continue that link, but we've still got to play 15 league games.

&quot;The alternative venues we've put forward, they've been rejected because they don't meet the league's stadium criteria.

&quot;There are a number of local teams where the pitches are holding up, like Gosport, Portchester and Bognor Regis, but the aim is to try to keep the team in the city for the local fans.

&quot;When you see the amount of money that's being bandied about the men's Premier League, you look at that asking: 'Where is that being filtered in to grassroots, non-league and women's football?'

&quot;These girls aren't asking for a lot. They're not asking for equal pay or anything like that. They're just asking to be treated fairly and be able to play the sport they love.

&quot;The Women's Super League is unbelievable, but don't forget us. We're still here. We don't want the margins getting too big. We've all got ambitions of getting to the top.&quot;

Portsmouth's postponed fixtures so far this season</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51269677</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-38</ID>
      <TITLE>Barrow players catch lift with fans from Dover after bus breaks down - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Barrow</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/7B28/production/_110782513_mediaitem110782512.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>&quot;You never know what you're going to get on Barrow away days because things never seem to go to plan.&quot;

Barrow's recent history has been eventful to say the least as the Cumbrian club has bounced around the higher echelons of non-league football since last appearing in the Football League nearly 50 years ago.

With the side seven points clear at the top of the National League and seemingly closing in on promotion, surely nothing could go wrong now?

But Tuesday's 740-mile round-trip to Dover Athletic proved to be anything but plain sailing and became an away day that will live long in the memory for the 23 fans that made their way from Holker Street to The Crabble.

It started off well - Barrow manager Ian Evatt bought the 23 sausage and bacon rolls for the team's journey, which began at 10:00 GMT for a 19:45 GMT kick-off in Kent, and the fans got to the ground an hour before the game began.

But then things went wrong...

Having gone behind to Will De Havilland's early strike, Barrow searched for an equaliser and found it when John Rooney - former England striker Wayne's younger brother - slotted home an 81st-minute penalty.

But Michael Woods got Dover's winner with two minutes to go to break the travelling fans' hearts.

&quot;We threw everything at it,&quot; Barrow fan Taylor Nelson told BBC Sport. &quot;We made all three changes and ended up with five strikers up front to try and get something out of the game - and that worked.

&quot;But from that point Dover realised they were able to be less conservative and attack us as we lacked numbers at the back. They exploited it perfectly.&quot;

After getting on board the bus home, the 23 fans had expected to make a quick getaway in the hope they might be back in Barrow by around 0500 GMT and grab an hour or two's sleep.

It was not to be.

&quot;There was a lot of confusion,&quot; Taylor said. &quot;Eventually the message was conveyed that we were having to wait for the team because their coach had broken down.

&quot;We offered them the space on our bus so we had to wait for them to get showered and changed.

&quot;Before they came on we had a brief discussion and said to try to avoid football talk,&quot; added Taylor, who had goalscorer Rooney and team-mate Scott Quigley sitting behind him.

&quot;It was a bit awkward, but we avoided football talk where possible and kept discussions outside football to save any embarrassment.&quot;

With the confusion surrounding how the team would get home there was no post-match food for the players to eat.

That meant a stop at the motorway services as the players bought what any finely-honed athlete would eat after a game - fried chicken.

&quot;We didn't realise they were going to take so long,&quot; joked Taylor.

&quot;We just thought they were going to nip to the shop and get something quick, so we all sat and waited on the coach expecting them to come back rather quickly. But instead we were all waiting for about half an hour as they were queuing up for KFC orders.

&quot;Then there were lots of diversions and that held us up even more - the journey took an hour-and-a-half more than it needed to.&quot;

Eighteen-year-old student Taylor finally got home at 0700 GMT on Wednesday after the bus containing fans and players arrived back at Holker Street 15 minutes earlier.

But there was no time for him to catch any shut-eye.

&quot;I've had no sleep,&quot; he added. &quot;I was straight to college for a politics lesson at 1000.&quot;

Barrow's next game is a comparatively short 550-mile round-trip to Barnet on Saturday in the FA Trophy.

Let's hope the wheels don't come off - either figuratively or metaphorically.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51385914</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-39</ID>
      <TITLE>James Milner: Liverpool midfielder watches youngsters in the FA Cup - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Liverpool</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/651F/production/_110778852_gettyimages-1198663261.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Goalkeeper Alisson was in Rio de Janeiro. Striker Roberto Firmino was in The Maldives. Midfielder Georginio Wijnaldum was in Dubai. And right-back Trent Alexander-Arnold was in Miami.

Just some of the sunshine destinations Liverpool's superstars found themselves in as the club's youngsters played Shrewsbury in an FA Cup tie on Tuesday night.

James Milner? The veteran of over 800 career matches was sitting on a bench at a chilly Anfield, supporting Curtis Jones and co in their replay against the mid-table League One side.

The former England midfielder, who is recovering from a hamstring injury, didn't just turn up five minutes before kick-off and watch the match either.
• Was Klopp correct to miss tie with Shrewsbury?

The 34-year-old trained with the team in the build up to the game and gave the kids - with an average age of 19 years and 102 days - a pre-match pep talk.

'I think he was desperate to get on'

According to Under-23 manager Neil Critchley, who was in charge with Jurgen Klopp staying away as the replay fell during the Premier League's winter break, he was even eager to play.

&quot;He trained with us [the day before] and he asked whether he could come along. I think the answer is 'Yes, of course you can'. It was very respectful to ask,&quot; Critchley said.

&quot;He was giving words of advice, he was getting right behind the players. He was vocal in the dressing room. He was animated. He was vocal behind me, I could hear him.

&quot;I don't think he's available [fit] yet... but he was jumping up and down behind me so I think he was desperate to get on.&quot;

Milner made his senior debut with Leeds at the age of 16, so knows what it is like to play on the big stage at a young age.

After the match, he tweeted: &quot;Outstanding performance from the boys, Critch and his staff &amp; fantastic turn out from the fans.&quot;

&quot;He was genuinely delighted at how the boys performed and I can't thank him enough,&quot; added Critchley.

&quot;He was buzzing. We've given him a game against Chelsea away to look forward to.&quot;

With Klopp likely to recall at least some of his senior players for the fifth-round tie against Chelsea, there's every chance Milner will be in action at Stamford Bridge thanks to the efforts of the youngest line-up in Liverpool's history.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51384244</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-02 00:00:00-40</ID>
      <TITLE>Jacksonville Jaguars to become first NFL team to play two games in one season outside US - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>American football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/F70F/production/_110774236_jaguars_wembley_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Jacksonville Jaguars will become the first NFL team to play two games in a season outside the United States by appearing twice in London in 2020.

The Jaguars will host both games at Wembley Stadium on consecutive Sundays during the 2020 season.

Their opponents have yet to be announced.

&quot;We're privileged to be the first team in NFL history to play two home games in London during a single season,&quot; said Jaguars owner Shahid Khan.

The Jaguars have played one home game at Wembley every year since 2013.

&quot;We're really looking forward to deepening our relationship with London and the UK as a whole, and would also like to thank our fans in the UK who have been phenomenal ever since our first visit, seven years ago,&quot; added Khan, who also owns Championship side Fulham.

The Jaguars have confirmed their home games against the Pittsburgh Steelers and the Chicago Bears will take place at TIAA Bank Field in Jacksonville, Florida.

In London they will therefore play two teams from the Houston Texans, the Indianapolis Colts, the Tennessee Titans, the Cleveland Browns, the Detroit Lions and the Miami Dolphins.

There will also again be two NFL matches at Tottenham Hotspur Stadium in the 2020 season though the participating teams are yet to be announced.

&quot;London is the sporting capital of the world, so I am absolutely delighted that the Jacksonville Jaguars have committed to playing two of their home games in our city from this year,&quot; said London mayor Sadiq Khan.

The Philadelphia Eagles became the first reigning Super Bowl champions to play in London in 2018 when they beat the Jaguars 24-18.

The Kansas City Chiefs produced a stunning comeback to beat the San Francisco 49ers to win this season's Super Bowl on Sunday.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/american-football/51377667</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
