<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/890A/production/_100728053_bafta1_netflix.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A look back at some of the stories we covered over the last seven days, from celebrity engagement proposals to this year's Bafta TV nominations.

The nominees for this year's Bafta TV Awards were announced in London. Netflix's Black Mirror and The Crown are the leading programmes this year with three nominations apiece.

Verne Troyer, best known for appearing in the Austin Powers films, was admitted to hospital in Los Angeles.

The actor's team assured fans he was &quot;resting comfortably&quot; and receiving &quot;the best care possible&quot;.

Nadine Dorries said Have I Got News For You was &quot;too vicious&quot; for most female guests and did not lend itself &quot;to women feeling comfortable&quot;.

The Conservative MP was speaking after show regular Ian Hislop claimed female politicians were &quot;reticent&quot; to be its guest host.
• Have I Got News For You 'too vicious' for women

Comedy duo Flo and Joan told the BBC that getting their TV break on a building society advert led to them receiving death threats.

&quot;You shouldn't be able to say things like that without any consequence,&quot; said Flo - real name Nicola Dempsey.

Meanwhile, another female comedy duo - Mel and Sue - got a critical drubbing for their revival of BBC One game show The Generation Game.

Critics described it as &quot;desperate&quot; and &quot;a shameless carbon copy&quot; of the versions broadcast in the 1970s and '80s.
• The Generation Game: What the critics said

This was also the week that fashion designer Marc Jacobs proposed to his boyfriend in a Mexican fast-food restaurant.

Jacobs follows a number of other celebrities - among them Pink, Seal and actor Neil Patrick Harris - to pop the question in an unusual locale.

Finally, we took a look at the strange phenomenon of so-called &quot;twin films&quot;.

The Mercy and Crowhurst - two films about amateur British sailor Donald Crowhurst - are two recent examples of films about the same subject to be released around the same time.

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-43658699</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/15A3B/production/_100453688_dodd2_pa.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It's been a busy - and sad - week in the world of entertainment. Here's a rundown of some of the stories we covered, the people we spoke to and the stars we lost.

The week began with the news that legendary comedian Sir Ken Dodd had died at the age of 90.

Known for his lengthy stand-up shows, protruding teeth and surreal catchphrases, he was one of Britain's most popular and recognisable entertainers.

Sir Paul McCartney, David Walliams, Sandi Toksvig and Pam Ayres were among many celebrities to pay tribute to the self-styled Squire of Knotty Ash.

Sir Paul spoke for many when he said he and his fellow Beatles &quot;always ended up in tears of laughter&quot; whenever their paths crossed.
• Ken Dodd and the end of a comedy era

This was also the week we said goodbye to comedian Jim Bowen, loved by millions for presenting darts-based game show Bullseye.

You can't beat a bit of Bully, as the Lancashire native demonstrated for 14 years at the helm of the viewers' favourite.

On Thursday, Strictly Come Dancing fans learned that professional dancing couple Kevin and Karen Clifton have separated after three years of marriage.

But the pair confirmed they will still be touring the UK together later this year.
• &quot;We've always felt the best thing is to be honest&quot;

Alexandra Burke made her own contribution to Strictly last year and will be embarking on a tour herself in 2018.

Yet that hasn't stopped her being on the brunt of some harsh criticism of late - something she told the BBC was down to the way the British confuse confidence with arrogance.

Showbiz reporter Lucy Ford had a surprise for Reese Witherspoon this week - a 15,000-word university dissertation on Legally Blonde.

Lucy's video of her presenting Reese with the document - tied with pink ribbon and pre-scented - soon went viral. &quot;It was a really sweet moment,&quot; she told the BBC.

She's been providing traffic news on BBC Radio 2 for 18 years, but Lynn Bowles has some news of her own for the station's listeners this week.

&quot;I'm afraid I'm going to be leaving Radio 2,&quot; she told Ken Bruce, going on to reveal that she will make her final appearance on 29 March.

Katy Perry faced a backlash after footage was aired of her kissing a 19-year-old during his audition for American Idol.

Benjamin Glaze said the experience made him &quot;uncomfortable&quot; and that he had hoped to save his first kiss for his first relationship.
• She kissed a boy and he didn't like it

Finally, it was reported that Danny Boyle will direct the next James Bond film after the Oscar-winning film-maker revealed he was working on a script with regular collaborator John Hodge.

Eon Productions have yet to confirm the news. Daniel Craig will return as 007 in the currently untitled film, which is set for release in November 2019.
• Boyle and Bond: What we know so far

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-43435828</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p063q0lp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A look back at some of the stories we covered this week, from the return of Worzel Gummidge to an Olivier Awards boo-boo.

To the surprise of precisely no one, theatrical sensation Hamilton was the big winner at the Olivier Awards on Sunday.

The hip hop history musical took home seven prizes - four more than The Ferryman, its closest competitor on the night.

Yet the organisers of the Oliviers had red faces on Monday after audience members spotted Sir Peter Hall had been left out of its In Memoriam tribute.

The Society of London Theatre sought to make amends by updating its video and naming one of its awards after the late theatre director.

This was also the week we reported that Worzel Gummidge was set to return to TV, in a new BBC series starring Mackenzie Crook as the scarecrow character made famous by Jon Pertwee.

The news inspired us to look back at some other remakes of telly favourites, from Sabrina the Teenage Witch to Beverly Hills, 90210.

After Ant McPartlin's absence from the final two episodes of Saturday Night Takeaway, ITV confirmed that his presenting partner Declan Donnelly would also host the Britain's Got Talent live shows without him.

McPartlin - who was charged with a drink-driving offence in March - will still feature in the pre-recorded audition episodes of the talent search's latest series, which kicks off this weekend.
• Dec to host Britain's Got Talent alone

We didn't need to phone a friend before attending the West End opening night of Quiz, James Graham's new play about the Who Wants To Be A Millionaire coughing scandal of 2001.

Graham revealed to us that Millionaire host Chris Tarrant had come to see the play - &quot;in disguise&quot; - during its pre-London run in Chichester. Tarrant was seen again this week at a memorial for the late film critic Barry Norman.
• 'The most British crime of all time'

Singer Mariah Carey chose this week to speak for the first time about her 17-year battle with bipolar disorder and the &quot;positive people&quot; who have helped her &quot;get back to doing what I love&quot;.

&quot;Until recently I lived in denial and isolation and in constant fear someone would expose me,&quot; she told People. &quot;It was too heavy a burden to carry and I simply couldn't do that anymore.&quot;

Fans of JRR Tolkien (it's a hard hobbit to break!) received good news this week: confirmation that The Fall of Gondolin is to be published as a stand-alone book for the first time.

Considered by many to be &quot;the Holy Grail of Tolkien texts&quot; (at least according to one expert), the book - which the author started writing in 1917 - tells of an elven city sacked by the Dark Lord Morgoth.

This was also the week we said a sad goodbye to two talented performers who left us far too young.

W1A actor Alex Beckett and The Overtones singer Timmy Matley both died suddenly, aged 35 and 36 respectively.

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-43757645</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Entertainment &amp; Arts - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/special/2015/newsspec_10857/bbc_news_logo.png?cb=1</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Culture Secretary Nicky Morgan has launched a public consultation on whether non-payment of the TV licence fee should remain a criminal offence.

Currently, anyone who watches or records live TV or uses iPlayer without a TV licence is guilty of a criminal offence and could go to prison.

Baroness Morgan said it was time to think about keeping the fee &quot;relevant&quot; in a &quot;changing media landscape&quot;.

The BBC said a 2015 review found the current system to be the fairest.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment_and_arts/</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/4A51/production/_99452091_beautyget.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lots has happened in the past week in the worlds of TV, film, art and comedy.

Here are some of the biggest stories, in case they passed you by.

Disney's Beauty and the Beast defeated Star Wars: The Last Jedi to become the UK's most popular film of 2017.

The film, starring Emma Watson, earned £4.1m more than The Last Jedi according to end of year box office rankings.

Stephen Fry announced he was stepping down as the host of the Bafta Film Awards after fronting the ceremony 12 times.

He said it was &quot;only right to stand down and let others take the Baftas on to new heights and greater glories&quot;.

Bafta thanked him for making the awards &quot;such memorable and joyous occasions&quot;. A replacement will be named on Tuesday, when this year's nominees are revealed.

On Tuesday, eight contestants entered the Celebrity Big Brother - and they were all women.

The likes of former politician Ann Widdecombe, Keeping up with the Kardashians star Malika Haqq and glamour model Jess Impiazzi were joined by male contestants on Friday.
• Who's in the new Celebrity Big Brother house?

Take Me Out presenter Paddy McGuinness tweeted this week to claim he was duped by someone posing as actor Derek Griffiths on Twitter.

The Take Me Out host says he paid £600 on eBay for what he thought was a charity dinner with the former Coronation Street actor.

The BBC's latest TV drama, McMafia debuted on Monday night with largely positive reviews from the critics.

James Norton - of Happy Valley and War and Peace fame - plays the son of a former Russian &quot;Godfather&quot;, who is trying to follow a straighter path.

Guardian critic Lucy Mangan described it as &quot;beautifully put together&quot; adding that &quot;the script is a cut above average&quot;.

Although it's been confirmed that Game of Thrones won't be back until 2019, its characters will feature on a new series of stamps, Royal Mail has announced.

The collection of 15 first-class stamps aims to highlight British contributions to the hit fantasy TV programme, based on the books by George R R Martin.

Paris Lees - a model, writer and campaigner has become the first openly transgender woman to be featured in British Vogue.

She is included in the issue alongside MP Stella Creasy and Gal-Dem magazine founder Liv Little to celebrate 100 years since women have had the right to vote in the UK.

Get Out star Daniel Kaluuya is among five actors to receive a nomination for this year's Bafta Rising Star award.

The other nominees are Florence Pugh, Josh O'Connor, Tessa Thompson and Timothee Chalamet, who won praise for his turn in Call Me By Your Name.
• Get Out star Kaluuya gets Bafta nod

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-42577834</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/BA0B/production/_98772674_043025885.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lots has happened in the past week in the worlds of TV, film, art and comedy. Here are some of the biggest stories, in case they passed you by.

Cheers and applause greeted the record-breaking sale of a 500-year-old painting of Jesus believed to be by Leonardo da Vinci.

The painting, known as Salvator Mundi (Saviour of the World), sold for $450m (£341m) - considerably more than the £45 it fetched back in 1958.

Read more on this story.

After weeks of speculation, ITV confirmed the line-up for this year's I'm A Celebrity... Get Me Out Of Here ahead of its launch on Sunday.

The participation of UK Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson's father Stanley was much remarked upon, possibly because he was one of the few names people had heard of.

Read more on this story.

Jimmy Fallon returned to his regular desk at NBC's Tonight Show, having absented himself a week to mourn his beloved mother Gloria.

&quot;Mom, I'll never stop trying to make you laugh,&quot; he said at the end of an emotional tribute to the woman he said had always been his &quot;best audience&quot;.

Read more on this story.

Large-scale venue owners rejoiced this week at the news that comedian Peter Kay is to tour the UK again after an eight-year hiatus.

The Bolton-born star said he had missed performing in front of a live audience and &quot;couldn't wait to get back up on stage&quot; from April 2018.

Read more on this story.

A row broke out this week over the skimpy outfits some of Wonder Women's fellow Amazons are seen wearing in the latest superhero film Justice League.

Actress Jessica Chastain was among those to express dismay after the costumes appeared to shrink compared with those in the stand-alone Wonder Woman film released earlier this year.

Read more on this story.

A reader's survey of the UK's favourite breakfast television hosts saw the top five places all go to male presenters.

The Radio Times poll kicked off a war of words between ITV's Piers Morgan and the BBC's Dan Walker after the former beat the latter by 38 votes.

Read more on this story.

Finally, tributes were paid to the actor Keith Barron following his death at the age of 83.

Born in south Yorkshire, the honey-voiced thespian was best known for his role as David Pearce in ITV's sitcom Duty Free.

Read more on this story.

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-42031759</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/F4A4/production/_100082626_gallery-comp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It's been a busy week in the world of film, music and entertainment.

Here's a round-up of some of the biggest stories from the last seven days, just in case they passed you by.

Guests at last Sunday's Bafta Film Awards showed their support for the Time's Up and Me Too campaigns by wearing black and sending messages from the stage.

Virtually all the stars at the London ceremony were in black and some were accompanied by rights campaigners.

One of the few in a colourful dress was best actress winner Frances McDormand - but she told the ceremony: &quot;I stand in full solidarity with my sisters.&quot;
• Stars (almost) unite in black at Baftas
• Three Billboards wins big at the Baftas

Then, on Wednesday, many music stars turned up to the Brit Awards wearing or carrying white roses as a mark of support for the Time's Up and Me Too movements.

Dua Lipa, who had five nominations, and Ed Sheeran, who was up for four awards, were among those who displayed roses.

But Paloma Faith told BBC News: &quot;The only thing I'm upset about tonight is not more men carrying white roses. I think they should have.&quot;

At the Brits ceremony itself, south London grime superstar Stormzy beat Ed Sheeran to the main prizes in a surprise result.

Stormzy, who seemed overwhelmed when he won best British male and best British album for Gang Signs and Prayer, also closed the show and criticised the prime minister's handling of the Grenfell Tower tragedy.

Sheeran didn't go home empty-handed - he was given the global success award.

It's fair to say Fergie's jazzy, slowed-down version of the Star-Spangled Banner at Sunday's NBA All-Star game wasn't a hit with everyone.

The US singer has apologised for her performance. She told TMZ: &quot;I've always been honoured and proud to perform the national anthem and last night I wanted to try something special for the NBA.

&quot;I'm a risk taker artistically, but clearly this rendition didn't strike the intended tone.&quot;

Christopher Eccleston told the BBC he thought his northern accent had held him back when trying to secure Shakespearean roles on stage.

The actor star said there is a perception in the industry that &quot;people like me can't be classical&quot;.

Some social media users demanded Little Mix member Jesy Nelson delete an Instagram post of herself wearing her hair in dreadlocks.

The 26-year-old unveiled her new hairstyle on Monday evening, but some followers suggested the picture was offensive to black people.

Nelson was accused of &quot;cultural appropriation&quot; and there were calls for her to apologise.

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-43173021</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/EE34/production/_97108906_emoji_sony.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A certain gold statuette dominated the past week's news... here's the lowdown on the Oscars in case you missed them, along with some of the other stories from the past seven days.

Before the Oscars, the Emoji Movie, an animated film starring James Corden and Patrick Stewart, swept the board at Hollywood's Razzie awards, which highlight the year's worst films.

It &quot;won&quot; four Golden Raspberry titles, including worst picture, director and screenplay.
• The Emoji Movie gets thumbs down from critics

He went to the Oscars for the first time in four decades - but before he did so, Star Wars' Mark Hamill said he would rather be at home watching the ceremony in his pyjamas.

Hamill - AKA Luke Skywalker - last attended in 1978 when Star Wars: A New Hope was up for best picture.

Speaking at one of the pre-Oscar award ceremonies, the Oscar Wilde Awards, where he was being honoured, he told us it was &quot;much more fun&quot; to watch from home.
• Oscars 2018: Star Wars' Mark Hamill on why he'd rather watch from home

On Oscars night itself, The Shape of Water, a film about a woman and an amphibious creature, won top honours.

Frances McDormand won best actress for Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri, and persuaded every female nominee to stand with her in a night full of statements about inclusion.

Britain's Gary Oldman was named best actor for playing Winston Churchill in World War Two epic Darkest Hour.

The Shape of Water won the most Oscars with four, including best film.
• Oscars 2018: The Shape of Water and Frances McDormand rule
• Why is everyone talking about this outfit?

But afterwards, a man was arrested on suspicion of stealing Frances McDormand's golden statuette.

Terry Bryant was arrested for grand theft after the statuette went missing from the Governor's Ball, and later pleaded not guilty.

McDormand was reunited with Oscar later that night.

Charli Howard told BBC News about her journey from being an anorexic teenager to a campaigner for body positivity.

&quot;Models are models for a reason,&quot; the 26-year-old said. &quot;Not everyone photographs in the same way.&quot;

In her first book, Misfit - a memoir that deals openly with her problems with eating disorders and mental health - she said she struggled to fit in during her school years, which led to her suffering from anxiety and ultimately being attracted to modelling as a way to escape her surroundings.

She now lives in the US full-time, working as a model - albeit one who is classed as plus-size.
• Charli Howard: Is this really a 'plus-size' model?

Actor Matt Smith revealed he nearly turned down his career-making role as the 11th Doctor in Doctor Who.

Speaking on Desert Island Discs, Smith said he had had &quot;a wobble&quot; after being told he'd be David Tennant's successor.

&quot;I was like, 'I don't think I'm going to do it',&quot; he told BBC Radio 4. &quot;My agent said, 'You're going to do it'.&quot;

He also said he was &quot;the wrong class&quot; to play Prince Philip in The Crown, but pulled it off thanks to &quot;a great wig&quot;.
• Matt Smith 'nearly turned down Doctor Who'

The NME, which is ceasing its print edition, was a massive part of many music fans' lives.

Before rock music was reported in the mainstream press, before music television, and way before the internet, the NME was one of the only places to find out information about bands - or even, sometimes, to see what they looked like.

During its heyday, music was also the most exciting expression of a youth culture that, some of the time at least, was changing British society.

The NME was a doorway to that world.
• NME: End of an era of excess, drugs and rock 'n' roll

Jeremy Clarkson will be grilling contestants as the new host of ITV quiz show Who Wants To Be A Millionaire?

It's returning for a week this spring to celebrate its 20th anniversary.

The ex-Top Gear presenter is replacing Chris Tarrant, who said in 2014 his days as a game show host were over and that he thought the programme had &quot;run its course&quot;.

On Friday, Clarkson said: &quot;I have always loved the show and am thrilled to be involved with its rebirth.&quot;
• Jeremy Clarkson replaces Chris Tarrant on Who Wants To Be A Millionaire?

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-43350387</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Missed this week's entertainment and arts news? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/A561/production/_99573324_globes1_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It's been a busy week in the world of film, television and entertainment.

Here's a round-up of some of the biggest stories from the last seven days, just in case they passed you by.

The stars wore black at the 75th Golden Globe awards in Beverly Hills in solidarity with victims of sexual abuse and harassment.

Big Little Lies was one of the night's big winners, though for many the highlight of the evening was the rousing speech that Oprah Winfrey delivered as she won an honorary award.

Her speech immediately prompted speculation she might be considering a bid for the White House in 2020.

In London, Bafta used the announcement of its film award nominations to reveal that Joanna Lumley will host this year's ceremony.

The Absolutely Fabulous actress said it was &quot;just so unbelievably thrilling&quot; to be replacing long-time host Stephen Fry on 18 February.
• Joanna Lumley to be new Baftas host

The BBC's Carrie Gracie resigned from her post as the corporation's China editor, citing pay inequality with male colleagues.

It later emerged that Radio 4's John Humphrys and North America editor Jon Sopel had joked about the gender pay gap during an off-air chat in the Today programme studio.

In an unusual move, Hollywood star Michael Douglas spoke out to deny a claim of improper sexual conduct before it was made public.

The 73-year-old actor said he had &quot;felt the need to get ahead&quot; of the situation and dismissed the allegation as &quot;a complete fabrication&quot;.

It was announced that DJ Jo Whiley will co-present a new drivetime show with Simon Mayo as part of a BBC Radio 2 shake-up.

The overhaul will also bring an end to such long-running programmes as The Arts Show, The Organist Entertains and Listen to the Band.

Motorhead announced that Eddie Clarke, the last surviving member of the band's classic line-up, had died in hospital at the age of 67.

Clarke, whose nickname was Fast Eddie, played with Ian &quot;Lemmy&quot; Kilmister and Phil &quot;Philthy Animal&quot; Taylor between 1976 and 1982.

Norwegian singer Sigrid was named the winner of BBC Music's Sound of 2018, much to her surprise.

The 21-year-old yelped with delight when told she would be following in the footsteps of such previous winners as Ellie Goulding, Sam Smith and Adele.

The makers of Will &amp; Grace revealed that Jennifer Lopez will be making a return visit to the revived US sitcom.

The singer, actress and talent show judge previously appeared in the show, as herself, in 2004.
• J-Lo to guest star in Will &amp; Grace

Follow us on Facebook, on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts, or on Instagram at bbcnewsents. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-42666284</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-08 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Entertainment &amp; Arts news stream - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-08</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://m.files.bbci.co.uk/modules/bbc-morph-news-waf-page-meta/4.1.2/bbc_news_logo.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>And we'll keep you signed in.

I'll do it later</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/entertainment-arts-47639448</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
