<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-01 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Ronaldo, Neymar, Tevez &amp; Hagi: Why 5 February is a birthday jackpot - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/2D75/production/_110773611_5th-feb-bday_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>If you were born on 5 February and you're not a professional footballer, you could be in the wrong job.

It just so happens this particular day is a birthday jackpot in the world of football.

There are not just a couple of big football names who share this birthday, there are actually quite a few.

We'll start with easily one of the best in the business, ever...

Five-time Ballon d'Or winner Cristiano Ronaldo is celebrating his 35th birthday on Wednesday... just days after scoring his 50th goal in 70 appearances for Juventus.

We're used to his routine brilliance but his CV is still stunning to consider - 623 goals in 830 club appearances, plus five Champions Leagues, six league titles and captaining Portugal when they won Euro 2016. And that's just some of his achievements.

And there's no sign of any slowing down.

From one birthday boy to another who's arguably almost as famous...

Neymar, 28 - aka the most expensive player of all time (222m euros)

You might have seen in the news that Neymar has already celebrated his birthday.

The Paris St-Germain striker hosted a lavish white-themed party at Parisian nightclub Yoyo, on Sunday, with a host of celebrities and fellow players including Edinson Cavani, Marco Verratti, Angel di Maria, and Memphis Depay among those on the guestlist.

A day later it was announced he would miss PSG's match with Nantes because of a rib injury.

From one South American forward to another...

Boca Juniors and Argentina striker Carlos Tevez is 36 on Wednesday.

Once part of the 'golden triangle of attacking talent' at Old Trafford alongside Ronaldo and Wayne Rooney, he became the 'Welcome to Manchester' poster boy (literally) for Manchester City just two years later.

Wonder if he'll be getting a birthday card from both sides of Manchester this year?

Former Barcelona, Real Madrid and Steaua Bucharest playmaker Gheorghe Hagi is widely regarded as Romania's greatest ever player.

With 124 appearances for his country between 1983 and 2000, some might argue he deserves a national holiday in his honour.

Now owner and manager of Romanian club Viitorul Constanta, he'll always be remembered for a stunning strike for his country in their 3-1 win over Colombia at USA '94.

He might be visiting Britain this year, as his son Ianis has just joined Rangers on loan from Genk.

The Sheffield United striker is next on the list of people who share a 5 February birthday. Yes, the list is still going.

Last week, Sharp played a role in the side's transfer announcement when the Blades confirmed the club record signing of Sander Berge from Genk.

Here he is playing a game of 'Honesty Cards' with team-mate John Fleck (and he does a good impression of another team-mate).

And we're not finished there, it's 'Sven, Sven, Sven'....

The former England manager celebrates his 72nd birthday on 5 February.

Responsible for taking the Three Lions to the quarter-finals of the 2002 and 2006 World Cups and Euro 2004, as well taking charge of Benfica, Lazio, Manchester City and Leicester, to name just a few, in a 43-year coaching career.

And even now, that's not all. Inter Milan's Stefan de Vrij, ex-Arsenal and Barcelona midfielder Giovanni van Bronckhorst, former Manchester United winger Adnan Januzaj, Sheffield Wednesday's Jordan Rhodes and ex-Tottenham defender Vedran Corluka all celebrate their birthdays on 5 February.

So if you're ever asked to pick a five-a-side using people who were born on your birthday, and your birthday is today, you've probably won.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51358322</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-01 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Jurgen Klopp: Liverpool manager follows Sir Alex Ferguson and Sam Allardyce in missing matches - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Football</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/F28F/production/_110759026_alex_ferguson_steve_mcclaren_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Weddings and Caribbean holidays, Jurgen Klopp certainly isn't alone in missing matches.

Immediately after Liverpool's 2-2 FA Cup draw at Shrewsbury Town, the German said he would not be on the touchline for the replay at Anfield nine days later.

Why? Because he wants to respect the inaugural winter break that the Premier League has introduced this season.

It got us thinking about the other occasions managers have missed games. Here are some of the more quirky reasons.

Who better to start with than one of the greatest managers the game has seen?

In 2000, Fergie's eldest son Mark was getting married in South Africa. Like many devoted football fans, the family forensically studied the fixture schedule to find a free weekend.

They managed to find one on 18 November - a scheduled international break. A Cape Town wedding in November - sounds lovely, doesn't it?

Only problem being, the governing bodies decided to move all the international fixtures to midweek, meaning Manchester United had a game on the Saturday.

It wasn't just any game either. It was a Manchester derby.

Ferguson said at the time: &quot;It couldn't have been any worse for me. There's nothing I can do. Steve McClaren will be in charge.

&quot;The only consolation is that with it being a morning kick-off, I will be able to watch the game in South Africa on television.&quot;

It turned out just fine though, with David Beckham's second-minute winner enough for the Reds to earn all three points.

One of the best midfielders of all time and Barnet? The combination never did feel quite right.

The Dutch star initially made a positive impact at the north London side before they eventually dropped out of the Football League.

Davids stayed at the club, assigning himself the number one shirt (who could forget?), but was sent off three times as the Bees spent a season in mid-table.

As part of his contract, he reportedly negotiated a clause that meant he didn't have to manage a game where an overnight stay beforehand was necessary - assistant Ulrich Landvreugd would take charge instead.

Picking and choosing when you can work? It's all right if you can get it.

Everyone gets ill from time to time, and managers are no different.

In January 2013, Warnock was feeling a little bit under the weather and had to leave his assistant Mick Jones in charge for Leeds' FA Cup third-round game against Birmingham City at Elland Road.

Warnock listened along on the radio as Leeds trailed 1-0 at the break. Cue the experienced gaffer getting on the blower and instructing Jones to make two half-time changes.

Jones went one step further and put Warnock on loud speaker and allowed him to deliver the team talk.

It worked as Luciano Becchio equalised before Leeds went on to win the replay.

If you want a job doing, Neil, do it yourself.

When Bruce was appointed Sheffield Wednesday boss on 2 January, 2019, the club's statement said he wasn't joining the Owls until 1 February and everyone was a bit confused.

It turned out Bruce was in Barbados having a holiday and taking in England playing West Indies in the cricket. What cricket fan doesn't want to join the Barmy Army on a tour?

The manager was taking some time out of the game to recover from a couple of operations and he'd made a promise to his family that he'd take a break after both his parents passed away in quick succession in 2018.

&quot;I wouldn't have taken the job if Sheffield Wednesday were not aware of the situation and what I needed to have done,&quot; Bruce said.

&quot;I was completely open and honest with them when we talked about me taking the job. It is extremely disappointing that people have tried to make something negative out of it.&quot;

Football management can often be a juggling act.

Allardyce wasn't the most popular person on Merseyside with his appointment in November 2017 disappointing an expectant Everton faithful.

He opened himself up to further criticism shortly after his arrival by not travelling to their Europa League game against Apollon Limassol, so he could spend more time with his first-team squad at their training base before the Merseyside derby that weekend.

The results? A 3-0 win in Cyprus and a 1-1 draw at Anfield.

A wedding on New Year's Day? What was Gray thinking? There's always a match on.

It sounds like poor planning but the 2017 date had been set two years earlier when the Quakers were in a different division.

To make matters worse, Gray's assistant Brian Atkinson was his best man.

Gray gave the team talk before leaving coach Sean Gregan and chief scout Harry Dunn to take charge of the National League North fixture away at Halifax, which finished 2-2.

It's worth remembering that it's not the first time the German has missed a first-team fixture this season.

He also missed December's 5-0 Carabao Cup quarter-final defeat against Aston Villa because he needed to be in Qatar the following day for the Club World Cup game against Monterrey.

Will they fare better this time and take a step closer to winning the Treble?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51357228</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-01 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Hearts: Fans group to take ownership by 'end of April' - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Hearts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/CF5F/production/_110778035_15003712.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Foundation of Hearts expects to take over ownership of the Scottish Premiership club by &quot;around the end of April&quot; after confirming it has repaid the £2.5m loan owed to Ann Budge.

The fans' group will take control when Budge hands over her 75.1% stake.

Budge joined forces with the Foundation when she paid £2.5m to take Hearts out of administration in 2014.

Since then, the Foundation's continued financial backing to the club includes £3m towards a new main stand.

Last August, Budge announced she intends to stay on as Hearts' chairwoman and chief executive until at least summer 2021 to assist in the transition to fan ownership.
• Stendel says 'more to come' from Clare
• Budge to stay on as Hearts CEO</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/football/51383726</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-07-01 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Coronavirus: Chinese Grand Prix in doubt as Shanghai suspends sports events - BBC Sport</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>[]</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-07-01</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Formula 1</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/onesport/cps/624/cpsprodpb/12BCC/production/_110784767_shanghai_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Sports authorities in Shanghai have recommended the suspension of all sporting events in the city as a result of the coronavirus outbreak.

The move casts further doubt on the Chinese Grand Prix, scheduled to be held in Shanghai on 19 April.

Its viability will be discussed by Formula 1 bosses on Wednesday.

The Shanghai Sports General Association instructed sports bodies to suspend events until the threat from the virus is over.

They were told to &quot;formulate a plan for epidemic prevention to avoid internal infections&quot; and to &quot;implement a daily hygiene management system and strengthen health education to urge employees to protect themselves&quot;.

F1 was not immediately available for comment but, within the sport, there is a growing belief that the Chinese Grand Prix will have to be at least postponed from its scheduled date.

And with a record 22-race programme this season, finding a new date for it in an already crowded calendar would not be easy.

At an F1 event on Tuesday evening, unveiling the second series of the sport's collaboration with Netflix, some senior team insiders were even questioning whether the inaugural Vietnamese Grand Prix could be at risk.

That race is scheduled to be held on 5 April in the Vietnamese capital Hanoi, about 100 miles from the Chinese border.

However, there have been only 10 cases of the virus in Vietnam - two fewer than Australia and Germany - so the risk appears remote for now.

Chinese health authorities are stepping up efforts to control the spread of the virus, with approximately 18 million people in the east of the country now required to stay at home.

In Wuhan, the epicentre of the virus, 11 large public venues including sports arenas are being turned into makeshift hospitals to provide an additional 10,000 beds for the sick. Two new hospitals have been built there since the outbreak started.

The World Health Organisation has declared a global health emergency over the outbreak but said it did not yet constitute a &quot;pandemic&quot;, or the worldwide spread of a new disease.

However, the number of cases in China jumped by nearly 4,000 on Tuesday to more than 24,300, with another 65 deaths bringing the total to 490.

The virus outbreak has led to the cancellation of a number of sporting events in China, including the World Athletics Indoor Championships in Nanjing, scheduled for 13-15 March, and a race of the all-electric Formula E series in Sanya the following weekend.

Olympic organisers also say they are &quot;seriously concerned&quot; about the spread of the coronavirus and the impact it could have on the Tokyo Games in Japan this July and August.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/formula1/51388857</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
