<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-04 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Entertainment | Arts | Rare drawings given to the nation</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The works, which were privately owned, have been accepted by the government instead of inheritance tax.

The haul is worth £13m and includes letters from Henry Moore, Barbara Hepworth, Graham Greene and TS Eliot.

The drawings include Reynolds' Cupid and Psyche, worth £420,000 and a pencil drawing by Blake of Isaac Newton.

All of the work was handed over under the Acceptance in Lieu Scheme (AIL), which allows inheritance tax bills to be settled with important art works and archives to an equivalent value.

The Museums, Libraries and Archives Council says the collections of letters - like those of poet Kathleen Raine - are particularly important, as people now communicate by telephone, e-mail and text rather than letter.

Chairman Mark Wood said: &quot;In five years, 140 offers, between them worth £140m have been completed resulting in many hundreds of items going to public collections.

&quot;The range of objects is breathtaking, from an ancient Egyptian bronze to 20th Century political archives.

&quot;Schemes such as this are absolutely essential if British museums are to retain their unique international status.&quot;

Blake's drawing of Isaac Newton is the only known study for one of his most famous works and the two other drawings handed over are also viewed as important.

Other works include Still Life with Lemons and Oranges by Luis Melendez and Christopher Wood's Zebra and Parachute, which were given to settle tax bills of £1m and £245,000 respectively.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/entertainment/arts/4702305.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-04 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Entertainment | Arts | Potter book smashes sales records</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince sold 6.9 million copies in the US and more than two million copies in the UK, beating all previous Potter records.

The sixth instalment in JK Rowling series was released worldwide in the early hours of Saturday.

The fifth Potter book sold five million copies in 24 hours in the US in 2003.

British publisher Bloomsbury said UK sales for the current book were 13% higher than first day sales of predecessor, Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix.

Estimates from Nielsen BookScan revealed 2,009,574 copies of Half-Blood Prince had been sold within 24 hours of release.

US sales of the sixth Harry Potter book have generated more than $100m (£57m) in revenue across the weekend - more than the combined box office sales of hit films, Charlie and the Chocolate Factory and The Wedding Crashers.

&quot;When a book beats out movies, we're in great shape,&quot; said Scholastic's Lisa Holton.

&quot;This is a cause for celebration, not just for Scholastic, but for book lovers everywhere,&quot; she added.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/entertainment/arts/4692093.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-04 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Entertainment | Arts | Potter fans snap up latest book</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Fans queued at bookshops for Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince's release at 0001 BST on 16 July.

Author JK Rowling was at Edinburgh Castle where she read to 70 young fans who won the chance to be at the launch and interview her.

Ten million copies were expected to be sold worldwide within 24 hours, including two million in the UK.

&quot;I'm excited about this book,&quot; Rowling said as she arrived at the castle.

&quot;You get a lot of answers in this book. I can't wait for everyone to read it.&quot;

The young competition winners were led into the castle, which has been transformed into the entrance hall of Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry for the event.

As the book was launched, Rowling appeared from behind a secret panel in the wall - shrouded by smoke - to read to them.

She told reporters that it meant &quot;everything&quot; to be in her home city for the launch.

&quot;I left my daughter behind with a copy of the book. It is the first time she has had her hands on it,&quot; Rowling said.

&quot;When I left she was laughing at something, which was quite encouraging, you can imagine.&quot;

The book has gone on sale in 15 countries - including the UK, US, Brazil and the Philippines - with many bookshops holding late night openings and Potter parties.

Book retailer Waterstone's opened 140 of its stores at midnight and online retailer Amazon received more than 400,000 advance orders in the UK alone.

A total of 550,000 copies of the book were sent around the UK by Royal Mail on Saturday, employing an extra 150 vans to deliver on time.

Britain's WH Smith chain said Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince sold at a rate of 13 copies per second overnight.

It said this broke the record set by previous instalment Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix, which sold eight copies per second when published in 2003.

Matthew Perren, manager of bookseller Ottaker's main Edinburgh branch, said about 50% of copies sold were the adult version of the book - featuring the same content but with a more &quot;grown-up&quot; cover design.

Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince was the first novel to be published simultaneously in Braille, large-print and standard versions in the UK.

Blind readers often have to wait months or years for new books to be converted into Braille.

At Mount Prospect, Illinois, more than 10,000 fans participated in a range of Potter-related activities, while in New York, the world's biggest toy shop - Toys R Us in Times Square - was transformed into the Hogwarts Academy.

Other countries, including India, Australia and New Zealand also held thousands of events to coincide with the launch.

The first five Harry Potter books have sold more than 265 million copies in 200 countries and have been translated into 62 languages.

But the run-up to the new book's release - the penultimate in the series - was not problem-free.

Newsround Online reporters were able to read key parts of the book when it went briefly on display in HMV.

The store said it was an honest mistake and took the book off display as soon as it realised its error. No-one was allowed to buy the copies.

One boy in the US, Sylum Mastropaolo, was sold a copy of the book by mistake on Monday, but he and his parents returned it to the shop.

A court order was issued in Canada banning the disclosure of the story's contents after a number of the books were sold by mistake.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/entertainment/arts/4683503.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-04 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Entertainment | Arts | Suicide bomb novel adverts axed</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The bookseller told the BBC News website of its &quot;great concern&quot; at the timing of the adverts for the novel, by debut writer Chris Cleave.

A police investigation has begun after four bombs killed more than 50 people on Thursday and injured about 700.

Cleave told the BBC News website he endorsed Waterstones' decision.

He added the timing was &quot;really morbid coincidence&quot;.

The novel focuses on a woman whose son and husband die when 11 suicide bombers target Arsenal's new £357m Emirates Stadium.

Published by Chatto and Windus, it is written as an open letter from the woman to Osama Bin Laden, the leader of the al-Qaeda network.

Waterstone's said they took immediate steps to try to stop the adverts from being printed, although some have already appeared as posters on London Underground.

One has also appeared on the inside cover of The Guardian's Saturday edition of its listings magazine The Guide, describing it as a &quot;twisted powerhouse of a novel&quot;.

However the newspaper said it was unable to prevent this from being printed, adding it allowed Waterstone's to take out a free advert &quot;explaining the situation and expressing sympathy for all the victims of these attacks&quot;.

&quot;We tried our hardest to pull the adverts - we are printing apologies for any that got through,&quot; Waterstone's said.

Cleave, 32, who formerly worked on the Telegraph's website and Lastminute.com, is based in London with his wife and son.

He told the BBC News website: &quot;It's a book about love against a world that's rocked by terror.

&quot;It's about how deeply important love is in rebuilding our lives. The woman in the book is trying to make Osama feel the love she had for her dead son.

&quot;She's convinced if she can make him feel love he won't be able to continue his campaign of hate. It's a cry for end of violence.&quot;

Cleave confirmed that the rights to the book were optioned in February by Archer Street Films, which made the first Bridget Jones film and Girl With a Pearl Earring.

Film Four backed the project and Bridget Jones director Sharon Maguire was lined up to direct it.

However they were currently unavailable for comment on whether London's recent events would affect their plans.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/entertainment/arts/4666963.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-04 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Entertainment | Arts | Hundreds of nudes cross the Tyne</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-04</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Starting at a chilly 0400 BST, they posed at four locations in Newcastle and Gateshead, donning plastic white ponchos to cross the River Tyne.

New York photographer Spencer Tunick enlisted the volunteers for Naked City, his first large-scale UK installation.

It follows his nude photo shoots in New York, Barcelona, Belgium and Brazil. &quot;There is a sensual element to it, but it's not a sexual experience,&quot; he said.

Gateshead's Baltic Centre said the work would show &quot;the poetic whole resulting from individual bodies arranged in a sculptural way in an urban setting&quot;.

This would &quot;challenge traditionally-held views on nudity and privacy as well as social and political issues surrounding art in the public sphere&quot;.

Volunteers from around the world - including Australia, Belgium and Peru - signed up, among them a vicar.

They had to dodge chips and kebab remnants dropped by the previous night's revellers as they made their way around a cordoned-off section of the Newcastle and Gateshead quaysides.

Designer Cally Daniels, 34, from Edinburgh, said the event had nothing to do with exhibitionism.

She said: &quot;It was strange not to be self-conscious in that environment - normally I wouldn't even wear a skirt, I only wear trousers, so nobody even sees my legs.&quot;

University lecturer Fiona Jamieson, from Newcastle, added: &quot;The photos are of nude people, but there is nothing sexual about it.

&quot;It's about being completely natural, normal human beings, and everyone can be in the photos.&quot;

A documentary following the event - Naked City: Spencer Tunick in Newcastle Gateshead - will be broadcast on BBC Three at 2100 BST on Sunday.

Tunick, 38, carried out the world's largest nude photo shoot in Barcelona in June 2003, when 7,000 volunteers stripped for the camera.

In 1994 both he and a female model were arrested in New York when she posed nude on top of an eight-foot high replica Christmas tree in Manhattan's Rockerfeller Center.

Among those taking part in Newcastle were Tunick fans who follow him around the world.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/entertainment/arts/4689421.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
