<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Petrol and diesel car sales ban brought forward to 2035 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Science &amp; Environment</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p0827z1y.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A ban on selling new petrol, diesel or hybrid cars in the UK will be brought forward from 2040 to 2035 at the latest, under government plans.

The change comes after experts said 2040 would be too late if the UK wants to achieve its target of emitting virtually zero carbon by 2050.

Boris Johnson unveiled the policy as part of a launch event for a United Nations climate summit in November.

He said 2020 would be a &quot;defining year of climate action&quot; for the planet.

The summit, known as COP26, is being hosted in Glasgow. It is an annual UN-led gathering set up to assess progress on tackling climate change.

Sir David Attenborough said at the launch event at London's Science Museum that he was looking forward to COP26 and found it &quot;encouraging&quot; that the UK government was launching a &quot;year of climate action&quot;.

&quot;The longer we leave it... the worse it is going to get,&quot; he said.

&quot;So now is the moment. It is up to us to organise the nations of the world to do something about it.&quot;
• How will the petrol and diesel car ban work?

In a statement made ahead of the launch, Mr Johnson said the ban on selling new petrol and diesel cars would come even earlier than 2035, if possible.

Hybrid vehicles are also now being included in the proposals, which were originally announced in July 2017.

People will only be able to buy electric or hydrogen cars and vans, once the ban comes into effect.

The change in plans, which will be subject to a consultation, comes after experts warned the previous target date of 2040 would still leave old conventional cars on the roads following the clean-up date of 2050.

The Scottish government does not have the power to ban new petrol and diesel cars but has already pledged to &quot;phase out the need&quot; for them by 2032 with measures such as an expansion of the charging network for electric cars.

Mr Johnson said the 2050 pledge was necessary because the UK's &quot;historic emissions&quot; meant &quot;we have a responsibility to our planet to lead in this way&quot;.

The announcement comes as COP26's former president Claire O’Neill, who was sacked on Friday, wrote a bitter letter accusing Mr Johnson of failing to support her work.

The prime minister's official spokesperson said Downing Street had &quot;no comment&quot; to make on the letter, but thanked Mrs O'Neill for her work towards the conference.

He said her replacement would be a &quot;ministerial post&quot; with details set out &quot;in due course.&quot;

Mr Johnson did not answer the BBC's David Shukman's questions about the row.

Mr Johnson said: “Hosting COP26 is an important opportunity for the UK and nations across the globe to step up in the fight against climate change.

“As we set out our plans to hit our ambitious 2050 net zero target across this year, so we shall urge others to join us in pledging net zero emissions.

“There can be no greater responsibility than protecting our planet, and no mission that a global Britain is prouder to serve.&quot;

At the Science Museum the prime minister added that a &quot;catastrophic period of global addiction&quot; to hydrocarbons had led to the planet being &quot;swaddled in a tea cosy&quot; of carbon dioxide.

But Green Party MP Caroline Lucas said on Twitter: &quot;Carbon emissions are not 'swaddling the planet like a tea cosy'. They are behind wildfires in Australia, soaring temperature records and the broken lives of those least responsible. The PM needs to understand that - and act.&quot;
• Clean car target 'needs to be sooner'

Friends of the Earth's Mike Childs said the government was &quot;right&quot; to bring forward the ban, but that 2030 would be better than 2035.

“A new 2035 target will still leave the UK in the slow-lane of the electric car revolution and meantime allow more greenhouse gases to spew into the atmosphere,&quot; he said.

He said the government could show &quot;real leadership&quot; ahead of COP26 by reversing plans to develop &quot;climate-wrecking roads and runways&quot;.

AA president Edmund King said: &quot;Drivers support measures to clean up air quality and reduce CO2 emissions but these stretched targets are incredibly challenging.&quot;

The chief executive of the society of motor manufacturers and traders (SMMT) accused the government of &quot;moving the goalposts&quot;.

&quot;With current demand for this still expensive technology still just a fraction of sales, it's clear that accelerating an already very challenging ambition will take more than industry investment,&quot; Mike Hawes said.

He said the government's plans must safeguard industry and jobs, as well as ensuring current sales of low emission vehicles were not undermined.

Meanwhile Mrs O’Neill accused Mr Johnson of promising money and people to support her work, but failing to deliver either.

She also said he admitted to her that he &quot;doesn't really get&quot; climate change and claimed he had refused to give Scottish First Minister Nicola Sturgeon an official role at COP26.

Cabinet minister Michael Gove said Mrs O'Neill was a &quot;close friend&quot; but that he disagreed with her comments.

He told BBC Radio 5 Live Mr Johnson described his own political outlook as &quot;that of a green Tory&quot;.

Mrs O'Neill said her &quot;absolute desire for action has not been comfortable for some&quot;, adding that this was &quot;not about me&quot; or Mr Johnson - but about working towards &quot;rapid decarbonisation&quot;.

She said at COP26 the UK must &quot;absolutely double down on taking our great leadership and ambitions in this space, and really energising the world as to why this is a huge opportunity&quot;.
• How much warmer is your city?
• What is your diet's carbon footprint?
• Where we are in seven charts

What questions do you have about a ban on the sale of petrol, diesel or hybrid cars and the COP26 conference in Glasgow?

In some cases your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy.

Use this form to ask your question:</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-51366123</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>PG Tips could be sold by Unilever as cuppa goes out of fashion - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/17EF9/production/_100214089_gettyimages-636702860.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The PG Tips and Lipton tea brands could be sold by consumer goods giant Unilever because they are falling out of favour with the public.

The firm is reviewing its tea business amid a slowdown in sales as more consumers switch to the herbal variety.

It is part of efforts by chief executive Alan Jope to refocus the firm and concentrate on fewer brands.

The announcement came as Unilever announced its slowest quarterly growth in a decade.

The firm said its sales in the final three months of 2019 were up just 1.5%. However, it said it expected a stronger performance in 2020.

Unilever said it would look at &quot;all options&quot; for the tea business, including a partial or full sale.
• Are young Brits falling out of love with the cuppa?

According to research firm Kantar, the British tea industry is worth £667m a year, but over the last two years, demand for traditional black tea has fallen by 2.7%.

In contrast, demand has risen for other types of tea, with herbal teas now worth £52m and cold infusions valued at £11.2m.

On social media, BBC News readers had a mixed reaction to the news of the potential sale.

Although she's not a fan of traditional black tea, Twitter user Helen said the move was &quot;surprising&quot;.

Another, James, said the British staple's decline was &quot;probably because loads more products are available now&quot;, and suggested consumers are told more often to avoid caffeine.

Mike posted about certain teas being more costly than supermarket own-brand equivalents.

And of course there were plenty of tea-related puns about this being a &quot;traves-tea&quot;.
• PG Tips was launched in the UK in 1930 by Manchester-based firm Brooke Bond
• Its original name was Pre-Gestee, implying that it had digestive properties. Grocers and salesmen shortened it to PG. The &quot;Tips&quot; was added in the 1950s
• PG Tips spawned the longest-running ad campaign on British TV, running for almost 50 years. It featured chimps dressed as humans and voiced by actors
• Within two years of the first TV appearance of the chimps in 1956, PG Tips was the UK's top-selling tea
• Brooke Bond was acquired by Unilever in 1984, but PG Tips continued to sell well
• Last year, PG Tips was overtaken as the UK's top tea brand by Twinings, which was then in turn leapfrogged by Yorkshire Tea

Despite the question mark over Lipton's future, it is rated by Unilever as one of its seven highest-earning brands.

The others are Dove soap, Knorr food products, Persil/Omo washing powder, Rexona deodorant, Hellmann's mayonnaise and Wall's ice cream (known as Ola, Algida, Kibon and Langnese in different parts of the world), according to the company's website.

Since he took over a year ago, Mr Jope has targeted what he calls &quot;brands with purpose&quot;, saying that brands which do not have a clear social or environmental function could be eliminated from Unilever's roster.

He told reporters last year that Unilever was taking a close look at such brands as Marmite, Magnum ice cream and Pot Noodle.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51309566</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Bank of England: City watchdog looks into pound's jump - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/BDBB/production/_110717584__110702774_boe_bbc.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The City watchdog is to investigate a jump in the pound which took place shortly before the Bank of England's interest rate announcement on Thursday.

The rise has raised questions over whether the decision to hold the Bank's base rate at 0.75% had been leaked.

The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) said: &quot;We are aware of the incident and are looking into it.&quot;

In December, the Bank referred to the FCA a leak of an audio feed of sensitive information to traders.
• UK rates held as economy shows signs of picking up

The value of sterling increased about 15 seconds before midday on Thursday, when the Bank's Monetary Policy Committee (MPC) made its announcement.

It rose from $1.3023 to $1.3089 against the dollar, and saw a similar increase against the euro.

The pound continued to rise following the announcement, although this was a smaller increase.

The Bank of England confirmed that it referred this incident to the FCA.

The FCA is the markets regulator. It does not usually look into &quot;spot&quot; currency trading, where one currency is traded for another for delivery on a specific date, but it can step in in certain circumstances. For example, if it affects other regulated markets.

Andrew Sentance, former member of the Bank's MPC, told the BBC's Today programme that its nine members make a decision on the interest rate one day before it is announced.

He said: &quot;There is confidential information circulating in the Bank for quite a long time.

&quot;But it could just be something coincidental, so we shouldn't jump to conclusions,&quot; Mr Sentance added.

In December, the Bank admitted that one of its suppliers had &quot;misused&quot; an audio feed of sensitive information.

The Bank's news conferences are usually broadcast via video, but there was also an audio back-up feed in case of problems.

This audio was available between five and eight seconds before the video feed, and was leaked to hedge fund traders.

This incident was also referred to the FCA, which is still looking into the matter. It has not launched a formal investigation into it.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51323091</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>'I wasn't allowed to buy my burrito with cash' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13567/production/_110670297_duggan.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>During a recent lunch hour in New York, a sea of office workers filled the Hudson Eats food court, where staff prepared pizza, barbecue and chopped salad orders at incredible speed.

Many people had ordered ahead by app, while credit cards dominated the other purchases. And at least two establishments refused cash altogether - as Nicholas Duggan discovered to his dismay when he pulled out dollars to pay for his burrito.

&quot;I was very taken aback,&quot; said the 29-year-old construction worker. &quot;Luckily I had my card on me.&quot;

Once dominant, cash has been steadily overtaken by credit cards and a growing number of electronic and mobile options. Some countries, including the US, are even toying with plans for digital currencies.

However, a growing number of places in the US are pushing back.

In January, New York City passed a law requiring businesses to accept dollar bills. The measure followed similar steps in Philadelphia, San Francisco, and New Jersey.

Several other cities, including Washington DC, are considering similar moves and Congress recently heard comments about a country-wide proposal.

Americans used cash for an estimated 26% of transactions last year, down from 40% in 2012, according to surveys by the US central bank.

The decline is not unique to the US. In the UK, the proportion of cash payments has dropped by more than half since 2008, sinking from 60% to 28% in 2018. In Sweden, cash accounts for just 6% of transactions, down from more than 35% in 2012.
• Cash or no cash - where do you stand?

The move away from cash has been a bonanza for credit card companies and newer firms such as Square, which handle electronic transactions. Consulting firm McKinsey expects revenue in the global payments industry to grow 6% annually over the next five years, to more than $2.7 trillion.

But about 6.5% of American households do not even have bank accounts - let alone &quot;digital wallets&quot;, according to the most recent US government estimates. That compares to less than 2% in the UK, and less than 1% in Sweden.

Studies show low income households in the US are much more likely to pay by cash.

Will Buie, 41, an oral historian who lives in New Jersey, said he feels restaurants with cashless policies are &quot;putting up a class barrier&quot;.

If you have money, he said, &quot;Why be limited in terms of what you can buy?&quot;

New York City Council member Ritchie Torres, who sponsored New York's law, said his goal was to protect people without access to bank accounts or credit cards against discrimination.

Cash also works in an emergency when the power is out and preserves privacy in an era when credit card companies and others widely share shopper histories, said Jay Stanley, a privacy expert at the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), which has lobbied in favour of the new laws.

Mr Stanley says he thinks the new laws should be seen in the context of rising public concern about privacy and big tech.

&quot;I think people understand that removing cash as an option will disempower them at some level,&quot; he said. &quot;We can act on convenience minute-by-minute and yet still have a larger vision for the kind of society we want.&quot;

Businesses that have gone cashless say they're formalising what most of their customers do anyway.

They argue that making the switch official is speedier for consumers, safer for staff, and less expensive, since it eliminates the costs of laborious end-of-day cash register counting.

&quot;It's clear that the future of currency is electronic,&quot; Leo Kremer, co-founder of Dos Toros, a cashless taqueria chain, told New York City Council last year.

In his testimony, Mr Kremer said that he sympathised with the bill's intent, but it wasn't fair to hold restaurants to a different standard than the many businesses - such as e-commerce firms - for which electronic payments are the norm.

&quot;Let's pull those members of our community forward into the modern financial system, rather than pulling the business community backward with a well-intentioned, but ill-advised and burdensome regulation,&quot; he said.

Sarah Wafula, a project manager who works in Manhattan, says she hardly ever carries cash, since using cards makes it easier to track purchases. Many of her friends do the same.

&quot;But just because you prefer it, doesn't mean it should be mandatory for everyone,&quot; she says. &quot;I don't think it's fair to have people be forced to pay using one specific way.&quot;

Even before New York's law was approved, an outcry against cashless policies had already prompted some previously cash-free businesses, such as popular salad chain Sweetgreen, to reverse course.

Mr Duggan said he was prepared with card on hand for his second Hudson Yards visit. But even two weeks later, he still couldn't quite believe a business had told him his money was no good.

&quot;I thought that was pretty wild,&quot; he said. &quot;It's all currency.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51214832</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>'I lost £4,000 in a call centre scam' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/0EE1/production/_109290830_p07rfzs4.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Doug Varey was offered security software which sounded like a good deal.

It turned out to be a frightening scam that cost him thousands of pounds. He was shown images which appeared to be of Russian gangsters buying weapons with his money, and handed over thousands of pounds to make it stop.

Indian police have now raided call centres thought to be involved.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50101368</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>'I was £32,000 in debt, it consumed every moment' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/202B/production/_110753280_darren_debt_bbc.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>After taking out one loan after another, then adding credit card debt, Darren had borrowed £32,000 he could not pay back.

The 44-year-old, from Stoke-on-Trent, was juggling minimum payments and was struggling to cope.

&quot;I was not reducing the debt, it was just going up month after month, year after year,&quot; he said.

&quot;I had all the highs of spending the money, but when I was low, it was low. It consumes every thought, every moment of the day just worrying about debt. It was awful.&quot;

Credit card companies have been told to write to between one million and two million people who are struggling to cope with debt and have paid no more than their minimum repayment.
• 'My overdraft cost will nearly double - why am I being punished?'

Darren received help and is now debt-free, but many people who are in the situation he found himself in are said to be in persistent debt.

This is defined as when customers have paid more in interest and charges than they have repaid of their borrowing over an 18-month period.

Previous research by the City regulator, the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), found these cardholders were paying an average of £2.50 in interest and charges for every £1 of debt they repaid.

Under its rules, credit card lenders are supposed to negotiate a manageable and sustainable repayment method and show patience if customers cannot pay the money back.

As of March, they also have the option of cancelling cards as a last resort.

But now, the FCA is worried that providers will jump straight to a wide-ranging programme of simply stopping the cards, without proper justification.

This holds the danger of making a bad situation even worse by cutting off access to credit.

The regulator has written to the firms to express its concern that many of them could be planning a blanket suspension.

&quot;If we find firms are not offering their customers the appropriate level of help, we will not hesitate to take action,&quot; said Jonathan Davidson, from the FCA.

'If the firms do this right, we estimate that this could save customers up to £1.3bn a year in lower interest charges.'

Debt advice groups and charities said people in these kinds of debt should not panic, but nor should they ignore letters from their credit card company. Instead, they should seek help.

&quot;New rules mean that they have to tell you when your repayments have been going more towards interest, charges and fees than the amount you actually owe,&quot; said Andrew Johnson, from the Money and Pensions Service.

&quot;You might be encouraged to increase your payments but if this would cause you more financial difficulty they have to offer you help.&quot;

The service has a guide on where to find free debt advice.

How the debt racks up
• A customer who borrows £3,000 on a credit card with an APR of 19%, and only makes minimum repayments - starting at £74 per month and reducing over time - would typically take 27 years and seven months to pay it off (assuming there is no further spending on the card). The interest paid would be £4,192
• If the customer fixed their repayments at £74 per month rather than only making minimum repayments, they would pay it off in five years and two months. The interest paid would be £1,576
• If they set their monthly repayment at £108 per month, they would pay their balance off in three years. The interest paid would be £879</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51358643</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Nearly one million miss tax return deadline - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12DB3/production/_110753277_personalfinance_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Nearly one million people in the UK missed the deadline for filing their tax return, but this was an improvement on the previous year.

A total of 11.1 million did hit the deadline of the end of Friday to complete their self-assessment tax forms.

Mostly those with more than one source of income and the self-employed are required to complete returns.

Anyone with a genuine excuse can talk to the tax authority to avoid fines.

Paper returns had an earlier deadline of 31 October, but a record 10.4 million people filled in the forms electronically for which the deadline is 31 January.

Last year, just over one million people missed the 31 January cut-off. Fines can be issued immediately for late filing.

More than 700,000 people submitted their tax returns on deadline day, peaking between in the hour from 16:00 GMT, when 56,969 filed. Some 26,562 people completed their returns in the final hour before the deadline.

Angela MacDonald, director general for customer services at HM Revenue and Customs (HMRC), said: &quot;Customers who have missed the deadline should contact HMRC.

&quot;The department will treat those with genuine excuses leniently, as it focuses penalties on those who persistently fail to complete their tax returns and deliberate tax evaders. The excuse must be genuine and HMRC may ask for evidence.&quot;

Previous, failed, excuses for missing the deadline in recent years had included someone claiming they were unable to log on because they were up a mountain in Wales.

The current system means HMRC could demand a penalty of £100 for late filing during the first three months after the deadline.

After three months, additional penalties of £10 per day can be demanded, up to a maximum of £900, followed by further charges six and 12 months after the deadline.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51358642</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>This is what a million pound coin looks like - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12498/production/_110540947_p080l6p5.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>An extremely rare Edward VIII sovereign has been sold for £1m, the most expensive UK coin ever sold. Only six of the 22-carat gold coins were ever made, and a quirk of the King's vanity makes them unique.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51143600</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>My Money: 'I made it through the day without spending a dollar' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1162C/production/_110421217_chelsea2.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>My Money is a new series looking at how people spend their money - and the sometimes tough decisions they have to make. Here, Chelsea Thomas from California records her spending over a week and shares tips for saving.

We're looking for more people to share what they spend their money on. If you're interested, please email my.money@bbc.co.uk or get in touch via our My Money (World) Facebook group, or if you live in the UK, please join our My Money (UK) Facebook group and we'll aim to contact you.

Chelsea is 32 years old and lives in Los Angeles. She is the practice manager and patient coordinator of a plastic surgery practice in Beverly Hills. Her interests include participating in animal rescue fundraiser events, and researching new trends in the health and beauty industry. She also likes doing activities with her dog Roscoe, like hiking or dog fashion photo shoots.

She recently went head-to-head with another blogger, Sunneva María Svövudóttir from Reykjavik in Iceland, on World Business Report - have a listen to hear Chelsea talk about what she spent her money on this week.

I woke up at 6:45 today to get ready for work. I am already in a good mood because I normally have to wake up at 6:00 for work, but due to the holidays my daily rush-hour commute to work is cut down by 45 minutes. I work on the other side of LA, so on a normal day it takes me about one hour and 15 minutes to make the 10-mile journey to my job.

However, today the city is almost empty so it takes me under 30 minutes to arrive at work. I would love to live closer to my job, but my crippling student loan debt doesn't allow me the luxury of living near my office, which happens to be situated in one of the most expensive neighbourhoods in the United States.

I arrive a bit early today, so I walk across the street to a coffee shop and get an iced coffee for $3.78 (£2.90). I bring my lunch with me to work and don't spend anything else the rest of my work day.

On my way home from work I need to stop and charge my car since it is fully electric. I charge at a public charger for one hour to get 20 miles which costs me $1.38.

When I get home my boyfriend and I celebrate the fact that neither one of us has to work the next two days by forgetting about our healthy food-only diet and ordering a bunch of pizza. We alternate who pays for meals and today is my turn - $21.75.

After eating enough pizza to make even yoga pants feel too tight, I decide I cannot do anything other than lay on the couch and watch Netflix all night. We make it half way through an hour-long episode, before I pass out asleep for the evening.

Today is New Year's Eve and I have the entire day off as well as tomorrow - woohoo! My boyfriend and I sleep in and have a light breakfast at home since we both still feel full from our pizza party last night.

We are planning on celebrating New Year's at a friend's house who is throwing a small party. We decide to go to Costco to pick up a bottle of alcohol and hostess gift since they typically have the best prices on items in my area. We decide on a bottle of Japanese whisky $32.84 and a box of liquor filled chocolates $18.60. We also get a bag of dog food while we are there since we are running low $43.57.

We decide to eat leftovers at home versus grabbing a bite somewhere since we are now running behind.

At 8:45 we leave to our friend's party. We call an Uber car and the 24-minute drive to her house costs $26.85. We spend the next few hours drinking cocktails, eating appetizers, and listening to music with friends. At around 1:30 we decide to call it a night and head home. We check the Uber app and the cost to call a car home has now skyrocketed to over $100! There has been a fare surge due to the holiday so we decide to hang out longer and wait for prices to drop.

At around 2:15 we check transportation prices again and they have been cut in half, still not what we want to spend but we are tired and eager to get home at this point. We call the car and spend $50.45 to get back home. Spending the car ride dreaming of getting into warm pyjamas and out of my uncomfortable heels and dress justifies the awful price for just a moment.

My boyfriend and I split the cost of everything 50/50 today so I'm fine with what I've spent, considering it's a holiday.

Today is New Year's day! A day where it is socially acceptable to lounge around and practice the art of doing positively nothing. I am off work today and because we stayed out so late last night I end up waking up after 11:00am - oops, half the day is already gone.

After complaining I am hungry for 30 minutes but not doing anything about it, my boyfriend agrees to go out and track us down some mid-afternoon breakfast bagels. He returns 30 minutes later with breakfast as well as additional food for dinner later. Both my stomach and my wallet are very happy.

After we eat we spend the rest of the day uneventfully playing video games and watching movies on Netflix, and congratulating ourselves on being adults and not getting drunk last night just because it's a holiday.

I remember my college days of spending an entire paycheck on dresses and drinking just because it was a holiday. Thanks but no thanks - welcome to adulthood. Normally my student loans come out of my account on the first of each month, but the banks are closed today so the withdrawal will not happen until tomorrow. I somehow made it through the day without spending a dollar - a New Year's miracle!

Back to work today. I wake up a little late this morning and struggle to get out of bed. My sleeping schedule is messed up from my days off. I eventually get out of bed and realize I wasted so much time I now don't have time to make breakfast.

I grab a protein bar and rush out the door. I get to work and realise I forget to bring my lunch. Ugh, I hate when this happens. When lunch time rolls around I walk down the street from my work to a local juice shop and get an acai bowl $10.90.

Today my student loans also come out of my account $859. I put a big portion of any extra income I get during the year towards my student loans so I can hopefully get them paid off quicker and not have the interest pile up. Sometimes seeing my friends spend their extra income on vacations and travelling I can feel down, thinking that this mountainous black hole of debt will never go away.

However, for the most part I always try to remain positive about the situation. I should feel grateful that I have a job that pays me enough to always pay my bills on time, something that hundreds of thousands of people in America who are plagued with monumental student loan debt struggle to do while also carrying the burden of keeping their families afloat. Thinking of this today is a great reminder to always be thankful and grateful for what I have.

I wake up early enough today to do a quick meditation. I've been trying to meditate more and more the last few months. I would love to join a local class but the costs in my area are outrageous for something I can do at home.

I pack some berries and chia seed pudding I made for lunch and make my way to work.

At lunchtime I notice I have a notification on my phone to put in my produce delivery order today. I subscribe to a wonderful food delivery service that focuses on the elimination of food waste. Weekly or bi-weekly I log onto my account to shop a list of &quot;imperfect&quot; food items that are perfectly fine but cannot be sold in stores due to being too small, an odd shape, or there is simply a surplus of an item.

We are able to buy an abundance of fresh organic fruits and vegetables this way at highly discounted prices. I have saved so much money using this service over the past few years since I am a vegetarian and my main food staples are fruits and vegetables. The order I place today comes to $16.82 for 10lbs of organic produce. I don't order too much because I still have a little left from last week's order.

My car lease payment has also been automatically deducted from my account today $146.59 as well as my car insurance $142.04 and home insurance $32.01.

On my way home from work I stop and pick up a caprese sandwich and green salad for dinner $13.14. I get home and catch up on some Real Housewives shows since my boyfriend is working late tonight.

Even though it's Saturday I wake up early. I listen to a podcast and clean up the house a bit while simultaneously drinking coffee and a protein shake. While I am cleaning I notice some stains on the walls that are not coming off. I actually noticed it a few weeks ago but now feel as though they are getting worse and it's driving me crazy!

I don't have any plans today so I make the impromptu decision to paint the walls. My boyfriend tries to talk me out of it saying we should have it done professionally. I briefly look online and see prices of several hundred dollars to have a room painted. No thanks, I'll figure it out.

I drive 10 minutes to a home improvement store and spend an hour picking out brushes and other accessories, and deciding between egg white and ultra pure white. Before admitting to myself I have no idea what I'm doing, and putting everything back in exchange for a pre-assembled painting kit, and googling the best brand of white wall paint to buy. I make it out of the store with probably not everything I need at $83.08.

I rush home and down some leftovers so I can quickly begin painting. Before I know it it's dark out and time to eat dinner. I am only half way done with my painting project so my boyfriend offers to go pick us up some food for dinner (anything to get out of the possibility of painting I suppose).

After eating I spend the rest of the evening painting, scrubbing spilled paint... and thinking about how I should have just paid a professional. However, with the cheap cost of DIY plus spitting the cost of supplies with my boyfriend it was ultimately worth it.

After spending the entire day inside yesterday painting I wake up feeling like I immediately need to get out of the house. I throw on some clothes and take my dog for a walk to a nearby juice shop. I get a green juice $8.75 and slice of zucchini bread $2.75 for breakfast and a quinoa veggie bowl to go for lunch later $11.99.

After breakfast we walk past a nearby pet shop. My only two money vices in life - makeup/skincare and dog anything. After a three-hour shopper's blackout in Sephora six months ago I actually forbid myself from buying any cosmetics until I run out of what I currently have. Dog stuff is still fair game since he's my one and only child.

I find a bag of treats, a chew toy, lavender-scented waste bags, senior vitamins and a mommy's best buddy t-shirt all on sale totalling $33.95. On the way out I also give a $15 donation to a local dog and cat fundraising team outside.

After lunch I meet a friend for coffee $4.85 and charge my car at a nearby public charger for an hour and 10 minutes while I'm there $1.17.

This evening my boyfriend and I go to a friend's house for dinner, who insists we do not bring anything at all along with us. Afterwards we head home to relax and get ourselves ready for the week ahead.

How does Chelsea feel about her week?

I spent a little spontaneously this week which is alright because of a handful of monetary gifts I received from family members for the holidays. A lot of my spending this week also went towards food and a few of my monthly bills.

Overall I am fine with my spending this week when looking it over. I try to balance responsible spending while I'm working to pay off my student loans while also allowing myself occasional frivolous spending without guilt or thinking about it since I work hard for my money!</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51021014</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Tourists being scammed for thousands in 'three cup trick' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>London</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/6032/production/_108262642_p07k7q82.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Undercover filming by BBC London has exposed a gambling scam that has got out of control on Westminster Bridge.

Secret filming by BBC reporter Gareth Furby shows as many as 14 gangs at one time occupying the bridge and trying to scam tourists out of thousands of pounds using an age-old &quot;three cup trick&quot;.

Unsuspecting tourists part with £50 a time with the false hope they can double their money.

The reality is, of course, they can never win.

Westminster council is now calling on the Metropolitan Police to launch a special operation to drive the gangs away.

The Met says it has been taking action, with 30 people arrested this year so far.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-49300219</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Wonga compensation 'an insult' to borrowers - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/D8F4/production/_110704555_61e97233-2e66-47c6-91c5-1a0d31d781f3.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>People who were mis-sold loans by the payday lender Wonga have been told that they will receive just 4.3% of the compensation they are owed.

Administrators have begun informing around 400,000 claimants by letter, some of whom have reacted in dismay.

Before its collapse, Wonga was vilified for its high-cost, short-term loans, seen as targeting the vulnerable.

One ex-customer told BBC News it was &quot;an insult&quot; to borrowers.

&quot;Trust has really been damaged by this company, and the amount of compensation is an insult to the people that have been hurt by this,&quot; said Jo from Basingstoke.

After Jo lost her full-time job and started in a role with fewer hours, she took out a series of loans with Wonga between 2010 and 2014 to make ends meet.

&quot;My partner also lost his job, so things were really difficult,&quot; she says.

&quot;We were stuck in a cycle where we were getting a payday loan out every month for between £50 and £100. It was really dangerous.&quot;

Wonga, which collapsed in 2018, was once the UK's biggest payday lender but its practices attracted intense scrutiny.

In 2014, the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) found it had lent money to many who would never be able to repay, prompting a crackdown on the sector.

Administrators have since received 380,000 eligible claims against the business worth £460m in total - an average of £1,200 a claim.

But while claimants were warned they would get &quot;significantly less&quot; than full compensation, few expected to get so little.

Jo says she was due a total of £208 in compensation, but was told she would only receive £8.

&quot;It's more effort than it's worth to be honest. I've changed my bank account since, and sending them all the forms and details that I would have to would take ages.

&quot;I'm also not sure if I can trust them with my details. People have been burnt,&quot; she says.

Sara Williams, who runs Debt Camel, said former customers had been &quot;badly let down&quot; by regulators.

&quot;Wonga ignored the regulator's rules about checking the affordability of loans and they were allowed to get away with this for 10 years.

&quot;Now customers are being let down again because they are not getting the compensation they deserve from the regulator.&quot;

Hundreds of ex-customers have vented their anger on the Debt Camel site. One said: &quot;We have all been exploited, and we all know how much we have been exploited by.

&quot;In my case £6,500, of which I'll receive less than £300.&quot;

Ms Williams said borrowers were not covered by the Financial Services Compensation Scheme, which is overseen by the FCA,

The scheme covers products such as payment protection insurance (PPI), fully reimbursing anyone who has been mis-sold to, but does not extend to payday loans.

&quot;Borrowers from many payday lenders have been unable to get proper compensation after the lender has had to close,&quot; Ms Williams said.

&quot;The FCA needs to rethink this and provide a safety net for people who were mis-sold unaffordable loans.&quot;

Wonga's administrators said claims should be paid within the next four weeks, later than the 20 January date initially promised.

They also said loans being refunded would be removed from people's credit records within the next six weeks - likely to be a relief to many.

Some people still owe money to Wonga but it is unclear what will happen to their balances.

Ms Williams said administrators were no longer taking payments and had said before that they were not likely to sell the loans to a debt collector.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51303908</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>UK interest rates held as economy shows signs of picking up - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/BA68/production/_110702774_boe_bbc.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Bank of England has held interest rates at 0.75% amid early signs of a pick-up in the UK and global economies.

In Mark Carney's final interest rate meeting as governor, the Bank's Monetary Policy Committee (MPC) voted 7-2 to keep rates unchanged.

Recent weak economic data had led to speculation rates could be cut, but Mr Carney said &quot;the most recent signs are that global growth has stabilised&quot;.

But the MPC said it was poised to cut interest rates if necessary.

Fewer companies in the UK are worried about Brexit, Mr Carney told a news conference following the rate decision. He added that survey data suggested UK growth will improve.

But he said: &quot;To be clear these are still early days and it's less of a case of so far so good than so far good enough,&quot; he said, again referring to the UK economy.

&quot;Although the global economy looks to be recovering, caution is warranted,&quot; he said. &quot;Evidence of a pick-up in growth is not yet widespread.&quot;

He said the coronavirus outbreak was a &quot;reminder of the need to be vigilant&quot; when it comes to bumps in economic growth around the world.

The nine MPC members have been split on rates since November.

Lower interest rates are good news for borrowers and bad news for savers because High Street banks use the Bank of England base rate as a reference point for many mortgages and savings accounts.

In a closely-watched decision, policymakers said they would monitor whether a recent improvement in business sentiment would lead to stronger economic growth.

The MPC said it stood ready to cut rates if there were signs that growth would remain subdued.

&quot;Policy might need to reinforce the expected recovery in UK GDP growth, should the more positive signals from recent indicators of global and domestic activity not be sustained,&quot; the MPC said.

Two members, Jonathan Haskel and Michael Saunders, argued that past business surveys of economic growth had not been reliable.

They continued to call for an immediate interest rate cut to 0.5%.

The Bank's latest economic estimates suggest the economy did not grow at all in the final three months of last year.

Weaker growth at the turn of the year is also expected to drag overall economic growth down to just 0.75% in 2020. This is down from a projection of 1.25% last November.

The UK economy is expected to expand by 0.2% in the first three months of this year.

The Bank said a trade deal between the US and China that lowers some tariffs would provide a boost to the global economy.

An expected rise in spending by the government in the March Budget could provide a further boost to growth, policymakers said.

Ruth Gregory, senior UK economist at Capital Economics, said she also expected stronger growth ahead.

&quot;Admittedly, the MPC left the door open to a rate cut in the coming months, but with the economy turning a corner and a big fiscal stimulus approaching, we suspect the next move in interest rates will be up not down, albeit not until next year.&quot;

The Bank said Brexit-related uncertainty had &quot;weighed on investment&quot; over the past few years.

Policymakers said companies' Brexit plans had diverted money towards preparing for the UK's departure from the EU that would otherwise be invested elsewhere.

This has reduced the UK's long-term growth prospects by limiting the space in which the economy can grow without the risk of overheating.

This would force the Bank to raise interest rates, which would in turn slow the UK economy.

Policymakers now believe the UK's potential growth has been reduced to 1.1%. This is down from 2.9% before the financial crisis and 1.6% over most of the past decade.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51309256</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>'Obscene' 18-month delay for DWP complaints - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13760/production/_110721797_parentsfighting.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>People with the most serious complaints about the Department for Work and Pensions (DWP) have to wait 18 months before their cases are investigated.

BBC Radio 4's Money Box has also learnt that nearly two-thirds of investigations miss their target of being cleared within 20 weeks.

One man in dispute with one of its agencies called the delay &quot;obscene&quot;.

The DWP said it understands &quot;the impact that waiting for an investigation can have on people and their families.&quot;

The most common complaints to the DWP include things like a failure to follow proper procedures, excessive delays and poor customer service.

Alan, who did not want his real name used, said he faces nearly a four-year wait in total before his case is resolved.

He first complained to the government-run Child Maintenance Service (CMS) in November 2017. He says it took thousands of pounds of a redundancy payment directly from his bank account.

The dispute has made his existing mental health problems worse and left him &quot;flatlining&quot;, he says.

He added that he is unable to motivate himself to work and is &quot;getting poorer by the day&quot;.

After 18 months, Alan's case still was not resolved. He was then given permission to take his complaint to the Independent Case Examiner (ICE).

ICE acts as a free, independent referee for people with complaints about the DWP - and its contracted services, which include things like the CMS, pension payments and disability benefits.

Alan was told his complaint had been accepted, but that it would be more than a year before someone was assigned to investigate it.

Even after that, Money Box has seen figures which suggest two-thirds of cases take longer than the 20-week target, while half of them take six months or even longer.

That means that hundreds of people face a wait of more than two years for their complaints to be resolved once they have been accepted by ICE.

He said: &quot;I am just one of thousands of people in this situation.

&quot;I think the delay in the complaints procedure is atrocious. It's symptomatic of a department that doesn't take its obligations to people it is dealing with seriously.&quot;

He added: &quot;It's a damning indictment of the modus operandi of the Department for Work and Pensions.&quot;

ICE only looks at the &quot;most serious complaints&quot; about services offered by the DWP.

That includes organisations such as Jobcentre Plus, the Pension Service, the Disability and Carers Service and Pension Wise, as well as the CMS.

ICE will only consider people's complaints if they have finished the complaints procedure with the original agency or organisation.

It then decides whether or not it will &quot;accept&quot; someone's complaint.

If it does, BBC Radio 4's Money Box programme has learnt through a freedom of information request there is a delay of about 18 months before it is opened.

Once it is opened, most cases require a full investigation with a 20-week target.

Money Box has seen figures which suggest that nearly two-thirds of cases miss this deadline.

The Department for Work and Pensions said in a statement: &quot;We want to make sure people can get the support they are entitled to if they have been treated unfairly, and understand the impact that waiting for an investigation can have on people and their families.

&quot;We are hiring and training new staff as quickly as we can, and cleared more complaints last year than in 2017-18.

&quot;The vast majority of complainants are satisfied with the service they receive.&quot;

You can hear more from BBC Radio 4's Money Box programme by listening here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51326471</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Customers 'overpaid for electricity for years' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/14BCB/production/_110693948_bzin1mmu.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Customers have overpaid on electricity for seven years because the regulator has made targets too easy for network operators, a watchdog has said.

The National Audit Office (NAO) said regulator Ofgem allowed the companies which run the wires and pylons to make bigger profits than they needed to.

This £800m of excess returns meant bills have been creeping up by £1.60 more than necessary per year.

Ofgem said the excess could have hit £13 without action.

Gillian Guy, from Citizens Advice, said the report was proof that &quot;energy networks have enjoyed a major windfall at the expense of consumers&quot;.

What happened when rules were set?

The privatised electricity supply business is divided into the supply companies - the ones customers deal with, which buy and sell the power - and companies which manage the delivery of electricity from power stations to our homes.

These transmission and distribution companies, which include the National Grid, are in the private sector but there is an upper limit to the return they are allowed to make, set by Ofgem.

Current rules, known as RIIO-1, give electricity networks an allowance to run and invest in their systems. If they spend less they can keep half of the savings and return half to customers.

During the full eight years of RIIO-1, due to end in 2021, the distribution networks expect to underspend by 3% on average. One company, National Grid Energy Transmission, forecasts a 22% underspend. Only one business will overspend its allowance.

The National Audit Office accuses Ofgem of being too fearful, when setting the controls, that the companies might fail and have to be rescued.

As a result, the NAO said, energy network investors have seen returns of 9%, compared with between 5% and 6% at other UK companies.

Ofgem has already indicated it will clamp down on generous investor returns as it plans for RIIO-2, the next round of price controls.

&quot;Our tough new round of price controls will lower returns to save consumers money, whilst pushing companies to go further on decarbonisation and ensuring we retain one of the world's most reliable energy systems,&quot; said Akshay Kaul, Ofgem's director of network price controls.

Gas and electricity networks have been heavily regulated since they started to be privatised in the late 1980s.

The supply business has benefited from a huge proliferation in competition, but Ofgem has been unable to encourage the same explosion in networks because they are natural monopolies.

Citizens Advice has campaigned for changes to network returns.

Ms Guy said: &quot;Ofgem has made good progress towards a tougher settlement next time around. The regulator must hold its nerve, resist the efforts of networks to water down its proposals and deliver a price control that works for consumers,&quot; she said.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51298733</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Washing machine owners must re-check for fire risk - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10AEB/production/_110213386_cx31r67z.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Owners of Hotpoint and Indesit washing machines may have to check again to see whether their model is on a recall list of fire-prone appliances.

An extra three models have been added to the host of machines that may catch fire owing to an overheating door mechanism.

It means that 5,000 more machines are being added to the 519,000 the company is trying to locate.

The company said adding to the list was common in the recall process.

What is the problem?

About 20% of the Hotpoint and Indesit washing machines sold since 2014 are affected by a safety fault and need to be recalled, a process that started earlier this month.

The company says it has identified 165,000 of the problem appliances so far and 70,000 have already been replaced or repaired. It has received calls or had contact from two million people.

Seventy-nine fires are thought to have been caused by an overheating door locking system, a fault which develops over time, according to Whirlpool, which owns the brands.

Whirlpool has set up a model checker online. Owners of Hotpoint and Indesit washing machines bought since October 2014 will need to enter the model and serial number of their appliance - found inside the door or on the back - to see if it is one of those affected.

Those who have previously checked, and been given the all clear, may need to check again. The company said it could contact 60% of those with the newly affected models, but customers should check.

There is also a free helpline, open every day, available on 0800 316 1442.

Slots for a modification or replacement machine are available straight away.

The model numbers of the appliances which have been added to the list, three weeks after the initial recall launch, owing to further analysis by the company.

They are WMAQC641PUK, WMAQG741PUK, and WMFG741GUK.

Jeff Noel, vice president of Whirlpool, said: &quot;With more than 30% of the affected products now accounted for, this campaign has already surpassed the UK average for a product recall campaign by a significant margin.

&quot;While this is good progress, we know there is still work to do. That's why we are working seven days a week to look after our customers and running a widespread campaign to raise awareness.

&quot;We are deeply sorry to our customers for the inconvenience this recall may cause but we are taking action because it is the right thing to do for people's safety. We will do whatever it takes to put the situation right.&quot;

The company has already been dealing with the recall of more than five million tumble dryers, sold over 11 years, which were found to be a fire danger.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51298725</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Would Greta Thunberg's generation play with these toys? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13666/production/_110626497_buildandgrow.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Choose one word to describe toy trends in recent years and it would be &quot;collectable&quot;.

Every box and packet, from pocket money mini-figures to expensive construction sets, has been urging children and their parents to complete the set. In other words, buy more and more.

Now that craze to pile up the plastic seems to have peaked, and there is a new word on toy-sellers' lips - sustainability.

They're responding to a generation of children who have gone on school strikes, following the lead of teenage campaigner Greta Thunberg, and are turning on their parents for failing to protect the planet.

What was clear from the Toy Fair, the annual jamboree in Olympia London which was held last week, is that small toymakers are leading the way.

Dan Robson came up with the idea of a 3D puzzle garden, while studying design at Northumbria University. The eco-friendly models scenes - such as a windmill or a volcano - are assembled from pop-out boards. Children then plant seeds to grow cress, pea, kale, rocket, lettuce or watercress in the little container of earth.
• Plastic toys: Is it time we cut back?

&quot;Our aim is to encourage children to grow their own, while educating them on how to grow and why it's important,&quot; says 32-years-old Mr Robson, who runs his Build and Grow business from in Blaydon, near Gateshead.

He considered what materials to use very carefully. The £15 play sets and packaging are made from recycled card and are printed using vegetable ink. The plastic container is recyclable, and even the soil is locally sourced.

Parents and children, he says, not only want a fun toy, but a responsible one too.

&quot;People are very aware now of their impact on the environment and this is driving a change in consumer habits,&quot; he says.

Such eco-innovation is not unique at the Toy Fair. On a nearby stall is another small business - Paper Engine - which has created build-your-own gadgets such as a telescope, a microscope, and a paper aeroplane launcher.

The business is a spin-off from the designers of pop-up books, which has now moved into the crowded creative toy sector.

The selling point is clear. Apart from the lens, the telescope is made entirely from paper and card.

The cardboard box in which it is delivered is self-contained and free from shrink wrap. The only issue that tests its environmental credentials is that, in order to keep costs down, the printing is done in China.

While the backlash against plastic packaging of toys has been vociferous for some time, the actual products themselves are now increasingly under the microscope.

&quot;We've been talking about sustainability for 10 years. It is not new. We've moved on but we are still not perfect,&quot; says Natasha Crookes, from the British Toy and Hobby Association.

The association, which represents manufacturers, has been working hard to make toys more durable, she says, allowing toys to be handed on to friends and family as children grow out of them.

Some 80% of parents donate used toys, she says, and the association tracks marine litter to ensure toys are not continually washed up. The results, she says, are encouraging. Buckets and spades and other litter left by families visiting the seaside are more of a problem than dumped plastic toys, she says.

Yet, gifts in children's stockings and presents under the Christmas tree last month were still primarily plastic, much of which ultimately ends up in landfill after a toy loses is lustre?

Parents are cutting back. Consumer awareness is driven by the children themselves, says Ms Crookes.

However, many manufacturers face regulatory problems if they try to go further, broadly for two reasons.

The first are the strict controls on the chemical content of toys. Regulations are tight on what a toy can be made of, to ensure it does not harm the children who play with it.

Put simply, manufacturers cannot use any old recycled plastic if they do not know exactly what is in it. So the recycled material needs to be clearly and cleanly sourced.

Secondly, in order to recycle toys efficiently just like any other product, they would need to be easily pulled apart. Again, this goes against regulations. Toy safety rules state toys, particularly for young children, should not be easily dismantled and become a choking hazard.

These are hurdles for big manufacturers, but they are not impossible to clear.

Italian-based toymaker Clementoni has a range supplying children from birth to 12 and over, and is making a statement.

It is aiming for its infant range to come from recycled plastic, certified and manufactured on site in Recanati. A range of puzzles, including packaging, made from recyclable materials has also been designed and will go on sale from March.

&quot;We are making an offer to the conscious consumer,&quot; says UK country manager Shahbaz Khan. &quot;But we accept it is only a first step.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51221865</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>'My overdraft cost will nearly double - why am I being punished?' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/5F23/production/_110755342_claire_griffiths_976.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>&quot;My overdraft cost will nearly double - why am I being punished?&quot;, asks Claire Griffiths from Northamptonshire.

From April, she predicts the cost of her £2,250 overdraft will jump from around £43 a month to over £74.

&quot;The increase is worrying,&quot; she says.

Ms Griffiths has had an arranged overdraft - agreed with her bank, NatWest - ever since she was a student 10 years ago.

NatWest is just one of several of the major banks to have recently announced much higher interest rates for overdrafts, in some cases twice as much as they were charging before.

Why have these changes happened?

An investigation by financial regulator the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) found that banks were making £2.4bn a year from overdrafts.

The customers who suffered most were the 14 million who slipped into unarranged overdrafts, without getting authorisation in advance from the bank, and paid much higher charges.

HSBC has been charging them £5 a day, Santander £6, NatWest £8 and TSB has been levying up to £10 a day. There can be other fees on top.

The FCA decided these charges were too high and too confusing so it banned treating people with unarranged overdrafts differently and it banned daily or monthly charges. The new rules will come into force from April this year.

But it means banks are lumping all their charges into the interest rate, which will commonly be around 40%, exposing just how expensive an overdraft can be.

What are the banks charging?
• Nationwide said it would bring in an interest rate of 39.9% to replace a daily fee of 50p for arranged overdrafts.
• HSBC said its interest rate would double from 19.9% to 39.9%.
• Santander's will also be 39.9%
• Barclays is not far behind with 35%.

To put those interest rates into context, the average quoted rate for credit card borrowing is just over 20%, according to the Bank of England.

Banks say only a minority of customers will actually lose out.

Keir from Cambridge has an unarranged overdraft, one he slipped into without permission from the bank. It cost him £360 last year.

&quot;It felt so demoralising when I saved some money to pay off a bit of the debt, and then all it covers is the monthly fees and interest,&quot; Keir says.

&quot;It was difficult to stop myself from going deeper into the red.&quot;

Keir has wrestled with his overdraft and managed to get it down by saving each week, but he is frightened by the jump in interest rates.

He will benefit from the removal of daily charges, something he says is good in principle.

However, Keir feels he was manipulated by his bank, which offered to increase his borrowing when he was vulnerable and could not afford to take on any more debt.

It is still open to banks to charge vulnerable customers more by applying a higher interest rate to their borrowing.

For instance, while Lloyds will charge most customers 39.9% but people with a bad credit record will pay 49.9%.

The fast-growing digital bank, Monzo, will apply rates of 19%, 29% or 39% according to your credit score. One of its rivals, Starling Bank, will charge 15%, 25% or 35%.

Who will the winners and losers be?

The fact that leading banks are charging roughly the same has become an embarrassment for the FCA.

So much so that it has asked them to explain why they have set &quot;very similar prices&quot;.

But the big question is how all this works out for the public, particularly for the most financially vulnerable families who have paid the steepest charges up until now.

Some customers, like Ms Griffiths, will lose out. For the most part they are people who borrow more and borrow for longer.

For instance, £500 borrowed for 30 days will cost an extra £5.77 from HSBC and £6.82 from Nationwide.

However, the FCA says that seven out of 10 overdraft users will either see no change in what they pay or will be better off.

Crucially, no one who goes into the red without permission should pay more and for some the gains will be big.

An unarranged overdraft of £100 for a week will be £52 cheaper with Santander and £55.35 cheaper with NatWest.

So in future how much you pay for an overdraft could still depend on how much financial trouble you happen to be in.

Ms Griffith's bank, NatWest, told us the majority of its customers would pay the same or be better off, but that it would be writing to customers who currently have high overdraft balances and will pay higher fees.

A NatWest spokesperson said: &quot;We've been working hard to make sure we have the right support in place.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51329091</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Syrians in Brazil: 'I am not a millionaire, but I will be' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>World</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12A01/production/_109298267_p07rjdpw.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Eyad and Joanna both left Syria to start a new life in Brazil.

They faced many challenges before setting up their businesses. Eyad is now a celebrity chef while Joanna works with other refugees to set up marketplaces and food events.

If their business plans work, the two young Syrians hope to become millionaires in a few years.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-50037334</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>Memorial benches: 'A quiet reminder of people gone, but not forgotten' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/9BF9/production/_109992993_dannybench4.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Veterans, friends and family come to sit on a bench in Bognor Regis to pause, reflect and remember serviceman Danny Johnston.

A simple plaque tells of his premature death, at the age of just 35.

The rest of the Hotham Park seat is far from simple. Unique carvings remind them of Danny's service - for the Princess of Wales's Royal Regiment and the Special Reconnaissance Regiment - and of his love for the music of The Rolling Stones and The Who.

&quot;We get comfort from it being here. Knowing he is not forgotten means so much to me,&quot; says his grieving mum Viv Johnston.

&quot;I hope this bench will be here for a long time after I am, and I hope that people will remember Danny, because he was a truly marvellous person.&quot;

Its legacy is important to Viv. It is a place for others who, like her first-born son, struggle to return to civilian life after serving for years in some of the most dangerous parts of the world. Danny had signed up at the age of 16 to be part of the regiment, nicknamed &quot;The Tigers&quot;, and later as part of the special forces in Iraq and Afghanistan. He took his own life in May 2018.

&quot;Local veterans come here when they are feeling down. It is a peaceful place to sit and think,&quot; she says, to the soundtrack of birdsong from the trees behind her.

The bench is very unusual. Not many park benches will feature the lead characters of Danny's favourite film, The Blues Brothers. The story of its commission, however, is typical of the many thousands of memorial benches across the UK.

His brother-in-law Wesley had encouraged Danny's friends to club together for a lasting memorial of his life. The bench was revealed to Viv on the anniversary of his death.

She hopes it stays in Hotham Park for many years, pointing out there is no option to take it home when you live in a first-floor flat with no garden.

For other grieving families, the installation of a dedicated bench may only prove to be a temporary monument. Individual councils set their own rules for benches and other memorials to loved ones. Many only guarantee their position and maintenance for 10 years after which they may be taken away, replaced, or owners asked to collect them.

Some local authorities have strict guidelines on what can and cannot be written on commemoration plaques. Council websites usually have a page explaining their specific approach.

Fundraising websites are awash with appeals for money to erect benches in a loved one's memory, but the cost can sometimes be prohibitive.

At the top end, at Birmingham's Botanical Gardens, a bench for 10 years with a plaque displaying up to 10 words costs £2,500. Some councils with stretched budgets and high demand for this service have doubled prices, or closed applications for popular spots.

These benches have critics, particularly in popular coastal sites. The head of the National Trust in Jersey sparked a furious debate in 2018 when he said it was crucial that beauty spots did not turn into graveyards with the proliferation of dedicated seats.

They also have enthusiastic supporters, using the place to sit and talk to tackle loneliness or as a way to highlight a particular charity or cause.

A few, like open technology enthusiasts Terence and Liz Eden, are preserving their legacy through websites and blogs. The couple designed and built Open Benches, a mapping site that allows people to upload pictures of benches in their area. To date, more than 15,000 have been added to the site, the vast majority of which are in the UK.

The plaques they chart are often sad, deeply personal, sometimes uplifting and occasionally funny.

&quot;There are blue plaques to commemorate the famous and influential figures of the past. For everyone else, there are memorial benches. A quiet reminder of the people gone, but not forgotten,&quot; the website says.

Terence says memorial benches are a &quot;low-cost, low-effort way to learn about our community&quot;, but admits his favourite is dedicated to a cat. One visitor described delving into the database as &quot;like [mobile treasure hunt-style game] Pokemon but for benches&quot;.

It has revealed that plaques are more likely to be dedicated to wives and mothers than husbands and fathers. The common phrases are: &quot;in loving memory&quot;, &quot;in our hearts&quot; and &quot;who loved this…[place/view etc]&quot;.

The view, and special nature of the site, are the inspiration for many families who chose to remember a loved one in this way.

Carol Kubicki, a 59-year-old travel writer, has spent much of the last decade, since retiring from the NHS, cataloguing some of the most spectacular of these views and telling the stories of those commemorated in her Memorial Bench Stories blog.

&quot;My friends thought I was nuts when I suggested it,&quot; she says. &quot;They laughed and said I now had far too much time on my hands.&quot;

There are, she says, far too many to gather in a comprehensive list. Some stories are also difficult to research, she says, but many of her favourites are those in the most spectacular sites. There are surprises too, she says, having discovered benches dedicated to actress Dame Thora Hird, and rock band Black Sabbath among others.

Ultimately, her aim is to reflect the respect that people have when they sit on a bench, read the commemoration on the plaque, and consider why it is a special place for a particular family.

The UK's biggest bereavement charity says benches can anchor families to memories of special times they spent with a loved one during their lives, rather than only recall an often traumatic end.

&quot;When someone dies, your relationship with them does not disappear. A traumatic death, something sudden or at the end of a long drawn out illness, can be at the forefront of your mind. A bench can help someone remember the good and joyous times alongside what might have been a very difficult ending,&quot; says Andy Langford, chief operating officer for Cruse Bereavement Care.

&quot;One lady told us a bench sometimes gave her comfort - a sense of peace and closeness to her husband, but sometimes she would go there and be able to have a cry and remember how much she misses him. Both are healthy parts of the grieving process.&quot;

So, for anyone sitting at a beauty spot or a local park, a memorial bench offers the chance to contemplate the lives lived by those commemorated on the plaque behind us and what lies ahead for those who remain.

Here are some more pictures of benches from Carol Kubicki's travels:

... and some pithy plaques from the Memorial Benches website:</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50646467</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>Black Friday: Do you know when you're being manipulated? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/BC71/production/_109914284_p07w87jq.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It is Black Friday week and in shop windows, across websites, on the radio and in your email inbox will be discounts to tempt you. Shoppers are expected to splurge almost £8bn online alone. But those deals may not all be what they seem. The BBC’s Consumer Affairs correspondent Colletta Smith visits Bangor University's consumer psych lab to learn just how we’re all influenced.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-50506683</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-02-02 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>Mental health at work: Five charts on the challenge - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-02-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Business</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/3A47/production/_110491941_gettyimages-628388904.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Poor mental health in the workplace is costing UK employers more, according to a new report by consultancy firm Deloitte and mental health charity Mind.

With workers often scared to talk about being unwell, and a lack of funding available, these five charts show the extent of the challenge bosses face.

The consultancy firm Deloitte said that a range of factors have contributed to a reported increase in cost.

Employees are spending unproductive hours at work when ill, rather than taking time off.

Some workers are also experiencing &quot;burnout&quot; as technology makes it easier to log extra time and check emails outside designated working hours, and more seem to be affected by mental health problems in recent years.

The overall number of sick days taken per employee fell from 5.3 to 4.4 between 2008 and 2018, while the amount of time lost because of mental health conditions went up.

Part of the increase in cost also comes down to a rise in wages paid to workers over the last few years.

The new research by Deloitte suggests that poor mental health cost UK bosses more than £43bn in 2018.

That is an increase of 16% since the last estimate of £37bn in 2016.

How can you put a price on mental health?

The wages people are paid when they're on sick leave is one way to estimate the cost.

But people often don't disclose that sick leave is for mental health problems.

So the true costs could be higher.

On the other hand, if your work just waits for you to come back in, it's not costing your employer that much.

And measuring the cost of underperformance caused by mental health is even more tricky.

If you're making a case to bosses, you'll need to speak pounds and pence.

But mental health problems are often hard to pin down precisely and the numbers describing them are no different.

The study follows up on a government-commissioned review that found about 15% of people at work have symptoms of a mental health condition.

The new study tracks the increase of &quot;presenteeism&quot;, or when people go to work despite not feeling up to it.

If staff are under pressure to attend work, the number of sick days taken falls, and the less productive they are when on-site.

According to Deloitte, this costs bosses more than when staff take a day off.

But only 12.4% of people give mental health conditions as the reason for being off sick, according to the Office for National Statistics.

Nurses and teachers take more time off

Those working in the public sector are more likely to take time off because of mental health problems.

A total of 81% of people working in schools, the NHS, or the police said they always or usually go into work when they should take time off for their mental health.

This number increases to 85% for private sector workers.

Previous research by the BBC found that the number of NHS mental health staff who had to take sick leave because of their own mental health issues had increased by 22% between 2012-13 and 2016-17.

At the time, the union Unite said that cuts to staff and services were putting extra pressure on NHS workers.

Young people are the 'most vulnerable'

Poor mental health among young people has been described as an &quot;epidemic&quot;.

Younger members of staff are the most vulnerable in the workplace, according to Mind.

The charity found that young people are more likely to use their holidays instead of taking days off work when experiencing poor mental health.

Staff turnover, sickness and lost productivity cost employers about 8% of the average salary for a young person aged 18 to 29 years old in 2018 - roughly equal to £1,723 per employee.

That was the highest proportion of salary of any age group, partly because young people receive lower wages.

Having grown up in the shadow of the financial crisis, money worries can seriously affect under-30s.

A total of 90% of young workers surveyed for Business in the Community said that their mental health is affected by the cost of living.

Under-25s now make up about 6.5% of all personal insolvencies, according to the Insolvency Service.

Experts have said that easy-to-access credit and less secure ways of working can create problems for young people.

They are also the most likely to take on more flexible, insecure types of work like driving for Uber or delivering food for Deliveroo. The TUC trades union body previously found that the number of people doing &quot;gig economy&quot; work had doubled within three years.

Details of organisations which offer advice and support can be found on the BBC's Actionline.

Or you can call for free, at any time, to hear recorded information on 0800 066 066.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-51093712</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
