<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Senedd as it happened: 4 February 2020 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Parliaments</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://m.files.bbci.co.uk/modules/bbc-morph-news-waf-page-meta/4.1.2/bbc_news_logo.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The final item today is a debate on the Report of the Commission on Justice in Wales

First Minister Mark Drakeford moves the motion proposing that the National Assembly for Wales:

1. Welcomes the landmark report of the Commission on Justice in Wales and the unprecedented body of evidence it generated, and thanks the members and staff of the Commission for their work;

2. Recognises the dedication and commitment to public service shown by the many people and organisations who work within the justice system, but nevertheless notes with dismay the central finding of the Commission that the people of Wales are let down by their justice system;

3. Supports the Welsh Government’s intention of both taking forward those recommendations within its current competence and working with other bodies to take forward recommendations within their responsibility;

4. Notes the Commission’s key finding that in order to make a lasting difference to the delivery of justice in Wales, policy must be determined and overseen in Wales; and

5. Supports the devolution of justice and policing, and full funding for each as a way of properly aligning the operation of the justice system with the wider policy objectives for Wales agreed by this Assembly.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/uk-politics-parliaments-51310459</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Independent Care Review statement - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://m.files.bbci.co.uk/modules/bbc-morph-news-waf-page-meta/4.1.2/bbc_news_logo.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lib Dem MSP Alex Cole-Hamilton praises Fiona Duncan for the conclusive way she has conducted this review.

Mr Cole-Hamilton tells the chamber right now in Scotland when you leave care a trap door shuts and you have no right to return.

He says the report calls for people to have a right to return to care.

The first minister says young people have told her about concerns about the arbitrary nature of age limits in relation to care

Ms Sturgeon says as corporate parents there is a responsibility for life for care experienced people.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51356872</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>First and Deputy first ministers face MLAs' questions - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>N. Ireland Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://m.files.bbci.co.uk/modules/bbc-morph-news-waf-page-meta/4.1.2/bbc_news_logo.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>We've got two departmental officials up now to take question about statutory rule (SR).

This has provoked some concern because changes to the regulations involving sporting events held on roads.

Andrew Muir says this has resulted in increased costs for event organisers and has led to some events being cancelled altogether.

Stephen Hughes (below) head of traffic and engineering policy, says that previously the matter had been dealt with by the police using powers they felt were &quot;more security-related&quot;.

He says the legislation was prepared to allow special events to be held on the road on a proper legal basis.

Mr Hughes says responsibility for safety on the road has now been passed on from the police to the event organisers.

&quot;That's the main problem,&quot; says Mr Muir.

Mr Hughes says he has started &quot;a preliminary review&quot; of the legislation.

Mr Muir says the legislation has been in place for three years and he would have expected the review to be at a much more advanced stage.

Mr Hughes says he hopes the review will be ready &quot;towards the summer&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/uk-northern-ireland-politics-51384784</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>John Bercow: Formal complaint lodged against former Commons Speaker - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/128B9/production/_110616957_128ea123-d878-4cd8-b5c0-c094d2cc5bba.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A complaint has been made against former Commons Speaker John Bercow by a previous senior adviser.

Lord Lisvane, who served as Clerk of the House between 2011 and 2014, said he submitted the formal complaint to the Parliamentary Commissioner for Standards on Wednesday.

It is believed to centre on bullying.

Mr Bercow, who stood down from his role last year, said Lord Lisvane had &quot;ample opportunity&quot; to raise issues in their five years working together.

In a statement, Mr Bercow said: &quot;At no stage did he do so, even though he became Clerk of the House - the most senior official. The timing of this intervention is curious.&quot;

The former Speaker, who spent 10 years in the role, has faced other accusations of bullying during his time in office, but has denied all the claims.

There have been reports Mr Bercow - who previously sat as a Conservative MP - has been nominated for a peerage by the outgoing Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn.

No 10 said the allegations were &quot;very concerning&quot; and should be &quot;investigated thoroughly&quot;.

The prime minister's spokesman added: &quot;There can be no place for bullying or abuse in Westminster or any workplace, and it is important that the parliamentary leadership responds fully and promptly to any concerns which are raised.&quot;

Lord Lisvane began working at the House of Commons in 1972 and has held a number of procedural roles, including clerk for Private Members' Bills and clerk for the European Scrutiny Committee.

He became Clerk Assistant and Director General of the Chamber and Committee Services in 2009, before stepping up to the Clerk of the House of Commons in 2011.

After standing down in 2014, he became a life peer and sits in the House of Lords as a crossbencher.

Former Leader of the Commons, Andrea Leadsom, said anyone found to have bullied or harassed colleagues in Parliament &quot;should not be offered a peerage&quot;.

The now-business secretary, who clashed with Mr Bercow on a number of occasions in the Commons, told BBC Radio 5 Live: &quot;I worked cross-party to put in place a complaints procedure which would mean anybody, whoever they are, including the Speaker of the House of Commons, or indeed of the Lords, would be subject to those same complaints procedures.

&quot;Specifically, we made sure if you were an MP and you were potentially going to be offered a peerage, that anything that was alleged against you would be taken into account.

&quot;So, I think it is really important, whoever you are, that all of those complaints are taken seriously.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51220144</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>New Commons Speaker Sir Lindsay Hoyle curbs Bercow era powers - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12BEB/production/_110697767_de27-1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>And another chunk of John Bercow's legacy is chipped away...

His successor as Commons Speaker, Sir Lindsay Hoyle, has announced a new system for handling situations where the Chair makes a ruling that departs from Commons rules or traditions.

In his decade in the Chair, John Bercow stretched or, on occasions, shattered long-established conventions and the provisions of Commons standing orders.

Speaker Bercow's rulings on apparently technical questions, like the number of amendments that could be allowed in a debate on the 2013 Queen's Speech, the selection of amendments to supposedly unamendable &quot;meaningful vote&quot; motions and his interpretation of the meaning in standing orders of the word &quot;forthwith&quot; (which had previously meant that a motion was debated immediately, without the opportunity for amendments to be put) were all controversial, and the first two had serious repercussions.

It is arguable that his 2013 ruling, which effectively allowed Tory Brexiteers to put an amendment to the Queen's Speech calling for an EU referendum, was the first pebble in the Brexit avalanche.

The power of the Chair to make such rulings is not exactly limited by the system announced by Sir Lindsay.

But it serves to highlight where a Speaker uses their power in a way that seems to go against the rules and conventions.

Sir Lindsay said that in the interests of transparency, he was creating a new system modelled on the power of accounting officers in government departments to &quot;seek ministerial direction&quot; when they believe they are being told to do something that is against the rules or outside normal policy.

In effect, they are requesting a written instruction, which would override their advice.

A similar procedure will in future apply where in the opinion of the Clerk of the House, the top adviser to the Speaker and the Commons, a ruling amounts to a substantial breach of Commons standing orders or of long-established conventions.

In those circumstances, the Clerk will be able to place a statement of their views in the Commons library, where it would be available to all MPs.

The effect would be to provide extra ammunition to MPs who wanted to challenge a controversial ruling by the Speaker.

The announcement was greeted by loud cheers, mainly from Conservative MPs, as it became clear that the Speaker was, sort of, renouncing Bercowesque powers to rewrite the rules and announcing a system which would, potentially, limit the powers of his office.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51293344</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Parliamentary bullying will not be tolerated, says Speaker - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/7E22/production/_110709223_d444393f-4548-4e01-8cda-f27f9d0578db.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Commons Speaker Sir Lindsay Hoyle has declared an end to bullying in Parliament, saying abusive behaviour will not be tolerated.

He told journalists at a Press Gallery lunch that he believed bullying had taken place and that Westminster had been an unhappy place.

But he said he wanted everyone working on the Parliamentary Estate to be respected.

&quot;I want to make this a better village for all of us,&quot; he said.

Sir Lindsay's predecessor John Bercow has been accused of bullying during his 10 years as Speaker, but he has &quot;categorically&quot; denied the claims.

Asked about the allegations, Sir Lindsay, who was previously a deputy Speaker, said he had not personally been bullied by Mr Bercow.

And when asked about whether he had witnessed any bullying, Sir Lindsay said: &quot;We had a working relationship - that's the best way to describe it.&quot;

Describing his own approach to the job of Speaker, Sir Lindsay said: &quot;It is about looking after everyone who works in this place.&quot;

He added: &quot;I do hope we can get the respect back.&quot;

Sir Lindsay also said: &quot;The bullying is over. We are not going to tolerate it.&quot;

Among those attending the lunch was former Black Rod David Leakey, who has accused Mr Bercow of bullying.

Mr Leakey, who was responsible for keeping order in the House of Lords, told BBC Newsnight in 2018 that he had seen &quot;bullying and unreasonable&quot; behaviour.

The ex-senior Parliament official said Mr Bercow created a climate of &quot;fear and intimidation&quot;.

Sir Lindsay said due process should take place when it comes to whether Mr Bercow should be made a peer; that his name should go forward, then the relevant authorities should decide whether his nomination is suitable.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51311862</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Jeremy Hunt wins health role in select committee ballot - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Parliaments</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/0315/production/_110698700_mediaitem110698697.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Ex-Health Secretary Jeremy Hunt has been elected to head a committee of MPs which scrutinises the performance of the NHS and government health policy.

Mr Hunt, who stood against Boris Johnson for the Tory leadership this summer, was the longest serving health secretary between 2010 and 2016.

He was among 15 select committee chairs elected in a secret ballot.

And former cabinet ministers Greg Clark and Karen Bradley will head the science and procedure committees respectively. A wide range of roles were up for grabs, with briefs ranging from transport to international trade.

Mr Hunt said he was &quot;honoured&quot; to be elected as chair of the health select committee and he would be pressing the government to move quickly to build a cross-party consensus for a funding settlement for care for the elderly.

There is a select committee for each governmental department, along with a few additional groups. They are made up of 11 or more members who carry out inquiries and create reports into a range of subjects.

They are seen as one of the most effective ways of holding ministers and civil servants to account.

The chairs of 13 committees, including education and home affairs, have already been named as the candidates for chairman ran uncontested.

Wednesday's elections do not include the intelligence and security committee (ISC) - the head of which is chosen through a separate process, with nominations provided by the prime minister after consultation with the leader of the opposition.

The long-awaited Russia report - into allegations of espionage, subversion and interference in UK democracy - will not be published until a new ISC is established. The timing of the committee's reconstitution is also in the gift of the PM.

Chairs of the committees are elected by MPs at the start of each Parliament.

Parties agree on the allocation of committees between them to make sure the chairs are a fair representation of the make-up of Parliament.

As Mr Johnson and his Conservatives won in December with an 80-strong majority, Tory MPs will chair 17 of them. Labour will head up nine, while the SNP will lead on two.

The biggest competition was for chair of the defence committee, with five Tory candidates vying for the top job.

Ex-defence minister Mr Ellwood saw off competition from Adam Holloway, Robert Courts, James Gray and Sir Bernard Jenkin.

And incumbent Mr Tugendhat won the hotly contested race to head the foreign affairs committee, defeating Crispin Blunt and Bob Seely.

The big Labour contest was for chair of the pensions committee, with Stephen Timms seeing off Debbie Abrahams, Chris Bryant and Karen Buck.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-parliaments-51294094</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-02 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Senedd Live - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-02</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Parliaments</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://m.files.bbci.co.uk/modules/bbc-morph-news-waf-page-meta/4.1.2/bbc_news_logo.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Rhun ap Iorwerth (Ynys Môn) seeks a statement following the announcement regarding the departure of Betsi Cadwaladr Health Board's Chief Executive.

Health minister Vaughan Gething replies that &quot;decisions on employment matters are for the board and its chair to make&quot;.

The chief executive of the under-fire health board will leave his job later this month.

Gary Doherty will leave Betsi Cadwaladr health board to become director of integration at Lancashire Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust.

The health board went into special measures in June 2015 and Mr Doherty started working there in February 2016.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/uk-politics-parliaments-51310465</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
