<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Meadow ruling 'risk to witnesses'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The General Medical Council found Sir Roy guilty of serious professional misconduct after his &quot;misleading&quot; evidence in the Sally Clark case.

Mrs Clark was convicted of murdering her two sons, but she was exonerated after an appeal in 2003.

The Society of Expert Witnesses said it was astonished by the decision.

Professor Sir Roy Meadow was found guilty for providing evidence which was misleading and &quot;fell short&quot; of the standards expected of a medical professional.

The Society said the whole system of using witnesses in court needed to be radically overhauled.

Tom Magner, a spokesman for the society, said &quot;The GMC panel has concentrated on one expert witness and one case.

&quot;Within these narrow limits they have thrown the book at Prof Meadow for what is acknowledged to be a situation in which he did not intend to mislead.

&quot;The severity of the penalty will cause many expert witnesses, particularly doctors, to reconsider whether to offer their services to the courts as expert witnesses.&quot;

During Mrs Clark's trial, Sir Roy said the probability of two natural unexplained cot deaths in the family was 73 million to one.

Mrs Clark was eventually freed after it become apparent that another witness at her trial, pathologist Alan Williams, had failed to disclose key medical evidence.

The chair of the GMC panel considering Sir Roy's case said it was vital the public had confidence in the experts brought before the court and that was why he had to be struck off, rather than be given a lesser penalty.

Sir Roy had stood by his evidence, but admitted his use of statistics at Mrs Clark's 1999 trial was &quot;insensitive&quot;.

The GMC said Sir Roy's conduct had been &quot;fundamentally unacceptable&quot;.

Frank Lockyer, Mrs Clark's father, who brought the case, broke down in tears as he welcomed the verdict on Friday.

He said: &quot;The GMC has applied the ultimate sanction to the doctor who played such a huge part in my daughter's conviction.

&quot;Now perhaps we, as a family, can put the last seven years of hell behind us and move on.&quot;

The figure given by Sir Roy in the trial was later disputed by the Royal Statistical Society and other experts have said that once genetic and environmental factors are taken into consideration, the odds are closer to 200 to one.

The panel's chairman, Mary Clark-Glass, said Sir Roy was an eminent paediatrician.

But she added: &quot;You should not have strayed into areas that were not within your remit of expertise.&quot;

The panel had earlier decided Sir Roy had not meant to mislead the Clark trial, but said his evidence had done so because it &quot;erroneously implied&quot; two natural deaths in a family would have to be independent of one another.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4688367.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Sir Roy Meadow struck off by GMC</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The GMC announced on Friday that Sir Roy had been found guilty of serious professional misconduct.

Sir Roy had stood by his evidence, but admitted his use of statistics at Mrs Clark's 1999 trial was &quot;insensitive&quot;.

Mrs Clark was convicted of murdering her two sons, but she was exonerated after an appeal in 2003.

The GMC said Sir Roy's conduct had been &quot;fundamentally unacceptable&quot;.

Frank Lockyer, Mrs Clark's father, who brought the case, broke down in tears as he welcomed the verdict.

He said: &quot;The GMC has applied the ultimate sanction to the doctor who played such a huge part in my daughter's conviction.

&quot;Now perhaps we, as a family, can put the last seven years of hell behind us and move on.&quot;

Mrs Clark was eventually freed after it become apparent that another witness at her trial, pathologist Alan Williams, had failed to disclose key medical evidence.

The chair of the GMC panel considering Sir Roy's case said it was vital the public had confidence in the experts brought before the court and that was why he had to be struck off, rather than be given a lesser penalty.

The paediatrician left the hearing without commenting on the GMC's decision.

During the trial, Sir Roy said the probability of two natural unexplained cot deaths in the family was 73 million to one.

The figure was later disputed by the Royal Statistical Society and other experts said that once genetic and environmental factors were taken into consideration, the odds of a second cot death in the same family were closer to 200 to one.

The panel's chairman, Mary Clark-Glass, said Sir Roy was an eminent paediatrician.

But she added: &quot;You should not have strayed into areas that were not within your remit of expertise.&quot;

The panel had earlier decided Sir Roy had not meant to mislead the Clark trial, but said his evidence had done so because it &quot;erroneously implied&quot; two natural deaths in a family would have to be independent of one another.

Giving evidence to the hearing, Sir Roy defended the calculations he used to arrive at the 73 million to one figure.

But he said he regretted comparing the odds of two cot deaths in the same family to that of a punter successfully backing an 80-1 shot at the Grand National four years in a row.

Sir Roy also gave evidence as an expert witness in the trials of two other women, Angela Cannings and Donna Anthony, who were both freed on appeal after being convicted of murdering their children.

Angela Cannings described the GMC decision as &quot;fantastic&quot; news, and called on Sir Roy to apologise.

&quot;It's an immense relief that justice has been done.&quot;

&quot;It is recognition for what he did wrong to us as a family, what he did wrong to the Clark family, what he has done wrong to other families.&quot;

George Hawks, solicitor for Donna Anthony, said: &quot;She is not vindictive. She just wanted him to acknowledge he had got it wrong in her case and offer her an apology.&quot;

The hearing had heard testimonies from leading paediatricians in support of Sir Roy, who retains a great deal of respect within the medical profession.

Professor Sir Alan Craft, President of the Royal College of Paediatrics and Child Health, said the decision to strike Sir Roy off was &quot;saddening&quot;.

He added: &quot;He has had a long and distinguished career in paediatrics in which he has undoubtedly saved the lives of many children.

&quot;We must be clear however that this hearing focussed solely on the evidence he gave in one particular court case. It does not reflect upon the rest of his career.&quot;

Sir Alan said the role of expert witnesses had to be examined urgently so improvements can be made and confidence in the system could be re-established.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4685511.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Hospitals treating blast victims</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>More than 700 people were hurt and at least 50 died in Thursday's attacks, with many people still missing.

Hospitals called in extra staff and cancelled non-urgent surgery to deal with the injured, but have now returned to normal working conditions.

People worried about relatives or friends should call 0870 1566 344.

On Saturday, Professor Jim Ryan, a senior A&amp;E consultant at University College Hospital - which is still treating 15 people - said: &quot;Most of the operations are on limbs. You have penetrating wounds, indented stone, debris, glass or metal.

&quot;There is also head injury management, and lung inhalation and injuries to the chest.&quot;

On Sunday, the Royal London Hospital, near Liverpool Street Station, said it was still treating 17 patients, seven who were in intensive care.

Chelsea and Westminster Hospital has four blast victims being treated in their specialist burns unit, after two were released on Saturday night.

The Royal Free Hospital, in north London, said it was still treating seven people, all in a stable condition, with one expected to be discharged later on Sunday.

And St Mary's Hospital, in Paddington, is treating five people. All were in a stable condition, with two said to be critical.

Thirteen people are still at Guy's and St Thomas's, near Waterloo, one in a critical condition but stable.

And Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, which set up makeshift facilities under its major incident plan as it does not have an A&amp;E department, still has two casualties.

A spokesman said they were &quot;doing reasonably well&quot; and may be discharged within the next 24 hours.

Charing Cross Hospital has two casualties, both of whom were transferred from St Mary's and are described as being in a stable condition.

Casualties have received visits from Health Secretary Patricia Hewitt, The Queen and Prince Charles.

Speaking at the Royal Free Hospital on Saturday, Ms Hewitt praised the NHS response, saying hospitals were &quot;almost immediately ready and could have coped with far more people had they needed to&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4669151.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Anger over Alzheimer drugs delay</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The National Institute for Clinical Excellence (NICE) proposed in March to restrict four Alzheimer's drugs because they are not good value for money.

A final decision on rivastigmine, memantine, donepezil and galantamine use was to be made this month.

NICE says it needs more time to check how much the drugs benefit patients.

It has asked drug companies for more data.

If it decides to go ahead with the withdrawal across England and Wales, thousands of patients will be denied the only drug treatment available to them, argue dementia charities and carers.

However, patients already taking the drugs would not have them withdrawn, NICE said.

The guidance does not mean the drugs do not work or are harmful - just that the cost to the NHS does not warrant the benefits gained from patients taking them.

The drugs, which campaigners estimate cost £2.50 per day per patient, improve memory and can make daily living tasks easier.

Campaigners and medical experts condemned the move, which reverses previous NICE guidance in 2001 that said the drugs should be used as standard.

A new alliance - Action on Alzheimer's Drugs - has now been formed.

Clive Ballard of the Alzheimer's Society and member of the alliance said: &quot;It's a complete delaying tactic.

&quot;The requirement for more evidence is ridiculous.

&quot;More than 32 placebo controlled clinical trials demonstrate they improve memory and every day activity.&quot;

He said it was &quot;absolutely outrageous&quot; to withhold a clinically effective treatment based on a &quot;modest cost&quot; of £2.50 per patient per day.

Professor Susan Benbow, Chair of the Faculty of Old Age Psychiatry at the Royal College of Psychiatrists, accused NICE of being ageist - a concern echoed by the Liberal Democrat spokesperson for Older People, Sandra Gidley MP.

Sandra Gidley said: &quot;NICE need to demonstrate that the way they calculate cost-effectiveness is not ageist and does not unfairly discriminate against older people.&quot;

Pauline Ford from the Royal College of Nursing said if the prescribing ban went ahead it would put doctors and nurses in a difficult position - they would have to explain that an effective treatment was not available for financial reasons.

Eisai Limited, the manufacturer of donepezil, and Pfizer, their co-marketing partner, said Nice's evaluation did not address the carer burden or potential gain to carers when Alzheimer's patients receive treatment.

Nor does it account for the potential cost savings made in delaying the need for nursing home placement or additional nursing care when patients are taking these medicines, said spokesman Professor Nick Bosanquet, professor of healthcare policy at Imperial College, London.

&quot;This unfairly tips the balance against these treatments and incorrectly leads to calculations that they are not cost effective,&quot; he said.

Andrew Dillon, chief executive of NICE and executive lead for this appraisal said: &quot;We are acutely aware of our responsibility to people with Alzheimer's disease, their families and carers, to ensure that every effort is made to obtain all the available evidence on these drugs.

&quot;We need to make the right decision, based on all the relevant evidence.

&quot;We think there is more data which could affect our decision and we are asking the drug companies for access to it.&quot;

He said the responses would be considered in October. A decision will be reached after that.

Conservative Shadow Health Secretary Andrew Lansley said: &quot;Nice are right to identify the need for more data on clinical effectiveness for sub-groups of patients.

&quot;However, the central issue is not resolved, which is that the benefits of prescribing shouldn't be limited to the NHS, but should also include the impact on carers and family.&quot;

Dr Richard Barker, director general of the ABPI, said: &quot;The door remains open for further discussion and it is vital that it is not slammed in the faces of people with Alzheimer's and those working with them to alleviate this distressing condition.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4693587.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Fake drugs find leads to recall</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA), in conjunction with Pfizer, is recalling packs of Lipitor 20mg tablets.

Only those bearing the batch number 004405K1 are affected.

The MHRA said patients were not at any immediate risk from the fake drugs, which should be returned to chemists.

Patients will then be given new supplies of the prescription-only drug.

Fake tablets can be identified because they do not come in sealed packets in which the genuine drug is provided.

Pfizer said hundreds of batch numbers were released each year, and the recall only applied to this one.

There were around three million prescriptions for Lipitor issued in 2004.

Seventy-three packets of counterfeit Lipitor have so far been discovered after a tip-off from customs officers in Rotterdam, Holland.

It is the third time since the beginning of 2004 that fake drugs have entered the pharmaceutical supply chain in the UK.

Last year, counterfeit batches of Cialis, used to treat impotence, and Reductil, used to treat obesity, were discovered.

Nimo Ahmed, head of intelligence at the MHRA, said: &quot;It is the vigilance of the MHRA that has led us to identify the counterfeit Lipitor and recall this product.

&quot;Although the quality of counterfeit medicines cannot be guaranteed, our testing of the counterfeit product indicates that there is no immediate risk to patients. If patients have any concerns about possible side-effects they should discuss them with their doctor.&quot;

Pfizer called for more effort to be made by authorities in the UK and Europe to ensure the safety of medicines

Kate Lloyd, medical director of Pfizer UK, said: &quot;Patient safety is our top concern and we are seriously alarmed at the discovery of counterfeit medicine in the UK.

&quot;Patient safety is at risk if counterfeit products can easily be introduced into the supply chain through cross-border trade, as patients will not gain the benefits their doctor intended when selecting their medicine.&quot;

She said measures including outlawing the repackaging of original manufacturers' medicines, supporting the introduction of tamper-resistant medicine packaging, and introducing a standardised European barcode for medicines could all help to protect medicine supplies.

However, Richard Freudenberg, of the British Association of European Pharmaceutical Distributors, told the BBC News website it was disingenuous of Pfizer to associate counterfeits with parallel distribution.

He said overlabelling or repackaging undertaken by parallel distributors was carried out under strict guidelines.

&quot;The impression left by Pfizer UK's medical director is that parallel distribution of medicines in Europe is thoroughly flawed and a soft target for counterfeiters to introduce their illegal and dangerous products into the market.

&quot;In fact, there has never been a single confirmed case in the UK of a counterfeit medicine reaching a patient as parallel distribution, ever.

Mr Freudenberg said the current fakes were a replica of the pack distributed by Pfizer in the UK.

&quot;Parallel distributors, however, are concerned about the future possibility of their entering the supply chain, and would be pleased to discuss with manufacturers available means to prevent this happening.&quot;

Professor Peter Weissberg, Medical Director of the British Heart Foundation (BHF), said: &quot;This is not an issue that should cause any worry for patients taking Lipitor.

&quot;We would urge any patients who have this particular batch number on their packet to follow the MHRA's advice and return the product to where they obtained it and seek a replacement of the genuine drug.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4725881.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Mobiles 'quadruple crash danger'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>They reached their estimates by looking at the phone bill records of 456 drivers needing hospital treatment after road crashes in Perth, Australia.

In the UK it is illegal to use a hand-held mobile phone while driving.

Safety campaigners say the University of Western Australia study in the British Medical Journal shows the rules should apply to hands-free phone use.

For each driver, the researchers assessed phone use immediately before a crash and on trips at the same time of day 24 hours, three days, and seven days before the crash for comparison.

Mobile phone use in the 10 minutes before a crash was associated with a four-fold increased likelihood of crashing.

This was irrespective of whether the driver was using a hand-held or hands-free phone.

Similar results were found for the interval up to five minutes before a crash.

Author Suzanne McEvoy and colleagues from the University of Western Australia said: &quot;More and more new vehicles are being equipped with hands-free phone technology.

&quot;Although this may lead to fewer hand-held phones used while driving in the future, our research indicates that this may not eliminate the risk.

&quot;Indeed, if this new technology increases mobile phone use in cars, it could contribute to even more crashes.&quot;

A spokesman from the Royal Society for the Prevention of Accidents said: &quot;This is exactly what we have said and have known for some time.

&quot;We hope that the people who callously think that their phone call is more important than somebody's life will get the message eventually when they see more and more research like this.&quot;

He said the current ban on using hand-held mobiles while driving, which can carry the penalty of a fine and in the future possibly also up to three points on the driver's licence, should be extended to hands-free phones.

However, the study authors said this would be difficult to enforce.

They said a possible solution might be to change mobile phones so that they cannot be used when vehicles are in motion, but added that industry was unlikely to embrace this.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4672657.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Gut hormone jab aids weight loss</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A team from Imperial College say the four-week trial suggested oxyntomodulin - naturally found in the intestine - could be a new way of tackling obesity.

The research in Diabetes said those on the hormone lost an average of 2.3kg (5lbs) in four weeks, compared to 0.5kg (1lb) for those on a dummy treatment.

Experts said more studies were needed to confirm the hormone's benefits.

Oxyntomodulin is normally released from the small intestine as food is consumed.

It tells the brain not to eat any more at the end of a meal when the body has had enough to eat.

The researchers, from Imperial College and Hammersmith Hospitals NHS Trust, studied the effect of boosting people's oxyntomodulin levels.

The team looked at 26 people who were all overweight or obese.

Fourteen injected themselves with oxyntomodulin 30 minutes before each meal, three times a day, for four weeks.

Twelve administered saline at the same frequency for the same period.

Neither doctors nor patients knew which group they were in during the study.

In addition to seeing greater weight loss, the group taking oxyntomodulin also had a reduced appetite, but they saw no change in their enjoyment of food.

Levels of leptin, a protein known to be responsible for regulating the body's energy expenditure, and adipose hormones, which encourage the build up of a type of tissue where fat cells are stored, were also found to be lower in the group having hormone injections.

Professor Steve Bloom, senior researcher at Imperial College London and Hammersmith Hospital, who led the study, told the BBC: &quot;We saw a dramatic rate of weight loss.&quot;

He said the fact that it was natural gave oxyntomodulin an advantage over other treatments.

Professor Bloom, who has set up Thiakis, a company in order to continue developing the treatment, added: &quot;You have your own oxyntomodulin every time you eat lunch or supper, so it's not quite like a drug.

&quot;I would anticipate it being completely safe and also, since you have your own oxyntomodulin, it isn't likely to ever stop working.&quot;

He said that was a problem with existing anti-obesity drugs.

But Professor Bloom said larger trials were needed to check the treatment was effective over longer periods.

Dr Ian Campbell, president of the National Obesity Forum, said the study was exciting.

He added: &quot;The weight-loss was significant, but questions need to be asked about what the weight loss would be with the additional lifestyle changes, and the efficacy over a period of time much longer than four weeks.

&quot;But it's certainly worthy of further investment and research.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4707923.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Experts debate bird flu strategy</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The World Health Organization says a pandemic of bird flu is inevitable and could cause 50,000 deaths in the UK.

It has warned that efforts to contain the spread of the current strain of the virus circulating in Asia have not been successful.

Indonesian authorities confirmed the first three human fatalities from the disease in the country on Wednesday.

Dr Dick Thompson, a WHO expert on bird flu, said the H5N1 variant of the virus currently circulating in Asia had the potential to become a more deadly form.

&quot;It jumps from animals to humans occasionally and when it does it causes severe disease.

&quot;If it acquires the ability to move easily from person to person it could ignite a pandemic.

&quot;It hasn't been contained, it seems to be spreading more widely. Recently we had reports of the virus turning up in migratory birds in western China.&quot;

Dr Thompson said the bird flu virus was very unstable, and its genes were always changing - that alone might be enough to trigger the creation of a more deadly form.

Alternatively, if the virus infected an animal or human also carrying a standard form of flu the two viruses could swap genes in a process called reassortment.

If this happens the consequences could be dramatic.

&quot;It would cause a lot of people to become very sick, very suddenly and it has the potential to overwhelm healthcare systems, and cause a lot of social disruption.&quot;

Dr Thompson said there was no way to stop a pandemic - if H5N1 did not mutate into a more deadly form, then it was only a matter of time before another variant did.

Dr Sandra Bell, director of homeland security for the Royal United Services Institute for Defence and Security Studies, said the UK was closely monitoring the situation, working on diagnostic techniques and putting in place contingency plans to ensure vital services would be maintained.

&quot;We don't know when it is going to come, or what it is going to be like, but we have put a lot of planning and preparation in place so that we can move very, very quickly in order to minimise the impact.&quot;

Dr Bell said an effective vaccine could only be produced once the exact nature of the mutated virus became apparent.

&quot;You cannot have a vaccine unless you have identified the strain, so you have got to wait until it has started, which is where you rely on your surveillance and quick diagnosis techniques to identify the strain very rapidly, and quickly produce a vaccine.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4698983.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Vitamin controls backed by Europe</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The proposals could ban around 200 supplements from sale and put restrictions on the upper limits of vitamin doses.

Some health experts wanted to see vitamins and minerals controlled in the same way as conventional medicines.

But critics argued the new rules were unnecessarily restrictive, and would deny consumers choice.

Under the EU Food Supplements Directive, due to come into effect in August, supplements will only be able to include vitamins and minerals taken from an approved list.

Minerals not currently on the approved list include tin, silicon, nickel, boron, cobalt and vanadium.

However, manufacturers of products already on the market will have until the end of December 2009 to change any of the banned ingredients to ensure that their product can continue to be sold in the future.

Also, the Alliance for Natural Health (ANH) said it interpreted the ban as applying only to synthetically produced supplements - and not to vitamins and minerals normally found in or consumed as part of the diet.

The ban had been challenged by the ANH, the Health Food Manufacturers' Association (HFMA) and the National Association of Health Stores (NAHS).

They argued the legislation would be too restrictive, and would threaten thousands of perfectly safe products.

The directive was first approved by EU governments in 2002 and was designed to tighten controls on the growing market in products sold under the health food heading - natural remedies, vitamin supplements and mineral plant extracts.

The HFMA and the ANH argued the directive was an unlawful restriction on freedom to trade, that implementation would impose an unnecessary burden on British business and there are no reasons to believe it is necessary to protect consumers' welfare.

After reviewing the evidence presented by both sides, European Court of Justice Advocate General Leendert Geelhoed said in April that the directive infringed legal guidelines in his opinion.

However, the court pointed out that certain restrictions could be justified by the protection of public health and considered the measures in question to be necessary and appropriate for the purpose of achieving that objective.

The British Dietetic Association backed the new plans.

It is concerned about patients admitted to hospital suffering liver failure and severe stomach problems after taking high doses of vitamins.

It said in some cases the supplements are preventing people getting the correct treatment for other chronic illness.

Spokeswoman Ursula Arens said consumers should not be greatly affected by the changes.

&quot;About 99% of products will not be affected.&quot;

The ruling was also welcomed by Sue Davies, of the consumer magazine Which?.

She said: &quot;It will ensure that products are safe, that they contain forms of vitamins and minerals that offer some benefit, and that they are clearly labelled.&quot;

Peter Aldiss, managing director of Holland and Barrett, said he was very disappointed by the decision.

&quot;There are hundreds of nutrients which are already very safely on sale with very strict laws in the UK.

&quot;This directive purely just takes those nutrients out of the reckoning - they're perfectly safe and they've been on sale for decades.&quot;

David Adams, director of HFMA, said the Prime Minister, who currently holds the EU Presidency, should get the legislation rewritten to allow the UK to include products on the market which would otherwise lie outside the list - a call echoed by the Conservative Party.

The ANH said its lawyers had interpreted the directive's restrictions to apply only to minerals and vitamins from synthetic sources.

Public Health Minister Caroline Flint, said government was concerned that some of the provisions in the Directive could be &quot;unduly burdensome&quot;, particularly for small companies making these products.

&quot;We have provided resources to help industry and small businesses supply the evidence necessary to allow their products to continue to stay on the market for the time being. This doesn't require them to do any new testing or provide new data at this stage.

&quot;The directive will also set maximum levels of vitamins and minerals in food supplements. We believe that any maximum dosage level should be based on scientific evidence. We will work with other member states and the European Commission on this basis.&quot;

It will be possible to add products to the approved list and none will be removed unless they are proved to be unsafe.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4670971.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Child death expert 'court ordeal'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Professor Sir Roy Meadow is accused of professional misconduct over evidence he gave in the 1999 trial of Sally Clark. She was jailed but later freed.

Sir Roy, who denies the charge, told the General Medical Council giving evidence was a &quot;legal jousting match&quot;.

It comes as the Lancet journal said the GMC case should not have been brought.

The leading medical journal said Sir Roy, who could be struck off if found guilty, had become a scapegoat and called for a royal commission to be set up to look into all the issues surrounding the case.

During the Clark trial, Sir Roy said the probability of two natural unexplained cot deaths in the family was 73 million to one.

The figure was later disputed by the Royal Statistical Society and other experts have said that once genetic and environmental factors are taken into consideration, the odds are closer to 200 to one.

Mrs Clark was eventually freed in 2003, after an appeal overturned her conviction.

Sir Roy also gave evidence as an expert witness in the trials of two other women, Angela Cannings and Donna Anthony, who were both freed on appeal after being convicted of murdering their children.

In his first day of his defence at the GMC he said giving evidence in criminal cases was an ordeal for which he had received no formal guidelines.

&quot;Giving evidence in court is a great ordeal I think for anybody and anyone who gives evidence in court is very nervous, however many times you have been there.&quot;

He said that like an exam, it was possible to come out of court furious for not expressing what one had said in a better way.

Sir Roy said a family court everything is geared towards the best interests of the child, not unlike medicine.

Reports are not censored, and the whole thing goes to the judge, he added.

But he said in criminal courts, the jurors must go on the results of a &quot;jousting match between the advocates.&quot;

Sir Roy also described research to the GMC which found that the sudden death of a child was a factor in mother's fabricating illness in a subsequent child - a condition known as Munchausen's Syndrome by Proxy.

He said evidence suggested that a significant proportion of children who had died suddenly may have been smothered by one of their parents, but added when he first suggested it he faced strong resistance.

But added: &quot;There was disbelief from social workers that this sort of thing could happen, either severe fabricated illness or smothering. It was a very difficult period.&quot;

The Lancet said the case was a legal and not a medical one.

Editor Dr Richard Horton said Sir Roy had been a &quot;lightning rod of blame&quot; for the wrongful conviction of Mrs Clark.

&quot;This misconceived pursuit of one man is wrong and threatens the effective delivery of child protection services in Britain.&quot;

He said the activities of the police, pathologists, lawyers and other experts involved in investigating suspicious death need to be considered together and says a royal commission should look at the issues.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4639967.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Cot death expert's stats sorrow</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Professor Sir Roy Meadow said his estimate of the likelihood of two cot deaths in her family used at her 1999 trial &quot;misled and confused&quot; people.

He denies charges of serious professional misconduct at the General Medical Council hearing.

Mrs Clark was cleared in 2003 of killing her sons Harry and Christopher.

During the GMC hearing, Robert Seabrook QC, acting for the GMC, asked Sir Roy if the way people had been misled about his evidence was something he was &quot;profoundly sorry&quot; about.

He replied: &quot;Yes it is.&quot;

Sir Roy had estimated the chance of a double cot death in Sally Clark's family was one in 73 million.

He told the hearing: &quot;I think it's self-evident it misled and confused a lot of people.&quot;

He said he was very sorry about it.

Sir Roy said he had not spoken sooner about his regrets because of legal advice and professional etiquette.

He said: &quot;It's been very, very difficult in keeping silent.&quot;

Sally Clark's father, Frank Lockyer, who brought the case against the paediatrician, said Sir Roy's comments were a &quot;a significant development&quot;.

Sir Roy had earlier told the GMC that at a committal hearing for Mrs Clark, he was asked by defence counsel about the one in 1,000 figure for sudden infant death syndrome.

He said he did not remember where the figure had come from, but when it appeared in an article he had written in an eminent paediatric journal, no one had questioned it.

Sir Roy said it was a &quot;reasonable ball park figure&quot; for the incidence of sudden infant death syndrome for the population as a whole.

He said he had squared it to reach a figure of one child per million for two such deaths in the same family

He then calculated that because of Sally Clark's age and the family's relative affluence, the likelihood in their case was one in 73 million - the figure he used during her trial.

It was later disputed by the Royal Statistical Society and other experts have said that once genetic and environmental factors are taken into consideration, the odds are closer to 200 to one.

Sir Roy had said he had taken the one in 73 million figure to be a &quot;mean figure and there would be a degree of variation on either side&quot;.

Last week he told the GMC he did not see himself as an expert statistician.

Sir Roy also gave evidence as an expert witness in the trials of two other women, Angela Cannings and Donna Anthony, who were both freed on appeal after being convicted of murdering their children.

He told the GMC he had concerns over the evidence he saw regarding both Harry and Christopher's deaths.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4657231.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Blast victims face more surgery</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Fewer than 70 people remain in hospital, many having had operations after losing limbs, and suffering burns and multiple body injuries.

But doctors said some would need more surgery. Four people are also being treated in a specialist burns unit.

Over 700 people were hurt and at least 50 died. People worried about relatives or friends should call 0870 1566 344.

Hospitals called in extra staff and cancelled non-urgent surgery to free up theatres to deal with the injured under their emergency plans, but all hospitals have now returned to normal working conditions

Professor Jim Ryan, a senior A&amp;E consultant at University College Hospital, which is still treating 15 people, said: &quot;Most of the operations are on limbs. You have penetrating wounds, indented stone, debris, glass or metal.

&quot;There is also head injury management, and lung inhalation and injuries to the chest.&quot;

He added many of the patients would be facing further surgery and complex care.

The Royal London Hospital, near Liverpool Street Station, said it was still treating 17 patients, seven who were in intensive care.

Alastair Wilson, A&amp;E clinical director at the hospital, said: &quot;There is still a lot of surgery to be done, probably over this weekend.&quot;

Chelsea and Westminster Hospital has also admitted six casualties for treatment in their specialist burns unit.

A spokeswoman said they would be assessed by a team of plastic surgeons before any decision was taken on their treatment.

The Royal Free Hospital in north London said it was still treating eight people and all were in a stable condition.

And St Mary's Hospital in Paddington is treating five people. All were in a stable condition with two said to be critical.

Thirteen people are still at Guy's and St Thomas's, near Waterloo, one in a critical condition but stable.

A spokeswoman said: &quot;Patients are being treated for smoke inhalation, burns and serious limb and chest injuries.&quot;

And Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, which set up makeshift facilities under its major incident plan as it does not have an A&amp;E department, still has two casualties.

Charing Cross Hospital has one casualty who was transferred from St Mary's.

Home Secretary Charles Clarke said: &quot;There are a number of people terribly injured in hospital still and we don't know how they're going to survive or not.&quot;

Casualties have received visits from Health Secretary Patricia Hewitt, The Queen and Prince Charles.

Speaking at the Royal Free Hospital, Ms Hewitt praised the NHS response, saying hospitals were &quot;almost immediately ready and could have coped with far more people had they needed to&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4665089.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Hospital care 'fails the elderly'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The three-month investigation revealed patients suffering a series of indignities at Brighton's zero-rated Royal Sussex County Hospital.

In one scene a patient is left to die on her own, and in another a patient is left waiting hours to go to the toilet.

Peter Coles, boss of the NHS trust covering the hospital, said: &quot;Clearly they are very disturbing images.&quot;

Margaret Haywood, a nurse with more than 20 years' experience, agreed to go undercover for the Panorama programme, wearing a hidden camera while working as a bank nurse at the hospital for 28 shifts on an acute medical ward.

She was joined by BBC journalist Shabnam Grewal who got a job in the ward with ISS Mediclean, a private company which has the contract to clean the hospital and serve food.

The programme has uncovered a series of failings. The ward did not keep care plans, which describe individual patient needs, and fluid charts detailing when patients have had a drink were not updated.

At one point in the programme, to be aired on Wednesday on BBC1 at 9pm, cancer patient Jessie Mowitt, 86, is seen being left to die on her own.

On another occasion Ms Grewal is told off by her boss for offering a patient a special meal.

And in another scene, when a patient asks for help, a nurse replies: &quot;No, not helping you. Sit down, please.&quot;

The patient then says: &quot;Oh Christ, you are a bully.&quot;

Only for the nurse to say: &quot;You're the one that is a bully, not me.&quot;

After going undercover, Ms Haywood said: &quot;Seeing this kind of care makes me feel angry, it makes me ashamed of my profession. We're talking about basic human needs here, basic nursing care.&quot;

Peter Coles, chief executive of the Brighton and Sussex University Hospitals Trust, who was shown the tape, said: &quot;Clearly they are very disturbing images and I was shocked to see them.

&quot;The first thing I would like to do is to apologise on behalf of the trust to those patients and their relatives for those lapses in quality of care that were uncovered at that time.&quot;

He said a number of complaints had been received about the ward before the BBC filming had begun and an investigation was launched.

A new ward manager and a series of new procedures were introduced in March.

But the Panorama programme also filmed the ward after that date and while improvements had been made, the footage showed the hospital was still failing to fill in care plans and fluid charts.

Two thirds of patients cared for in hospital wards are over the age of 65, and with an ageing population that figure is set to rise.

Undercover Nurse - A Panorama Special on Wednesday on BBC1 at 9pm</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4697757.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Testicular cancer drug effective</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A single dose of a drug is as effective at treating testicular cancer as two to three weeks of radiotherapy, research has found. Scientists say carboplatin could become the preferred treatment for the most common type of testicular cancer. It might also eventually allow surgeons to remove just the affected part of a testicle - rather than the whole organ. The study, funded by the Medical Research Council, is published in The Lancet medical journal. One dose of carboplatin in the short term is as safe as radiation and it's less toxic 

 Nearly 2,000 men in the UK are diagnosed with testicular cancer each year and the incidence has doubled in the last 30 years. Most men are diagnosed when the cancer is confined to the testis, known as stage I disease. The most common type of stage I testicular cancer is seminoma, for which the standard treatment is surgery followed by a course of radiotherapy. Radiotherapy is extremely effective in preventing recurrence of the cancer, but there are potential side effects. There is a short term risk of temporary infertility and gastric irritation, and in the longer term more serious problems can include damage to the cardiovascular system and a slightly increased risk of developing new primary cancers in other organs. The latest study compared nearly 1,500 patients treated either with radiotherapy or carboplatin. A single injection of the drug was as effective in preventing recurrence as two to three weeks of daily radiotherapy. Two years after treatment 97.7% of the carboplatin group were free of cancer, compared to 96.7% of the radiotherapy group. In the three months after starting treatment, patients treated with carboplatin took less time off work and suffered substantially less lethargy than those having radiotherapy. They also appeared to be less likely to develop tumours in the remaining testicle. The risk was one in 200 in the carboplatin group, compared with one in 50 in the radiotherapy group. Lead researcher Professor Tim Oliver, from Barts and The London, Queen Mary's School of Medicine and Dentistry, said: &quot;This large trial establishes, after 20 years of research and uncertainty, that one dose of carboplatin in the short term is as safe as radiation and it's less toxic. &quot;It might also open the way to enabling lumpectomy surgery for stage I seminoma and using chemotherapy for testis conservation.&quot; Sally Stenning, senior statistician at the MRC Clinical Trials Unit said: &quot;We will need to follow patients for several more years before we can be certain that tumour recurrence has been prevented rather than just delayed, but these results are nevertheless extremely encouraging. &quot;They are particularly good news for those countries where radiotherapy equipment is scarce.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4700755.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Cot death expert defends evidence</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Professor Sir Roy Meadow is charged with professional misconduct over his evidence - Mrs Clark was jailed for killing two sons but cleared in 2003.

Sir Roy, who denies the charge, told the General Medical Council he used &quot;ball park figures&quot; in his evidence.

It comes as the Lancet journal said Sir Roy was a &quot;scapegoat&quot;, and the GMC case should not have been brought.

In a statement, Mrs Clark said she was &quot;incensed&quot; by the Lancet's controversial intervention.

Sally Clark was convicted of murdering her two baby sons, Christopher and Harry.

Sir Roy told the GMC hearing that at a committal hearing for Mrs Clark, he was asked by defence counsel about the one in 1,000 figure for sudden infant death syndrome.

He said he did not remember where the figure had come from, but when it appeared in an article he had written in an eminent paediatric journal, no one had questioned it.

Sir Roy said it was a &quot;reasonable ball park figure&quot; for the incidence of sudden infant death syndrome for the population as a whole.

He said he had squared it to reach a figure of one child per million for two such deaths in the same family

He then calculated that because of Sally Clark's age and the family's relative affluence, the likelihood in their case was one in 73 million - the figure he used during her trial.

It was later disputed by the Royal Statistical Society and other experts have said that once genetic and environmental factors are taken into consideration, the odds are closer to 200 to one.

Sir Roy said he took the one in 73 million figure to be a &quot;mean figure and there would be a degree of variation on either side&quot;.

But he told the GMC he did not see himself as an expert statistician.

&quot;Although I have published quite a lot of papers, it's been mainly qualitative work rather than quantative work.&quot;

Asked what view he took of the risk of recurrence in 1999, Prof Meadow said it was &quot;tiny, and for clinical purposes probably not meaningful&quot;.

He added that he had an interest in cases where there were a lot of deaths and knowledge of such details led him to take a particular interest in the recurrence rates of sudden infant death syndrome.

Sir Roy also gave evidence as an expert witness in the trials of two other women, Angela Cannings and Donna Anthony, who were both freed on appeal after being convicted of murdering their children.

He told the GMC he had concerns over the evidence he saw regarding both Harry and Christopher's deaths.

&quot;I could not think of natural causes for the two deaths,&quot; he said.

Sir Roy began his defence on the same day the Lancet published its commentary on the case.

Editor Dr Richard Horton said Sir Roy had been a &quot;lightning rod of blame&quot; for the wrongful conviction of Mrs Clark.

&quot;This misconceived pursuit of one man is wrong and threatens the effective delivery of child protection services in Britain.&quot;

But, in a statement, Mrs Clark and her husband Steve said: &quot;We are surprised that the editor of a respected professional journal felt it appropriate to publish such partisan comments like this at such a time,&quot; they said.

&quot;If the editor of a national newspaper had done the same in the middle of a criminal trial, on the day when the defence was due to open its case, then he might well have found himself in court for contempt for attempting to prejudice the outcome of the proceedings.&quot;

The case was adjourned until Monday morning when Prof Meadow will continue to give evidence.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4641587.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Scan choice to cut waiting lists</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The scheme will begin in November, and will use both spare NHS capacity and private contractors.

Initially it will be offered to patients waiting longer than 20 weeks for a MRI or CT scan.

By April 2006 it will be extended to patients waiting longer than 16 weeks for most imaging scans.

Under the new scheme, the maximum waiting time for a scan should fall to 20 weeks.

But doctors have expressed concerns about funds being diverted from the NHS to the private sector.

Announcing the scheme, Health Secretary Patricia Hewitt admitted that many patients were caught in a 'bottleneck' of waiting for a scan or other diagnostic service, before they are referred for an operation.

She said: &quot;We have already made it clear that by 2008 nobody will wait longer than 18 weeks from GP referral to their treatment in hospital.

&quot;Speedier access to diagnostic tests is an essential part of achieving that.

&quot;Whilst we build this capacity, I want to make sure that no patient has to wait longer than necessary for their scan if there is somewhere else in the NHS or independent sector that can provide it more quickly.&quot;

Ms Hewitt said the most serious cases, such as where a GP suspects cancer, are already fast-tracked for diagnostic tests.

&quot;However, those patients waiting for less urgent scans should still get them as soon as the NHS can provide.&quot;

Dr Paul Miller, chairman of the British Medical Association's consultants committee, expressed concern at the involvement of private sector units.

&quot;We think the NHS can do more for the money. Generally, we know that private providers have been costing more than the NHS.

&quot;Very broadly the private providers have been being funded at 10-15% more than the NHS when they have been doing things like cataract operations and hip operations.

Dr Miller also feared that the private sector would be able to cherry-pick straightforward cases.

&quot;We know that there are NHS scanners standing unused because of lack of funding to run them.

&quot;We should concentrate our funding on NHS scanners first of all before diverting funds away to private sector providers.

&quot;There are many trusts around the country that have got really severe financial problems, and if they lose a block of funding to a private sector provider that is only going to make the situation worse.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4713527.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Blast victims remain in hospital</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Many patients underwent surgery after losing limbs and suffering multiple injuries. Four victims are also being cared for at a specialist burns unit.

Hospitals called in extra staff and cancelled non-urgent surgery to deal with the injured under emergency plans.

Over 700 people were hurt and at least 50 died. People worried about relatives or friends should call 0870 1566 344.

Some 23 people have been admitted to University College Hospital, five of which are intensive care.

Professor Jim Ryan, a senior A&amp;E consultant at University College Hospital, which is still treating 23 people, said: &quot;Most of the operations are on limbs. You have penetrating wounds, indented stone, debris, glass or metal.

&quot;There is also head injury management, and lung inhalation and injuries to the chest.&quot;

He added many of the patients would be facing further surgery and complex care.

And doctors at Whitechapel's Royal London Hospital, which saw the most casualties with more than 200 people being brought in, are still treating 19 people, seven of which are in the intensive care.

A&amp;E clinical director Alastair Wilson said: &quot;There is still a lot of surgery to be done, probably over this weekend.

&quot;When you see so many people who have been injured unnecessarily that is not good. That has upset people.&quot;

The Royal Free Hospital in north London said 13 were still in hospital, five of whom had undergone surgery. All were in a stable condition, a spokeswoman said.

And St Mary's Hospital in Paddington is treating 10 people, two of which are in a critical condition.

Three of St Mary's patients have been transferred to Chelsea and Westminster Hospital's specialist burns unit, bringing the number there to four.

A spokeswoman for Chelsea and Westminster said they were being assessed by a team of plastic surgeons.

Eleven people are still at Guy's and St Thomas's, near Waterloo, one in a critical condition. The others are all in a stable condition, and four of them are expected to undergo surgery later.

A spokeswoman said: &quot;Patients are being treated for smoke inhalation, burns and serious limb and chest injuries.&quot;

And Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, which set up makeshift facilities under its major incident plan as it does not have an A&amp;E department, still has four blast casualties.

Home Secretary Charles Clarke said: &quot;There are a number of people terribly injured in hospital still and we don't know how they're going to survive or not.&quot;

Casualties have received visits from Health Secretary Patricia Hewitt and Prince Charles.

Speaking at the Royal Free Hospital, Ms Hewitt praised the NHS response, saying hospitals were &quot;almost immediately ready and could have coped with far more people had they needed to&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4663671.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Men 'in denial' over weight gain</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Official statistics show that 65% of adult men are overweight or obese, but the survey of over 2,000 men found only 40% thought they were in these groups.

Most of the men questioned were unaware being overweight or obese, or inactive, increases the risk of cancer.

Experts urged overweight men to become more active and eat a balanced diet rich in fruit and vegetables.

The survey was released to launch Cancer Research UK's Man Alive Campaign.

Around 65% of those questioned had no idea that being overweight or obese increased their chance of developing cancer, with 75% not aware that being physically inactive also increased their risk.

The survey also found just 22% of those questioned eat five portions of fruit and vegetables per day, and two-thirds fail to meet the recommended target of 30 minutes of moderate exercise five times a week.

Cancer Research UK experts said men were not heeding health warnings to maintain a healthy body weight.

They warned obesity could be responsible for as many as 40,005 cases of cancer in UK men every year.

Recently published research suggested obesity increases the risk of bowel cancer by 60%.

Being obese also doubles the risk of being diagnosed with kidney, oesophageal and stomach cancer, as well as being a risk factor for bladder cancer.

Good diet and regular exercise are two factors that can help in reducing the risk of developing cancer, they said.

Professor Jane Wardle, the director of Cancer Research UK's Health Behaviour Unit, said: &quot;In the space of 10 years, the rate of obesity for British men has increased two thirds.

&quot;Women are overweight too but our research shows that more of them know they have a problem and that's the first step in putting it right.&quot;

She added: &quot;Men need to be made aware of the problem, know how to fix the problem and be given the support to succeed.

&quot;Only then will they reduce their risk of cancer.&quot;

Dr Lesley Walker, director of information at Cancer Research UK, said: &quot;It's vital that men understand how they can reduce their risk of cancer.

&quot;The best present that anyone can give themselves is to stop smoking, it is by far the most important step in reducing cancer risk.&quot;

But she added: &quot;In men who don't smoke, obesity is one of the biggest known causes of preventable cancer.

&quot;With rates of obesity for UK men growing faster than anywhere else in Europe, we are sounding a wake up call to all men and their partners to become more active, eat healthier diets and make sensible lifestyle choices.

&quot;To lose those spare tyres, be more active and eat a balanced diet that is rich in fruit and veg and low in sugar and fat.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4642547.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Doctors 'fear criminal charges'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Medics can be charged with involuntary manslaughter if they make a mistake because of reckless behaviour.

Doctors argue the law is too open to interpretation and needs reforming. Prosecutions used to be rare, but have risen sharply since 1990.

The Home Office said the issue was likely to be looked at in its murder review, to be launched shortly.

Involuntary manslaughter is defined as when an individual kills someone as a result of some blameworthy act on their part, but without actually intending to cause death or serious injury.

The offence has long being controversial because of its lack of clarity - nine years ago the Law Commission called for its abolition on those grounds.

Prosecution of doctors used to be rare - from 1867 to 1989 there were only seven cases, according to British Medical Journal research.

But during the 1990s, 17 doctors were charged with the offence, which is also known as criminal negligence, and since 2000 another 11 have been charged.

Cases have involved doctors being charged following deaths of patients during surgery and after being given medication.

Dr Paddy Glackin, a GP from Brent, in London, put forward a motion on the issue to the British Medical Association's annual conference in Manchester last week.

He said prosecutions should be stopped until the law was reformed.

&quot;It used to be that if you made a genuine mistake and a patient died you would not face charges. That is not the case anymore.

&quot;Prosecutions are being pursued arbitrarily, and it is unfair because too much is left to interpretation.&quot;

Ian Barker, a solicitor in the Medical Defence Union's legal department, said the rise in prosecutions had occurred because the definition of the offence had been relaxed and because society had become more litigious.

And he added: &quot;What you will not see in the statistics is that there has been a significant rise in those doctors that are investigated, but not charged.&quot;

Dr Jan Wise, chairman of the BMA's medico-legal committee, said it was concerning as doctors could often face months of not being able to practice while unfounded allegations were followed up.

He said: &quot;It is a serious matter.&quot;

A spokeswoman for the Home Office said there was set to be a murder review in the forthcoming months which would look at a host of issues and concerns, including those raised about involuntary manslaughter.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4642743.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-20</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Smoking 'could increase TB risk'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A team from Stellenbosch University, in South Africa, studied 2,400 people living in Cape Town.

Some 82% of those who smoked, or who had done previously for at least a year, tested positive for TB, compared with 70% in the non-smokers' group.

Writing in Thorax, the researchers say smoking might reduce the ability of the lungs to fight off infections.

All those who took part in the study were asked about their smoking habits and given a tuberculin skin test to check if they were infected with TB.

People were defined as smokers if they had ever smoked for at least a year.

Smokers were also asked the average number of cigarettes they had smoked each day.

Basic information such as age, sex, education level, body mass index, and income was also taken into account.

Of 1,309 current smokers or ex-smokers, 1,070 (82%) had a positive skin test, compared with 70% (762) of the 1092 people who had never smoked.

The more cigarettes someone had smoked over their life, the higher the risk was that they would have a positive test.

The researchers, led by Dr Saskia de Boon, from the Desmond Tutu TB Centre at Stellenbosch University, said the reason for the link was not confirmed.

But they said smoking could reduce the lungs' ability to fight off infections, including TB.

They stress further evidence is needed to investigate the association.

And they said they could not discount the possibility that the link between TB infection and smoking was merely down to socio-economic and behavioural differences.

Writing in Thorax, Dr Graham Bothamley, of the East London TB Network, based at the Homerton Hospital, said: &quot;The association of smoking with pulmonary TB might be explained by a reduced specific immunity and possibly enhanced non-specific inflammatory response.&quot;

Dr Peter Ormerod, of the British Thoracic Society, said: &quot;This study supports other evidence showing an association between smoking and TB risk.

&quot;Smoking damages macrophages in the lungs, which are the first line of defence against infections.

&quot;People who smoked would therefore be more at risk of acquiring TB.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4638449.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-21</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Breast cancer drug fast-tracked</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Patricia Hewitt intervened after concern Herceptin was being denied to patients who could benefit.

The National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence (NICE) will now assess whether the drug should be made widely available on the NHS.

Herceptin is already used to treat women with advanced breast cancer.

It is specifically targeted at the one in four patients who have a form of the disease known as HER2 positive breast cancer.

But it is not yet licensed for treating breast cancer in its early stages.

However, preliminary tests have shown the drug is effective when given to these patients.

But more work needs to be done to be certain that the benefits of the treatment outweigh any potentially damaging side effects.

Ms Hewitt said she had asked NICE to start work on assessing the drug as soon as possible so it is in a position to act quickly if and when the drug receives a licence.

The manufacturer, Roche, says it is likely to apply for a licence next year. A licence may granted within two or three months of the application.

Ms Hewitt said: &quot;I have the deepest sympathy for the pain and suffering that cancer patients and their families experience and completely understand why they want to see any drug that can help made more widely available.&quot;

He said: &quot;Preliminary results on the use of Herceptin for early stage breast cancer are encouraging and it is important that the NHS receives timely advice on the clinical and cost effectiveness of these treatments.&quot;

John Melville, general manager of Roche UK, said: &quot;We are doing everything within our power to gain a European marketing licence for early stage HER2 positive breast cancer patients as soon as possible, and we estimate a decision will be made by the European medicines regulatory agency (EMEA) between July and November 2006.&quot;

The charity CancerBACUP highlighted delays in patients accessing Herceptin in a report earlier this year.

Spokesperson Derryn Borley said: &quot;Cancer patients who call our helpline want to know how soon they can get access to outstanding new treatments.

&quot;It is important that the entire system of assessing cancer treatments is speeded up, from licensing to NICE guidance for use in the NHS.&quot;

Professor Alan Ashworth, of Breakthrough Breast Cancer, said: &quot;Now that NICE have agreed to fast track the appraisal of Herceptin it's absolutely vital that it is licensed, and urgent consideration is given to enable access to standard testing for HER2 at diagnosis, if the potential benefits of this drug to save lives are to be realised quickly.&quot;

BUPA, the major medical insurance company, announced this week that it would pay for patients with early stage breast cancer to use Herceptin.

Dr Natalie-Jane Macdonald, BUPA medical director, said: &quot;Historically we have funded Herceptin as a treatment for late stage breast cancer in line with its current licence.

&quot;However, given the impressive results of recent trials, we have decided to fund it for the treatment early stage breast cancer for HER2 positive patients because we believe it will directly benefit women with this diagnosis, and their families.&quot;

Mrs Hewitt has also asked NICE to fast track assessment of Velcade, a drug for the treatment of multiple myeloma.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4702535.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-22</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Warning over maternity care risk</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Healthcare Commission highlighted overcrowding, dirty toilets, a shortage of midwives and inadequate organisation after investigations at three units.

Health Minister Liam Bryne admitted services were &quot;not yet good enough&quot; and said an action plan was being drawn up.

The commission blamed bad management for the problems. It is due to publish a broader report on the NHS on Monday.

The investigations - at three units that have suffered high mortality rates in the last two years - also found doctors who did not explain what was happening to patients, and staff too busy to advise on feeding and bathing of new babies.

Sir Ian Kennedy, who chaired the report, called on NHS trusts in England and Wales to review their maternity services because of huge differences between the best and worst.

He blamed a lack of effective leadership and management in units which were failing to achieve high standards. Staff training and the ability to work in teams was also lacking.

&quot;I find it surprising that a service like the NHS, with so many dedicated people working in it, can have pockets of really poor practice, where we have not learned from the wisdom and knowledge and experience that has been put around for a long time as to how to deliver babies in a safe manner, and how to look after mothers.

&quot;We are still not doing it as well as we should, and it is a matter that we need to get a grip on.&quot;

The majority of the 650,000-plus births every year in the UK take place in NHS hospitals.

&quot;However services are not yet good enough to meet the needs of all women and babies, wherever they live and whoever they are, and that is why the government continues in reforming, as well as investing in, maternity services in the UK.&quot;

Shadow health secretary Andrew Lansley said: &quot;These findings from the Healthcare Commission are deeply worrying.

&quot;They show that despite increasing resources for the NHS, a lack of genuine reform means resources are wasted and services are not held accountable for the standards they meet and to the wishes of patients.&quot;

Mikaela Morris, a senior midwife at St Peter's Hospital in Surrey, which was investigated by the commission, said her unit had suffered from a shortage of midwives.

At one stage they were operating with about 70 when they needed 100.

&quot;It is a big national problem. We have not had enough people wanting to become midwives.&quot;

But she urged people to join the profession, saying while it could have &quot;tragic moments&quot; it was &quot;very very rewarding&quot;.

The report into the broader NHS is expected to show that staff shortages, aged buildings, poor training and weak management are hitting standards.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4691977.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-23</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Co-op bans additives from foods</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The company said it had decided to remove the additives after concerns about their effects on children and others sensitive to their effects.

Food additives have been linked to hyperactivity in children.

But nutritionists said, while some might be intolerant to additives, there was insufficient evidence to link them to such behavioural disorders.

The Co-op ban covers 12 colourings, all of which are legally permitted.

The Co-op has now banned a total of 21 colourings.

The chain said some are already illegal in the US and Japan.

Natural alternatives to the colourings and monosodium glutamate are now being used in many foods.

But 27 products, including pink and white marshmallows, canned strawberries in syrup and Chinese style spare ribs, have been axed because no replacements could be found.

The store's crisps, and its chicken and mushroom pasta sauce are among the products no longer containing MSG - which is used as a flavour enhancer.

Sweets such as dolly mixtures and flying saucers no longer contain colourings such as Quinoline Yellow (E104), Cochineal (E120), and Indigo Carmine (E132).

Christine Clarke, head of Co-op brand, said: &quot;The removal of MSG and these colours is in direct response to these concerns and the Co-op brand food range now has no added MSG and is free of these colours, even though we have had to de-list a number of products as a result.&quot;

A spokesman for the British Dietary Association said: &quot;E numbers have all been given a European classification, which means they've all been tested and are safe.

&quot;But the additives which the Co-op are removing are some of the prime suspects that do cause intolerances in a small number of people - although not as many as you might think.

He added: &quot;It is pleasing that the Co-op has done this. But we would not want people to think all E numbers are bad.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4670953.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-24</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Day surgery theatres under-used</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Healthcare Commission found 45% of the theatre time in England allocated for day surgery was going to waste.

It put the blame on cancelled operations, late starts, and excessive delays between operations.

The commission said using day surgery more efficiently could reduce pressure on ward beds, bring down waiting lists and improve care for patients.

Its report found at least an extra 74,000 patients a year could have day surgery, rather than be admitted as inpatients, if the least efficient units started employing the practices of the best.

This would release inpatient beds for operations on other patients.

The report follows a warning from Health Secretary Patricia Hewitt that high levels of investment in the NHS will not continue indefinitely - and that efficiency savings must be made.

Anna Walker, chief executive of the Healthcare Commission, said: &quot;When patients stay overnight for something which could be done in a single day, patients are inconvenienced and resources are wasted.

&quot;NHS trusts need to investigate why more day surgery is not being done and do all that they can to reduce cancellations.&quot;

The Healthcare Commission will discuss its findings with individual trusts.

The report, which examined 313 day surgery units in England, found one in 10 cancelled more than a third of the available operating theatre sessions and many patients had their operations cancelled at short notice.

Staff numbers in day surgery units were found to be rising faster than their activity.

But in nearly 40% of day surgery units no single consultant was in charge - a factor, the report says, which may be hampering more efficient use of resources.

The total number of day surgery admissions for 25 common procedures increased by 12% over the last four years.

However, much of this was down to a big increase in cataract surgery. The proportion of day surgery cases for a number of common procedures actually went down.

The report said there had been improvements in booking procedures, and in providing patients with information about their operation.

A Department of Health spokesman said the NHS Plan, published in 2000, stressed that day surgery was often a good option for patients, who can recover in the comfort of their own homes.

&quot;Over the last few years, the NHS Modernisation Agency has worked with the NHS to promote and improve day surgery.

&quot;As the Healthcare Commission report shows, there is scope for further improvement.

&quot;We will continue to support the NHS in this area, as part of our pledge to ensure that by December 2008, no patient waits more than 18 weeks from GP referral to the start of their treatment.&quot;

Around 740,000 day surgery operations are performed in England each year.

Procedures appropriate for day surgery include hernia repair, tonsillectomies, and removal of ganglions.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4664109.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-25</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | North-South cancer divide mapped</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Office for National Statistics &quot;Cancer Atlases&quot; for the 1990s show an obvious North-South divide for cancers.

Scots and Northerners are more prone to lung and stomach cancer, which appear to be linked to smoking and alcohol use as well as socio-economic deprivation.

The ONS estimates that over 25,000 of the cancers and 17,000 of the cancer deaths could be preventable - around three quarters by helping smokers quit and drinkers cut down on their alcohol consumption.

The incidence and death rates for cancers of the lung, larynx, lip, mouth and pharynx - all known to be related to heavy smoking and alcohol intake - were lower than average in the south and midlands of England, but higher than average across the north of England and Scotland between 1991 and 2000.

Geographical patterns for bladder, kidney, oesophageal (gullet) and stomach cancers were similar.

Scotland also came out worse for colorectal cancer, along with Ireland and Northern Ireland.

Rates of cervical cancer were higher than average in the north of England, urban west midlands and, again, in Scotland, but were not related to local cancer screening differences.

There was little geographical variation in the incidence and death rates of breast, ovary and prostate cancers, however. The ONS looked at 21 different cancers overall.

The incidence of all cancers combined in Scotland, England and Wales rose gradually over the 1970s and 1980s then levelled off in the 1990s to over 270,000, partly due to better diagnosis, says the ONS.

The most common remain lung, colorectal, breast and prostate cancer.

A Department of Health spokeswoman said the data would help the NHS plan its work towards beating cancer.

&quot;It is crucial that preventative actions to help people lead a healthy lifestyle are implemented first in those areas where prevalence of cancer is particularly high.

&quot;This is why we have recently established a group of the 88 most health deprived areas in England who will be the first to pilot initiatives such as health trainers and enhanced Stop Smoking Services as set out in the White Paper on Public Health.&quot;

She said the data in this report pre-dated the Cancer Plan, which was published in 2000 and set out a comprehensive programme of work over 10 years aimed at tackling cancer inequalities.

&quot;Five years in, we are seeing results - there has been a 12% reduction in cancer mortality since 1997 - well on the way to achieving the Government's aim of a 20% reduction by 2010.&quot;

Dr Lesley Walker of Cancer Research UK, said: &quot;We know that half of all cancers - equivalent to around 135,000 cases a year in the UK - could be prevented by changes to lifestyle.&quot;

He said tackling exposure to secondhand smoke at work, which causes more than 600 deaths each year across the UK, would help and backed a new call for a total ban on smoking in public plances.

Cancer Research UK's Chief Executive, Professor Alex Markham, said: &quot;All workers have a right to work in a smokefree environment, and a comprehensive ban on smoking in enclosed public places - without exemptions - is the only practical way we can give them the protection they deserve.

&quot;Ireland has shown that smokefree legislation works best when it contains as few exemptions as possible. Scotland's courage in adopting similarly comprehensive legislation sets yet another example to Westminster.&quot;

Macmillan Cancer Relief said money must be invested to identify the barriers that are preventing some disadvantaged groups from accessing cancer services.

Conservative Shadow Health Secretary Andrew Lansley said: &quot;There are a range of socio-economic factors that contribute to the North-South divide in cancer rates. But there are still measures, such as the even distribution of vital drugs, which the government has failed to introduce.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4651669.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-26</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Blast injured remain in hospital</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>More than 700 people were hurt and at least 50 died in Thursday's attacks, with many people still missing.

Hospitals called in extra staff and cancelled non-urgent surgery to deal with the injured, but have now returned to normal working conditions.

People worried about relatives or friends should call 0870 1566 344.

Dr Andres Izquierdo-Martin, accident and emergency consultant at the Royal Free Hospital, in north London, which is still treating five people, one in intensive care, said it was obvious when they saw the injured coming in that there had been a blast.

&quot;The injuries were smoke inhalation, burns all around the face and shrapnel.&quot;

He said the priority was to stabilise the injured and move them to the wards for more treatment.

Dr Izquierdo-Martin said the atmosphere was very calm and professional.

&quot;The staff are used to dealing with the injuries. We were working as a normal casualty again within a few hours.&quot;

He said they were already preparing for the next event, should there be one.

University College Hospital is still treating 14 people, five who are in intensive care for serious injuries.

The Royal London Hospital, near Liverpool Street Station, is treating 16 patients - seven in intensive care.

The hospital treated 208 of people injured in the explosions overall. Of these, 27 were admitted. One patient died. All of the others have been discharged.

Chelsea and Westminster Hospital has two blast victims being treated in their specialist burns unit, after four have already been released.

St Mary's Hospital, in Paddington, is treating five people. One is still in a critical condition while the other four have injuries ranging from serious to minor.

Fourteen people are still at Guy's and St Thomas's, near Waterloo, one in a critical condition but stable.

All of the blast victims treated at Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, which set up makeshift facilities under its major incident plan as it does not have an A&amp;E department, have since been discharged.

Charing Cross Hospital has one casualty who is stable after discharging another one over the weekend. Both had been transferred from St Mary's.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4672427.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-27</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | 'Disparities' in UK's healthcare</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Nuffield Trust report is the first to assess the health service UK-wide since devolution.

The report highlights a growing health gap between rich and poor, and an &quot;unrelenting rise&quot; in cases of the superbug MRSA.

It also found waits for operations are longer in Wales and Northern Ireland than in England and Scotland.

The report shows that in September 2004 7% of patients in Scotland and 9% of patients in England had waited for more than six months for an operation. In Wales the figure was a massive 36%.

It also looks at individual clinical proceedures. For instance, not a single hospital in Wales is meeting the target of giving clot busting drugs to heart attack patients with 60 minutes of the time of call to the emergency services.

The report contains more than a 160 pages of charts with summaries that assess and compare services across the UK, and with other developed countries.

As well as the effectiveness of healthcare services, it looks at access to treatment, resourcing, safety, and disparities between different parts of the UK.

The data will be updated regularly to provide policy-makers and patients with the latest information.

The report attempts to rationalise the often-conflicting information about how the health service is doing.

The Health Foundation, an independent research charity, says the report will be hugely influential and important.

Stephen Thornton, the foundation's chief executive, said: &quot;It's the first time anything like this had been done - giving a clear picture of how the NHS is doing.&quot;

He said that the foundation would invest £2.5m over the next five years to enable the report to be updated online -to be used as a benchmark by policy-makers, patients and the media.

Mr Thornton added that the Health Foundation would also develop the report's findings to assess the issue of value for money - whether the recent big increases in NHS funding had been well-spent.

A Department of Health spokeswoman said: &quot;We welcome the report which outlines some impressive successes in improving the quality of healthcare in the UK.

&quot;There are significant benefits from knowing this information as it provides a basis for improving the quality of healthcare and performance.

&quot;We will therefore look at this report closely, particularly as in some instances the data used from different sources presents a conflicting picture of performance.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4657459.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-28</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | GMC finds Clark professor guilty</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>GMC members are now considering whether this amounts to serious professional misconduct and if so what sanctions, if any, to impose.

Sir Roy has stood by his evidence, but admitted his use of statistics at Mrs Clark's 1999 trial was &quot;insensitive&quot;.

Mrs Clark was convicted of murdering her two sons, but exonerated in 2003.

During the trial, Sir Roy said the probability of two natural unexplained cot deaths in the family was 73 million to one.

The figure was later disputed by the Royal Statistical Society and other experts have said that once genetic and environmental factors are taken into consideration, the odds are closer to 200 to one.

The GMC ruled on Wednesday that Sir Roy did not intend to mislead in evidence he gave at Mrs Clark's trial.

However, members of the disciplinary panel decided his overall evidence was misleading and that he &quot;erroneously implied&quot; that two deaths in a family would be independent of one another.

Mrs Clark was eventually freed after it become apparent that another witness at her trial, pathologist Alan Williams, had failed to disclose key medical evidence.

Putting the case for the GMC at the start of the hearing, Robert Seabrook QC said Sir Roy had been a pre-eminent paediatrician and child expert with many achievements during a long career.

However, he said he had been in breach of his duties as an expert witness in the Clark trial.

&quot;He either didn't understand what he was doing, should not have given evidence and was incompetent to do so, or he was using the information carelessly in support of the proposition that Sally Clark smothered her babies.&quot;

Giving evidence, Sir Roy defended the calculations he used to arrive at the 73 million to one figure.

But he said he regretted comparing the odds of two cot deaths in the same family to that of a punter successfully backing an 80-1 shot at the Grand National four years in a row.

&quot;The situation in which I was giving evidence was one in which there was a family grieving, two children had died and the mother had been accused of murder,&quot; he told the hearing.

&quot;To raise a subject like the Grand National, that is exciting and vibrant, is insensitive and I should have thought of more appropriate odds.&quot;

Sir Roy also gave evidence as an expert witness in the trials of two other women, Angela Cannings and Donna Anthony, who were both freed on appeal after being convicted of murdering their children.

Speaking outside the hearing, Mrs Clark's father Frank Lockyer said: &quot;No one is in any doubt that the evidence on which my daughter was convicted was seriously flawed.

&quot;This hearing was first and foremost about culpability and accountability which seems to have been well and truly settled.&quot;

The hearing, which was adjourned until Thursday, heard testimonies from leading paediatricians in support of Sir Roy, who retains a great deal of respect within the medical profession.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4679113.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-29</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Neonatal units 'are overwhelmed'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Most said they had not been able to take any more sick and premature babies because they had had too few nurses.

Charity Bliss, which surveyed 153 units, found this led to many babies having to travel hundreds of miles for a cot, and called for more investment.

The Department of Health said it was considering the evidence from Bliss.

Bliss said putting in 2,700 additional nurses could save the lives of up to 500 babies a year.

The UK has some of the worst perinatal (up to seven days after birth) and infant mortality rates for Western Europe.

Death rates for babies and infants increased in 2003 for the first time in many years, from 5.2 deaths per 1,000 to 5.3 per 1,000.

Perinatal mortality figures for that year were the worst since 1996, at 8.5 per 1,000.

There are also wide variations in infant mortality rates across the country. In parts of Scotland, a baby is three times as likely to die before its first birthday than in the south of England.

Bliss says £75m would pay for the staff increase needed to give adequate care in neonatal care units, allowing those in intensive care to receive the same one-to-one nursing that children and adults are entitled to.

Only 2% of units currently achieve that standard, which is set down by the British Association of Perinatal Medicine.

Of the 153 units who responded to the survey - carried out by the National Perinatal Epidemiology Unit, on Bliss' behalf -72% said they had closed their doors to new admissions at least once in the preceding six months.

Bliss said one hospital, St Michael's in Bristol, had only been able to take new admissions on three days out of 30 in June this year.

A spokeswoman for the trust said it worked with other hospitals in the area so they could take referrals when it was full.

The Bliss survey found units did take babies where they could - 95% reported they had accepted more babies than they felt they should have done.

Rob Williams, chief executive of Bliss, said: &quot;More and more babies are being born prematurely. Each year, more are surviving.&quot;

He said a baby born weighing 2lb (0.9kg) 20 years ago had a 20% chance of surviving, but that had now increased to 80%.

But Mr Williams added: &quot;This report puts the spotlight on a health service that remains severely under-resourced even while other parts of the NHS are seeing big improvements.&quot;

Bliss has also launched a &quot;bill of rights&quot; for babies, outlining their right to high quality, sensitive care.

'More to do'

Professor Neil Marlow, of the British Association of Perinatal Medicine, said: &quot;It is vital that neonatal services and the government continually review provision of care, so we can improve the outlook for these vulnerable infants.

&quot;This report highlights some critical shortfalls that still need to be addressed.&quot;

A spokeswoman for the Department of Health said, while mothers and babies needed to be cared for as close to home as possible, some babies needed specialised care.

But she added: &quot;There is clearly more to do.&quot;

She said the department would consider the evidence from Bliss to see where more could be achieved.

Shadow Health Secretary Andrew Lansley said: &quot;It is vital we give paediatric services dedicated resources and structure to ensure service capacity, staffing and standards can be enhanced.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4679599.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-30</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Shake-up of NHS dentistry planned</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Ministers propose three bands of charges, setting maximum prices for different levels of treatment.

Under the plans a general check-up would cost £15 and a filling £41. Treatment would cost a maximum of £183.

It is hoped the long-waited measures - already put back 12 months - will help address some of the long-standing problems with NHS dentistry.

They include plans for a new contract for dentists, which will see them paid for the overall service they provide to a patient, rather than for each separate treatment.

Latest figures show that half the population are not registered with a surgery.

There is also a shortfall of 1,800 dentists as many have been attracted into doing private work where they say they can spend more time with patients.

The average NHS dentists sees about 50 patients a day - twice the number private dentists do - as they are paid per treatment they carry out.

Currently, there are over 400 different charges for dental work.

Patients, who can pay up to £384, often do not know what the total cost will be before they start treatment.

The cost of a check-up is currently £6, but ministers say the new £15 charge will cover a more comprehensive oral health assessment, which could include x-rays, scale and polish.

Guidelines from the National Institute for Health and Clinical Excellence suggest most people do not need a six-monthly check-up. Some may only need to see a dentist once every 18 months.

Health Minister Rosie Winterton said the new system would be less confusing and boost oral health by providing more preventative advice.

&quot;Many people complain that they don't understand their bills, and are confused over what is NHS and what is private treatment.

&quot;The new dental charging system will enable dentists to give a simple answer to patients' question 'what is my NHS treatment going to cost?' and 'what treatment will I get for the money?'

&quot;The new system is fairer for patients. Those with low treatment needs will attend less often, and patients with high treatment needs should find their NHS dental treatment cheaper.&quot;

Roger Goss, co-director of Patient Concern, was concerned about fees for basic care rising.

&quot;If it costs more to go to see a dentists I do not think that will be conducive to good dental health. It is more likely to deter people going.&quot;

The British Dental Association said the current system was not working for either dentists or patients as there were too many different prices for treatment.

She said the new system needed to be more simple.

The proposals will be put out for a three month period of consultation.

Shadow Health Minister Andrew Murrison said: &quot;To most people, a visit to the dentist is for a check-up and minor work such as fillings.

&quot;The fact that these charges have doubled means that more people will pay more under Labour, which does little to encourage a preventative approach.

&quot;Moreover, there is every danger that cheaper emergency care will replace the now expensive check-up.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4657355.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-31</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Elderly face years of ill health</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A House of Lords Science and Technology Committee report says more must be done to make older people healthier and to improve their quality of life.

It calls on the government to apply scientific resources to improve health in old age.

And says the elderly must be helped to live longer in their own homes.

Lord Sutherland of Houndwood, who chaired the inquiry, said: &quot;At a time when people are living longer, their last years should be years of good health and active engagement in society.

&quot;Instead, older people believe their last years are increasingly a time of ill health and isolation.

&quot;The government should do much more to support ageing-related research and to promote its application.&quot;

The committee said simple measures could make a big difference.

For instance, locating scanners in A&amp;E departments could reduce death and disability from strokes.

At present less than half of patients have a brain scan within two days.

Better use of funds

The report found NHS targets are vague, and that resources are spent to meet treatment targets, when they might be more effectively spent on prevention strategies.

It calls for investment in technologies which allow people to monitor health in their own homes.

It also calls for action on social and economic factors, which it says greatly influence the rate of ageing.

For instance, older people often die of diseases caused by cold and damp.

The government has said it aims to eliminate fuel poverty by 2010 but the report says that without more resources it will miss this target.

It also criticises the government's failure to implement a review of housing standards.

Transport and communication must be planned with an ageing population in mind to guard against social isolation, the report says.

It also calls for funding to promote exercise and healthy eating.

Dr James Goodwin, head of research at Help the Aged, said &quot;For the first time in history, the number of people aged over 65 in the UK exceeds those under 16.

&quot;Quite simply, we are sitting on a demographic time bomb. We are completely unprepared for the fact that our baby boomer generation will sooner rather than later be hitting their 70s and 80s.

&quot;If we don't place more resources into ageing research now we will be unable to cope with the implications of age-related disease, dependence and frailty in 20 years time.&quot;

Dr Goodwin expressed disappointment that the inquiry did not recommended setting up a National Institute on Ageing to centrally coordinate ageing research in the UK</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4701207.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-32</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Patient loses right-to-food case</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Leslie Burke, 45, who has a degenerative brain condition, fears artificial nutrition could be stopped against his wishes when he cannot talk.

Mr Burke, from Lancaster, had won a landmark ruling, supporting his right to artificial nutrition and hydration.

But the GMC appealed, saying doctors could be put in an impossible position.

Following the Appeal Court verdict, the GMC said it hoped Mr Burke was now reassured he would receive the treatment he needs, including artificial nutrition and hydration and that nothing in its guidance prevented this.

Mr Burke has cerebellar ataxia - an umbrella term for nervous system disorders that cause a lack of co-ordination, but do not affect mental faculties.

He knows he will one day lose the power of speech and control of his limbs.

Artificial nutrition is classed as a form of treatment by the GMC and therefore last July's ruling, which was hailed as a breakthrough for the rights of terminally-ill patients, raised questions about medical interventions.

In the original case, Mr Burke argued the GMC's advice, which gives doctors in cases such as his the ultimate say on what treatment to give a patient in the final stages, was an infringement of his human rights.

But during the appeal hearing, Philip Havers, QC, representing the GMC, said the original ruling had fundamentally altered the nature of doctor/patient relationships and was not in the best interests of the patient.

He said doctors would have to provide treatment which they knew would be of no benefit or could even be harmful.

GMC president Professor Sir Graeme Catto said &quot;Patients should be reassured by this judgement which emphasises the partnership needed to resolve end of life issues.&quot;

&quot;Our guidance makes it clear that patients should never be discriminated against on the grounds of disability.&quot;

And he added the GMC had always maintained that no patient would die from starvation and dehydration.

Mr Burke said: &quot;Obviously I am disappointed that I have not got all that I wished for.

&quot;I have every wish to take it to the House of Lords even though for me personally I should be OK.&quot;

He was refused permission to take the case to the Law Lords, but can petition the house for a hearing.

Dr Vivienne Nathanson, the British Medical Association's head of ethics and science, which supported the GMC case, said decisions about curtailing treatment were &quot;one of the hardest choices&quot; to make.

She said the judgement was a welcome &quot;clarification&quot;.

But Joyce Robins, co-director of human rights campaign group Patient Concern, which helped argue Mr Burke should have the right to food and water, said the decision was &quot;a huge step backwards for patients&quot;.

And Liz Sayce, of the Disability Rights Commission, said she was still concerned that the wishes of all patients might not be respected.

&quot;The judgement is fine for people who have the capacity to speak. But the difficulty is when you don't have that capacity, it will be back to the doctor taking the decision entirely themselves.&quot;

Voluntary Euthanasia Society chief executive Deborah Annetts urged the government to step in to create a comprehensive framework for end of life decision-making to create a &quot;better partnership between patients and doctors&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4721061.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-33</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Blast victims remain in hospital</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Doctors worked through the night treating the injured for burns, amputations and multiple body injuries.

Many hospitals called in extra staff as they instigated their emergency plans.

More than 700 people were hurt and 37 died in the four blasts. People worried about relatives or friends are being advised to call 0870 1566 344.

Home Secretary Charles Clarke said he expected the death toll to rise.

&quot;There are a number of people terribly injured in hospital still and we don't know how they're going to survive or not - and so I'm not going to speculate on figures - but I do think it will be higher than 37,&quot;

Whitechapel's Royal London Hospital saw the most casualties with more than 200 people being brought in - of those 26 remained in hospital on Friday, seven in the intensive care unit and 19 on wards.

Senior consultant Laurence Gant said in a statement: &quot;The Royal London Hospital was fully staffed last night. All staff due on duty made their way into work despite transport difficulties.

&quot;We are continuing to treat inpatients from yesterday's incident.&quot;

The Royal Free Hospital in north London said 13 were still in hospital, five of whom had undergone surgery. All were in a stable condition, a spokeswoman said.

Some 27 people have been admitted to University College Hospital, four are said to be in a serious condition.

Professor Jim Ryan, a senior A&amp;E consultant who is leading the major incident team, said: &quot;The characteristic injury of a terrorist incident is multiple injuries to multiple body systems, and that is what we have seen.&quot;

A dozen people are being treated at Guy's and St Thomas's, near Waterloo.

A spokeswoman said: &quot;Patients are being treated for smoke inhalation, burns and serious limb and chest injuries.&quot;

Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, which set up makeshift facilities under its major incident plan as it does not have an A&amp;E department, treated 22 people - 18 of which stayed overnight.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4659641.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-34</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Dirty hospitals to escape charges</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Launching a consultation on the plans, ministers expressed concern that hospitals might not disclose relevant details in order to avoid prosecution.

Large fines were also ruled out because of the possible impact on patient care.

However, hospital bosses could be sacked for failing to tackle problems such as superbugs.

Health Secretary Patricia Hewitt had originally said in May that failing hospitals could face prosecution.

The measures to crack down on hospital hygiene are contained in a statutory code which would apply to all NHS bodies, independent healthcare providers and care homes.

The Healthcare Commission would be responsible for monitoring whether these institutions were complying with the code.

Any that failed to meet the hygiene standards would be issued with an &quot;improvement notice&quot; stipulating the action that the body should take and within what timescale.

If the organisation met the standards in the required time period, no further action would be taken.

However, if it failed, the Healthcare Commission would then refer the case up to the Secretary of State (or the Monitor if it is a Foundation Trust).

In some circumstances, this might lead to the dismissal of the trust board or individual members.

Ministers said the sanctions were likely to be applied only in &quot;the most exceptional circumstances&quot;.

Health minister Patricia Hewitt told BBC Radio 4's Today programme: &quot;The ultimate sanction here, if you have a hospital that simply isn't getting to grips with the problem, is you would get rid of the senior official who wasn't getting the job done.&quot;

She said the government had stopped short of suggesting criminal prosecutions because of concerns hospitals might be tempted not to disclose relevant information.

The threat of large fines was also rejected as sums big enough to have an impact were likely to affect patient care.

Similar proposals will be extended to the private and voluntary health care sectors and to care homes, she said.

Ms Hewitt said she believed that hospitals would take the new measures &quot;extremely seriously&quot;.

&quot;What we wanted was a system that would ensure very fast action and an absolute focus on making our hospitals safe.

&quot;If they are not doing enough to get infections under control and if the Healthcare Commission is telling them `Here are the steps you have got to take in our statutory improvement notice' and they know their jobs are on the line, that is tough stuff and I have no doubt at all it will work.&quot;

Dr Gill Morgan, chief executive of the NHS Confederation, said: &quot;We are delighted that the government proposals published today reject the option of introducing criminal sanctions against NHS trusts if the code of practice is breached - singling out individual managers for blame won't help beat MRSA.

&quot;Tough decisions need to be taken to tackle healthcare associated infections but they need to be taken by NHS trusts in partnership with patients, the public and their staff.&quot;

Conservative Shadow Health Secretary Andrew Lansley accused the government of being complacent over hospital acquired infections by not acting quicker.

Liberal Democrat Shadow Health Secretary Steve Webb said legislation would not solve the problem.

He said: &quot;The most effective solution is to tackle the high bed occupancy rates which means nurses do not have time to clean beds properly and patients are shunted from ward to ward.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4683691.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-35</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Blood donors warned over vCJD</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>All gave blood to three people in 1993/4 who have since died from the human form of mad cow disease.

Precautions were brought in during 1999 when it became apparent that there was a potential for the prion disease to be transmitted through donor blood.

The Department of Health has asked the 100 donors to notify their doctors so extra precautions can be taken if they have surgery or other invasive care.

They are also being asked not to donate any more blood, tissue or organs. The department said the move was a precautionary measure.

A further 3,000 people who received blood from the donors but have not shown signs of vCJD may also be contacted.

It is not known whether the source of vCJD in the three patients who died was related to the blood that they received or BSE-infected meat that they ate.

Back in September, the government identified 17 people who received blood transfusions from people who went on to develop vCJD and sent out 6,000 letters to others informing them of the potential risk.

Since 1997 all cases of vCJD that are reported to the National CJD Surveillance Unit and diagnosed as having &quot;probable&quot; vCJD are passed on to the National Blood Service which searches its blood donor records.

If the patient has given blood, subsequently any stocks of that blood are immediately destroyed.

White blood cells, which it is thought may carry the greatest risk of transmitting the disease, have been removed from all blood used for transfusion since 1999.

And blood products have been prepared from plasma imported from the US since 1998.

At the end of December 2003, the total number of vCJD cases was in the UK was 145, including 139 deaths.

There is no test for the brain wasting disease so those at risk have no way of knowing whether they have vCJD.

Chief Medical Officer Sir Liam Donaldson said: &quot;When a recipient of a blood transfusion goes on to develop vCJD, we have to consider the possibility that the infection could have been passed on through the transfusion.

&quot;Until a reliable blood screening test becomes available, it is sensible to proceed with highly precautionary measures such as this to rule out any possibility of onward transmission of the disease.&quot;

Dr Angela Robinson from the National Blood Service said: &quot;This notification exercise will affect in the order of 100 donors.

&quot;If you have donated blood in the last five years and are not contacted shortly, you can be assured that you are not involved in this new safety measure and need to take no further action.

&quot;For those people who are involved, this information may be difficult to absorb. That is why we have set up the National Blood Service helpline and are working with their doctors and other clinicians, to ensure that they have the information and support they need.&quot;

She urged the public to continue donating blood, saying that the NHS depended on this continued commitment in order to be able to save lives.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4699349.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-36</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Fewer hospitals get three stars</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Problems with finances and targets caused a fall in the number of hospitals achieving the top grade for the first time in four years.

But the Healthcare Commission said primary care, mental health and ambulance trusts had improved.

However, the watchdog warned the whole health service had to get its finances in order or patient care would suffer.

One in four NHS trusts - one in three if just hospital trusts are taken into account - ended the last financial year in the red, with a combined deficit of £500m. Overall this was balanced out by surplus elsewhere.

Hospitals also struggled with a range of government targets.

Sixty-two out of 159 hospital trusts with A&amp;E units failed to meet the 98% target for the number of people waiting for four hours.

One in 10 also failed to achieve the nine-month wait for an operation.

The problems meant that the number of hospital trusts achieving three or two stars dropped by 5% compared to the previous year.

Among the trusts achieving zero stars was Surrey and Sussex Healthcare NHS, which failed against a number of key targets including financial management and A&amp;E targets.

Brighton and Sussex University Hospitals NHS Trust was also awarded zero stars, failing on waiting times and financial management.

However, the proportion of hospital trusts which had the top rating was still greater than primary care, mental health or ambulance trusts.

Overall, 42 of the 173 trusts dropped a grade, including six flagship foundation trusts. Foundation trust regulator Monitor said this would not affect their elite status.

But the star-ratings, which assess performance across a range of areas including waiting times, access to GPs, financial management, patient care and death rates, showed improvements had been made in reducing MRSA and the death rates for cancer, stroke and heart disease.

Healthcare Commission chief executive Anna Walker said if the problems with finances were not solved patient care could &quot;suffer&quot;.

She added: &quot;The overall improvement in performance this year should not be underestimated. Today the targets are a lot tougher, but despite this many trusts are raising to the challenge.

&quot;The fly in the ointment is financial performance.&quot;

Dr Gill Morgan, chief executive of the NHS Confederation, which represents health service managers, said the health service has performed well despite an &quot;ever more demanding set of targets&quot;.

During the last year the number of patients having to be seen within four hours by A&amp;E units rose from 90% to 98%.

But she said: &quot;There is no doubt that finances remain tight for many NHS organisations as a result of significant cost pressures including pay modernisation schemes, and prescribing expensive new drugs whose costs run ahead of inflation.&quot;

Dr Paul Miller, chairman of the BMA's consultants committee, said many trusts had struggled with the A&amp;E target as it was not &quot;realistic or sustainable&quot;.

And he warned patients not to pay too much attention to the ratings as they take &quot;little account of the standard of clinical care or the success of treatments or operations&quot;.

Liberal Democrat health spokesman Steve Webb said some trusts were facing tough times, while Shadow Health Secretary Andrew Lansley said the NHS finances were &quot;close to meltdown&quot;.

But the Department of Health hailed the results as an &quot;improvement in performance&quot;.

This is the last year trusts will receive star-ratings. From next year they will be replaced by a &quot;health check&quot; which will involve self-assessment and spot inspections.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4718405.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-37</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Premature babies 'need advocates'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Scope, which represents people with cerebral palsy, fears some babies are being denied life-saving treatment.

It says doctors and parents may be using statistics on the chances of extremely premature babies developing a disability to withdraw care from them.

Doctors said Scope's proposals would be unworkable because of the speed with which decisions often had to be made.

Recent research suggested babies born extremely prematurely have an almost 50% chance of developing a moderate to severe disability.

The charity's comments come as the respected Nuffield Council on Bioethics carries out a public consultation on the way extremely premature babies, born at less than 28 weeks gestation, should be treated in the NHS.

Among the questions the consultation is asking is whether the economics of treating and then bringing up a disabled child should be a factor in decisions made by doctors and parents about whether to continue treating very sick babies.

Doctors say, in some cases, they are having to turn away from busy neo-natal intensive care units babies who have a good chance of survival because incubators are being used by extremely premature babies who have significantly lower life chances.

A recent survey by the premature baby charity Bliss found 70% of neo-natal units have had to shut their doors to new admissions at some point in the last six months.

The charity called for the appointment of 2,700 extra nurses.

Richard Parnell, head of research and public policy at Scope, said: &quot;I think Scope's major concern about this debate is who actually acts in the interests of the child.&quot;

Parents of extremely premature babies and doctors will often hold conferences before the birth or within hours of birth to decide whether to continue with intensive care.

Mr Parnell said that wrongly saw disability as a &quot;risk&quot; and so looked at how wanted the child was before making a decision.

&quot;I have spoken to paediatricians who take into account the circumstances of the family, if the family has more than one child, if the birth is unplanned then that would influence them one way, and if the birth was planned and very much wanted that would influence them another way.

&quot;That raises huge concerns in my mind about who is acting in that child's interests.&quot;

Only about a quarter of babies born at less than 25 weeks live, although that is four times as many as compared with 20 years ago.

Until recently, no-one really knew what their long term prospects were.

The Epicure study has been following the lives of 300 extremely premature babies over six years and has found that just under half have developed a moderate or severe disability including cerebral palsy and autism.

Doctors have said Scope's suggestion would be unworkable as sometimes decisions have to be made within minutes.

&quot;Sometimes it's a very fast moving situation and you really can't wait around,&quot; said Professor Andrew Whitelaw, head of neonatology at the University of Bristol.

&quot;In any case I would say the doctor is always advocating what is best in the interests of the child so there is no need for another person to be involved.&quot;

One mother described to BBC Radio Five how her son born at 24 weeks gestation was given life-saving steroids.

Now, five years later, he has developed severe autism, which has had an enormous impact on the family.

When asked whether she thought the right decision had been made to give life-saving treatment to her son, she answered, &quot;I don't know. I love my son to bits, but it has been a very long, very hard, very tough five years.

&quot;There have been times when I wonder whether we did him any favours and there are times where I dread to think what the future holds for him.&quot;

She said more investment needed to be made into supporting parents coping with bringing up disabled children.

Matthew Chapman's report, Too Young to Live, can be heard on Five Live on Sunday 31 July at 1100 BST and 1900BST and after that at the Five Live Report website.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4728747.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-38</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | TV ads show smoking is 'unsexy'</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>One of the government-funded images carries the strapline &quot;Your penis thinks you should stop smoking&quot; to highlight the risk of impotency.

Ministers say fears about fertility and attractiveness are stronger motivators for young people to quit than health.

A survey suggests one in two smokers would quit to improve their sex appeal.

The NHS Smoking Helpline questionnaire also revealed that more than two-thirds of young men and women believe smoking makes them less attractive.

Half of men said they associated smoking with wrinkles, bad skin and less enjoyable kissing.

Another of the ads shows stark images of the effect of smoking on women's appearance and attractiveness to men, with messages such as &quot;If you smoke, you stink&quot;, &quot;Minging teeth&quot; and &quot;Cat's bum mouth&quot;.

Websites called &quot;Staying Hard&quot; and Ugly Smoking&quot; will also be launched, alongside a sticker campaign in pub and club toilets.

Public Health Minister Caroline Flint said: &quot;This latest series of adverts marks a new and exciting route for the campaign.

&quot;A key part of our drive to reduce overall smoking prevalence is getting the message to harder-to-reach young adult audiences.

&quot;We know 70% of smokers want to stop smoking; however, with younger people, fears about attractiveness and fertility can be a stronger motivation to quit than fears about health.

&quot;It is hoped that the hard hitting messages in this new campaign will make young people quit smoking for good.&quot;

Smoking increases the risk of erectile dysfunction by around 50% for men in their 30s and 40s and up to 120,000 men from the UK in this age group are impotent as a direct result of smoking, experts estimate.

Clive Gingell, chairman of the Sexual Dysfunction Association, said: &quot;By making men aware of how smoking can affect their sexual performance in middle age, hopefully this new campaign should provide men with an additional and compelling reason to quit.&quot;

Dr Bav Shergill, from the British Skin Foundation, said: &quot;Giving up smoking can not only add years to your life, it also adds years to your appearance and can help stop premature aging before it's too late.&quot;

However, Simon Clark, director of the smokers' lobby group Forest, said: &quot;To try and suggest that smoking is a major cause of impotence is a scare tactic.

&quot;It's nasty because it is not only setting out to de-normalise smoking, but really to make smokers feel incredibly guilty about their habit.&quot;</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4636579.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-05-10 00:00:00-39</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC NEWS | Health | Europe bans chemical use in toys</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>BBC News</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-05-10</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Health</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>None</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Phthalates have been linked to damage to the reproductive system, and an increased risk of asthma and cancer.

They are also used in the manufacture of lubricants and solvents, and are found in cosmetics, medical equipment, paints and packaging.

A temporary ban had been in place in Europe since 1999.

Toy manufacturers have criticised the proposed ban, pointing to an EU risk assessment that said the chemicals were safe.

However, a study by New York's University of Rochester, published in May, found exposure to the chemicals was linked to a higher risk of genital abnormalities in baby boys.

Previous research on animals had suggested phthalates may damage reproductive development by disrupting hormone levels.

John Bowis, a British Conservative MEP, said: &quot;Nobody is going to be killed by chewing them, but potentially there is a carcinogenic threat.

&quot;That is why, under the precautionary principle, with scientific advice, one takes action.&quot;

MEPs voted to ban the use of six types of phthalates in children's toys.

Three types were banned outright, and the others will be barred from use in toys which can be put in the mouth.

The European Commission will issue guidance on how the ban is to be implemented.

It is also to conduct a review into the use of phthalates in other products, in particular medical devices.

MEPs also approved a review into the use of fragrances in children's toys.</TEXT>
      <URL>http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/health/4651391.stm</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
