<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Jennifer Lopez and Shakira sparkle at the Super Bowl - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/34A2/production/_110747431_lopezshak.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>&quot;Let's show the world what two little Latin girls can do,&quot; Jennifer Lopez told Shakira, shortly before playing the Super Bowl Half Time Show in Miami.

In the event, the duo showed they could sing, belly dance, crowd surf, knee slide, pole dance and even play drums.

It was a kinetic and sometimes dizzying set, as the Latin singers raced through 20 songs in just 12 minutes.

And after two years of under-cooked half time shows, their vibrant, kitsch spectacle was a breath of fresh air.

Unlike Justin Timberlake in 2018 and Maroon 5 last year, the two performers thrashed out a focused and upbeat set-list that concentrated on their biggest hits, offset by breath-taking choreography and fistfuls of Vegas glitter.

They mostly heeded Lady Gaga's warning that &quot;I better hear no lip-syncing&quot; at the Super Bowl, proving themselves to be accomplished live vocalists even while spinning around the stage like marionettes.

&quot;Hola Miami!&quot; shouted Shakira, opening the show with the disco strut of She Wolf before segueing to the grungy rock of Empire, and throwing in a few bars of Led Zeppelin's Kashmir as she wigged out on a black sequinned guitar.

She brought out Puerto Rican singer Bad Bunny to duet on a cover of Cardi B's I Like It, and wrapped up six minutes later with her biggest hit, Hips Don't Lie, while being carried across the audience on her back.

Throughout her segment,the Colombian singer, who was celebrating her 43rd birthday, looked like she was having an absolute blast.

At one point, she leaned into the TV cameras, waggled her tongue and trilled. Although some viewers made fun, others pointed out the singer, whose father is Lebanese, was performing a traditional Arabic vocal celebration known as the zaghrouta.

Lopez arrived next, perched atop a replica of the Empire State Building while singing, somewhat incongruously, that she was &quot;still Jenny from the block&quot;.

Dressed in a studded leather body suit, the singer showed off her punchy, staccato dance moves; as well as the gravity-defying pole dancing skills she learned while playing Ramona in last year's box office smash Hustlers.

She was joined by Colombia's J Balvin to play Que Calor and Mi Gente. Later, her 11-year-old daughter Emme Maribel Muñiz, sang the club hit Let's Get Loud.

During the show's only moment of political frisson, Emme sang the chorus of Bruce Springsteen's Born In The USA while Lopez draped herself in a Puerto Rican flag, a not-so-subtle dig at the Trump administration's handling of aid for the island after it was devastated by two hurricanes in 2017.

Lopez, who is of Puerto Rican parentage, previously donated $1m in proceeds from her Las Vegas residency to the relief effort.

But overall, the half time show was conceived as &quot;an all-inclusive party, a party that integrates cultures and diversity,&quot; said Shakira at a pre-game press conference last week.

It certainly managed to incorporate more than half-a-dozen musical styles, from salsa and reggaeton to hip-hop and Afro-fusion; although the break-neck pace meant several songs were over before you could sneeze.

The singers only appeared together for the finale, a celebratory version of Shakira's Waka Waka which, confusingly, was the official anthem of an entirely separate sporting event - the 2010 World Cup.

The show also incorporated a tribute to basketball legend Kobe Bryant, who died alongside his daughter and seven others in a helicopter crash last weekend.

As Lopez's daughter performed the opening bars of Let's Get Loud, a giant cross illuminated the field of Miami's Hard Rock stadium in yellow and purple, the colours of Bryant's team, the Los Angeles Lakers.

Before the performance, Lopez said she had wanted to honour the athlete as soon as she learned of the tragedy from her fiance, Alex Rodriguez.

&quot;I was in the middle of rehearsing [when] Alex came to me with tears in his eyes and he's like, 'You're not gonna believe what happened,'&quot; Lopez recalled. &quot;He was devastated.&quot;

&quot;I think it's affecting everybody so much because it's reminding everybody how fragile life is and how we have to appreciate every single moment,&quot; she added.

With hits like Waiting For Tonight and Whenever, Wherever in the 2000s, Shakira and Lopez helped clear a path for the stream of Latin artists who've flooded the charts over the last few years.

At the start of their career, the prospect of a Super Bowl show sung half in Spanish would have been unimaginable - a fact that was not lost on Shakira.

&quot;Being at the Super Bowl is very symbolic in a way, and I feel we have a great responsibility with the Latinos around the world,&quot; she told Reuters.

&quot;There is a lot to celebrate about our Latin culture, and it is a great opportunity to be on this very important stage.&quot;

The NFL says there are 30.2 million Hispanic football fans in the United States, an increase of two million since 2017.

&quot;The league's Hispanic fanbase has continued to grow rapidly,&quot; said an NFL spokesperson, &quot;and our outreach to the Hispanic community is an important year-round initiative&quot;.

However, they are not represented on the field, with the Miami Herald reporting that only 16 of the NFL's 1,696 players in the 2018 season were of Hispanic origin.

Before Sunday's clash between San Francisco 49ers and the Kansas City Chiefs began, pop star Demi Lovato (who is also of Latin heritage) gave a full-throated, melismatic rendition of the US national anthem.

Standing on a giant, football-shaped platform, and dressed in a simple white suit, Lovato was accompanied by Christine Sun Kim, who provided interpretation in American sign language.

Earlier, soul singer Yolanda Adams opened proceedings with a soulful rendition of America The Beautiful with the Children's Chorus of Miami.

None of the performers are paid for appearing, but the exposure is priceless.

The TV audience for the Super Bowl has never dropped below 100 million in the US, and last year's half time performers, Maroon 5, saw their sales jump by 488%.

Two years earlier, downloads of Lady Gaga's music increased by more than 1,000% after a 12-minute tour-de-force that began with a stage dive from the roof of the Houston's NRG Stadium.

The most-watched Super Bowl show of all time was Katy Perry's shark-infested spectacular in 2015, which drew 120.7 million viewers.
• I Like It (Cardi B cover, with Bad Bunny)

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51352285</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Cynthia Erivo: 'Hopefully this year will be a turning point' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1546B/production/_110774178_p0828wz3.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Cynthia Erivo is nominated for Best Actress in this year's Oscars, for her portrayal of slave-turned-abolitionist Harriet Tubman.

She is the only person of colour to be nominated in the four acting categories, and told the BBC she wants &quot;to make sure it doesn't look like this every single time&quot;.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51378961</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Jay-Z explains his and Beyonce's Super Bowl 'protest': 'It just happened' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Newsbeat</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10B5/production/_110777240_gettyimages-1202008249.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Jay-Z says he and Beyonce were not staging a protest when they stayed seated during the US national anthem at the 2020 Super Bowl.

He says the couple were in &quot;artist mode&quot; when they didn't stand while Demi Lovato sang The Star Spangled Banner.

It lead to speculation they were sending a message of support to former NFL player Colin Kaepernick who first kneeled during the anthem in 2016.

He was protesting racial injustice and has been without a team since 2017.

In a video, obtained by TMZ, Jay-Z and Beyonce can be seen sat down while others around them are stood during Demi's performance.
• Colin Kaepernick: From one man kneeling to a movement dividing a country

But during a Columbia University lecture on Tuesday 4 February - two days after the Super Bowl - the rapper insisted it &quot;just happened&quot;.

In 2018 Demi Lovato was hospitalised after a suspected drug overdose.

&quot;We were talking about how beautiful she looks and how she sounds and what she's gone through in her life for her to be on the stage and we're so proud of her,&quot; he said.

At the lecture, Jay-Z also explained that he produced all the musical performances at the Super Bowl as part of his deal with the NFL as its live music entertainment strategist.

He said he was also preoccupied wondering if the sound levels were too low and what the TV cameras were picking up.

Referring to Shakira and Jennifer Lopez performing the half time show, he said a &quot;silent protest&quot; from him was unnecessary as the diverse group of performers was &quot;the biggest, loudest protest of all&quot;.

When Kaepernick began protesting in 2016 it encouraged other players to do the same - but divided the country and sparked the anger of US President Donald Trump, who accused those kneeling of disrespecting the flag and called for them to be sacked.

Listen to Newsbeat live at 12:45 and 17:45 weekdays - or listen back here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-51382994</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Al Pacino is up for a Bafta for his role in The Irishman - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/11340/production/_110746407_p0823flg.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Baftas 2020: 'Didn't I win for Serpico in the 70s?'

Forty-four years after winning his first Bafta, Al Pacino is vying for another with his role in The Irishman.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51350887</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Gene Reynolds: Tributes paid to Mash and Lou Grant co-creator - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/18503/production/_110778599_reynolds2_976getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Gene Reynolds, a former president of the Directors Guild of America (DGA) who co-created such classic TV shows as Mash and Lou Grant, has died aged 96.

The director and producer worked with Larry Gelbart to create the TV version of Mash - often stylised as M*A*S*H.

He won three Emmys for the show and another two for Lou Grant before serving two terms as DGA president.

&quot;Good night old friend,&quot; tweeted Lou Grant star Ed Asner. &quot;I was blessed to know you. Thank you for everything.&quot;

Thomas Schlamme, the DGA's current president, remembered Reynolds as being &quot;passionate... spirited in his beliefs and dedicated until the end&quot;.

Born in Cleveland, Ohio in 1923, Eugene Reynolds Blumenthal started out as a film extra before landing roles in Captains Courageous and the Andy Hardy films.

After serving in the navy during World War Two, he became a director on such 1960s TV shows as My Three Sons, Leave It to Beaver and Hogan's Heroes.

Tasked with developing a TV version of Robert Altman's 1970 film Mash, he was instrumental in recruiting writer Larry Gelbart and star Alan Alda.

The series, which followed the fortunes of a mobile army surgical hospital in the Korean War, ran for 11 seasons.

Reynolds left Mash in 1977 to co-create Lou Grant, a spin-off from The Mary Tyler Moore Show about a Los Angeles newspaper editor.

His later credits included Blossom, a comedy about a teenage girl played by future Big Bang Theory star Mayim Bialik.

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51383355</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Baftas 2020: The highlights - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13D7A/production/_110747218_p08240g9.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>One of the stars of The Irishman, Robert De Niro, could be honoured for his role as a producer on the film.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51351347</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>JayStation: 'Death hoax' YouTuber charged with assault - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/318F/production/_110778621_youtube1_976.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A YouTube celebrity who confessed to pretending that his girlfriend had been killed has been arrested and charged with assault and assault with a weapon.

Toronto Police confirmed Jason Ethier - known online as ImJayStation - would appear in court on 16 March.

It is not clear if the charges relate to the hoax, which the 29-year-old said was intended to boost YouTube views.

Ethier claimed in January that Alexia Marano, his then-girlfriend, had been killed by a drunk driver.

He went on to make videos that showed him visiting her memorial and attempting to contact her via a Ouija board.

The deception unravelled when suspicious viewers began to question his story.

In a confession video, Ethier claimed Marano had been in on the scam from the beginning.

He then said she had left him and that she was &quot;trying to ruin his life&quot; by allegedly accusing him of assault.

Writing on Twitter, Marano herself said there was &quot;nowhere to go but up&quot; and claimed to be &quot;just a little girl caught in the crossfire&quot;.

Toronto Police confirmed to the BBC on Tuesday that a warrant was issued on Monday and that Ethier had been arrested and charged.

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51383361</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>Frankie Bridge on mental health: 'I couldn't cope with everyday life' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Newsbeat</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12ABD/production/_110777467_frankie976.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>In 2011, girl group The Saturdays were filming a music video in Iceland for their single My Heart Takes Over.

But one of the members - Frankie Bridge - just didn't want to do it.

&quot;I'd reached a point where I couldn't cope with everyday life,&quot; she tells Radio 1 Newsbeat.

After years of poor mental health, that was the point when those closest to Frankie decided she needed to go into a specialist mental health hospital.

&quot;I was constantly crying and telling my partner [footballer Wayne Bridge] that I didn't really want to be here anymore.&quot;

The video shoot would last two days and was already paid for, so Frankie and her manager decided she'd keep working and be admitted when it was over.

&quot;Luckily it was a moody shoot so I didn't have to put on this happy, smiley front,&quot; she says.

'I'm sharing my story to tell people they're not alone'

On her return to the UK she went into hospital where she was &quot;terrified but relieved&quot;.

&quot;It was a sense of relief that I could hand my life over to someone else. I was no longer my own responsibility. It was the hospital's responsibility to keep me alive and make me better.&quot;

For years, Frankie has chatted openly about her mental health issues and the way she has coped - and struggled - with things like depression, anxiety and suicidal thoughts.

She's now written a book, Open: Why Asking for Help Can Save Your Life, because she's &quot;proud&quot; to have come out the other side and be happy.

&quot;I still suffer with depression and anxiety but I just know how to deal with it better now.

&quot;It's not a self-help book,&quot; she says. &quot;I'm sharing my story to tell people they're not alone.&quot;

During her time in The Saturdays, she says her bandmates - Rochelle, Vanessa, Mollie and Una - didn't know the extent of her health problems until they saw her have a panic attack.

&quot;It frightened them and they were shocked at how bad it was because up to that point I was so good at hiding it.&quot;

She also remembers her first live TV appearance after coming out of the psychiatric hospital.

It was on the BBC's Children In Need and for anyone watching it went without a hitch - but when she sees the performance on YouTube now she laughs and says how she was &quot;faking it&quot;.

Frankie's life in the band meant she was used to getting ready with loads of people around her and being in a manic changing room.

However, coming out of hospital and going back into that environment was &quot;too intense&quot;.

&quot;I had a panic attack in the toilets because I was so overwhelmed. I felt I looked really sad.&quot;

One of the constants in Frankie's life has been her husband, ex-footballer Wayne Bridge, who she's been with for a decade.

&quot;At the time, I didn't think how much it was affecting him and now I feel awful.

&quot;We'd only been together a year and he's got this new girlfriend and he's having to take her into a psychiatric hospital. He could have easily walked away then.&quot;

'It can't be fixed'

Frankie says Wayne struggled too but he took the time to try to understand what she was going through.

&quot;My doctors had sessions with him to explain what was happening and why I was feeling a certain way.&quot;

She says she tells Wayne to try to not &quot;fix her&quot;.

&quot;All I need is for you to listen to me because it can't be fixed,&quot; she says.

&quot;Just be there, embrace it and let them know they're not alone.&quot;

Frankie and Wayne have two young children - Parker and Carter - but pregnancy was also tough for Frankie to balance with her depression.

&quot;It was weird because one of the reasons I wanted to get better was because I wanted to have children and I wanted to be a young mum,&quot; she says.

&quot;When I got pregnant I had no control over my body. I had water retention, I had morning sickness and I put on a lot of weight really quickly.&quot;

Frankie had also had an eating disorder, and says it was hard to accept the changes to her body, which was made worse by people online commenting on her appearance.

&quot;It fed into every insecurity that I had. My body had been my armour and I no longer had that anymore.&quot;

Now she's preparing for Sport Relief's latest celebrity challenge, On Thin Ice - and it's for a cause that's close to her heart.

&quot;I'm really nervous because I've had no time to train. It's all in aid of mental health I couldn't say no,&quot; she says.

Frankie and other celebrities (including Radio 1's Nick Grimshaw) will trek 100 miles across a frozen lake in Mongolia.

&quot;It's all about ticking off those things that I'm anxious about going into situations that make me uncomfortable to prove to my anxieties that they're wrong.&quot;

Visit the Radio 1 Advice Pages for more information about mental health issues.

Listen to Newsbeat live at 12:45 and 17:45 weekdays - or listen back here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-51377490</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>BBC: TV licence fee decriminalisation consultation launches - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/13F17/production/_110778618_new-comp.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Culture Secretary Nicky Morgan has launched a public consultation on whether non-payment of the TV licence fee should remain a criminal offence.

Currently, anyone who watches or records live TV or uses iPlayer without a TV licence is guilty of a criminal offence and could go to prison.

Baroness Morgan said it was time to think about keeping the fee &quot;relevant&quot; in a &quot;changing media landscape&quot;.

The BBC said a 2015 review found the current system to be the fairest.

The consultation, which will last eight weeks with the government publishing its response this summer, will also look at the viability of an alternative enforcement scheme.

Decriminalisation would not mean non-payment would become voluntary. It could instead mean it would become a civil offence similar to non-payment of council tax or an electricity bill.

In a speech on Wednesday, Baroness Morgan said many people thought it wrong that &quot;you can be imprisoned for not paying the TV licence and its enforcement punishes the vulnerable&quot;.

&quot;We are launching a public consultation to make sure we have a fair and proportionate approach to licence fee penalties and payments, that protects those most in need in society,&quot; she added.

The culture secretary also announced a new flexible payment scheme, called the Simple Payment Plan, to help those struggling to pay, including the over-75s.

It will allow people to spread the fee out into a number of manageable instalments.

&quot;This will help prepare the BBC and public service broadcasting for the future and make sure it continues to work for our society, our economy, and the public which funds it,&quot; said Baroness Morgan.

Last year, Treasury minister Rishi Sunak said the Prime Minister Boris Johnson had ordered a review of the sanction for non-payment of the £154.50 charge, which funds the BBC.

Confirmation of the consultation comes two days after it was announced the fee is to increase by £3, from £154.50 to £157.50, from 1 April 2020.

It also follows the controversy last year over the decision to scrap free licences for some over-75s, a decision which saw a number of celebrities joining the call for the decision to be overturned.

From June, only over-75s who are claiming pension credit will be eligible to a free TV licence.

Baroness Morgan said her plans should not be seen as &quot;any kind of attack on the BBC&quot;.

The broadcaster is an &quot;incredibly important organisation in the UK and around the world&quot;, she said.

But it was the government's &quot;duty&quot; to look into the issue of funding.

In a statement, the BBC said &quot;a detailed government-commissioned review (in 2015) found the current system to be the fairest and most effective&quot;.

&quot;It did not recommend change - in part because the current system is effective in ensuring payment with very few people ever going to prison.

&quot;If there are changes, they must be fair to law abiding licence fee payers and delivered in a way that doesn't fundamentally undermine the BBC's ability to deliver the services they love.&quot;

In 2018, more than 121,000 people were convicted and sentenced for evasion and issued with an average fine of £176.

There were around 26 million TV licences being used in the UK last year, generating £3.69bn in income for the BBC.

If decriminalisation of the TV licence fee were to go through, it would have a considerable impact on BBC funding.

The DCMS (Department for Digital, Culture, Media and Sport) said the government would take into account the impact on the corporation in the context of the overall licence fee settlement, for which negotiations begin later this year.

A previous government review in 2015 looked into whether a fine for non-payment could be issued under civil law instead, similar to the fees for breaking parking, bus lane and congestion charge rules.

The review also examined whether unpaid TV licence fees should be considered a civil debt in the same way as unpaid utility bills or council tax.

However, it recommended against changing the criminal sanctions regime, saying decriminalisation could bring with it an increased risk of evasion.

A consultation is a process used by public bodies that invites the public to provide their views and feedback on a particular proposal.

The members of the public who are asked are individuals and organisations that would be affected directly or indirectly by a project or a decision.

They include those who have the ability to influence the decision, both positively and negatively. They can also be people who simply have an interest in the project.

There is no maximum or minimum number of respondents; It's open to anyone over 16.

Consultations last for a proportionate amount of time and consist of a limited number of clear, concise questions.

Follow us on Facebook or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51373372</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Warnings over British independent film scene's 'spiral of decline' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/775B/production/_110755503_judypa_cut.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>British film may have been celebrated at the Baftas on Sunday, but new figures have revealed a sharp drop in the number of UK films made last year.

The figures, from the BFI, showed a large reduction in the amount of money spent on homegrown independent movies.

New BFI chief executive Ben Roberts said there were &quot;major challenges&quot; for the British independent film sector.

Stewart Le Marechal, who produced 2018's Swimming with Men, said the scene was in &quot;a spiral of decline&quot;.

The amount of money spent making films and high-end television in the UK rose 16% to a record £3.6bn in 2019, the annual figures showed - thanks to Hollywood studios and US TV giants shooting more in Britain.

But spending on British films with no studio backing dropped by 45% to £175m, and the number of homegrown productions with budgets over £500,000 fell from 94 in 2018 to 49 last year.

The 2019 numbers are likely to rise to some extent as the BFI finishes gathering its information, but the final figures will still show a significant decline.

Growing problems finding funding and greater competition from TV are to blame, according to those in the British film industry.

Le Marechal, whose 2018 comedy Swimming with Men starred Rob Brydon and Jim Carter, said the industry has been in a cycle of decline for a decade.

The problems are &quot;definitely something that we've been watching happen over the last 10 years, and I think it's just getting harder and harder&quot; to get films made, he told BBC News.

It all stems back to the financial crash of 2007-08, when producers started to find it harder to raise money in advance. This meant they struggled to attract big-name actors and had to cut budgets, Le Marechal believes.

&quot;You're going in a downward spiral where, because you've got a lower-budget film, it's harder to sell to buyers because they say 'This is a smaller project',&quot; says the producer, whose recent projects include the documentary Last Breath.

&quot;It's very difficult to halt that. Obviously people still are managing to make films, but as you can see, they're far fewer, and invariably, they're much lower budget.

&quot;That makes it then harder for them to punch above their weight when they actually do make it to the marketplace, if they make it to the marketplace at all.&quot;

Independent British films released last year include Judy, Fighting with My Family, Blinded by the Light, Wild Rose and Mary, Queen of Scots.

The BFI doesn't count films made with Hollywood money, such as Sir Sam Mendes's Bafta-winning 1917, in its domestic figures.

Pippa Harris, producer of 1917, recently told Screen International that the biggest challenge currently facing the industry is the increasing difficulty to persuade studios to fund films unless they are part of a franchise or based on something well-known.

&quot;We were extremely fortunate to be allowed to make 1917 without any major stars in the leads, but that freedom is rare,&quot; she said. (Sir Sam's name probably sealed the deal.)

Other producers and directors have shifted to the small screen. Last year, the amount spent on high-end TV in the UK rose by 29% to a record £1.66bn.

Clare Mundell's company Synchronicity Films used to make just features. Now around 80% of its work is in TV, making shows like BBC One drama The Cry, starring Jenna Coleman.

She says homegrown movies are caught in a &quot;perfect storm&quot;, caused by changes to film financing and the &quot;massive upswing&quot; in opportunities in TV.

Television is often more attractive because the revenues - from budgets afforded by outlets like Netflix, or the rights offered to production companies by British broadcasters - are more reliable, she says.

&quot;In the midst of all that opportunity, it can be really hard to decide to risk your time going in to make a feature film at £1.5m, which may never see the light of day and from which you'll probably not make a penny.&quot;

Bodies like BBC Films, Film4 and the BFI have been mainstays of the industry and are still backing British films and new talent.

But one crucial change, Mundell believes, is an overhaul of the Enterprise Investment Scheme - a tax incentive that attracted investors by cushioning some of their risk, but is now not open for most film projects.

The consequences of the decline in British films are &quot;really troubling&quot;, she says.

&quot;Very often they are films that are championing the talent of the future, the British directorial voices that in years to come will go on and have long and illustrious careers.

&quot;If there are fewer films being financed at that level, then there are fewer opportunities for directors, writers, producers [and] actors.

&quot;And if we've got 50% fewer independent British films being made, then we've got 50% fewer stories being authored about the themes that matter to Britain.&quot;

Another producer who has switched to TV is James Richardson. His company Vertigo Films made 2008's Bronson, which gave Tom Hardy an early starring role, and 2010's Monsters, helmed by future Rogue One director Gareth Edwards.

&quot;Would we make them in the current climate? I don't think so,&quot; he says. &quot;And that's really sad, because it just means there are some amazing productions which are not able to be made.&quot;

Vertigo also made StreetDance, which reaped £11.6m at the UK box office in 2010. &quot;The numbers that flowed down to us and the film-makers at the end of this massive success were not fantastic,&quot; Richardson says.

&quot;The British independent film structures have got fundamental flaws to them, in terms of the way that finance happens and the terms in which producers and talent end up making any money.&quot;

Richardson and his producing partner made the move to TV six years ago, and now make Bulletproof and Britannia for Sky.

&quot;What's come into its place is this extraordinarily dynamic and incredibly creative TV world, where the film-makers are making the most extraordinary things,&quot; he says.

&quot;And coupled with that you've got the most beautiful films being made. 1917 gets made. Yes, it's a studio movie, but it's a beautiful British movie.&quot;

In 2018, the BFI published an in-depth report into the state of independent British film that concluded &quot;the traditional business model for independent film is no longer fit for purpose&quot;.

The BFI's Ben Roberts says: &quot;The whole ecosystem for making films and reaching audiences is undergoing huge structural change globally.

&quot;New channels are opening up new opportunities for audiences but also for film-making talent - in short there is more fluidity for talent in moving between film and television,&quot; he adds.

He cites established movie-makers like Ben Wheatley, Lenny Abrahamson and Andrew Haigh, who are also working in TV.

&quot;The good news is that there is more demand for film on all screens and more opportunities for our film-making talent,&quot; Roberts continues.

&quot;But from our perspective it is also producing major challenges for the independent sector, much of which was highlighted by the work of the BFI's Independent Film Commission.

&quot;It's important that we ensure independent film-making is sustained, because it is the lifeblood of film culture. It is very much a priority.&quot;

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51347201</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>Oscars 2020: The lowdown on international film nominees - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/10091/production/_110618656_best_international_film_com.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Academy Awards have a new category this year - in name at least.

There has been an Oscar for best foreign language film since 1947, although the title could vary in the early years. But when two years ago producers Larry Karaszewski and Diane Weyermann took over running the category it didn't take long to decide the old title should go.

Karaszewski said last year: &quot;The word 'foreign' was starting to seem strange, because there was really nothing foreign about the movies that we were seeing. They were just not in the English language.&quot;

So now Academy members are voting to choose the best international feature film.

The submission rules remain unchanged - one film per country with limited amounts of English dialogue.

But the voting procedure has always been more complex than for most categories and more differences have been instigated.

The most significant is that shortlisted films can be watched online. This allows more Academy members to participate in the voting process.

More than 90 films submitted have come down to a final five. Here we give an overview of each.

Poland's track record in this category: Eleven previous nominations including one win.

What's it about?: Daniel is a young man living in a tough juvenile detention centre where violence is common. He's allowed out to travel to a village in the countryside to work in a sawmill. The village priest comes to assume Daniel has just left a Catholic seminary and appoints him his unofficial stand-in while he goes away. It could all be the set-up to a comedy of mistaken identity - and there is humour in the film. But Daniel (played by Bartosz Bielenia) offers the villagers the emotional consolation they needed after a recent tragedy but which never materialised. They accept and perhaps even love him (though some of them may suspect he's not what he claims to be). The violent Daniel blossoms into something far better but then reality lunges into view.

Chances of winning: At the film's centre is a remarkable performance by Bartosz Bielenia, working with a strong screenplay based loosely on real events. Bielenia shows Daniel's hardened viciousness but slowly allows the audience to sense goodness growing inside him - perhaps even a soul. A man devoid of morality becomes the most moral person in the film. It's hard not to care about his fate, though the audience guesses his pretence will be discovered eventually. Though it's not likely to win, the careers of Bielenia and director Komasa will benefit.

North Macedonia's track record in this category: One nomination, as Macedonia, in 1994

What's it about?: It's a documentary, focusing on the tough lives of Hatidze Muratova (who's in her 50s) and her mother Nafize in countryside a few miles from the capital Skopje. Hatidze, an absolute gift for any documentary-maker, survives mainly by keeping bees and selling their honey at market. A family moves in nearby: any initial suspicion is soon replaced by warmth as Hatidze accepts them almost as her own. The bees become a joint project. But financial pressures encourage the newly arrived family to over-harvest the honey. Problems emerge.

Chances of winning: It's rare a documentary gets nominated in this category. (The film is also nominated for best documentary feature.) It was shot over a period of three years by a small crew: the result was 400 hours of rushes which have been expertly edited down. There are a few moments which feel as if they may have been recreated for the camera but overall it's an insight into a life most audiences will know nothing about. No documentary has yet won in the category but Hatidze's personality alone makes the film worth seeing. The directors have now bought her a new house.

France's track record in this category: 40 nominations with 12 wins. (Only Italy has won more often)

What's it About?: Abandon thoughts of Jean Valjean, Inspector Javert and anthems sung on barricades. The film takes its title from the Victor Hugo novel but it's set in the modern social housing estate of les Bosquets in eastern Paris. (Parts of the book are set around the same area.) Stéphane is a policeman transferred to a unit which patrols the tough neighbourhood by car. Tensions, some racial, simmer with residents. The two officers Stéphane is assigned to - one white, one black - have learnt to cut corners if they see the need. A lion cub is stolen from a circus, which at first seems almost comic. Then a violent incident occurs which the police need to hide. But a complication emerges: the incident was filmed from a drone.

Chances of winning: Director Ladj Ly is from a Malian immigrant family and grew up in the area, where there were big riots in 2005. It's his first feature film and it took the Jury Prize at Cannes last year. Much of the screenplay works well as a police procedural but it's strange that though he digs into the policemen's characters we're left needing to learn more about individuals in the community. At times plot and characterisations don't convince. Stéphane comes across as improbably naive about colleagues' attitudes to policing a tough beat and the background of day-to-day life for the mainly African families barely registers. There's ample tension in the first half but as mayhem kicks off the story loses some of its grip.

Spain's track record in this category: 19 nominations, including four wins

What's it about?: Salvador Mallo (played by Antonio Banderas) is a respected Spanish film-maker who's financially well-off but beginning to feel his age - it's not clear he will ever make another film. His health is failing and he is increasingly prone to depression and dependence on drugs. In extended flashbacks to childhood we see his love for his mother (played by Penelope Cruz), the first stirrings of gay sexuality and the sparky intelligence which set him apart as a boy. Struggling to rediscover a creative path, Mallo goes to visit the star of an early hit with whom he fell out many years ago.

Chances of winning: Almodovar (now 70) has been nominated twice before in this category and won in 1999 for All About My Mother. He also took an Oscar for his screenplay for Talk to Her so he's a known quantity with Oscar voters. Almodovar insists Pain and Glory isn't explicitly autobiographical but there are clear parallels with his own life. The film's attractively shot and designed and the performances are excellent. The story's quieter and more considered than many of his early works though sometimes it feels the director is revisiting old ground. But if there's one thing Academy members love it's a screen full of good-looking people lamenting how tough it is to be a film-maker.

South Korea's track record in this category: It's the first South Korean film nominated in this category

What's it about?: The film is a dark and intricately worked out farce with a strong streak of class-based satire (and with more violence than farce normally involves). The Kim family lives in a crowded &quot;semi-basement&quot; where they just about get by financially. A friend suggests the son could make cash filling in for him as tutor to a wealthy but wildly dysfunctional family. One-by-one the existing domestic staff disappear as he schemes to get his entire family employed. The Kims seem secure financially at last. Of course fate has other ideas.

Chances of winning: Parasite took the Palme d'Or at Cannes last year and has just won best film not in the English language at this year's Baftas. There are many Hollywood executives who since then have wished they'd come up with the story, thrown it to a US writer and sat back to await the Oscar plaudits. As well as best international film it's nominated for best picture, best director, best screenplay, best editing and best production design. It's worth buying a ticket just to ogle the gorgeous house for a couple of hours (it was built especially on a movie lot). Many see the film as the most predictable of shoo-ins at this year's Oscars. Some Academy members may feel it's wasteful to hand the award to a film likely to win in other categories... though last year Roma took best foreign language film despite having nine other nominations.

If Parasite does win, and after Alfonso Cuaron's success last time, does that suggest this category is undergoing a fundamental shift toward the mainstream? Is the era over when an accomplished but little-noticed film could come from nowhere to take this Oscar?

Follow us on Facebook or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51136829</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Super Bowl 2020: James Bond, Top Gun and Black Widow trailers unveiled - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/105E5/production/_110754076_super1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Trailers for the Top Gun sequel, the new James Bond film and other keenly anticipated movies have been unveiled during this year's Super Bowl.

Fans also got new glimpses of Black Widow and the new Minions movie.

Bill Murray, Chris Rock and Winona Ryder were a few of the Hollywood stars enlisted to star in adverts on one of the biggest nights in the US television-watching calendar.

The cost of a 30-second spot during the game can be more than $5m (£3.8m).

Yet that is considered a price worth paying for the exposure a slot during the annual American Football showdown can bring to a film, TV show or product.

The 30-second trailer for No Time To Die, the 25th official Bond film, opened with a previously unseen scene showing Daniel Craig's Bond in a hi-tech glider.

&quot;Have you ever flown one of these things before?&quot; he asks Lashana Lynch's Nomi, a fellow secret agent, who responds with &quot;Nope&quot;.

The &quot;official game day spot&quot; continued with a promise that &quot;the 25th film will change everything&quot; when it arrives in cinemas in April.

The film, billed as Craig's final outing as Bond, will see his character return to active service to combat a new adversary, played by Bohemian Rhapsody's Rami Malek.
• What we learned from the first James Bond trailer

Two of this year's Oscar nominees were seen joining forces in the promo for Black Widow, the latest superhero film from Marvel Studios.

Scarlett Johansson and Florence Pugh appear alongside Rachel Weisz in the 30-second teaser for the first stand-alone outing for Johansson's Natasha Romanoff character.

&quot;At some point we all have to choose between what the world wants you to be and who you are,&quot; she is heard saying amid scenes of explosive mayhem.

Johansson and Pugh were both up for prizes at Sunday's Bafta Film Awards - two in Scarlett's case - but each left empty-handed.
• Seven talking points from the Black Widow trailer

There was more ominous voiceover work in the trailer for Top Gun: Maverick, this time emanating from actor Miles Teller.

&quot;My dad believed in you,&quot; his character is heard telling Pete &quot;Maverick&quot; Mitchell, played by Tom Cruise. &quot;I'm not going to make the same mistake.&quot;

The long-awaited sequel to 1986's Top Gun sees Cruise's hotshot jet pilot become instructor to the son of his deceased former flying partner.

Dramatic scenes of Cruise in the cockpit of an F/A-18F Super Hornet pad out the trailer for the film, which lands in cinemas in July.

Other sequels to be promoted during the Super Bowl included Fast &amp; Furious 9, A Quiet Place Part II and Minions: The Rise of Gru.

The latter - another outing for the yellow helpers from the Despicable Me series - promised a check-list of elements including &quot;action, bad guys, snacks, explosions [and] nuns&quot;.

A similar tactic was employed by an ad for The SpongeBob Movie: Sponge on the Run, whose own itinerary included &quot;fast cars, robots [and] a wise sage&quot; played by Keanu Reeves.

A promo for the new Sonic the Hedgehog film, meanwhile, saw US sports stars Michael Thomas, Kyle Busch and Allyson Felix sing the praises of its spiny hero.
• Sonic The Hedgehog gets 'glow up of the century'

Streaming giants also got in on the action during Sunday's game, with Amazon Prime unveiling an ad for its new drama Hunters.

The series, which premieres later this month, stars Al Pacino as the head of a team of Nazi-hunters out to thwart the creation of a Fourth Reich in 1970s America.

Disney + also unveiled its own forthcoming wares, a trio of shows built around characters from the Marvel Cinematic Universe - The Falcon and the Winter Soldier, WandaVision and Loki.

Another Disney enterprise, its live action retelling of 1998 animation Mulan, was promoted by a trailer running two minutes in length.

Other Super Bowl adverts saw famous names co-opting scenes from well-known films to promote products.

They included Bill Murray, who appeared in an ad for car giant Jeep, which saw him parody scenes from his 1993 comedy Groundhog Day.

Bryan Cranston was seen wielding an axe in an advert for soft drink Mountain Dew, which spoofed horror classic The Shining.

Sylvester Stallone, meanwhile, recreated his iconic Rocky Balboa character as part of a series of adverts for Facebook fronted by comedian Chris Rock.

Winona Ryder could be seen travelling to the Minnesotan city of Winona in a Squarespace ad, while Jonah Hill reunited with Martin Scorsese, who directed him in 2013's The Wolf of Wall Street, for Coca Cola, and Gal Gadot and Molly Ringwald popped up in other spots.

In between all that, the Kansas City Chiefs pulled off a sensational comeback to beat the San Francisco 49ers and lift the the Vince Lombardi Trophy.

This year's Half Time Show in Miami saw Latin singers Jennifer Lopez and Shakira perform a sizzling 12-minute set comprising 20 different songs.

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51354787</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Bafta Film Awards 2020: 10 things we learned at the ceremony - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/C142/production/_110747494_ward_getty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It was undoubtedly 1917's night at the Baftas, with seven awards including best film, but the ceremony's hottest topic was diversity.

Host Graham Norton opened by saying it was &quot;the year when white men finally broke through... 11 nominations for Joker - the story of a white man who makes himself even whiter&quot;. He joked that Once Upon a Time in Hollywood harked back to 50 years ago when film was &quot;a misogynistic male-dominated industry, resistant to change&quot;.

The Bafta nominations have been criticised for the serious lack of diversity. All the acting nominees this year were white, while no female directors have now been nominated since 2013.

It &quot;simply cannot be right in this day and age&quot; to still be talking about diversity, said the Duke of Cambridge, while Joker star and best actor winner Joaquin Phoenix took aim at &quot;systemic racism&quot; in the film industry.

Rebel Wilson flew the flag for the lack of female directors, saying of the all-male nominees: &quot;I don't think I could do what they do, honestly, I just don't have the balls.&quot;
• Does current Bafta voting system need to change?

But those who addressed the issue in the winners' press room were more upbeat, even sounding optimistic about the future.

1. 'Going in right direction' on diversity

Top Boy and Blue Story star Micheal Ward said: &quot;I feel like we're going in the right direction.&quot; He was hopeful that once &quot;people like me can see there's a lot more opportunities&quot;, they'll get into &quot;stuff like this and hopefully get nominated&quot;.

Parasite's South Korean director Bong Joon Ho also had high hopes: &quot;From the various efforts we've been putting in, we will arrive where we do have diversity in this industry, whether it's about gender, sexuality or people of colour.&quot;

Renee Zellweger simply felt &quot;grateful that there is more material out there that speaks to a wider audience&quot;.

&quot;I think it's important that content should reflect society more completely - I agree with that,&quot; said the Judy star and best actress winner.

The Bafta organisers will no doubt be keen that their voters are listening.

Rebel Wilson drew several sharp intakes of breath for her speech, including her comments on Cats, in which she played Jennyanydots.

The film has performed badly with critics and at the box office, and Wilson said: &quot;I made this dress by sewing two old dresses together. The red is from that one time I didn't win Miss Australia and the black is from a funeral I just went to for the feature film Cats.

&quot;Strangely not nominated for any awards, I'm not sure if everyone here is across the controversy, but this year there has been a distinct lack of nominations for felines.&quot;

The Force was with the Star Wars actor when he confidently predicted that Joker wouldn't sweep the board, despite having the most nominations.

As award ceremonies go, this wasn't a particularly surprising one, but Boyega was still spot on.

4. Laura Dern kept it in the family

Surely not many families can boast two best supporting actress wins across two generations... but Laura Dern can lay claim to this, after winning her Bafta for Marriage Story.

Her mother, actress Diane Ladd, won in 1976 for Alice Doesn't Live Here Anymore.

&quot;My award is a homage to my incredible mother - to be honoured in same category as her means more than I can express, I'm so grateful,&quot; she said backstage.

If Robert De Niro says you don't have to sit through all three-and-a-half hours of Netflix's mob film in one go, then it must be okay.

He told the BBC that as long as you can appreciate &quot;the meaning&quot; of the film, you can break it up a bit. Phew.

Andy Serkis limped to the Baftas after &quot;a skiing faux pas on New Year's Day&quot;, using a pretty sharp-looking set of black velvet and diamante crutches.

He's 40 days into directing Venom 2 with Tom Hardy and told BBC News the costume team gave his crutches a makeover for the red carpet.

7. Jojo Rabbit was one swear-word away from an R-rating

Taika Waititi, whose satirical look at World War Two won him best adapted screenplay, said he &quot;wants young people to see his film&quot; JoJo Rabbit. But he also wanted to include a particularly strong swear-word about Hitler.

&quot;You can have this word once in a movie, but anything above that is an automatic R-rating so that one word was really important to me, I was determined to keep it,&quot; he said after winning his Bafta.

So the film got a 12A rating in the UK. Had it got an R-rating in the US, anyone aged under 17 would have to be accompanied by an adult.

8. The small star of For Sama was very lively

Every parent of young children has experienced this, where you're trying to make a serious point to other adults - and all your child wants to do is run around, preferably with you in tow.

For Sama won best documentary for its searing portrayal of a journalist and doctor and their young daughter, enduring bombing and bloodshed in Aleppo.

Waad Al-Kateab had taken her daughter Sama on stage to collect the award, so by the time they got to the press room, the four-year old had some steam to let off. Al-Kateab and her husband Hamza wisely let her run around while they spoke.

She said of her film: &quot;We're trying to shed light on what's happening and tell the governments and decision makers - I hope all of this recognition will make it stand out. This is not about aliens, it's about people like them.&quot;

Hamza added that hospitals are being bombed, and said: &quot;Critics say it's hard to watch, it's harder that it's happening.&quot;

Sama ran the length of the press stage and played with the microphones before scampering off with her parents.

Hugh Grant was on stage to present an award just after Renee Zellweger won her Bafta.

He briefly slipped back into character from Bridget Jones's Diary, saying: &quot;Well done Jones. That was a very silly little dress.&quot;

In the film of the book, Zellweger played the hapless and desirable Bridget, who is hotly pursued by Grant's character Daniel Cleaver (the cad) and Colin Firth's remote but honourable Mark Darcy.

Zellweger told the press room Grant's comment was &quot;pretty cool, makes you feel like you're one of the [British] gang and it's quite a gang to be part of&quot;.

The Marriage Story and Jojo Rabbit nominee wore a lot of feathers to the Baftas, so it's not surprising a few dislodged on her way to the ceremony.

BBC News found a few after she'd gone, and they were rather beautiful. Let's hope she floated home in a cloud of pink that stayed intact for the rest of the evening.

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51351472</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Lupita Nyong'o: 'Books don't have to be about white people' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Family &amp; Education</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/714E/production/_110760092_p0826nnf.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Star of 12 Years A Slave, Lupita Nyong'o visited Harris Westminster Sixth Form, London to mentor young women on leadership and the importance of literacy in an event hosted by the National Literacy Trust in partnership with Lancôme.

Nyong'o, now a best-selling author, told the BBC she didn't even like reading when she was young.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/education-51364502</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Baftas 2020: Stars walk the red carpet - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/8768/production/_110746643_p0823t8b.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Some of the world's biggest film stars are gathering in London for the 2020 Bafta Awards.

Joker, 1917 and The Irishman are among the most heavily nominated movies at this year's ceremony, being held at the Royal Albert Hall in London.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51351975</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-06-06 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Dynamo: How Crohn's made me '150% better at magic' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-06-06</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Entertainment &amp; Arts</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/105F/production/_110719140_gettyimages-1154011415.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Magician Dynamo has said his struggle with Crohn's disease and arthritis has made him &quot;150% better at magic&quot;.

At the height of his illness, doctors told Dynamo, whose real name is Steven Frayne, that he may never be able to use his hands to perform magic again.

&quot;I was like, I'm Dynamo, I've got to figure out a way to do it,&quot; he told The Travel Diaries podcast.

&quot;I do the impossible. I'm not going to go out like this.&quot;

He decided to put the magic in the audience's hands, and &quot;try and empower them&quot;, he told podcast host Holly Rubenstein.

&quot;But over time I started to get the use of my hands back. I had all these new skills that I'd developed in my hospital bed - and the old skills coming back too. So although I'm not 100% healthy yet, I am technically 150% better at magic.&quot;

Dynamo's health forced him to step back from the limelight at the height of his success, having played arena tours and starred in TV shows including Dynamo: Magician Impossible.

In 2018, he addressed a dramatic change in his appearance, explaining that his medication regime caused him to &quot;put on quite a lot of body weight&quot; and develop a rash.

He told The Travel Diaries he used two months in hospital to conceive his forthcoming Sky One series, Beyond Belief.

&quot;I was on a lot of heavy medication, which made me go a little bit crazy. But some of the ideas that came into my head were out of this world. I wrote them down in my little black book and this series brings those ideas to life.&quot;

The three-part special shines a light on Dynamo's journey towards recovery, as well as taking viewers across the globe as he performs &quot;heart-stopping magic&quot;.

As far as his own travels are concerned, Dynamo recently shared photos from his time gorilla-trekking in Rwanda.

&quot;I almost died a year and a half ago. I [didn't] want to wait too long to tick off the number one thing on my bucket list.&quot;
• Crohn's disease is a condition in which parts of the digestive system become swollen
• It affects people of all ages and starts in childhood or early adulthood
• The main symptoms are diarrhoea, stomach aches and cramps, tiredness and weight loss
• There is no cure for the disease, but treatments can control the symptoms
• In some cases surgery is undertaken to remove a small part of the digestive system

Follow us on Facebook, or on Twitter @BBCNewsEnts. If you have a story suggestion email entertainment.news@bbc.co.uk.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-51324801</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
