<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<DATA>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-1</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: How will it affect my holidays to Europe? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/CB49/production/_104914025_holgetty.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>After Brexit life goes on as normal for British families - and that includes making plans for holidays.

Here's what we know about your holidays in the European Union after Brexit.

The EU rules also apply to travelling to Switzerland, Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein as well.

Am I OK to book a holiday in the EU?

If you are planning to travel to the EU in 2020, you can expect everything to stay the same as when the UK was still an EU member.

Under the UK-EU deal, there will be a transition period, when EU rules and regulations will still apply in the UK.

The transition after Brexit day lasts until the end of 2020. The deal allows for an extension by one or two years, but the UK government has ruled that out.

During the transition, the two sides will negotiate their future relationship.

So if you are booking a holiday for 2021 or beyond, your rights will depend on the future UK-EU relationship, which is yet to be negotiated.

What documents will I need?

The main question most people want to know is whether or not they will need a visa to get to the EU.

You will can still travel freely with a passport until the end of the transition period, in 2020. This applies to UK citizens going to the EU and EU citizens coming to visit the UK.

After transition, tourists from the UK will be allowed to visit EU countries for up to 90 days in every 180 days without a visa, but they will not be allowed to work or study. The EU says this will remain the case for as long as the UK gives the same visa-free travel to EU citizens who want to visit the UK.

Unrelated to Brexit, in 2021 the EU will also be introducing a US-style visa-waiver scheme, which people will have to use if they come from countries that do not need a visa for the EU.

It's called the Etias (European Travel Information and Authorisation System) and will cost €7 (£6.30) and be valid for three years.

When it comes to travel to and from the Republic of Ireland, nothing will change. British and Irish citizens will still be able to continue to travel freely within the Common Travel Area - the UK, Ireland, the Isle of Man, Guernsey and Jersey.

Will there be bigger queues at the airport?

During the transition period there will be no additional border checks so airport queues should not be longer.

If you are wondering whether to join the &quot;EU&quot; or the &quot;non-EU&quot; queue at your destination, the Foreign and Commonwealth Office (FCO) says you will be able to use &quot;EU/EEA passport gates, until at least 31 December 2020&quot;.

What happens from 2021 will depend on the UK-EU talks on the future relationship.

Do I have to get a new passport?

No. Your current passport will be valid for travel until its date of expiry, during the transition.

From 1 January 2021, for travelling in the EU, you will need to have at least six months left on an adult or child passport to travel.

What about the European Health Insurance Card - EHIC?

The EHIC scheme will continue during the transition period.

About 27 million people in the UK have the EHIC, which entitles the holder to state-provided medical treatment in the EU, Switzerland, Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein. It covers both pre-existing medical conditions and emergency care.

What happens to your EHIC in the future will be decided in the negotiations on the future EU-UK relationship.

The government has warned that EHIC cards might not be valid from 2021 and has advised travellers to be sure to get the right travel insurance, especially if they have existing conditions.
• What will happen with my EHIC after Brexit?

What will happen with compensation for airline delays?

Passengers will continue to be entitled to assistance or compensation if there are boarding problems, delays or cancellations.

The Department for Transport has confirmed anyone on a flight from the UK will have the same passenger rights that apply today, both during and after the transition.

What about ferries and Eurostar?

The government says your rights as a rail passenger using either domestic or cross-border rail services such as Eurostar will remain unchanged.

The EU regulations on rail passengers' rights as well as on rules on ferries, coaches and buses are incorporated into UK law, so the protection for passengers will continue in the future.

There's currently a system in place that allows you to travel in the EU without being charged extra for &quot;roaming&quot; - so you can use your mobile for calls, text and data as you would in the UK.

This system will continue during the transition.

What happens after that will depend on what is agreed about the UK's future economic relationship with the EU.

Even if nothing is agreed, the UK has passed legislation that would provide some safeguards to consumers, such as:
• a £45-a-month limit for data usage abroad, after which they would have to opt in for more
• informing consumers when they are about to reach their data allowance
• Mobile roaming: What will happen after Brexit?

What happens if I want to drive abroad - will I need a new licence?

If you want to drive on your holiday in Europe in 2020, you will be able to do so without any additional requirements.

What happens after the transition depends on the arrangements with each country.

Some countries will require drivers to have an International Driving Permit (IDP), especially for longer visits, which can be bought at post offices for £5.50.

Specific advice for each country is available from the government's website.

For UK citizens living in the EU, it's a bit more complex. You may need to exchange your UK licence for a licence issued by an EU country.

Again, the government has issued specific advice for each country.

In some countries, if you wait until after the end of the transition period, you may need to take another driving test.
• Driving after Brexit: What you need to know

Is anything changing with duty free?

Duty-free shopping within the EU came to an end in 1999 and will not return during the transition.

Any changes after the transition will be determined by the EU-UK negotiations.

What about my pets?

Any pet passports issued in the UK will be valid during the transition.

If you're travelling with your pet for the first time in 2020, you'll have to visit your vet to get a pet passport.

Once the transition ends, the EU pet passports will no longer be valid.

The exact rules on what to do when travelling with your pet will depend on the future UK-EU deal.

The UK will be able to apply to the European Commission to become a &quot;listed country&quot; under the EU pet travel laws.

The exact detail on what will happen if the UK becomes an EU listed country is explained on the government website.
• Pet passports: What will happen after Brexit?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-46627083</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-2</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: A seven-year timeline featuring Ariana, Pokemon and GoT - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Newsbeat</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/593D/production/_105854822_pa_getty_reuters_toppikachu.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Brexit - it seems like it took forever, but now it's finally upon us - with the UK leaving the EU on 31 January 2020.

When the referendum was first announced, Kanye and Jay-Z were still friends and Prince Harry and Meghan Markle hadn't even met yet.

Sir Alex Ferguson was managing in the Premier League and Will.i.am and Britney were number one.

Here are some of the key moments in the Brexit timeline - with a little help from Adele, Pokemon and Leicester City.

Prime Minister David Cameron announces that the UK will get a &quot;very simple in or out choice&quot; on EU membership - if the Conservatives win the next election.

Willi.i.am's Scream &amp; Shout, featuring Britney Spears, is top of the charts and Barack Obama has just started his second term as US president.

Fast forward two years, and the Conservatives win the election outright and Ed Miliband resigns as Labour leader.

Meanwhile, emoji becomes the fastest growing language in the UK, according to a university professor.

After finishing renegotiations on the UK's relationship with the EU, David Cameron announces that there will be a referendum on 23 June 2016.

A few days later, Adele cleans up at the Brit Awards, winning best British single for Hello, best British album, best British female solo artist and the global success award.

23 June 2016: The UK votes to leave the EU

The fact that Leicester City are Premier League champions is still sinking in.

The referendum is held, and the UK votes to leave the EU. David Cameron announces his resignation as prime minister.

A few days later, England lose 2-1 to Iceland in Euro 2016, and Roy Hodgson resigns as manager - while Wales make it all the way to the semi-finals.

Prince Harry has recently gone on a blind date with US actress Meghan Markle - although the world won't know this until a few months later.

Theresa May becomes the UK's new prime minister and promises to lead a &quot;one nation&quot; government that works for all not just the &quot;privileged few&quot;.

The country spends the rest of the summer getting into mass brawls, using phones while driving and trespassing onto railway tracks - all to try and catch some Pokemon.

Sam Allardyce has just left his post as England manager after he was secretly filmed discussing how to &quot;get around&quot; international football rules, and Gareth Southgate takes temporary charge.

Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie have recently split after 12 years together - as have Taylor Swift and Tom Hiddleston after three months.

Prime Minister Theresa May announces that the UK will leave the EU on 29 March 2019 - which seems like an age away.

Cheryl has just given birth to her and Liam Payne's baby son, Bear.

The process for leaving the EU, called Article 50, is triggered - which officially starts the two-year countdown to Brexit.

Prime Minister Theresa May calls a surprise general election for June, and it's predicted the Conservative party will win easily.

The UK has another thing on its mind as well - Ed Sheeran's new album ÷ (Divide) is taking the charts by storm.

In a shock result, the Conservative Party loses its majority in the House of Commons which makes it a lot harder for Theresa May to pass future laws.

The UK - and the world - are at the height of Reggaeton-mania, with Despacito reigning in the charts.

A last-minute deal between the EU and UK is agreed.

It says there will be no &quot;hard border&quot; between the UK and Ireland, the rights of EU citizens in the UK and UK citizens in the EU will be protected, and the so-called &quot;divorce bill&quot; will cost around £39bn.

Meanwhile every Sunday, the whole nation's getting its mind blown by David Attenborough's Blue Planet II.

A day after Brexit Secretary David Davis resigns, Foreign Secretary Boris Johnson also resigns. It's over Theresa May's &quot;Cheqeurs plan&quot; for leaving the EU.

But England's attention is focused on Russia and Gareth Southgate's waistcoat for the upcoming World Cup semi-final against Croatia. It's England's best chance to reach a final in a generation.

Theresa May agrees the text of the withdrawal agreement with the EU, but it's not well-received back in the UK.

England's World Cup glory is now just a distant memory after the team failed to make it to the final.

12 December 2018: Theresa May wins vote of no confidence

Conservative MPs who are unhappy with the prime minister's performance trigger a vote of no confidence in her as party leader - which she wins by 200 to 117.

Ariana Grande is in the middle of a six-week run at the top of the charts with Thank U, Next.

16 January 2019: Theresa May wins another vote of no confidence

This time, the vote of no confidence is for the whole of parliament to vote on - not just the Conservatives. It comes after the prime minister's Brexit deal was voted down by MPs.

Theresa May wins again - this time 325 to 306.

In the National Television Awards, Ant and Dec win - again - for best presenter, making it 18 wins in a row.

Seven Labour MPs quit their party because of issues which include Brexit. They're joined by another Labour and three Conservative MPs over the next few days.

Meanwhile, there is a new twist in the story of Empire actor Jussie Smollett - who had claimed he was attacked two men in a homophobic and racist incident.

Police in Chicago say the &quot;trajectory of the investigation&quot; has changed and later arrest and charge him &quot;disorderly conduct/filing a false police report&quot;.

10 March 2019: Prime Minister comes back with legal changes

The Prime Minister returns from a meeting in Strasbourg with the news that &quot;legal changes&quot; have been made to her proposed Brexit plans.

The most significant amendment centres around the border between Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland.

Meanwhile after dating for two years former baseball star Alex Rodriguez and Jennifer Lopez announce their engagement. He popped the question on a beach in The Bahamas.

With just 16 days before Britain is due to leave the European Union - MPs overwhelmingly reject Theresa May's Brexit deal for a second time.

On the same night Manchester City handed a thrashing of their own - they beat German side Schalke 7-0 (8-2 on aggregate) to secure a Champions League quarter final spot.

Some things you just can't get enough of. Game of Thrones, for instance, or time left to leave the EU.

In the same week that the UK was granted an extension of the Article 50 period to 31 October, the eighth and final season of Game of Thrones hit screens.

The end of Game of Thrones doesn't go down too well with viewers, with more than 1.8 million people signing a petition to have the whole thing re-done because they didn't like how it ended.

OMG, more than a million people are going to storm Area 51 in America to discover the secrets about aliens the US government are keeping secret!

Except it never happens - despite all the interest on social media. Things do get serious enough for an official warning to be issued, though.

Something that does happen in July 2019 is that Boris Johnson becomes Prime Minister, following Theresa May's resignation announcement on 24 May.

28 October 2019: Another pushback, this time until 31 January

Boris Johnson promised he would &quot;get Brexit done&quot; when he became PM, but if there's one person we really trust to get things done after what goes down in October 2019, it'd be Coleen Rooney.

She outs her mate........... Rebekah Vardy's account as the person allegedly selling stories on her to the tabloids, resulting in one of the most gripping celebrity stories of the year - it's the sort of can-do attitude many people believe the UK was built upon.

Boris Johnson does manage to secure another Brexit extension, though.

While the UK's celebrating Jacqueline Jossa becoming queen of the jungle, an (arguably) more important vote is about the take place.

The third general election in five years results in the Conservative party getting a huge majority - they go from having fewer than half of the 650 MPs in the House of Commons, to 365.

Christmas comes early for Conservatives in the UK - and the result pretty much ends the arguments around whether the UK leaves or remains in the UK.

The 31 January leaving date is on.

That's it, we're off (from 11pm). Although nothing really changes on the day the UK officially leave the EU.

Not that Big Ben will bong us out, though.

But it's somehow not the biggest news story of the week (that's the spread of the coronavirus). It's not even the second.

That's because in the same week as Brexit finally happens, US basketball star Kobe Bryant is killed, alongside his daughter, in a helicopter accident.

Listen to Newsbeat live at 12:45 and 17:45 weekdays - or listen back here.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-47356852</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-3</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What is a level playing field? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Reality Check</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/15303/production/_110578768_gettyimages-1192540935.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>&quot;Without a level playing field on environment, labour, taxation and state aid, you cannot have the highest quality access to the world's largest single market,&quot; European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen said in a speech at the London School of Economics.

She was talking about what kind of access the United Kingdom could have to the European single market after Brexit.

It is a question set to dominate negotiations on a post-Brexit trade deal, which will probably begin about a month after the UK's departure from the European Union (EU), on 31 January.

And the answer depends, to a large extent, on what's known as the level playing field.

To what does a level playing field refer?

It is a trade-policy term for a set of common rules and standards that prevent businesses in one country undercutting their rivals and gaining a competitive advantage over those operating in other countries.

In other words, it's about fair and open competition - and it's an important part of the EU single market (in which member countries allow the free movement of people, goods, services and money).

Part of a trade negotiation is working out how widespread level playing field provisions should be.

But the areas in which the EU is most insistent they must be maintained are:

Is the EU trying to make the UK a special case?

Yes and no.

On the one hand, almost all trade agreements involve level playing field provisions, because all parties are keen to ensure their businesses aren't operating at a commercial disadvantage.

And the closer a trading relationship is, the stricter those rules become.

But the EU is also taking other factors into account - notably, that the UK is one of the world's largest economies and is right on its doorstep.

The political declaration that sets out the framework for the future relationship between the EU and the UK makes this link explicit.

Given the &quot;geographic proximity and economic interdependence&quot; of the two sides, it says, the future relationship must include &quot;robust commitments to ensure a level playing field&quot;.

What this means in practice is if the UK wants a trade deal that involves zero tariffs (no taxes on goods crossing borders) and zero quotas (no limits on the amount of goods that can be traded), the EU will expect it to sign up to stricter rules than those set out in other recent EU trade agreements with countries such as Canada or Japan.

It's because there is far more trade involved and the stakes are higher.

What are the options?

Prime Minister Boris Johnson has said he wants a zero-tariff zero-quota deal but also insists on the UK's right to diverge or move away from EU rules and regulations when it wants to.

So that could mean sticking close to EU rules in some areas but not in others.

The EU adds a third zero to the equation - &quot;zero dumping&quot;, which means the strictest level playing field rules it can negotiate.

One option is to have what are known as non-regression clauses, which means the two sides would agree not to water down the shared rules they currently have.

Another, tougher, option is to insist on what's called dynamic alignment, which would mean if the EU changed its rules in the future, the UK would automatically make the same changes.

And that's partly what the trade negotiations will be about?

Yes. And both sides are - predictably - digging in a bit.

The early signs are a number of EU countries, including those that do a lot of trade with the UK, are taking a tough line and insisting on dynamic alignment in several policy areas, including state aid and environmental regulations that affect businesses.

But that won't be acceptable in London. Last week, Chancellor Sajid Javid told the Financial Times: &quot;There will not be alignment, we will not be a rule taker.&quot;

Former Prime Minister Theresa May's initial version of the withdrawal agreement with the EU contained a series of legally binding level playing field provisions within it.

Boris Johnson's version doesn't - it relegates most of those rules (apart from some that relate to trade between Northern Ireland and the EU) to the non-binding political declaration.

So agreement on a level playing field regime is going to have to be negotiated before the end of the post-Brexit transition period, in December 2020.

And it is fair to say the two sides will begin a long way apart.

Not only is there disagreement on what should be covered, there is also no meeting of minds yet on how any future disputes should be resolved.

It's another reminder that, after Brexit, the UK will remain a friend and partner of the EU but it will also become a rival.

What claims do you want BBC Reality Check to investigate? Get in touch</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/51180282</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-4</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit day and the battle over Europe in '75 - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/126CE/production/_110707457_p081t380.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>In 1975, the UK voted in a referendum to stay in the European Common Market. Two people from opposing sides of the campaign spoke to the BBC about opinions then, and what has changed now.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51296017</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-5</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: European Parliament overwhelmingly backs terms of UK's exit - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p081srhr.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Members of the European Parliament have overwhelmingly backed the terms of the UK's departure from the EU.

MEPs ratified the Brexit Withdrawal Agreement by 621 votes to 49 following an emotional debate in Brussels.

After the vote, MEPs marked the UK's exit by singing Auld Lang Syne.

Several British MEPs said they hoped the UK would return one day although Eurosceptics, including the Brexit Party's Nigel Farage, used their final speeches to tear into the EU.

The UK is due to leave the bloc at 23:00 GMT on Friday.

Ratification of the withdrawal agreement, agreed by the UK and EU in October, was not in doubt after it easily cleared its committee stage last week.
• As it happened: An emotional send-off for Britain
• New Scottish MEP sworn in - for four days
• Tears and relief as the UK's MEPs bid goodbye
• Mavericks to mainstream: The long campaign for Brexit

Signing the letter confirming the EU's consent, the Parliament's president, David Sassoli, said the two sides must heed the words of the late Labour MP Jo Cox when approaching their future relationship and recognise &quot;there is more that unites us than divides us.&quot;

&quot;You are leaving the EU but you will always be part of Europe…It is very hard to say goodbye. That is why, like my colleagues, I will say arrivederci.&quot;

Wednesday's session saw those on either side of the Brexit debate, including the UK's 73 MEPs, celebrate or lament the end of British EU membership.

Some MEPs marked the occasion with songs - others wore &quot;always united&quot; scarves.

The Parliament's Brexit spokesman, Guy Verhofstadt, said it was &quot;sad to see a country leaving that has twice given its blood to liberate Europe&quot;.

He added that British MEPs had brought &quot;wit, charm, and intelligence&quot; as well as &quot;stubbornness&quot;, and would be missed.

President of the European Commission Ursula von der Leyen said ratification of the withdrawal deal was &quot;only a first step&quot; towards a new partnership between the EU and the UK.

The two should &quot;join forces&quot; in areas such as climate change, she said, and seek a close partnership following the UK's exit on Friday.

&quot;We will always love you and we will not be far,&quot; she told the UK in closing.

The EU's Brexit negotiator Michel Barnier also wished the UK well, saying the bloc would approach talks on the future relationship with &quot;patience&quot; and &quot;objectivity&quot; while defending its members' interests.

On the other side, though, Conservative MEP and prominent Eurosceptic Daniel Hannan said opinion in Britain turned against the bloc when it became clear &quot;the aspiration was to have the EU as a quasi-state&quot;.

&quot;If at any stage Britain had been able to have a trade-only relationship that would have been enough,&quot; he went on, but added: &quot;You are losing a bad tenant and gaining a good neighbour.&quot;

Mr Farage - who has been campaigning for the UK's exit since before he was first elected to the Brussels Parliament in 1999 - used his final speech to excoriate the EU.

&quot;I want Brexit to start a debate right across Europe - what do we want from Europe?&quot; he said, arguing that &quot;trade, friendship, co-operation and reciprocity&quot; between nations could be achieved without &quot;all of these institutions and all of this power&quot;.

He and his fellow Brexit Party MEPs waved Union flags before walking out of the chamber en masse.

A tearful Molly Scott Cato was applauded and hugged by her colleagues after she spoke of her &quot;grief and regret&quot; at Brexit and the hope she would return to the European Parliament &quot;one day&quot;.

&quot;While now is not the time to campaign to rejoin the EU, we must keep the dream alive,&quot; the Green Party MEP said.

Belgian MEP Philippe Lamberts said the EU must learn lessons from the UK's decision to leave.

He said the bloc had to &quot;regain the hearts and minds of European citizens&quot; by focusing on what it could do for the many, not the few.

Earlier, the S&amp;D coalition, which houses Labour's 10 MEPs, displayed a sign aimed at departing British members, which read: &quot;It's not goodbye, it's au revoir.&quot;

On Tuesday evening, several MEPs in the Green group also held a ceremony to mark the UK's departure.

While Brexit Party MEPs spoke of their joy and relief at leaving, others shared messages of sadness on social media as they prepared to vote for the last time.

The Green Party's Alexandra Phillips tweeted: &quot;I'm devastated to be leaving the best job in the world. I get to make real change every day while being surrounded by 27 different languages and cultures.&quot;

Liberal Democrats shared pictures of gifts from the pro-European Renew Europe group.

After the UK leaves, there will be an 11-month transition period in which the two sides hope to negotiate their future economic relationship.

Trade talks are expected to begin in earnest in early March. The European Parliament will also get a say in ratifying any future trade deal.

The UK has insisted talks should not extend beyond 31 December 2020 when a transition period - which will see the UK follow EU rules - comes to an end.

President Sassoli told CNN on Tuesday that the timetable for a deal was tight.

He said the UK's exit would be &quot;painful&quot; for the bloc but building a new partnership based upon friendly co-operation and mutual interests was now essential.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51287430</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-6</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: All you need to know about the UK leaving the EU - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12EE7/production/_110634577_gettyimages-631597526.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The UK stopped being a member of the European Union (EU) after 23:00 GMT on 31 January 2020.

For those not following every twist and turn, this is what you need to know.

Brexit - British exit - refers to the UK leaving the EU.

A public vote (known as a referendum) was held in June 2016, when 17.4 million people opted for Brexit. This gave the Leave side 52%, compared with 48% for Remain.

What is the European Union?

The EU is an economic and political union involving 28 European countries. It allows free trade, which means goods can move between member countries without any checks or extra charges. The EU also allows free movement of people, to live and work in whichever country they choose.

The UK joined in 1973 (when it was known as the European Economic Community) and it will be the first member state to withdraw.

What happens after Brexit day?

After the UK formally leaves the EU on 31 January 2020, there is still a lot to talk about and months of negotiation will follow.

While the UK has agreed the terms of its EU departure, both sides still need to decide what their future relationship will look like.

This will be worked out during the transition period (which some prefer to call the implementation period), which begins immediately after Brexit day and is due to end on 31 December 2020.

During this 11-month period, the UK will continue to follow all of the EU's rules and its trading relationship will remain the same.
• Seven things that will change after Brexit day

What needs to be agreed?

The transition period is meant to give both sides some breathing space while a new free trade agreement is negotiated.

This is needed because the UK will leave the single market and customs union at the end of the transition. A free trade agreement allow goods to move around the EU without checks or extra charges.

If a new one cannot be agreed in time, then the UK faces the prospect of having to trade with no deal in place. That would mean tariffs (taxes) on UK goods travelling to the EU and other trade barriers.

Aside from trade, many other aspects of the future UK-EU relationship will also need to be decided. For example:

Prime Minister Boris Johnson insists the transition period will not be extended, but the European Commission has warned that the timetable will be extremely challenging.
• What is the transition period?
• Brexit: What happens next?

What is the Brexit deal?

The transition period and other aspects of the UK's departure were agreed in a separate deal called the withdrawal agreement.

Most of that was negotiated by Theresa May's government. But after Mr Johnson replaced her in July 2019, he removed the most controversial part - the backstop.

The backstop was designed to ensure there would be no border posts or barriers between Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland after Brexit. If needed, it would have kept the UK in a close trading relationship with the EU.

Under Mr Johnson's deal, a customs border will effectively be created between Northern Ireland and Great Britain. Some goods entering Northern Ireland from Great Britain will be subject to checks and will have to pay EU import taxes (known as tariffs).

These would be refunded if goods remain in Northern Ireland (ie are not moved to the Republic of Ireland).

Supporters of the new customs arrangement say it will allow the UK to negotiate its own trade deals with other countries - something that would not have been possible under the backstop.

The rest of the withdrawal agreement is largely unchanged from the one negotiated by Mrs May. This includes:
• The rights of EU citizens in the UK and British citizens in the EU (which will remain the same during the transition)
• How much money the UK is to pay the EU (estimated to be down to about £30bn)

Why did Brexit take so long?

Brexit was originally meant to happen on 29 March 2019, but the deadline was delayed twice after MPs rejected the deal negotiated by Mrs May, the prime minister at the time.

Many Conservative MPs and the DUP (the government's then ally in Parliament) were unhappy with the backstop - arguing that the UK could remain trapped in the arrangement for years with no way out.

After MPs voted down the deal for a third time, Mrs May resigned.

Mr Johnson needed a Brexit extension of his own after MPs failed to get the revised deal passed into law.

This led to the new deadline of 31 January 2020.

With Parliament still in deadlock, Mr Johnson called an early general election, to which MPs agreed.

The election, which happened on 12 December 2019, resulted in a Conservative majority of 80.

With a sizeable majority in Parliament, it proved straight forward to pass the Brexit legislation.

What questions do you have about Brexit and the future?

In some cases your question will be published, displaying your name, age and location as you provide it, unless you state otherwise. Your contact details will never be published. Please ensure you have read our terms &amp; conditions and privacy policy.

Use this form to ask your question:</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-32810887</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-7</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: The Devon village that held an EEC-joining party - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/16FEF/production/_110719149_ivybridgeparade.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Ivybridge in Devon held a big party when the UK joined the European Economic Community in 1973.

Unlike most of the rest of the South West, which voted heavily Leave in the Brexit referendum, the area voted narrowly to Remain in 2016.

How do Ivybridge's residents feel now we're leaving?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51296016</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-8</ID>
      <TITLE>'Empathy' for independent Scotland joining the EU says Tusk - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Scotland politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p0822npr.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Former European Council president Donald Tusk says Brussels feels &quot;empathy&quot; towards an independent Scotland joining the European Union.

Nicola Sturgeon has said an independent Scotland would seek full EU membership.

When asked if this would be looked upon favourably, Mr Tusk said there would be enthusiasm but he warned the country would not be automatically accepted.

Foreign Secretary Dominic Raab warned the comments could encourage &quot;separatist tendencies&quot; in the EU.

They were &quot;rather un-European and rather irresponsible,&quot; he added.

&quot;I'm not sure European leaders, let alone here in the UK, would actually welcome that comment,&quot; he said.

Mr Tusk, who served as European Council president for five years until November last year, told the BBC's The Andrew Marr Show that he feels &quot;very Scottish, especially after Brexit&quot;.

When asked about the prospect of an independent Scotland joining the EU, the Polish politician said he had to &quot;respect the internal debate in the United Kingdom&quot; and it was not his role to intervene.

But when pressed on the level of support in the EU towards an independent Scotland joining the union, he said: &quot;Emotionally I have no doubt that everyone will be enthusiastic here in Brussels, and more generally in Europe.

&quot;If you ask me about our emotions, you will witness I think always empathy.&quot;

However he warned that any future entry bid on the part of an independent Scotland would not be automatically accepted - &quot;formalities&quot; and treaty agreements would still need to be adhered to.
• Herman Van Rompuy says Brexit 'has changed EU view of Scotland'
• Scotland would 'seek a way back in' to EU

It came as other European leaders expressed sadness at the UK leaving the EU.

French President Emmanuel Macron said he was &quot;deeply sad&quot; while the EU's Guy Verhofstadt pledged to try and &quot;ensure the EU is a project you'll want to be a part of again&quot;.

Mr Tusk's comments come after his predecessor, Herman Van Rompuy, last year said he believes Brexit has changed EU attitudes to Scottish independence.

Britain officially left the European Union on Friday at 23:00 GMT after 47 years of membership, and more than three years after it voted to do so in a referendum.

Scotland voted in favour of the UK staying in the EU by 62% to 38% in 2016.

The overall UK result backed Leave by 51.9% to 48.1%.

In a speech on Brexit day, Nicola Sturgeon said there was &quot;real and profound sadness&quot; felt by many Scots, also tinged with anger.

An independent Scotland would require the backing of all 27 EU members to join the trading bloc and there are a number of countries which have already applied and started accession negotiations.

The European Policy Centre think-tank, of which Mr Van Rompuy is president, last year published an analysis on independent Scottish membership of the EU.

It concluded that the EU should &quot;engage positively&quot; with Scotland in the event of independence, if there had been a properly constituted referendum.

But it said Scotland could not expect &quot;special treatment&quot; and that the Scottish government would have to accept all the obligations of membership, including agreeing in principle to join the euro.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-51342714</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-9</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: Jargon-busting guide to the key terms - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/09B9/production/_105298420_index_image_brexit_jargon_976_v4.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Confused by all the Brexit jargon in the news? Here's a glossary to demystify commonly used EU-related terms.
• 31 January 2020, when the UK's membership of the European Union officially came to an end.
• Under Boris Johnson's revised Brexit deal, Northern Ireland will follow some EU rules.
• In order for the arrangement to continue, the Northern Ireland Assembly will need to give consent.
• This will come in the form of a vote every four years.
• If the Northern Ireland Assembly votes against, the arrangement will come to an end two years later during which time the &quot;joint committee&quot; would make recommendations to the UK and EU on &quot;necessary measures&quot;.
• Once the joint committee is set up, it will consist of a panel of UK and EU representatives.
• Under it, some goods entering Northern Ireland from GB will have to pay EU import taxes (known as tariffs).
• The tax will only have to be paid on goods which are deemed &quot;at risk&quot; of entering the Republic of Ireland.
• The list of &quot;at risk&quot; goods will be decided at a later date.
• If goods subsequently remain in Northern Ireland (ie do not travel to the Republic of Ireland), companies will be able to apply for a refund on the tax they've paid.

What is in Boris Johnson's Brexit plan?
• How rules and regulations could differ between the EU and the UK after Brexit.
• The money the UK agrees to pay to the EU as part of a Brexit deal.
• Under Theresa May's deal it was widely expected to total about £39bn, to be paid over a number of years.
• It was based on UK's share of EU budgets up to 2020 as well as continuing liabilities such as EU civil servants' pensions.
• Some of that money has been paid as part of the UK's normal membership contributions already.
• The Office for Budget Responsibility (OBR) estimates that the bill is now around £30bn.
• The joint committee is a panel which will be set up to supervise how the Brexit deal is put into action.
• It will be made up of an equal number of UK and EU representatives.
• A no-deal Brexit would mean the UK leaving the European Union and cutting ties immediately, with no agreement in place.
• However, the UK left on 31 January with the withdrawal deal negotiated by Boris Johnson.
• A transition period started on the next day, ending on December 31 2020.
• If no UK-EU trade deal is ready, the UK would then have to follow World Trade Organization rules to trade with the EU and other countries, until a deal is ready to be implemented.
• EU citizens and their families who have been living in the UK for five years can apply for &quot;settled status&quot;, which allows them to stay in the UK for as long as they wish.
• Any child born in the UK to a mother with settled status will automatically become a British citizen.
• Settled status means you can work in the UK, use the NHS, have access to pensions and benefits and travel in and out of the UK.
• Applications from people with serious criminal convictions, or where there are other security concerns, can be rejected.
• The transition period is intended to allow time for the UK and EU to agree their future relationship.
• The UK will have no say in the making of new EU laws during the transition but will have to follow all EU rules, including freedom of movement.
• The transition is due to last until 31 December 2020 and could be extended by up to two years if both the UK and the EU wanted.
• However, Boris Johnson has ruled out any extension to the transition.

What is the transition period?
• If countries don't have free-trade agreements, they usually trade with each other under rules set by the World Trade Organization.
• Each country sets tariffs - or taxes - on goods entering. For example, cars passing from non-EU countries to the EU are charged at 10% of their value.
• But tariffs on some agricultural products are much higher - dairy averages more than 35%.
• If the UK chooses to put no tariffs on goods from the EU, it must also have no tariffs on goods from every WTO member.

Reality Check: What does a 'WTO Brexit' mean?

Brexit - British exit - refers to the UK leaving the EU. A public vote was held in June 2016, to decide whether the UK should leave or remain.
• What is in Boris Johnson's Brexit plan?
• What will happen to the EHIC after Brexit?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-43470987</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-10</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit Party MEP Widdecombe leaves leave EU Parliament, led by a bagpiper - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/149A7/production/_110719348_p081x5q8.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Brexit Party MEP Ann Widdecombe has left the European Parliament in Brussels for the last time, led by a bagpiper.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51325236</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-11</ID>
      <TITLE>We've Brexited - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/146F7/production/_110730738_p07yj1sq.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The moment we have been wanging on about for two and a half years.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51337615</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-12</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: NI Assembly votes to withhold Brexit bill consent - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Northern Ireland</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p080x5lj.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The Northern Ireland Assembly has passed a motion withholding consent for the UK's withdrawal from the European Union.

The motion put forward by the Executive Office asked MLAs to consider parts of the Brexit bill that affected Northern Ireland.

It passed without a formal division on Monday.

All 18 Westminster MPs from Northern Ireland opposed the prime minister's Brexit deal last month.

The bill includes a role for the assembly in deciding whether Northern Ireland should still follow some EU customs rules.

The motion was to &quot;affirm that the assembly does not agree to give its consent&quot; to that.
• As Brexit becomes law, what will it mean for NI?
• EU 'will not be rushed' on Brexit trade deal

A request by the TUV leader Jim Allister for the assembly debate to be delayed until next week was rejected by MLAs.

Mr Allister argued the Executive Office had only submitted the motion on Friday and that there had not been enough time for MLAs to propose amendments.

The Speaker Alex Maskey said it was &quot;regrettable&quot; the motion had not been tabled earlier.

First Minister Arlene Foster apologised for the short notice, but said she felt it was important the assembly had its say on the matter before the EU Withdrawal Bill receives its third reading in the House of Lords on Tuesday.

A former secretary of state has said the government's Brexit plans will do &quot;untold damage&quot; to Northern Ireland businesses.

Labour's Lord Hain said the government was asking small and medium businesses in Northern Ireland to &quot;buy a pig in a poke&quot;.

He said NI businesses have been told they would just have to adjust to new regulations, but it was still not clear what those would be.

Lord Hain also accused the government of &quot;trying to have it both ways&quot;.

&quot;On the one hand they're saying to businesses in Northern Ireland and to politicians it's important that you reform and make the Northern Ireland economy more competitive - fair enough,&quot; he said.

&quot;But then they are imposing enormous shackles on the ability of enterprises to succeed with these uncertain, potentially costly, administerially difficult burdens that they will have to bear for trading across into Great Britain.&quot;

He added: &quot;I don't think the government is being fair with Northern Ireland - either its businesses or its politicians - by telling them they have to reform and on the other hand making it more difficult for them to do so by weakening the economy.&quot;

After the UK leaves the EU on 31 January, it will enter an 11-month transition period, where it will largely follow EU rules but will not have any representation in the bloc's institutions.

At the end of the transition period, Northern Ireland will continue to follow EU rules on agricultural and manufactured goods, while the rest of the UK will not.

Additionally, the whole of the UK will leave the EU's customs union but Northern Ireland will continue to enforce the EU's customs code at its ports.

This will mean some new checks and processes for goods moving between Northern Ireland and other parts of the UK.

The details of those processes have to be negotiated between the EU and UK and new systems for businesses will have to implemented.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-northern-ireland-51174448</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-13</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit video explainers: What is it all about? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p06y4b80.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>BBC correspondents on the background, jargon, (and some of the) questions and answers as the UK prepares to leave the EU.

These short films aired on BBC News in 2017 and 2018 and reflect the situation at that time.

Find out more about Brexit issues on our special index

Two sides of Theresa May's deal in 96 seconds

Brexit deal: Does this mean everything is decided?

The Brexit agreement summarised in two minutes

What do all these Brexit terms mean?

Is the EU really united over Brexit?

What are the options available for the UK?

What will happen to trade?

What will Brexit mean for the union?</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-46201339</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-14</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: Britain 'will not be aligning with EU rules' - Raab - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/images/ic/1024x576/p0822qx1.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Britain will &quot;not be aligning with EU rules&quot; in any post-Brexit trade deal, the foreign secretary has said.

Dominic Raab argued agreeing to stick strongly with EU regulations would &quot;defeat the point of Brexit&quot;.

But Irish PM Leo Varadkar said the UK needed to commit to a level playing field to get a free trade deal.

Talks to negotiate a free trade deal between the UK and the EU are due to start next month, following the UK's formal withdrawal from the bloc.

On Monday Boris Johnson is expected to set out his position ahead of those talks, where he will tell the EU he is prepared to accept customs checks at Britain's borders if he cannot secure the sort of trade deal he wants.

EU chief negotiator Michel Barnier will also outline his approach to negotiations.
• Brexit: What happens next?
• Seven things Brexit will change and seven it won't

One option the PM could support would be a Canada-style free trade deal which allows tariff-free trade for the majority of goods, but would not cover the UK's service industry - which accounts for more than 80% of UK jobs.

Reports in recent days have suggested EU chiefs want the UK to continue to follow EU rules on standards and state subsidies - while accepting the jurisdiction of the European Court of Justice in any trade disputes.

The PM is expected to say that he will accept no alignment and no jurisdiction of the European courts when talks start in March.

He is also preparing to say he would rule out relaxing rules on workers' rights, food hygiene standards and environmental protections.

Speaking to the BBC's Andrew Marr Show, Mr Varadkar said it was possible for the UK to have a &quot;Canada-style agreement&quot;.

However, he added: &quot;Canada isn't the UK; you're geographically part of the European continent, we share seas and airspace and our economies are very integrated.

&quot;And one thing we feel very strongly in the EU is that if we are going to have tariff-free, quota-free trade with the UK, which is essentially what we have with Canada on almost everything, then that needs to come with a level playing field.

&quot;We, for example would have very strong views on fair competition and state aid.&quot;

A level playing field is a trade policy phrase for a set of common rules and standards that prevent businesses in one country undercutting their rivals over those operating in other countries in areas such as workers' rights and environmental protections.

He also cautioned against &quot;setting rigid red lines&quot; for the post-Brexit trade negotiations arguing &quot;it makes coming to an agreement more difficult because the other side doesn't feel like it has got a fair deal unless those red lines are turned pink.&quot;

Mr Raab said the UK would enter trade talks &quot;with a spirit of goodwill&quot; but added &quot;the legislative alignment - it just ain't happening&quot;.
• Mavericks to mainstream: The long campaign for Brexit

Labour's John McDonnell said Mr Johnson's desire to diverge from EU rules &quot;contradict&quot; what the PM had previously said on protecting environmental, consumer and employment rights.

&quot;On the one hand he said there will be [protections] on the other hand he is sabre-rattling saying that won't happen in the negotiations,&quot; he said.

But Brexit Party leader Nigel Farage welcomed the prime minister's approach arguing it was in the UK's &quot;national interest&quot; to be &quot;a competitor on their [the EU's] doorstep.&quot;

The government also wants to make progress in striking free trade agreements with countries such as the United States, Japan, Australia and New Zealand.

The EU's own approach to the negotiations needs to be agreed by all 27 member states - which would be unlikely to happen before the end of February.

While the UK officially left the EU at 23:00 GMT on Friday, it will remain wedded to EU rules during a transition period which ends in December this year.

The UK can request an extension to this transition period, but Mr Johnson has previously said he will not do so.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-51345776</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-15</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: How did we get here? The past four years in two minutes - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/3F71/production/_110714261_p081v68m.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>It's been more than three years since the UK voted to leave the European Union but now it's about to happen.

Through two changes of prime minister, two general elections, and more votes in parliament than anyone cares to remember, here's a quick recap of how we got here.

Read more: Your simple guide to the UK leaving the EU</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51296015</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-16</ID>
      <TITLE>Michel Barnier: 'We are weaker than if we were together' - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>Europe</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/12AFD/production/_110714567_p081vpwf.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Lessons need to be learnt from Brexit, according to Europe's chief negotiator Michel Barnier.

He told the BBC's Europe editor Katya Adler that the EU needs to listen to the people of Europe more closely in the future and he is expecting tough negotiations with the UK in order to deliver a &quot;free and fair&quot; trade deal.

Read more: PM to hail 'dawn of a new era' as Brexit day arrives
• Brexit: How did we get here? The past four years in two minutes</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-51319607</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-17</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What happens now? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/120A2/production/_110709837_brexit_flowchart_conservative_maj_29_01_640-nc.png</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>The UK left the EU on 31 January 2020 and has now entered an 11-month transition period.

During this period the UK effectively remains in the EU's customs union and single market and continues to obey EU rules.

However, it is no longer part of the political institutions. So, for example, there are no longer any British MEPs in the European Parliament.
• What is Boris Johnson's deal with the EU?

The first priority will be to negotiate a trade deal with the EU. The UK wants as much access as possible for its goods and services to the EU.

But the government has made clear that the UK must leave the customs union and single market and end the overall jurisdiction of the European Court of Justice.

Time is short. The EU could take weeks to agree a formal negotiating mandate - all the remaining 27 member states and the European Parliament have to be in agreement. That means formal talks might only begin in March.

The government has ruled out any form of extension to the transition period.

If no trade deal has been agreed and ratified by the end of the year, then the UK faces the prospect of tariffs on exports to the EU.

The prime minister has argued that as the UK is completely aligned to EU rules, the negotiation should be straightforward. But critics have pointed out that the UK wishes to have the freedom to diverge from EU rules so it can do deals with other countries - and that will make negotiations more difficult.

It's not just a trade deal that needs to be sorted out. The UK must agree how it is going to co-operate with the EU on security and law enforcement. The UK is set to leave the European Arrest Warrant scheme and will have to agree a replacement. It must also agree deals in a number of other areas where co-operation is needed.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-46393399</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-18</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What is in Boris Johnson's new deal with the EU? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/26B3/production/_109270990_hi056542621.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>A revised Brexit deal has been agreed by the UK and EU. What is in it?

Most of the changes - to the deal agreed by Theresa May with EU in November 2018 - are to do with the status of the Irish border after Brexit. This issue has dominated talks for months.

All sides want to avoid the return of a &quot;hard border&quot; between Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland after Brexit - with checks and infrastructure that could be targeted by paramilitary groups.

Coming up with solutions to this - acceptable to all sides - has been very challenging.

The new protocol replaces the controversial Irish backstop plan in Theresa May's deal. Much of the rest of that deal will remain.

Here are some of the key new parts:

The whole of the UK will leave the EU customs union. The customs union is an agreement between EU countries not to charge taxes called tariffs on things coming from other EU countries, and to charge the same tariffs as each other on things coming from outside the EU.

Leaving the customs union means the UK will be able to strike trade deals with other countries in the future.

Legally there will be a customs border between Northern Ireland (which stays in the UK) and the Republic of Ireland (which stays in the EU), but in practice things won't be checked on that border.

The actual checks will be on what is effectively a customs border between Great Britain and the island of Ireland, with goods being checked at &quot;points of entry&quot; into Northern Ireland.

Taxes will only have to be paid on goods being moved from Great Britain to Northern Ireland if those products are considered &quot;at risk&quot; of then being transported into the Republic of Ireland.

A joint committee made up of UK and EU representatives will decide at a later date what goods are considered &quot;at risk&quot;.

If taxes are paid on &quot;at risk&quot; goods that do not end up being sent on from Northern Ireland into the EU, the UK would be responsible for whether to refund the money.

Individual travellers won't have their baggage checked and taxes will not have to be paid by individuals sending goods to other people.

Separately, there will be limits agreed by the joint committee on the amount of help the government can give to Northern Irish farmers. The figure will be based on the amount they currently receive from the EU's Common Agricultural Policy.
• Where have the UK and EU compromised?
• Brexit deal: What does it mean?
• Brexit: What happens now?
• Have UK voters changed their minds on Brexit?

When it comes to the regulation of goods (that's the rules they have to follow on things like labelling and manufacturing processes) Northern Ireland would keep to EU rules rather than UK rules.

That removes the need for checks on goods including food and agricultural produce at the border between Ireland and Northern Ireland, because both will be part of an &quot;all-island regulatory zone&quot;.

But it adds to the checks between the rest of the UK - which will not necessarily be sticking to EU single market rules - and Northern Ireland.

This will be done by UK officials at &quot;points of entry&quot; into Northern Ireland, but the EU will have the right to have its own officials present.

It seems those EU officials may be able to overrule UK officials. The agreement states that EU representatives will be able to ask UK authorities to take certain steps in individual cases and they will have to do so.

Because Northern Ireland will be set apart from the rest of the UK when it comes to customs and other EU rules, the deal gives its Assembly a vote on these new arrangements.

But this vote would not happen until four years after the end of the transition period (the time after Brexit when everything stays the same to allow everyone to prepare for the changes while the UK's future relationship with the EU is discussed). The transition period is due to run until at least the end of 2020. So the four-year period would run until the end of 2024.

If the Northern Ireland Assembly votes against the new arrangements, they would stop applying two years later, during which time the &quot;joint committee&quot; would make recommendations to the UK and EU on what to do about this.

If there were to be no agreement during this two year period, some form of hard border could re-emerge in Ireland, but it's unlikely that would be allowed to happen.

If the Assembly accepts the continuing provisions by a simple majority, they will then apply for another four years. If the deal has &quot;cross-community support&quot; then they will apply for eight years.

The deal defines cross-community support as more than 50% of unionist and nationalist Assembly members voting in favour, or at least 40% of members from each designation if in total at least 60% of members have voted in favour.

The UK government has said that if the Northern Ireland Assembly is still not sitting at that point, it will make alternative arrangements to make sure a vote can take place.

The new agreement says that EU law on value added tax (VAT - a tax added when you make purchases) will apply in Northern Ireland, but only on goods, not services.

But it also allows Northern Ireland to have different VAT rates to the rest of the UK, which would not normally be allowed under EU law.

For example, if the UK decided to reduce the VAT on household fuel to zero, Northern Ireland would still have to keep it at 5%, which is the EU minimum.

It also means that Northern Ireland may get the same VAT rates on certain goods as the Republic of Ireland, to stop there being an unfair advantage on either side of the border.

Some things have not changed:

Much of Mrs May's original Brexit deal will remain as part of the overall agreement. Some of the key areas are:

The transition - a period of time during which all of the current rules stay the same allowing the UK and the EU to negotiate their future relationship - is due to last until the end of December 2020.

The UK will need to abide by EU rules and pay into the EU budget, but will lose membership of its institutions.

The transition can be extended, but only for a period of one or two years.

Both the UK and EU must agree to any extension.

UK citizens in the EU, and EU citizens in the UK, will retain their residency and social security rights after Brexit.

Freedom of movement rules will continue to apply during transition. This means that UK nationals will be able to live and work in EU countries (and EU nationals will be able to live and work in UK) during this period.

Anyone who remains in the same EU country for five years will be allowed to apply for permanent residence.

The UK will have to settle its financial obligations to the EU.

There is no precise figure but the biggest part of this &quot;divorce bill&quot; will be the UK contributions to the EU budget until the end of the transition period at the end of 2020.

When Brexit was delayed it meant that some of that money was paid as the UK's normal membership contributions, so less of it was part of the divorce bill.

When the Brexit date was 31 October 2019, the Office for Budget Responsibility (OBR) estimated that the bill was about £32.8bn (down from £39bn).

To reach an estimate of what the bill would be for departure on 31 January 2020, you could subtract the £1.62bn that the OBR said was left to pay in membership fees in 2019 and 14% of the £10.69bn for the whole of 2020 (it's more than one twelfth because the EU usually requests a higher proportion of the contributions earlier in the year). That gives a total of just under £30bn.

The OBR expects that most of the money - about three-quarters of the total - would be paid by 2022, with some relatively small payments still being made in the 2060s.

This is addressed in the political declaration. This text, which is not legally binding, has also been revised by UK/EU negotiators.

It says that both sides will work towards a Free Trade Agreement (FTA) and a high-level meeting will happen in June 2020 to see how that work is going.

The text also contains a new paragraph on the so-called &quot;level playing field&quot; - the degree to which the UK will agree to stick closely to EU regulations in the future.

The references to a &quot;level playing field&quot; were removed from the legally-binding withdrawal agreement and put in the political declaration, which is not binding.

It says that both sides will keep the same high standards on state aid, competition, social and employment standards, the environment, climate change, and &quot;relevant tax matters&quot;.

What claims do you want BBC Reality Check to investigate? Get in touch</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-50083026</URL>
   </DOC>
   <DOC>
      <ID>bbc2017-03-03 00:00:00-19</ID>
      <TITLE>Brexit: What will change after Friday, 31 January? - BBC News</TITLE>
      <AUTHER>['https://www.facebook.com/bbcnews']</AUTHER>
      <DATE>2017-03-03</DATE>
      <TOPIC>UK Politics</TOPIC>
      <IMAGE>https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/1024/branded_news/1133C/production/_110606407_gettyimages-181134468.jpg</IMAGE>
      <TEXT>Now that the UK has formally left the European Union, it immediately enters an 11-month transition period.

During the transition the UK will continue to obey EU rules and pay money to the EU. Most things will stay the same but there will be some changes:

Familiar faces such as Nigel Farage and Ann Widdecombe are among the UK's 73 MEPs who will automatically lose their seats in the European Parliament.

That's because, at the moment of Brexit, the UK will leave all of the EU's political institutions and agencies.

However, in addition to the UK following EU rules during the transition period, the European Court of Justice will continue to have the final say over legal disputes.

UK Prime Minister Boris Johnson will have to be specially invited if he wants to join other leaders at EU Council summits in the future.

British ministers will also no longer attend regular EU meetings that decide things such as fishing limits.

3. We will be hearing a lot about trade

The UK will be able to start talking to countries around the world about setting new rules for buying and selling goods and services.

It has not been allowed to hold formal trade negotiations with countries like the US and Australia while it remained an EU member. Brexit supporters argue that having the freedom to set its own trade policy will boost the UK's economy.

There's also a lot to be discussed with the EU. Agreeing a UK-EU trade deal is a top priority, so extra charges on goods and other trade barriers aren't needed when the transition ends.

If any trade deals are reached, they won't be able to start until the transition period ends.
• Sir John Curtice: Do Britons now agree about Brexit?

Blue passports will be making a return, more than 30 years after they were replaced by the current burgundy design.

Announcing the change in 2017, then Immigration Minister, Brandon Lewis, praised the return to the &quot;iconic&quot; blue-and-gold design, first used in 1921.

The new colour will be phased in over a number of months, with all new passports issued in blue by the middle of the year.

Existing burgundy passports will continue to be valid.

About three million commemorative 50p Brexit coins bearing the date &quot;31 January&quot; and the inscription: &quot;Peace, prosperity and friendship with all nations&quot;, will enter circulation on Friday.

The coin has received a mixed reaction, with some Remain supporters saying they will refuse to accept it.

The government had planned to introduce a similar coin on 31 October, the date Brexit was previously meant to happen.

However, those coins had to be melted down and recycled after the deadline was extended.

The team that handled the UK-EU negotiations and no-deal preparations will disband on Brexit day.

The Department for Exiting the European Union was set up by former Prime Minister Theresa May in 2016.

For the upcoming talks, the UK's negotiating team will be based in Downing Street.

7. Germany won't extradite its citizens to the UK

It won't be possible for some suspected criminals to be brought back to the UK if they flee to Germany.

Germany's constitution does not allow its citizens to be extradited, unless it's to another EU country.

&quot;This exception cannot apply any more after the UK has left EU,&quot; a spokesman from the German Federal Ministry of Justice told BBC News.

It's unclear if the same restrictions will apply to other countries. Slovenia, for example, says the situation is complicated, while the European Commission was unable to provide comment.

The UK Home Office says the European Arrest Warrant will continue to apply during the transition period. (That means Germany will be able to extradite non-German citizens.)

However, it adds that if a country's laws prevent extradition to the UK it &quot;will be expected to take over the trial or sentence of the person concerned&quot;.
• What is the transition period?

Seven things that will stay the same...

Because the transition period begins immediately after Brexit, the vast majority of other things remain the same - at least until 31 December 2020 including:

Flights, boats and trains will operate as usual.

When it comes to passport control, during the transition period, UK nationals will still be allowed to queue in the areas reserved for EU arrivals only.

As long as they are valid, these will continue to be accepted.
• Driving after Brexit: What you need to know

These are the cards that provide UK nationals with state-provided medical treatment in case of illness or accident.

They can be used in any EU country (as well as Switzerland, Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein) and will continue to be valid during the transition period.
• Will the EHIC still be valid after Brexit?

4. Living and working in the EU

Freedom of movement will continue to apply during the transition, so UK nationals will still be able to live and work in the EU as they currently do.

The same applies for EU nationals wanting to live and work in the UK.

UK nationals living in the EU will continue to receive their state pension and will also receive the annual increase.
• How will Brexit affect UK pensioners in Europe?

The UK will continue to pay into the EU budget during the transition. This means existing schemes, paid for by EU grants, will continue to be funded.

UK-EU trade will continue without any extra charges or checks being introduced.</TEXT>
      <URL>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-politics-51194363</URL>
   </DOC>
</DATA>
